EU rejects German call to boycott British lamb .
Peter Blackburn
BRUSSELS 1996-08-22
The European Commission said on Thursday it disagreed with German advice to consumers to shun British lamb until scientists determine whether mad cow disease can be transmitted to sheep .
Germany 's representative to the European Union 's veterinary committee Werner Zwingmann said on Wednesday consumers should buy sheepmeat from countries other than Britain until the scientific advice was clearer .
" We do n't support any such recommendation because we do n't see any grounds for it , " the Commission 's chief spokesman Nikolaus van der Pas told a news briefing .
He said further scientific study was required and if it was found that action was needed it should be taken by the European Union .
He said a proposal last month by EU Farm Commissioner Franz Fischler to ban sheep brains , spleens and spinal cords from the human and animal food chains was a highly specific and precautionary move to protect human health .
Fischler proposed EU-wide measures after reports from Britain and France that under laboratory conditions sheep could contract Bovine Spongiform Encephalopathy ( BSE ) -- mad cow disease .
But Fischler agreed to review his proposal after the EU 's standing veterinary committee , mational animal health officials , questioned if such action was justified as there was only a slight risk to human health .
Spanish Farm Minister Loyola de Palacio had earlier accused Fischler at an EU farm ministers ' meeting of causing unjustified alarm through " dangerous generalisation . "
.
Only France and Britain backed Fischler 's proposal .
The EU 's scientific veterinary and multidisciplinary committees are due to re-examine the issue early next month and make recommendations to the senior veterinary officials .
Sheep have long been known to contract scrapie , a brain-wasting disease similar to BSE which is believed to have been transferred to cattle through feed containing animal waste .
British farmers denied on Thursday there was any danger to human health from their sheep , but expressed concern that German government advice to consumers to avoid British lamb might influence consumers across Europe .
" What we have to be extremely careful of is how other countries are going to take Germany 's lead , " Welsh National Farmers ' Union ( NFU ) chairman John Lloyd Jones said on BBC radio .
Bonn has led efforts to protect public health after consumer confidence collapsed in March after a British report suggested humans could contract an illness similar to mad cow disease by eating contaminated beef .
Germany imported 47,600 sheep from Britain last year , nearly half of total imports .
It brought in 4,275 tonnes of British mutton , some 10 percent of overall imports .
Rare Hendrix song draft sells for almost $ 17,000 .
LONDON 1996-08-22
A rare early handwritten draft of a song by U.S. guitar legend Jimi Hendrix was sold for almost $ 17,000 on Thursday at an auction of some of the late musician 's favourite possessions .
A Florida restaurant paid 10,925 pounds ( $ 16,935 ) for the draft of " Ai n't no telling " , which Hendrix penned on a piece of London hotel stationery in late 1966 .
At the end of a January 1967 concert in the English city of Nottingham he threw the sheet of paper into the audience , where it was retrieved by a fan .
Buyers also snapped up 16 other items that were put up for auction by Hendrix 's former girlfriend Kathy Etchingham , who lived with him from 1966 to 1969 .
They included a black lacquer and mother of pearl inlaid box used by Hendrix to store his drugs , which an anonymous Australian purchaser bought for 5,060 pounds ( $ 7,845 ) .
The guitarist died of a drugs overdose in 1970 aged 27 .
China says Taiwan spoils atmosphere for talks .
BEIJING 1996-08-22
China on Thursday accused Taipei of spoiling the atmosphere for a resumption of talks across the Taiwan Strait with a visit to Ukraine by Taiwanese Vice President Lien Chan this week that infuriated Beijing .
Speaking only hours after Chinese state media said the time was right to engage in political talks with Taiwan , Foreign Ministry spokesman Shen Guofang told Reuters : " The necessary atmosphere for the opening of the talks has been disrupted by the Taiwan authorities . "
State media quoted China 's top negotiator with Taipei , Tang Shubei , as telling a visiting group from Taiwan on Wednesday that it was time for the rivals to hold political talks .
" Now is the time for the two sides to engage in political talks ...
that is to end the state of hostility , " Thursday 's overseas edition of the People 's Daily quoted Tang as saying .
The foreign ministry 's Shen told Reuters Television in an interview he had read reports of Tang 's comments but gave no details of why the negotiator had considered the time right for talks with Taiwan , which Beijing considers a renegade province .
China , which has long opposed all Taipei efforts to gain greater international recognition , was infuriated by a visit to Ukraine this week by Taiwanese Vice President Lien .
China says time right for Taiwan talks .
BEIJING 1996-08-22
China has said it was time for political talks with Taiwan and that the rival island should take practical steps towards that goal .
Consultations should be held to set the time and format of the talks , the official Xinhua news agency quoted Tang Shubei , executive vice chairman of the Association for Relations Across the Taiwan Straits , as saying late on Wednesday .
German July car registrations up 14.2 pct yr / yr .
FRANKFURT 1996-08-22
German first-time registrations of motor vehicles jumped 14.2 percent in July this year from the year-earlier period , the Federal office for motor vehicles said on Thursday .
The office said 356,725 new cars were registered in July 1996 -- 304,850 passenger cars and 15,613 trucks .
The figures represent a 13.6 percent increase for passenger cars and a 2.2 percent decline for trucks from July 1995 .
Motor-bike registration rose 32.7 percent in the period .
The growth was partly due to an increased number of Germans buying German cars abroad , while manufacturers said that domestic demand was weak , the federal office said .
Almost all German car manufacturers posted gains in registration numbers in the period .
Volkswagen AG won 77,719 registrations , slightly more than a quarter of the total .
Opel AG together with General Motors came in second place with 49,269 registrations , 16.4 percent of the overall figure .
Third was Ford with 35,563 registrations , or 11.7 percent .
Only Seat and Porsche had fewer registrations in July 1996 compared to last year 's July .
Seat posted 3,420 registrations compared with 5522 registrations in July a year earlier .
Porsche 's registrations fell to 554 from 643 .
GREEK SOCIALISTS GIVE GREEN LIGHT TO PM FOR ELECTIONS .
ATHENS 1996-08-22
The Greek socialist party 's executive bureau gave the green light to Prime Minister Costas Simitis to call snap elections , its general secretary Costas Skandalidis told reporters .
Prime Minister Costas Simitis is going to make an official announcement after a cabinet meeting later on Thursday , said Skandalidis .
-- Dimitris Kontogiannis , Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4
BayerVB sets C$ 100 million six-year bond .
LONDON 1996-08-22
The following bond was announced by lead manager Toronto Dominion .
BORROWER BAYERISCHE VEREINSBANK
AMT C$ 100 MLN COUPON 6.625 MATURITY 24.SEP.02
TYPE STRAIGHT ISS PRICE 100.92 PAY DATE 24.SEP.96
FULL FEES 1.875 REOFFER 99.32 SPREAD +20 BP
MOODY AA1 LISTING LUX PAY FREQ =
S&P = DENOMS ( K ) 1-10-100 SALE LIMITS US / UK / CA
NEG PLG NO CRS DEFLT NO FORCE MAJ =
GOV LAW GERMAN HOME CTRY = TAX PROVS STANDARD
MGT / UND 0.275 SELL CONC 1.60 PRAECIP =
UNDERLYING GOVT BOND 7.0 PCT SEPT 2001
NOTES BAYERISCHE VEREINSBANK IS JOINT LEAD MANAGER
-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7658
Venantius sets $ 300 million January 1999 FRN .
LONDON 1996-08-22
The following floating-rate issue was announced by lead manager Lehman Brothers International .
BORROWER VENANTIUS AB ( SWEDISH NATIONAL MORTGAGE AGENCY )
AMT $ 300 MLN SPREAD - 12.5 BP MATURITY 21.JAN.99
TYPE FRN BASE 3M LIBOR PAY DATE S23.SEP.96
LAST MOODY AA3 ISS PRICE 99.956 FULL FEES 10 BP
LAST S&P AA+ REOFFER =
NOTES S SHORT FIRST COUPON
LISTING LONDON DENOMS ( K ) 1-10-100 SALE LIMITS US / UK / JP / FR
NEG PLG YES CRS DEFLT NO FORCE MAJ IPMA 2
GOV LAW ENGLISH HOME CTRY SWEDEN TAX PROVS STANDARD
MGT / UND 5 BP SELL CONC 5 BP PRAECIP =
NOTES ISSUED OFF EMTN PROGRAMME
-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8863
Port conditions update - Syria - Lloyds Shipping .
Port conditions from Lloyds Shipping Intelligence Service --
LATTAKIA , Aug 10 - waiting time at Lattakia and Tartous presently 24 hours .
Israel plays down fears of war with Syria .
Colleen Siegel
JERUSALEM 1996-08-22
Israel 's outgoing peace negotiator with Syria said on Thursday current tensions between the two countries appeared to be a storm in a teacup .
Itamar Rabinovich , who as Israel 's ambassador to Washington conducted unfruitful negotiations with Syria , told Israel Radio it looked like Damascus wanted to talk rather than fight .
" It appears to me the Syrian priority is still to negotiate .
The Syrians are confused , they are definitely tense , but the general assessment here in Washington is that this is essentially a storm in a teacup , " he said .
Rabinovich is winding up his term as ambassador .
He will be replaced by Eliahu Ben-Elissar , a former Israeli envoy to Egypt and right-wing Likud party politician .
Israel on Wednesday sent Syria a message , via Washington , saying it was committed to peace and wanted to open negotiations without preconditions .
But it slammed Damascus for creating what it called a dangerous atmosphere .
Syria accused Israel on Wednesday of launching a hysterical campaign against it after Israeli television reported that Damascus had recently test fired a missile .
It said its arms purchases were for defensive purposes .
" The message that we sent to ( Syrian President Hafez al- ) Assad is that Israel is ready at any time without preconditions to enter peace negotiations , " Israeli Foreign Minister David Levy told Israel Radio in an interview .
Tension has mounted since Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu took office in June vowing to retain the Golan Heights Israel captured from Syria in the 1967 Middle East war .
Israeli-Syrian peace talks have been deadlocked over the Golan since 1991 despite the previous government 's willingness to make Golan concessions .
Peace talks between the two sides were last held in February .
" The voices coming out of Damascus are bad , not good .
The media ...
are full of expressions and declarations that must be worrying ...
this artificial atmosphere is very dangerous because those who spread it could become its prisoners , " Levy said .
" We expect from Syria , if its face is to peace , that it will answer Israel 's message to enter peace negotiations because that is our goal , " he said . "
We do not want a war , God forbid .
No one benefits from wars . "
Israel 's Channel Two television said Damascus had sent a " calming signal " to Israel .
It gave no source for the report .
Netanyahu and Levy 's spokesmen said they could not confirm it .
The television also said that Netanyahu had sent messages to reassure Syria via Cairo , the United States and Moscow .
Polish diplomat denies nurses stranded in Libya .
TUNIS 1996-08-22
A Polish diplomat on Thursday denied a Polish tabloid report this week that Libya was refusing exit visas to 100 Polish nurses trying to return home after working in the North African country .
" This is not true .
Up to today , we have no knowledge of any nurse stranded or kept in Libya without her will , and we have not received any complaint , " the Polish embassy 's charge d'affaires in Tripoli , Tadeusz Awdankiewicz , told Reuters by telephone .
Poland 's labour ministry said this week it would send a team to Libya to investigate , but Awdankiewicz said the probe was prompted by some nurses complaining about their work conditions such as non-payment of their salaries .
He said that there are an estimated 800 Polish nurses working in Libya .
Two Iranian opposition leaders meet in Baghdad .
Hassan Hafidh
BAGHDAD 1996-08-22
An Iranian exile group based in Iraq vowed on Thursday to extend support to Iran 's Kurdish rebels after they were attacked by Iranian troops deep inside Iraq last month .
A Mujahideen Khalq statement said its leader Massoud Rajavi met in Baghdad the Secretary-General of the Kurdistan Democratic Party of Iran ( KDPI ) Hassan Rastegar on Wednesday and voiced his support to Iran 's rebel Kurds .
" Rajavi emphasised that the Iranian Resistance would continue to stand side by side with their Kurdish compatriots and the resistance movement in Iranian Kurdistan , " it said .
A spokesman for the group said the meeting " signals a new level of cooperation between Mujahideen Khalq and the Iranian Kurdish oppositions " .
Iran heavily bombarded targets in northern Iraq in July in pursuit of KDPI guerrillas based in Iraqi Kurdish areas outside the control of the government in Baghdad .
Iraqi Kurdish areas bordering Iran are under the control of guerrillas of the Iraqi Kurdish Patriotic Union of Kurdistan ( PUK ) group .
PUK and Iraq 's Kurdistan Democratic Party ( KDP ) the two main Iraqi Kurdish factions , have had northern Iraq under their control since Iraqi forces were ousted from Kuwait in the 1991 Gulf War .
Clashes between the two parties broke out at the weekend in the most serious fighting since a U.S.-sponsored ceasefire last year .
Mujahideen Khalq said Iranian troops had also been shelling KDP positions in Qasri region in Suleimaniya province near the Iranian border over the last two days .
It said about 100 Iraqi Kurds were killed or wounded in the attack .
Both Iran and Turkey mount air and land strikes at targets in northern Iraq in pursuit of their own Kurdish rebels .
A U.S.-led air force in southern Turkey protects Iraqi Kurds from possible attacks by Baghdad troops .
Saudi riyal rates steady in quiet summer trade .
MANAMA 1996-08-22
The spot Saudi riyal against the dollar and riyal interbank deposit rates were mainly steady this week in quiet summer trade , dealers in the kingdom said .
" There were no changes in Saudi riyal rates .
The market was very quiet because of summer holidays , " one dealer said .
The spot riyal was put at 3.7504 / 06 to the dollar .
One-month interbank deposits were at 5-1/2 , 3/8 percent , three months were 5-5/8 , 1/2 percent and six months were 5-3/4 , 5/8 percent .
One-year funds were at six , 5-7/8 percent .
Israel approves Arafat 's flight to West Bank .
JERUSALEM 1996-08-22
Israel gave Palestinian President Yasser Arafat permission on Thursday to fly over its territory to the West Bank , ending a brief Israeli-PLO crisis , an Arafat adviser said .
" The problem is over .
The president 's aircraft has received permission to pass through Israeli airspace but the president is not expected to travel to the West Bank before Monday , " Nabil Abu Rdainah told Reuters .
Arafat had been scheduled to meet former Israeli prime minister Shimon Peres in the West Bank town of Ramallah on Thursday but the venue was changed to Gaza after Israel denied flight clearance to the Palestinian leader 's helicopters .
Palestinian officials accused right-wing Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu of trying to stop the Ramallah meeting by keeping Arafat grounded .
Arafat subsequently cancelled a meeting between Israeli and PLO officials , on civilian affairs , at the Allenby Bridge crossing between Jordan and the West Bank .
Abu Rdainah said Arafat had decided against flying to the West Bank on Thursday , after Israel lifted the ban , because he had a busy schedule in Gaza and would not be free until Monday .
Arafat to meet Peres in Gaza after flight ban .
JERUSALEM 1996-08-22
Yasser Arafat will meet Shimon Peres in Gaza on Thursday after Palestinians said the right-wing Israeli government had barred the Palestinian leader from flying to the West Bank for talks with the former prime minister .
" The meeting between Peres and Arafat will take place at Erez checkpoint in Gaza and not in Ramallah as planned , " Peres ' office said .
Palestinian officials said the Israeli government had barred Arafat from overflying Israel in a Palestinian helicopter to the West Bank in an attempt to bar the meeting with Peres .
Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has accused opposition leader Peres , who he defeated in May elections , of trying to undermine his Likud government 's authority to conduct peace talks .
Afghan UAE embassy says Taleban guards going home .
Hilary Gush
DUBAI 1996-08-22
Three Afghan guards brought to the United Arab Emirates last week by Russian hostages who escaped from the Taleban militia will return to Afghanistan in a few days , the Afghan embassy in Abu Dhabi said on Thursday .
" Our ambassador is in touch with the UAE foreign ministry .
Their return to Afghanistan will take place in two or three days , " an embassy official said .
" The embassy is issuing them travel documents for their return to their homeland .
There is no objection to their travel , " he added .
The three Islamic Taleban guards were overpowered by seven Russian aircrew who escaped to UAE state Sharjah last Friday on board their own aircraft after a year in the captivity of Taleban militia in Kandahar in southern Afghanistan .
The UAE said on Monday it would hand over the three to the International Red Crescent , possibly last Tuesday .
It has since been silent on the issue .
When asked whether the three guards would travel back to Kandahar or the Afghan capital Kabul , the embassy official said : " That has not been decided , but possibly Kandahar . "
Kandahar is the headquarters of the opposition Taleban militia .
Kabul is controlled by President Burhanuddin Rabbani 's government , which Taleban is fighting to overthrow .
The embassy official said the three men , believed to be in their 20s , were currently in Abu Dhabi .
He did not elaborate .
The Russians , working for the Aerostan firm in the Russian republic of Tatarstan , were taken hostage after a Taleban MiG-19 fighter forced their cargo plane to land in August 1995 .
Taleban said its shipment of ammunition from Albania was evidence of Russian military support for Rabbani 's government .
Moscow said the crew 's nationality was coincidental .
Numerous diplomatic attempts to free the seven failed .
The Russians , who said they overpowered the guards -- two armed with Kalashnikov automatic rifles -- while doing regular maintenance work on their Ilyushin 76 cargo plane last Friday , left the UAE capital Abu Dhabi for home on Sunday .
Iraq 's Saddam meets Russia 's Zhirinovsky .
BAGHDAD 1996-08-22
Iraqi President Saddam Hussein has told visiting Russian ultra-nationalist Vladimir Zhirinovsky that Baghdad wanted to maintain " friendship and cooperation " with Moscow , official Iraqi newspapers said on Thursday .
" President Saddam Hussein stressed during the meeting Iraq 's keenness to maintain friendship and cooperation with Russia , " the papers said .
They said Zhirinovsky told Saddam before he left Baghdad on Wednesday that his Liberal Democratic party and the Russian Duma ( parliament ) " are calling for an immediate lifting of the embargo " imposed on Iraq after its 1990 invasion of Kuwait .
Zhirinovsky said on Tuesday he would press the Russian government to help end U.N. trade sanctions on Iraq and blamed Moscow for delaying establishment of good ties with Baghdad .
" Our stand is firm , namely we are calling on ( the Russian ) government to end the economic embargo on Iraq and resume trade ties between Russia and Iraq , " he told reporters .
Zhirinovsky visited Iraq twice in 1995 .
Last October he was invited to attend the referendum held on Iraq 's presidency , which extended Saddam 's term for seven more years .
PRESS DIGEST - Iraq - Aug 22 .
BAGHDAD 1996-08-22
These are some of the leading stories in the official Iraqi press on Thursday .
Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy .
THAWRA
- Iraq 's President Saddam Hussein meets with chairman of the Russian liberal democratic party Vladimir Zhirinovsky .
- Turkish foreign minister says Turkey will take part in the Baghdad trade fair that will be held in November .
IRAQ
- A shipload of 12 tonnes of rice arrives in Umm Qasr port in the Gulf .
PRESS DIGEST - Lebanon - Aug 22 .
BEIRUT 1996-08-22
These are the leading stories in the Beirut press on Thursday .
Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy .
AN-NAHAR
- Confrontation is escalating between Hizbollah and the government .
- Prime Minister Hariri : Israeli threats do no serve peace .
AS-SAFIR
- Parliament Speaker Berri : Israel is preparing for war against Syria and Lebanon .
- Parliamentary battle in Beirut ..
The three main lists have been prepared .
AL-ANWAR
- Continued criticism of law violation incidents -- which occurred in the Mount Lebanon elections last Sunday .
AD-DIYAR
- Financial negotiations between Lebanon and Pakistan .
- Hariri to step into the election battle with an incomplete list .
NIDA'A AL-WATAN
- Maronite Patriarch Sfeir expressed sorrow over the violations in Sunday ' elections .
CME live and feeder cattle calls range mixed .
CHICAGO 1996-08-22
Early calls on CME live and feeder cattle futures ranged from 0.200 cent higher to 0.100 lower , livestock analysts said .
The continued strong tone to cash cattle and beef markets should prompt further support .
Outlook for a bullish cattle-on-feed report is also expected to lend support and prompt some bull spreading , analysts said .
However , trade will likely be light and prices could drift on evening up ahead of the report .
Cash markets are also expected to be quiet after the record amount of feedlot cattle traded this week , they said .
Kindercare says debt buy to hit Q1 results .
MONTGOMERY , Ala .
1996-08-22
KinderCare Learning Centers Inc said on Thursday that a debt buyback would mean an extraordinary loss of $ 1.2 million in its fiscal 1997 first quarter .
The company said that during the quarter , which began June 1 , it bought $ 30 million par value of its outstanding 10-3/8 percent senior notes due 2001 .
The notes were bought for $ 31.5 million .
Philip Maslowe , chief financial officer of the preschool and child care company , said the buyback " offered an opportunity to reduce the company 's weighted average interest costs and improve future cash flows and earnings . "
RESEARCH ALERT - Lehman starts SNET .
-- Lehman analyst Blake Bath started Southern New England Telecommunciations Corp with an outperform rating , his office said .
-- The analyst set a 12-month price target of $ 45 and a fiscal 1996 year earnings estimate of $ 3.09 per share , his office said .
-- The analyst also set an earnings estimate for the 1997 year , but the figure was not immediately available .
-- Southern New England closed at 38-1/2 Wednesday .
-- E. Auchard , Wall Street bureau , 212-859-1736
Gateway Data Sciences Q2 net rises .
PHOENIX 1996-08-22
Summary of Consolidated Financial Data
( In Thousands , except per share data )
Six Months Ended Quarter Ended
Jul 31 , Jul 31 , Jul 31 , Jul 31 ,
1996 1995 1996 1995
Income Statement Data :
Total Revenue $ 10,756 $ 13,102 $ 7,961 $ 5,507
Software Revenue 2,383 1,558 1,086 1,074
Services Revenue 1,154 692 624 465
Operating Income 906 962 599 515
Net Income 821 512 565 301
Earnings Per Share 0.31 0.34 0.19 0.20
Jul 31 , 1996 Jan 31 , 1996
Balance Sheet Data :
Working Capital $ 5,755 ( $ 881 )
Cash and Cash Equivalents 2,386 93
Total Assets 14,196 7,138
Shareholders ' Equity 5,951 ( 1,461 )
Greek socialists give PM green light for election .
ATHENS 1996-08-22
The Greek socialist party 's executive bureau gave Prime Minister Costas Simitis its backing if he chooses to call snap elections , its general secretary Costas Skandalidis told reporters on Thursday .
Prime Minister Costas Simitis will make an official announcement after a cabinet meeting later on Thursday , said Skandalidis .
-- Dimitris Kontogiannis , Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4
PRESS DIGEST - France - Le Monde Aug 22 .
PARIS 1996-08-22
These are leading stories in Thursday 's afternoon daily Le Monde , dated Aug 23 .
FRONT PAGE
-- Africans seeking to renew or obtain work and residence rights say Prime Minister Alain Juppe 's proposals are insufficient as hunger strike enters 49th day in Paris church and Wednesday rally attracts 8,000 sympathisers .
-- FLNC Corsican nationalist movement announces end of truce after last night 's attacks .
BUSINESS PAGES
-- Shutdown of Bally 's French factories points up shoe industry crisis , with French manufacturers undercut by low-wage country competition and failure to keep abreast of trends .
-- Secretary general of the Sud-PTT trade union at France Telecom all the elements are in place for social unrest in the next few weeks .
-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 42 21 53 81
Well repairs to lift Heidrun oil output - Statoil .
OSLO 1996-08-22
Three plugged water injection wells on the Heidrun oilfield off mid-Norway will be reopened over the next month , operator Den Norske Stats Oljeselskap AS ( Statoil ) said on Thursday .
The plugged wells have accounted for a dip of 30,000 barrels per day ( bpd ) in Heidrun output to roughly 220,000 bpd , according to the company 's Status Weekly newsletter .
The wells will be reperforated and gravel will be pumped into the reservoir through one of the wells to avoid plugging problems in the future , it said .
-- Oslo newsroom +47 22 42 50 41
Finnish April trade surplus 3.8 billion markka - NCB .
HELSINKI 1996-08-22
Finland 's trade surplus rose to 3.83 billion markka in April from 3.43 billion in March , the National Customs Board ( NCB ) said in a statement on Thursday .
The value of exports fell one percent year-on-year in April and the value of imports fell two percent , NCB said .
Trade balance ( million markka ) :
April ' 96 March ' 96 Jan-April ' 96 Jan-April ' 95
Imports 10,663 10,725 43,430 40,989
Exports 14,494 14,153 56,126 56,261
Balance +3,831 +3,428 +12,696 +15,272
The January-April 1995 import figure was revised from 39,584 million markka and the export figure from 55,627 million markka .
The Bank of Finland earlier estimated the April trade surplus at 3.2 billion markka with exports projected at 14.5 billion and imports at 11.3 billion .
The NCB 's official monthly trade statistics are lagging behind due to changes in customs procedures when Finland joined the European Union at the start of 1995 .
-- Helsinki Newsroom +358 - 0 - 680 50 245
Dutch state raises tap sale price to 99.95 .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-22
The Finance Ministry raised the price for tap sales of the Dutch government 's new 5.75 percent bond due September 2002 to 99.95 from 99.90 .
Tap sales began on Monday and are being held daily from 07.00 GMT to 15.00 GMT until further notice .
The ministry had raised 2.3 billion guilders from sales of the new bond by the close of trade on Wednesday .
-- Amsterdam newsroom +31 20 504 5000
German farm ministry tells consumers to avoid British mutton .
BONN 1996-08-22
Germany 's Agriculture Ministry suggested on Wednesday that consumers avoid eating meat from British sheep until scientists determine whether mad cow disease can be transmitted to the animals .
" Until this is cleared up by the European Union 's scientific panels -- and we have asked this to be done as quickly as possible -- ( consumers ) should if at all possible give preference to sheepmeat from other countries , " ministry official Werner Zwingmann told ZDF television .
" I do not want to say that there is a concrete danger for consumers , " he added . "
There are too many holes in what we know , and these must be filled very quickly . "
Bonn has led efforts to ensure consumer protection tops the list of priorities in dealing with the mad cow crisis , which erupted in March when Britain acknowledged humans could contract a similar illness by eating contaminated beef .
The European Commission agreed this month to rethink a proposal to ban the use of suspect sheep tissue after some EU veterinary experts questioned whether it was justified .
EU Farm Commissioner Franz Fischler had proposed banning sheep brains , spleens and spinal cords from the human and animal food chains after reports from Britain and France that under laboratory conditions sheep could contract Bovine Spongiform Encephalopathy ( BSE ) -- mad cow disease .
But some members of the EU 's standing veterinary committee questioned whether the action was necessary given the slight risk to human health .
The question is being studied separately by two EU scientific committees .
Sheep have long been known to contract scrapie , a similar brain-wasting disease to BSE which is believed to have been transferred to cattle through feed containing animal waste .
British officials say sheep meat is perfectly safe to eat .
ZDF said Germany imported 47,600 sheep from Britain last year , nearly half of total imports .
It brought in 4,275 tonnes of British mutton , some 10 percent of overall imports .
After the British government admitted a possible link between mad cow disease and its fatal human equivalent , the EU imposed a worldwide ban on British beef exports .
EU leaders agreed at a summit in June to a progressive lifting of the ban as Britain takes parallel measures to eradicate the disease .
GOLF - SCORES AT WORLD SERIES OF GOLF .
AKRON , Ohio 1996-08-22
Scores from the $ 2.1
million NEC World Series of Golf after the first round
Thursday at the 7,149 yard , par 70 Firestone C.C course
( players U.S. unless stated ) :
66 Paul Goydos , Billy Mayfair , Hidemichi Tanaka ( Japan )
68 Steve Stricker
69 Justin Leonard , Mark Brooks
70 Tim Herron , Duffy Waldorf , Davis Love , Anders Forsbrand
( Sweden ) , Nick Faldo ( Britain ) , John Cook , Steve Jones , Phil
Mickelson , Greg Norman ( Australia )
71 Ernie Els ( South Africa ) , Scott Hoch
72 Clarence Rose , Loren Roberts , Fred Funk , Sven Struver
( Germany ) , Alexander Cejka ( Germany ) , Hal Sutton , Tom Lehman
73 D.A. Weibring , Brad Bryant , Craig Parry ( Australia ) ,
Stewart Ginn ( Australia ) , Corey Pavin , Craig Stadler , Mark
O'Meara , Fred Couples
74 Paul Stankowski , Costantino Rocca ( Italy )
75 Jim Furyk , Satoshi Higashi ( Japan ) , Willie Wood , Shigeki
Maruyama ( Japan )
76 Scott McCarron
77 Wayne Westner ( South Africa ) , Steve Schneiter
79 Tom Watson
81 Seiki Okuda ( Japan )
SOCCER - GLORIA BISTRITA BEAT 2-1 F.C. VALLETTA .
BISTRITA 1996-08-22
Gloria Bistrita ( Romania ) beat 2-1 ( halftime 1-1 ) F.C. Valletta ( Malta ) in their Cup winners Cup match , second leg of the preliminary round , on Thursday .
Scorers :
Gloria Bistrita - Ilie Lazar ( 32nd ) , Eugen Voica ( 84th )
F.C. La Valletta - Gilbert Agius ( 24th )
Attendance : 8,000
Gloria Bistrita won 4-2 on aggregate and qualified for the first round of the Cup winners Cup .
REUTER
HORSE RACING - PIVOTAL ENDS 25-YEAR WAIT FOR TRAINER PRESCOTT .
YORK , England 1996-08-22
Sir Mark Prescott landed his first group one victory in 25 years as a trainer when his top sprinter Pivotal , a 100-30 chance , won the Nunthorpe Stakes on Thursday .
The three-year-old , partnered by veteran George Duffield , snatched a short head verdict in the last stride to deny Eveningperformance ( 16-1 ) , trained by Henry Candy and ridden by Chris Rutter .
Hever Golf Rose ( 11-4 ) , last year 's Prix de l ' Abbaye winner at Longchamp , finished third , a further one and a quarter lengths away with the 7-4 favourite Mind Games in fourth .
Pivotal , a Royal Ascot winner in June , may now be aimed at this season 's Abbaye , Europe 's top sprint race .
Prescott , reluctant to go into the winner 's enclosure until the result of the photo-finish was announced , said : " Twenty-five years and I have never been there so I thought I had better wait a bit longer . "
He added : " It 's very sad to beat Henry Candy because I am godfather to his daughter . "
Like Prescott , Jack Berry , trainer of Mind Games , had gone into Thursday 's race in search of a first group one success after many years around the top of his profession .
Berry said : " I`m disappointed but I do n't feel suicidal .
He ( Mind Games ) was going as well as any of them one and a half furlongs ( 300 metres ) out but he just did n't quicken . "
HORSE RACING - NUNTHORPE STAKES RESULTS .
YORK , England 1996-08-22
Result of the Nunthorpe Stakes , a group one race for two-year-olds and upwards , run over five furlongs ( 1 km ) on Thursday :
1. Pivotal 100-30 ( ridden by George Duffield )
2. Eveningperformance 16-1 ( Chris Rutter )
3. Hever Golf Rose 11-4 ( Jason Weaver )
Eight ran .
Favourite : Mind Games ( 7-4 ) finished 4th
Distances : a short head , 1-1/4 lengths .
Winner owned by the Cheveley Park Stud and trained by Sir
Mark Prescott at Newmarket .
Value to winner : 72,464 pounds sterling ( $ 112,200 )
TENNIS - RESULTS AT TOSHIBA CLASSIC .
CARLSBAD , California 1996-08-21
Results from the
$ 450,000 Toshiba Classic tennis tournament on Wednesday
( prefix number denotes seeding ) :
Second round
1 - Arantxa Sanchez Vicario ( Spain ) beat Naoko Kijimuta ( Japan )
1-6 6-4 6-3
4 - Kimiko Date ( Japan ) beat Yone Kamio ( Japan ) 6-2 7-5
Sandrine Testud ( France ) beat 7 - Ai Sugiyama ( Japan ) 6-3 4-6
6-4
8 - Nathalie Tauziat ( France ) beat Shi-Ting Wang ( Taiwan ) 6-4
6-2
TENNIS - RESULTS AT HAMLET CUP .
COMMACK , New York 1996-08-21
Results from the
Waldbaum Hamlet Cup tennis tournament on Wednesday ( prefix
number denotes seeding ) :
Second round
1 - Michael Chang ( U.S. ) beat Sergi Bruguera ( Spain ) 6-3 6-2
Michael Joyce ( U.S. ) beat 3 - Richey Reneberg ( U.S. ) 3-6 6-4
6-3
Martin Damm ( Czech Republic ) beat 6 - Younes El Aynaoui
( Morocco ) 5-7 6-3 3-0 retired
Karol Kucera ( Slovakia ) beat Hicham Arazi ( Morocco ) 7-6 ( 7-4 )
7-5
SOCCER - DALGLISH SAD OVER BLACKBURN PARTING .
LONDON 1996-08-22
Kenny Dalglish spoke on Thursday of his sadness at leaving Blackburn , the club he led to the English premier league title in 1994-95 .
Blackburn announced on Wednesday they and Dalglish had parted by mutual consent .
But the ex-manager confessed on Thursday to being " sad " at leaving after taking Blackburn from the second division to the premier league title inside three and a half years .
In a telephone call to a local newspaper from his holiday home in Spain , Dalglish said : " We came to the same opinion , albeit the club came to it a little bit earlier than me . "
He added : " If no one asked , I never opened my mouth .
I have stayed out of the way and let them get on with the job .
The club thought it ( the job ) had run its course and I came to the same conclusion . "
Dalglish had been with Blackburn for nearly five years , first as manager and then , for the past 15 months , as director of football .
CRICKET - ENGLISH COUNTY CHAMPIONSHIP SCORES .
LONDON 1996-08-22
Close of play scores in four-day
English County Championship cricket matches on Thursday :
Second day
At Weston-super-Mare : Durham 326 ( D. Cox 95 not out ,
S. Campbell 69 ; G. Rose 7-73 ) .
Somerset 236-4 ( M. Lathwell 85 ) .
Firsy day
At Colchester : Gloucestershire 280 ( J. Russell 63 , A. Symonds
52 ; A. Cowan 5-68 ) .
Essex 72-0 .
At Cardiff : Kent 128-1 ( M. Walker 59 , D. Fulton 53 not out ) v
Glamorgan .
At Leicester : Leicestershire 343-8 ( P. Simmons 108 , P. Nixon
67 not out ) v Hampshire .
At Northampton : Sussex 368-7 ( N. Lenham 145 , V. Drakes 59 not
out , A. Wells 51 ) v Northamptonshire .
At Trent Bridge : Nottinghamshire 392-6 ( G. Archer 143 not
out , M. Dowman 107 ) v Surrey .
At Worcester : Warwickshire 255-9 ( A. Giles 57 not out , W. Khan
52 ) v Worcestershire .
At Headingley : Yorkshire 305-5 ( C. White 66 not out , M. Moxon
66 , M. Vaughan 57 ) v Lancashire .
CRICKET - ENGLAND V PAKISTAN FINAL TEST SCOREBOARD .
LONDON 1996-08-22
Scoreboard on the first day of the
third and final test between England and Pakistan at The Oval on
Thursday :
England first innings
M. Atherton b Waqar Younis 31
A. Stewart b Mushtaq Ahmed 44
N. Hussain c Saeed Anwar b Waqar Younis 12
G. Thorpe lbw b Mohammad Akram 54
J. Crawley not out 94
N. Knight b Mushtaq Ahmed 17
C. Lewis b Wasim Akram 5
I. Salisbury not out 1
Extras ( lb-11 w-1 nb-8 ) 20
Total ( for six wickets ) 278
Fall of wickets : 1-64 2-85 3-116 4-205 5-248 6-273
To bat : R. Croft , D. Cork , A. Mullally
Bowling ( to date ) : Wasim Akram 25-8-61-1 , Waqar Younis
20-6-70-2 , Mohammad Akram 12-1-41-1 , Mushtaq Ahmed 27-5-78-2 ,
Aamir Sohail 6-1-17-0
Pakistan : Aamir Sohail , Saeed Anwar , Ijaz Ahmed ,
Inzamam-ul-Haq , Salim Malik , Asif Mujtaba , Wasim Akram , Moin
Khan , Mushtaq Ahmed , Waqar Younis , Mohammad Akam
SOCCER - FERGUSON BACK IN SCOTTISH SQUAD AFTER 20 MONTHS .
GLASGOW 1996-08-22
Everton 's Duncan Ferguson , who scored twice against Manchester United on Wednesday , was picked on Thursday for the Scottish squad after a 20-month exile .
Glasgow Rangers striker Ally McCoist , another man in form after two hat-tricks in four days , was also named for the August 31 World Cup qualifier against Austria in Vienna .
Ferguson , who served six weeks in jail in late 1995 for head-butting an opponent , won the last of his five Scotland caps in December 1994 .
Scotland manager Craig Brown said on Thursday : " I 've watched Duncan Ferguson in action twice recently and he 's bang in form .
Ally McCoist is also in great scoring form at the moment . "
Celtic 's Jackie McNamara , who did well with last season 's successful under-21 team , earns a call-up to the senior squad .
CRICKET - ENGLAND 100-2 AT LUNCH ON FIRST DAY OF THIRD TEST .
LONDON 1996-08-22
England were 100 for two at lunch on the first day of the third and final test against Pakistan at The Oval on Thursday .
SOCCER - KEANE SIGNS FOUR-YEAR CONTRACT WITH MANCHESTER UNITED .
LONDON 1996-08-22
Ireland midfielder Roy Keane has signed a new four-year contract with English league and F.A. Cup champions Manchester United .
" Roy agreed a new deal before last night 's game against Everton and we are delighted , " said United manager Alex Ferguson on Thursday .
TENNIS - RESULTS AT CANADIAN OPEN .
TORONTO 1996-08-21
Results from the Canadian Open
tennis tournament on Wednesday ( prefix number denotes
seeding ) :
Second round
Daniel Nestor ( Canada ) beat 1 - Thomas Muster ( Austria ) 6-3 7-5
Mikael Tillstrom ( Sweden ) beat 2 - Goran Ivanisevic ( Croatia )
6-7 ( 3-7 ) 6-4 6-4
3 - Wayne Ferreira ( South Africa ) beat Jiri Novak ( Czech
Republic ) 7-5 6-3
4 - Marcelo Rios ( Chile ) beat Kenneth Carlsen ( Denmark ) 6-3 6-2
6 - MaliVai Washington ( U.S. ) beat Alex Corretja ( Spain ) 6-4
6-2
7 - Todd Martin ( U.S. ) beat Renzo Furlan ( Italy ) 7-6 ( 7-3 ) 6-3
Mark Philippoussis ( Australia ) beat 8 - Marc Rosset
( Switzerland ) 6-3 3-6 7-6 ( 8-6 )
9 - Cedric Pioline ( France ) beat Gregory Carraz ( France ) 7-6
( 7-1 ) 6-4
Patrick Rafter ( Australia ) beat 11 - Alberto Berasategui
( Spain ) 6-1 6-2
Petr Korda ( Czech Republic ) beat 12 - Francisco Clavet ( Spain )
6-3 6-4
Daniel Vacek ( Czech Republic ) beat 13 - Jason Stoltenberg
( Australia ) 5-7 7-6 ( 7-1 ) 7-6 ( 13-11 )
Todd Woodbridge ( Australia beat Sebastien Lareau ( Canada ) 6-3
1-6 6-3
Alex O'Brien ( U.S. ) beat Byron Black ( Zimbabwe ) 7-6 ( 7-2 ) 6-2
Bohdan Ulihrach ( Czech Republic ) beat Andrea Gaudenzi ( Italy )
6-3 4-6 6-1
Tim Henman ( Britain ) beat Chris Woodruff ( U.S. ) , walkover
CRICKET - MILLNS SIGNS FOR BOLAND .
CAPE TOWN 1996-08-22
South African provincial side Boland said on Thursday they had signed Leicestershire fast bowler David Millns on a one year contract .
Millns , who toured Australia with England A in 1992/93 , replaces former England all-rounder Phillip DeFreitas as Boland 's overseas professional .
SOCCER - EUROPEAN CUP WINNERS ' CUP RESULTS .
TIRANA 1996-08-22
Results of European Cup Winners '
Cup qualifying round , second leg soccer matches on Thursday :
In Tirana : Flamurtari Vlore ( Albania ) 0 Chemlon Humenne
( Slovakia ) 2 ( halftime 0-0 )
Scorers : Lubarskij ( 50th minute ) , Valkucak ( 54th )
Attendance : 5,000
Chemlon Humenne win 3-0 on aggregate
In Bistrita : Gloria Bistrita ( Romania ) 2 Valletta ( Malta ) 1
( 1-1 )
Scorers :
Gloria Bistrita - Ilie Lazar ( 32nd ) , Eugen Voica ( 84th )
Valletta - Gilbert Agius ( 24th )
Attendance : 8,000
Gloria Bistrita win 4-2 on aggregate .
In Chorzow : Ruch Chorzow ( Poland ) 5 Llansantffraid ( Wales ) 0
( 1-0 )
Scorers : Arkadiusz Bak ( 1st and 55th ) , Arwel Jones ( 47th ,
own goal ) , Miroslav Bak ( 62nd and 63rd )
Attendance : 6,500
Ruch Chorzow win 6-1 on aggregate
In Larnaca : AEK Larnaca ( Cyprus ) 5 Kotaik Abovyan ( Armenia )
0 ( 2-0 )
Scorers : Zoran Kundic ( 28th ) , Klimis Alexandrou ( 41st ) ,
Milenko Kovasevic ( 60th , penalty ) , Goran Koprinovic ( 82nd ) ,
Pavlos Markou ( 84th )
Attendance : 5,000
AEK Larnaca win 5-1 on aggregate
In Siauliai : Kareda Siauliai ( Lithuania ) 0 Sion
( Switzerland ) 0
Attendance : 5,000
Sion win 4-2 on agrregate .
In Vinnytsya :
Nyva Vinnytsya ( Ukraine ) 1 Tallinna Sadam ( Estonia ) 0 ( 0-0 )
Attendance : 3,000
Aggregate score 2-2 .
Nyva qualified on away goals rule .
In Bergen : Brann ( Norway ) 2 Shelbourne ( Ireland ) 1 ( 1-1 )
Scorers :
Brann - Mons Ivar Mjelde ( 10th ) , Jan Ove Pedersen ( 72nd )
Shelbourne - Mark Rutherford ( 5th )
Attendance : 2,189
Brann win 5-2 on aggregate
In Sofia : Levski Sofia ( Bulgaria ) 1 Olimpija ( Slovenia ) 0
( 0-0 )
Scorer : Ilian Simeonov ( 58th )
Attendance : 25,000
Aggregate 1-1 .
Olimpija won 4-3 on penalties .
In Vaduz : Vaduz ( Liechtenstein ) 1 RAF Riga ( Latvia ) 1 ( 0-0 )
Scorers :
Vaduz - Daniele Polverino ( 90th )
RAF Riga - Agrins Zarins ( 47th )
Aggregate 2-2 .
Vaduz won 4-2 on penalties .
In Luxembourg : US Luxembourg ( Luxembourg ) 0 Varteks Varazdin
( Croatia ) 3 ( 0-0 )
Scorers : Drazen Beser ( 63rd ) , Miljenko Mumler ( penalty ,
78th ) , Jamir Cvetko ( 87th )
Attendance : 800
Varteks Varazdin win 5-1 on aggregate .
In Torshavn : Havnar Boltfelag ( Faroe Islands ) 0 Dynamo
Batumi ( Georgia ) 3 ( 0-2 )
Dynamo Batumi win 9-0 on aggregate .
In Prague : Sparta Prague ( Czech Republic ) 8 Glentoran
( Northern Ireland ) 0 ( 4-0 )
Scorers : Petr Gunda ( 1st and 26th ) , Lumir Mistr ( 19th ) ,
Horst Siegl ( 24th , 48th , 80th ) , Zdenek Svoboda ( 76th ) , Petr
Gabriel ( 86th )
Sparta win 10-1 on aggregate .
In Edinburgh : Hearts ( Scotland ) 1 Red Star Belgrade
( Yugoslavia ) 1 ( 1-0 )
Scorers :
Hearts - Dave McPherson ( 44th )
Red Star - Vinko Marinovic ( 59th )
Attendance : 15,062
Aggregate 1-1 .
Red Star win on away goals rule .
In Rishon-Lezion : Hapoel Ironi ( Israel ) 3 Constructorul
Chisinau ( Moldova ) 2 ( 2-1 )
Aggregate 3-3 .
Constructorul win on away goals rule .
In Anjalonkoski : MyPa-47 ( Finland ) 1 Karabach Agdam
( Azerbaijan ) 1 ( 0-0 )
Mypa-47 win 2-1 on aggregate .
In Skopje : Sloga Jugomagnat ( Macedonia ) 0 Kispest Honved
( Hungary 1 ( 0-0 )
Kispest Honved win 2-0 on aggregate .
Add Hapoel Ironi v Constructorul Chisinau
Scorers :
Rishon - Moshe Sabag ( 10th minute ) , Nissan Kapeta ( 26th ) ,
Tomas Cibola ( 58th ) .
Constructorol - Sergei Rogachev ( 42nd ) , Gennadi Skidan
( 87th ) .
Attendance : 1,500 .
SOCCER - GOTHENBURG PUT FERENCVAROS OUT OF EURO CUP .
BUDAPEST 1996-08-21
IFK Gothenburg of Sweden drew 1-1 ( 1-0 ) with Ferencvaros of Hungary in the second leg of their European Champions Cup preliminary round tie played on Wednesday .
Gothenburg go through 4-1 on aggregate .
Scorers :
Ferencvaros :
Ferenc Horvath ( 15th )
IFK Gothenburg :
Andreas Andersson ( 87th )
Attendance : 9,000
SOCCER - BRAZILIAN CHAMPIONSHIP RESULTS .
RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-08-22
Results of midweek
matches in the Brazilian soccer championship .
Bahia 2 Atletico Paranaense 0
Corinthians 1 Guarani 0
Coritiba 1 Atletico Mineiro 0
Cruzeiro 2 Vitoria 1
Flamengo 0 Juventude 1
Goias 3 Sport Recife 1
Gremio 6 Bragantino 1
Palmeiras 3 Vasco da Gama 1
Portuguesa 2 Parana 0
TENNIS - NEWCOMBE PONDERS HIS DAVIS CUP FUTURE .
SYDNEY 1996-08-22
Australian Davis Cup captain John Newcombe on Thursday signalled his possible resignation if his team loses an away tie against Croatia next month .
The former Wimbledon champion said the immediate future of Australia 's Davis Cup coach Tony Roche could also be determined by events in Split .
" If we lose this one , Tony and I will have to have a good look at giving someone else a go , " Newcombe was quoted as saying in Sydney 's Daily Telegraph newspaper .
Australia face Croatia in the world group qualifying tie on clay from September 20-22 .
Under Newcombe 's leadership , Australia were relegated from the elite world group last year , the first time the 26-time Davis Cup winners had slipped from the top rank .
Since taking over as captain from Neale Fraser in 1994 , Newcombe 's record in tandem with Roche , his former doubles partner , has been three wins and three losses .
Newcombe has selected Wimbledon semifinalist Jason Stoltenberg , Patrick Rafter , Mark Philippoussis , and Olympic doubles champions Todd Woodbridge and Mark Woodforde to face the Croatians .
The home side boasts world number six Goran Ivanisevic , and Newcombe conceded his players would be hard-pressed to beat the Croatian number one .
" We are ready to fight to our last breath -- Australia must play at its absolute best to win , " said Newcombe , who described the tie as the toughest he has faced as captain .
Australia last won the Davis Cup in 1986 , but they were beaten finalists against Germany three years ago under Fraser 's guidance .
BADMINTON - MALAYSIAN OPEN RESULTS .
KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-22
Results in the Malaysian
Open badminton tournament on Thursday ( prefix number denotes
seeding ) :
Men 's singles , third round
9/16 - Luo Yigang ( China ) beat Hwang Sun-ho ( South Korea ) 15-3
15-7
Jason Wong ( Malaysia ) beat Abdul Samad Ismail ( Malaysia ) 16-18
15-2 17-14
P. Kantharoopan ( Malaysia ) beat 3/4 - Jeroen Van Dijk
( Netherlands ) 15-11 18-14
Wijaya Indra ( Indonesia ) beat 5/8 - Pang Chen ( Malaysia ) 15-6
6-15 15-7
3/4 - Hu Zhilan ( China ) beat Nunung Subandoro ( Indonesia ) 5-15
18-15 15-6
9/16 - Hermawan Susanto ( Indonesia ) beat 1 - Fung Permadi ( Taiwan )
15-8 15-12
Women 's singles 2nd round
1 - Wang Chen ( China ) beat Cindana ( Indonesia ) 11-3 1ama ( Japan ) beat Margit Borg ( Sweden ) 11-6 11-6
Sun Jian ( China ) beat Marina Andrievskaqya ( Sweden ) 11-8 11-2
5/8 - Meluawati ( Indonesia ) beat Chan Chia Fong ( Malaysia ) 11-6
11-1
Gong Zhichao ( China ) beat Liu Lufung ( China ) 6-11 11-7 11-3
Zeng Yaqiong ( China ) beat Li Feng ( New Zealand ) 11-9 11-6
5/8 - Christine Magnusson ( Sweden ) beat Ishwari Boopathy
( Malaysia ) 11-1 10-12 11-4
2 - Zhang Ning ( China ) beat Olivia ( Indonesia ) 11-8 11-6
TENNIS - REVISED MEN 'S DRAW FOR U.S. OPEN .
NEW YORK 1996-08-22
Revised singles draw for the
U.S. Open tennis championships beginning Monday at the U.S .
National Tennis Centre ( prefix denotes seeding ) :
Men 's Draw
1 - Pete Sampras ( U.S. ) vs. Adrian Voinea ( Romania )
Jiri Novak ( Czech Republic ) vs. qualifier
Magnus Larsson ( Sweden ) vs. Alexander Volkov ( Russia )
Mikael Tillstrom ( Sweden ) vs qualifier
Qualifier vs. Andrei Olhovskiy ( Russia )
Mark Woodforde ( Australia ) vs. Mark Philippoussis ( Australia )
Roberto Carretero ( Spain ) vs. Jordi Burillo ( Spain )
Francisco Clavet ( Spain ) vs. 16 - Cedric Pioline ( France )
------------------------
9 - Wayne Ferreira ( South Africa ) vs. qualifier
Karol Kucera ( Slovakia ) vs. Jonas Bjorkman ( Sweden )
Qualifier vs. Christian Rudd ( Norway )
Alex Corretja ( Spain ) vs. Byron Black ( Zimbabwe )
David Rikl ( Czech Republic ) vs. Hicham Arazi ( Morocco )
Sjeng Schalken ( Netherlands ) vs. Gilbert Schaller ( Austria )
Grant Stafford ( South Africa ) vs. Guy Forget ( France )
Fernando Meligeni ( Brazil ) vs. 7 - Yevgeny Kafelnikov ( Russia )
------------------------
4 - Goran Ivanisevic ( Croatia ) vs. Andrei Chesnokov ( Russia )
Scott Draper ( Australia ) vs. Galo Blanco ( Spain )
Renzo Furlan ( Italy ) vs. Thomas Johansson ( Sweden )
Hendrik Dreekman ( Germany ) vs. Greg Rusedski ( Britain )
Andrei Medvedev ( Ukraine ) vs. Jean-Philippe Fleurian ( France )
Jan Kroslak ( Slovakia ) vs. Chris Woodruff ( U.S. )
Qualifier vs. Petr Korda ( Czech Republic )
Bohdan Ulihrach ( Czech Republic ) vs. 14 - Alberto Costa
( Spain )
------------------------
12 - Todd Martin ( U.S. ) vs. Younnes El Aynaoui ( Morocco )
Andrea Gaudenzi ( Italy ) vs. Shuzo Matsuoka ( Japan )
Doug Flach ( U.S. ) vs. qualifier
Mats Wilander ( Sweden ) vs. Tim Henman ( Britain )
Paul Haarhuis ( Netherlands ) vs. Michael Joyce ( U.S. )
Michael Tebbutt ( Australia ) vs. Richey Reneberg ( U.S. )
Jonathan Stark ( U.S. ) vs. Bernd Karbacher ( Germany )
Stefan Edberg ( Sweden ) vs. 5 - Richard Krajicek ( Netherlands )
------------------------
6 - Andre Agassi ( U.S. ) vs. Mauricio Hadad ( Colombia )
Marcos Ondruska ( South Africa ) vs. Felix Mantilla ( Spain )
Carlos Moya ( Spain ) vs. Scott Humphries ( U.S. )
Jan Siemerink ( Netherlands ) vs. Carl-Uwe Steeb ( Germany )
Qualifier vs. qualifier
David Wheaton ( U.S. ) vs. Kevin Kim ( U.S. )
Nicolas Lapentti ( Ecuador ) vs. Alex O'Brien ( U.S. )
Karim Alami ( Morocco ) vs. 11 - MaliVai Washington ( U.S. )
------------------------
13 - Thomas Enqvist ( Sweden ) vs. Stephane Simian ( France )
Guillaume Raoux ( France ) vs. Filip Dewulf ( Belgium )
Mark Knowles ( Bahamas ) vs. Marcelo Filippini ( Uruguay )
Todd Woodbridge ( Australia ) vs. qualifier
Kris Goossens ( Belgium ) vs. Sergi Bruguera ( Spain )
Qualifier vs. Michael Stich ( Germany )
Qualifier vs. Chuck Adams ( U.S. )
Javier Frana ( Argentina ) vs. 3 - Thomas Muster ( Austria )
------------------------
8 - Jim Courier ( U.S. ) vs. Javier Sanchez ( Spain )
Jim Grabb ( U.S. ) vs. Sandon Stolle ( Australia )
Patrick Rafter ( Australia ) vs. Kenneth Carlsen ( Denmark )
Jason Stoltenberg ( Australia ) vs. Stefano Pescosolido ( Italy )
Arnaud Boetsch ( France ) vs. Nicolas Pereira ( Venezuela )
Carlos Costa ( Spain ) vs. Magnus Gustafsson ( Sweden )
Jeff Tarango ( U.S. ) vs. Alex Radulescu ( Germany )
Qualifier vs. 10 - Marcelo Rios ( Chile )
------------------------
15 - Marc Rosset ( Switzerland vs. Jared Palmer ( U.S. )
Martin Damm ( Czech Republic ) vs. Hernan Gumy ( Argentina )
Nicklas Kulti ( Sweden ) vs. Jakob Hlasek ( Switzerland )
Cecil Mamiit ( U.S. ) vs. Alberto Berasategui ( Spain )
Vince Spadea ( U.S. ) vs. Daniel Vacek ( Czech Republic )
David Prinosil ( Germany ) vs. qualifier
Qualifier vs. Tomas Carbonell ( Spain )
Qualifier vs. 2 - Michael Chang ( U.S. )
BASEBALL - ORIOLES ' MANAGER DAVEY JOHNSON HOSPITALIZED .
BALTIMORE 1996-08-22
Baltimore Orioles manager Davey Johnson will miss Thursday night 's game against the Seattle Mariners after being admitted to a hospital with an irregular heartbeat .
The 53-year-old Johnson was hospitalized after experiencing dizziness .
" He is in no danger and will be treated and observed this evening , " said Orioles team physician Dr. William Goldiner , adding that Johnson is expected to be released on Friday .
Orioles ' bench coach Andy Etchebarren will manage the club in Johnson 's absence .
Johnson is the second manager to be hospitalized this week after California Angels skipper John McNamara was admitted to New York 's Columbia Presbyterian Hospital on Wednesday with a blood clot in his left calf .
Johnson , who played eight seasons in Baltimore , was named Orioles manager in the off-season replacing Phil Regan .
He led the Cincinnati Reds to the National League Championship Series last year and guided the New York Mets to a World Series championship in 1986 .
Baltimore has won 16 of its last 22 games to pull within five games of the slumping New York Yankees in the American League East Division .
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE STANDINGS AFTER WEDNESDAY 'S GAMES .
NEW YORK 1996-08-22
Major League Baseball
standings after games played on Wednesday ( tabulate under won ,
lost , winning percentage and games behind ) :
AMERICAN LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
NEW YORK 72 53 .576 -
BALTIMORE 67 58 .536 5
BOSTON 63 64 .496 10
TORONTO 58 69 .457 15
DETROIT 44 82 .349 28 1/2
CENTRAL DIVISION
CLEVELAND 76 51 .598 -
CHICAGO 69 59 .539 7 1/2
MINNESOTA 63 63 .500 12 1/2
MILWAUKEE 60 68 .469 16 1/2
KANSAS CITY 58 70 .453 18 1/2
WESTERN DIVISION
TEXAS 73 54 .575 -
SEATTLE 64 61 .512 8
OAKLAND 62 67 .481 12
CALIFORNIA 58 68 .460 14 1/2
THURSDAY , AUGUST 22 SCHEDULE
OAKLAND AT BOSTON
SEATTLE AT BALTIMORE
CALIFORNIA AT NEW YORK
TORONTO AT CHICAGO
DETROIT AT KANSAS CITY
TEXAS AT MINNESOTA
NATIONAL LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
ATLANTA 79 46 .632 -
MONTREAL 67 58 .536 12
NEW YORK 59 69 .461 21 1/2
FLORIDA 58 69 .457 22
PHILADELPHIA 52 75 .409 28
CENTRAL DIVISION
HOUSTON 68 59 .535 -
ST LOUIS 67 59 .532 1/2
CHICAGO 63 62 .504 4
CINCINNATI 62 62 .500 4 1/2
PITTSBURGH 53 73 .421 14 1/2
WESTERN DIVISION
SAN DIEGO 70 59 .543 -
LOS ANGELES 66 60 .524 2 1/2
COLORADO 65 62 .512 4
SAN FRANCISCO 54 70 .435 13 1/2
THURSDAY , AUGUST 22 SCHEDULE
ST LOUIS AT COLORADO
CINCINNATI AT ATLANTA
PITTSBURGH AT HOUSTON
PHILADELPHIA AT LOS ANGELES
MONTREAL AT SAN FRANCISCO
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE RESULTS WEDNESDAY .
NEW YORK 1996-08-22
Results of Major League
Baseball games played on Wednesday ( home team in CAPS ) :
American League
California 7 NEW YORK 1
DETROIT 7 Chicago 4
Milwaukee 10 MINNESOTA 7
BOSTON 6 Oakland 4
BALTIMORE 10 Seattle 5
Texas 10 CLEVELAND 8 ( in 10 )
Toronto 6 KANSAS CITY 2
National League
CHICAGO 8 Florida 3
SAN FRANCISCO 12 New York 11
ATLANTA 4 Cincinnati 3
Pittsburgh 5 HOUSTON 2
COLORADO 10 St Louis 2
Philadelphia 6 LOS ANGELES 0
SAN DIEGO 7 Montreal 2
BASEBALL - GREER HOMER IN 10TH LIFTS TEXAS PAST INDIANS .
CLEVELAND 1996-08-22
Rusty Greer 's two-run homer in the top of the 10th inning rallied the Texas Rangers to a 10-8 victory over the Cleveland Indians Wednesday in the rubber game of a three-game series between division leaders .
With one out , Greer hit a 1-1 pitch from Julian Tavarez ( 4-7 ) over the right-field fence for his 15th home run .
" It was an off-speed pitch and I just tried to get a good swing on it and put it in play , " Greer said . "
This was a big game .
The crowd was behind him and it was intense . "
The shot brought home Ivan Rodriguez , who had his second double of the game , giving him 42 this season , 41 as a catcher .
He joined Mickey Cochrane , Johnny Bench and Terry Kennedy as the only catchers with 40 doubles in a season .
The Rangers have won 10 of their last 12 games and six of nine meetings against the Indians this season .
The American League Western leaders have won eight of 15 games at Jacobs Field , joining the Yankees as the only teams with a winning record at the A.L. Central leaders ' home .
Cleveland lost for just the second time in six games .
The Indians sent the game into extra innings in the ninth on Kenny Lofton 's two-run single .
Ed Vosberg ( 1-0 ) blew his first save opportunity but got the win , allowing three hits with two walks and three strikeouts in 1 2/3 scoreless innings .
Dean Palmer hit his 30th homer for the Rangers .
In Baltimore , Cal Ripken had four hits and snapped a fifth-inning tie with a solo homer and Bobby Bonilla added a three-run shot in the seventh to power the surging Orioles to a 10-5 victory over the Seattle Mariners .
The Mariners scored four runs in the top of the fifth to tie the game 5-5 but Ripken led off the bottom of the inning with his 21st homer off starter Sterling Hitchcock ( 12-6 ) .
Bonilla 's blast was the first time Randy Johnson , last season 's Cy Young winner , allowed a run in five relief appearances since coming off the disabled list on August 6 .
Bonilla has 21 RBI and 15 runs in his last 20 games .
Baltimore has won seven of nine and 16 of its last 22 and cut the Yankees ' lead in the A.L. East to five games .
Scott Erickson ( 8-10 ) laboured to his third straight win .
Alex Rodriguez had two homers and four RBI for the Mariners , who have dropped three in a row and 11 of 15 .
He became the fifth shortstop in major-league history to hit 30 homers in a season and the first since Ripken hit 34 in 1991 .
Chris Hoiles hit his 22nd homer for Baltimore .
In New York , Jason Dickson scattered 10 hits over 6 1/3 innings in his major-league debut and Chili Davis belted a homer from each side of the plate as the California Angels defeated the Yankees 7-1 .
Dickson allowed a homer to Derek Jeter on his first major-league pitch but settled down .
He was the 27th pitcher used by the Angels this season , tying a major-league record .
Jimmy Key ( 9-10 ) took the loss as the Yankees lost their ninth in 14 games .
They stranded 11 baserunners .
California played without interim manager John McNamara , who was admitted to a New York hospital with a blood clot in his right calf .
In Boston , Mike Stanley 's bases-loaded two-run single snapped an eighth-inning tie and gave the Red Sox their third straight win , 6-4 over the Oakland Athletics .
Stanley owns a .367 career batting average with the bases loaded ( 33-for-90 ) .
Boston 's Mo Vaughn went 3-for-3 with a walk , stole home for one of his three runs scored and collected his 116th RBI .
Scott Brosius homered and drove in two runs for the Athletics , who have lost seven of their last nine games .
In Detroit , Brad Ausmus 's three-run homer capped a four-run eighth and lifted the Tigers to a 7-4 victory over the reeling Chicago White Sox .
The Tigers have won consecutive games after dropping eight in a row , but have won nine of their last 12 at home .
The White Sox have lost six of their last eight games .
In Kansas City , Juan Guzman tossed a complete-game six-hitter to win for the first time in over a month and lower his league-best ERA as the Toronto Blue Jays won their fourth straight , 6-2 over the Royals .
Guzman ( 10-8 ) won for the first time since July 16 , a span of six starts .
He allowed two runs -- one earned -- and lowered his ERA to 2.99 .
At Minnesota , John Jaha 's three-run homer , his 26th , capped a five-run eighth inning that rallied the Milwaukee Brewers to a 10-7 victory over the Twins .
Jaha added an RBI single in the ninth and had four RBI .
Jose Valentin hit his 21st homer for Milwaukee .
SOCCER - COCU DOUBLE EARNS PSV 4-1 WIN .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-22
Philip Cocu scored twice in the second half to spur PSV Eindhoven to a 4-1 away win over NEC Nijmegen in the Dutch first division on Thursday .
He scored from close range in the 54th minute and from a bicycle kick 13 minutes later .
Arthur Numan and Luc Nilis , Dutch top scorer last season , were PSV 's other marksmen .
Ajax Amsterdam opened their title defence with a 1-0 win over NAC Breda on Wednesday .
SOCCER - DUTCH FIRST DIVISION SUMMARY .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-22
Summary of Thursday 's only
Dutch first division match :
NEC Nijmegen 1 ( Van Eykeren 15th ) PSV Eindhoven 4 ( Numan 11th ,
Nilis 42nd , Cocu 54th , 67th ) .
Halftime 1-2 .
Attendance 8,000
SOCCER - DUTCH FIRST DIVISION RESULT .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-22
Result of a Dutch first
division match on Thursday :
NEC Nijmegen 1 PSV Eindhoven 4
SOCCER - SHARPSHOOTER KNUP BACK IN SWISS SQUAD .
GENEVA 1996-08-22
Galatasaray striker Adrian Knup , scorer of 26 goals in 45 internationals , has been recalled by Switzerland for the World Cup qualifier against Azerbaijan in Baku on August 31 .
Knup was overlooked by Artur Jorge for the European championship finals earlier this year .
But new coach Rolf Fringer is clearly a Knup fan and included him in his 19-man squad on Thursday .
Switzerland failed to progress beyond the opening group phase in Euro 96 .
Squad :
Goalkeepers - Marco Pascolo ( Cagliari ) , Pascal Zuberbuehler ( Grasshoppers ) .
Defenders - Stephane Henchoz ( Hamburg ) , Marc Hottiger ( Everton ) , Yvan Quentin ( Sion ) , Ramon Vega ( Cagliari ) Raphael Wicky ( Sion ) .
Midfielders - Alexandre Comisetti ( Grasshoppers ) , Antonio Esposito ( Grasshoppers ) , Sebastien Fournier ( Stuttgart ) , Christophe Ohrel ( Lausanne ) , Patrick Sylvestre ( Sion ) , David Sesa ( Servette ) , Ciriaco Sforza ( Inter Milan ) Murat Yakin ( Grasshoppers ) .
Strikers - Kubilay Turkyilmaz ( Grasshoppers ) , Adrian Knup ( Galatasaray ) , Christophe Bonvin ( Sion ) , Stephane Chapuisat ( Borussia Dortmund ) .
ATHLETICS - IT 'S A RECORD - 40,000 BEERS ON THE HOUSE .
BRUSSELS 1996-08-22
Spectators at Friday 's Brussels grand prix meeting have an extra incentive to cheer on the athletes to world record performances -- a free glass of beer .
A Belgian brewery has offered to pay for a free round of drinks for all of the 40,000 crowd if a world record goes at the meeting , organisers said on Thursday .
It could be one of the most expensive rounds of drinks ever .
The meeting is sold out already .
Two world records are in serious danger of being broken at the meeting -- the women 's 1,000 metres and the men 's 3,000 metres .
GOLF - GERMAN OPEN FIRST ROUND SCORES .
STUTTGART , Germany 1996-08-22
Leading first round
scores in the German Open golf championship on Thursday ( Britain
unless stated ) :
62 Paul Broadhurst
63 Raymond Russell
64 David J. Russell , Michael Campbell ( New Zealand ) , Ian
Woosnam , Bernhard Langer ( Germany ) , Ronan Rafferty , Mats
Lanner ( Sweden ) , Wayne Riley ( Australia )
65 Eamonn Darcy ( Ireland ) , Per Nyman ( Sweden ) , Russell Claydon ,
Mark Roe , Retief Goosen ( South Africa ) , Carl Suneson
66 Stephen Field , Paul Lawrie , Ian Pyman , Max Anglert
( Sweden ) , Miles Tunnicliff , Christian Cevaer ( France ) ,
Des Smyth ( Ireland ) , David Carter , Lee Westwood , Greg
Chalmers ( Australia ) , Miguel Angel Martin ( Spain ) ,
Thomas Bjorn ( Denmark ) , Fernando Roca ( Spain ) , Derrick
Cooper
67 Jeff Hawksworth , Padraig Harrington ( Ireland ) , Michael
Welch , Thomas Gogele ( Germany ) , Paul McGinley ( Ireland ) ,
Gary Orr , Jose-Maria Canizares ( Spain ) , Michael Jonzon
( Sweden ) , Paul Eales , David Williams , Andrew Coltart ,
Jonathan Lomas , Jose Rivero ( Spain ) , Robert Karlsson
( Sweden ) , Marcus Wills , Pedro Linhart ( Spain ) , Jamie
Spence , Terry Price ( Australia ) , Juan Carlos Pinero ( Spain ) ,
Mark Mouland
SOCCER - UEFA REWARDS THREE COUNTRIES FOR FAIR PLAY .
GENEVA 1996-08-22
Norway , England and Sweden were rewarded for their fair play on Thursday with an additional place in the 1997-98 UEFA Cup competition .
Norway headed the UEFA Fair Play rankings for 1995-96 with 8.62 points , ahead of England with 8.61 and Sweden 8.57 .
The rankings are based on a formula that takes into account many factors including red and yellow cards , and coaching and spectators ' behaviour at matches played at an international level by clubs and national teams .
Only the top three countries are allocated additional places .
The UEFA Fair Play rankings are : 1 .
Norway 8.62 points
2. England 8.61
3. Sweden 8.57
4. Faroe Islands 8.56
5. Wales 8.54
6. Estonia 8.52
7. Ireland 8.45
8. Belarus 8.39
9. Iceland 8.35
10. Netherlands 8.30
10. Denmark 8.30
10. Germany 8.30
13. Scotland 8.29
13. Latvia 8.29
15. Moldova 8.24
16. Yugoslavia 8.22
16. Belgium 8.22
18. Luxembourg 8.20
19. France 8.18
20. Israel 8.17
21. Switzerland 8.15
21. Slovakia 8.15
23. Poland 8.12
23. Portugal 8.12
25. Georgia 8.10
26. Ukraine 8.09
26. Spain 8.09
26. Finland 8.09
29. Macedonia 8.07
30. Lithuania 8.06
31. Austria 8.05
32. Russia 8.03
33. Romania 8.02
33. Turkey 8.02
35. Hungary 7.98
36. Czech Republic 7.95
37. Greece 7.89
37. Northern Ireland 7.89
39. Italy 7.85
40. Cyprus 7.83
41. Armenia 7.80
42. Slovenia 7.77
43. Croatia 7.75
44. Bulgaria 7.73
45. Malta 7.40
CRICKET - POLICE COMMANDOS ON HAND FOR AUSTRALIANS ' FIRST MATCH .
COLOMBO 1996-08-22
Armed police commandos patrolled the ground when Australia opened their short tour of Sri Lanka with a five-run win over the country 's youth team on Thursday .
Australia , in Sri Lanka for a limited overs tournament which also includes India and Zimbabwe , have been promised the presence of commandos , sniffer dogs and plainclothes policemen to ensure the tournament is trouble-free .
They are making their first visit to the island since boycotting a World Cup fixture in February because of fears over ethnic violence .
Australia , batting first in Thursday 's the warm-up match , scored 251 for seven from their 50 overs .
Ricky Ponting led the way with 100 off 119 balls with two sixes and nine fours before retiring .
The youth side replied with 246 for seven .
Australian coach Geoff Marsh said he was impressed with the competitiveness of the opposition .
" We were made to sweat to win , " he said .
ONE ROMANIAN DIES IN BUS CRASH IN BULGARIA .
SOFIA 1996-08-22
One Romanian passenger was killed , and 14 others were injured on Thursday when a Romanian-registered bus collided with a Bulgarian one in northern Bulgaria , police said .
The two buses collided head on at 5 o'clock this morning on the road between the towns of Rousse and Veliko Tarnovo , police said .
A Romanian woman Maria Marco , 35 , was killed .
The accident was being investigated , police added .
-- Sofia Newsroom , 359-2-84561
OFFICIAL JOURNAL CONTENTS - OJ L 211 OF AUGUST 21 , 1996 .
*
( Note - contents are displayed in reverse order to that in the printed Journal )
Corrigendum to Commission Regulation ( EC ) No 1464/96 of 25 July 1996 relating to a standing invitation to tender to determine levies and / or refunds on exports of white sugar ( OJ No L 187 of 26.7.1996 )
Corrigendum to Commission Regulation ( EC ) No 658/96 of 9 April 1996 on certain conditions for granting compensatory payments under the support system for producers of certain arable crops ( OJ No L 91 of 12.4.1996 )
Commission Regulation ( EC ) No 1663/96 of 20 August 1996 establishing the standard import values for determining the entry price of certain fruit and vegetables END OF DOCUMENT .
In Home Health to appeal payment denial .
MINNETONKA , Minn .
1996-08-22
In Home Health Inc said on Thursday it will appeal to the U.S. Federal District Court in Minneapolis a decision by the Health Care Financing Administration ( HCFA ) that denied reimbursement of certain costs under Medicaid .
The HCFA Administrator reversed a previously favorable decision regarding the reimbursement of costs related to the company 's community liaison personnel , it added .
The company said it continues to believe the majority of the community liaison costs are coverable under the terms of the Medicare program .
" We are disappointed with the administrator 's decision but we continue to be optimistic regarding an ultimate favorable resolution , " Mark Gildea , chief executive officer , said in a statement .
In Home Health said it previously recorded a reserve equal to 16 percent of all revenue related to the community liaison costs .
Separately , In Home Health said the U.S. District Court in Minneapolis ruled in its favor regarding the reimbursement of certain interest expenses .
This decision will result in the reimbursement by Medicare of $ 81,000 in disputed costs .
" This is our first decision in federal distrct court regarding a dispute with Medicare , " Gildea said . "
We are extremely pleased with this decision and we recognize it as a significant step toward resolution of our outstanding Medicare disputes . "
-- Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787
Oppenheimer Capital to review Oct. div .
NEW YORK 1996-08-22
Oppenheimer Capital LP said on Thursday it will review its cash distribution rate for the October quarterly distribution , assuming continued favorable results .
The company , which reported improved first quarter earnings for the period ended July 31 , 1996 , declared a quarterly distribution of $ 0.65 per partnership unit for the quarter ended July .
Best sees Q2 loss similar to Q1 loss .
RICHMOND , Va .
1996-08-22
Best Products Co Chairman and Chief Executive Daniel Levy said Thursday he expected the company 's second-quarter results to be similar to the $ 34.6 million loss posted in the first quarter .
He also told Reuters before the retailer 's annual meeting that the second quarter could be better than the first quarter ended May 4 . "
We could do even better , " he said .
The second-quarter results are expected to be released in September .
Levy said seeking bankruptcy protection was not under consideration .
Best emerged from Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection in June 1994 after 3-1/2 years .
" Bankruptcy is always possible , particularly when you lose what we are going to lose in the first half of this year , " Levy said . "
But this is not something we are striving to do . "
The Richmond-based retailer lost $ 95.7 million in the fiscal year ended February 3 .
That was the second-largest loss in the company 's history .
Levy said that Best planned to open two new stores this fall .
The company announced in March that it was closing seven stores and backing out of nine new lease agreements .
At the time , Best said it did not plan to open any new stores this fall .
It currently operates 169 stores in 23 states .
For last year 's second quarter , which ended July 29 , 1995 , Best posted a loss of $ 7.1 million , or $ 0.23 per share , on sales of $ 311.9 million .
Measles exposure can lead to bowel disease - study .
LONDON 1996-08-23
Women who get measles while pregnant may have babies at higher risk of Crohn 's disease , a debilitating bowel disorder , researchers said on Friday .
Three out of four Swedish babies born to mothers who caught measles developed serious cases of Crohn 's disease , the researchers said .
Dr Andrew Wakefield of the Royal Free Hospital School of Medicine and colleagues screened 25,000 babies delivered at University Hospital , Uppsala , between 1940 and 1949 .
Four of the mothers had measles while pregnant .
" Three of the four children had Crohn 's disease , " Wakefield 's group wrote in the Lancet medical journal .
Crohn 's is an inflammation of the bowel that can sometimes require surgery .
It causes diarrhoea , abdominal pain and weight loss .
The researchers said the three children involved had especially severe cases .
Exposure to viruses can often cause birth defects .
Most notably , women who get rubella ( German measles ) have a high risk of a stillborn baby .
All the key numbers - CBI August industrial trends .
LONDON 1996-08-23
Following are key data from the August monthly survey of trends in UK manufacturing by the Confederation of British Industry ( CBI ) .
CBI MONTHLY TRENDS ENQUIRY ( a ) AUG JULY JUNE MAY
- total order book - 10 - 22 - 13 - 17
- export order book - 14 - 13 - 11 - 7
- stocks of finished goods +17 +19 +17 +25
- output expectations * +22 +22 +12 +16
- domestic price expectations * 0 - 1 +6 +4
NOTES - * over the coming four months ;
- ( a ) in percent , giving balance between those
replying " above normal " and those replying " below normal . "
The survey was conducted between July 23 and August 14 and involved 1,305 companies , representing 50 industries , accounting for around half of the UK 's manufactured exports and some two million employees .
-- Rosemary Bennett , London Newsroom +44 171 542 7715
London shipsales .
LONDON 1996-08-22
- Secondhand tonnage brokers reported the sale of the following vessels .
Iron Gippsland - ( built 1989 ) 87,241 dwt sold to Greek buyers for $ 30 million .
Sairyu Maru No : 2 - ( built 1982 ) 60,960 dwt sold to Greek buyers for $ 15.5 million .
Stainless Fighter - ( built 1970 ) 21,718 dwt sold at auction for $ 6 million .
Some of these sales may not be final as they may be subject to inspection , survey or other conditions .
Garlic pills do n't lower cholesterol , study finds .
LONDON 1996-08-22
Garlic pills may not lower blood cholesterol and studies that show they do may be flawed , British researchers have reported .
A study by a team of doctors at Oxford University has found people with high blood cholesterol do not benefit significantly from taking garlic tablets .
The study involved 115 people with high blood cholesterol levels .
They were given 900 milligrams a day of dried garlic powder or placebo tablets . "
There were no significant differences between the groups receiving garlic and placebo , " they wrote in the Journal of the Royal College of Physicians .
Those taking part were told to eat a low-fat diet for six weeks before they started taking the pills , and their blood cholesterol measured before and after the six-week period .
The researchers said this would make their findings more accurate .
Several studies have found garlic pills can lower blood pressure and blood cholesterol .
But the Oxford team disputed these findings and said either previous trials may have been interpreted incorrectly , those taking part were not given special diets beforehand or the duration of the studies may have been too short .
The six-month trial was funded by the British Heart Foundation and Lichtwer Pharma GmbH , which makes Kwai brand garlic tablets .
The study did not address whether whole garlic could affect cholesterol .
-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7950
Britain gives aid to volcano-hit Caribbean island .
LONDON 1996-08-22
Britain said on Thursday it would give 25 million pounds ( $ 39 million ) of development aid to the Caribbean island of Montserrat , where much of the population living in the south has fled to avoid a volcano .
The volcano in the Soufriere hills has erupted three times in the past 13 months and last April some 4,500 people living in the capital , Plymouth , and southern areas were evacuated to the north , where many are living in public shelters and schools .
" This assistance will provide a fast track development programme for the designated ( northern ) safe area , " Britain 's Overseas Development Administration said in a statement .
Britain gave 8.5 million pounds ( $ 13 million ) to Montserrat , which is one of its dependent territories , when the volcano first became active .
Overseas Development Minister Lynda Chalker said a recent census had shown most Montserratians wanted to remain on the island . "
The development of the north will help them to do just that , " she said .
Tennis - Philippoussis looms for Sampras in U.S. Open .
Bill Berkrot
NEW YORK 1996-08-22
World number one Pete Sampras , seeking his first Grand Slam title of the year , and women 's top seed Steffi Graf , aiming for her third , should be able to ease into the year 's final major , which begins on Monday .
Sampras opens the defence of his U.S. Open crown against David Rikl of the Czech Republic , while top-ranked Graf begins her title defence against Yayuk Basuki of Indonesia .
Wednesday 's U.S. Open draw ceremony revealed that both title holders should run into their first serious opposition in the third round .
Looming in Sampras 's future is a likely third-round date with recent nemesis Mark Philippoussis , the rising Australian who took out Sampras in the third round of the Australian Open in January .
Sampras avenged that defeat with a straight sets win over the 19-year-old power hitter in the second round at Wimbledon and their rubber match in New York could provide some first-week fireworks .
While only a stunning upset will keep Graf from sailing through to a predictable semifinal showdown with third seed Arantxa Sanchez Vicario , the German star could also be tested in the third round where she will probably face 28th-ranked veteran Natasha Zvereva of Belarus .
There will be no repeat of last year 's men 's final with eighth-ranked Andre Agassi landing in Sampras 's half of the draw .
Bumping Agassi up to the sixth seeding avoided the possibility that he would run into Sampras as early as the quarter-finals , but they could lock horns in the semis .
Olympic champion Agassi meets Karim Alami of Morocco in the first round .
Surprise second seed Michael Chang , ranked third in the world , opens against Czech Daniel Vacek , while women 's second seed Monica Seles drew American Anne Miller as her first victim .
Second-ranked Austrian Thomas Muster , who was seeded third , did not have the luck of the draw with him .
In the first round Muster faces American Richey Reneberg , who has been playing some of the best tennis of his career of late .
If he survives , Muster is seeded to run into either fifth-seeded Wimbledon champion Richard Krajicek of the Netherlands or 12th-seeded American Todd Martin in the quarter-finals in Chang 's half of the draw .
Perhaps the best , yet most unfortunate , first-round matchup of the men 's competition pits eighth seed Jim Courier against retiring star Stefan Edberg .
The popular Swede is playing his final major tournament next week and the two-time champion 's Grand Slam farewell could well be a one-match affair .
With the exception of a Philippoussis showdown , Sampras looks to have landed in a comfortable quarter of the draw with the likes of Frenchman Cedric Pioline and ailing French Open champion Yevgeny Kafelnikov , who is nursing a rib injury , in his path .
Seles , runner-up to Graf last year , is seeded to run into fifth-ranked German Anke Huber in the quarter-finals with fourth seed Conchita Martinez or eighth-seeded Olympic champion Lindsay Davenport looking like her most likely semifinal opponents .
But Huber will be tested immediately with a first-round encounter against dangerous 18th-ranked South African Amanda Coetzer .
Sanchez Vicario , runner-up to Graf at the French Open and Wimbledon , begins play against a qualifier in a quarter of the draw that includes young talent Martina Hingis , the 16th seed , before a probable quarter-final clash with seventh-seeded veteran Jana Novotna .
Martinez begins play against Ruxandra Dragomir of Romania .
-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800
RTRS - Tennis - Muster upset , Philippoussis wins , Stoltenberg loses .
TORONTO 1996-08-21
Top-seeded Thomas Muster of Austria was beaten 6-3 7-5 by 123rd-ranked Daniel Nestor of Canada on Wednesday in his first match of the $ 2 million Canadian Open .
A lefthander with a strong serve , Nestor kept the rallies short by constantly attacking the net and the tactic worked in the second-round match against Muster , playing his first match after receiving a first-round bye along with the other top eight seeds .
The tournament also lost its second seed on the third day of play when second-seeded Goran Ivanisevic of Croatia was beaten 6-7(3-7 ) 6-4 6-4 by unseeded Mikael Tillstrom of Sweden .
Other seeded players advancing were number three Wayne Ferreira of South Africa , number four Marcelo Rios of Chile , number six MaliVai Washington of the United States and American Todd Martin , the seventh seeed .
Eighth seed Marc Rosset of Switzerland was eliminated in a one hour , 55 minute battle by unseeded Mark Philippoussis of Australia .
Philippoussis saved a match point at 5-6 in the third-set tie break before winning 6-3 3-6 7-6 ( 8-6 ) .
Philippoussis 's compatriot , 13th seed Jason Stoltenberg , was not as fortunate .
He held one match point at 9-8 in a marathon third-set tie break but was beaten 5-7 7-6 ( 7-1 ) 7-6 ( 13-11 ) by unseeded Daniel Vacek of the Czech Republic .
" I knew I had to serve well and keep the points short and that 's what I was able to do , " said Nestor , who ranks 10th in doubles .
There were only two service breaks in the match .
The lanky Canadian broke Muster at 4-3 in the first set and 5-5 in the second before ending the match on his third match point when the Austrian hit a service return long .
" I probably did n't hit five ground strokes in the whole match , " said Muster , only partly joking . "
The way he was chipping and charging and serving and volleying I did n't really get my timing playing from the baseline . "
" He played a good match , took a few chances , and every time he was down he was able to come up with a big first serve . "
Playing at night was not Muster 's preference . "
I asked for a day match and they gave me a night match , " he said . "
I do n't like playing under the lights but maybe it would not have made any difference . "
Ivanisevic rallied from a 2-5 deficit in the first set but then played erratically against the 44th-ranked Tillstrom , who was a surprise winner over his famous compatriot Stefan Edberg in the second round at Wimbledon .
Ivanisevic hit 32 aces but was outplayed from the back court by the 24-year-old Tillstrom .
The sixth-ranked Ivanisevic , who lost in the final at Indianapolis to world number one Pete Sampras of the U.S. last Sunday , made a quick getaway after his loss but did say : " Something was not there when I arrived ( in Toronto ) .
I did n't feel good .
And I did n't have a good feeling as soon as I lost in my doubles ( on Tuesday ) . "
" I thought he looked a little unfocused at certain times on his ground strokes , " said Tillstrom .
The 19-year-old Philippoussis , who beat Sampras in the third round of this year 's Australian Open , stayed calm in a nervy third-set tie break against Rosset .
" I 'm pleased because I did n't play that great today , but I fought really well , " he said . "
When I was down 2-5 in the tiebreak ( in the third set ) , I just thought about winning my two serves and hoped that he might get tight .
Then he shanked a forehand at to make it 5-all and that helped me back . "
Soccer - Results of South Korean pro-soccer games .
SEOUL 1996-08-22
Results of South Korean pro-soccer games played on Wednesday .
Anyang 3 Chonnam 3 ( halftime 2-0 )
Puchon 0 Suwon 0 ( halftime 0-0 )
Standings after games played on Wednesday ( tabulate under - won , drawn , lost , goals for , goals against , points ) :
W D L G / F G / A P
Puchon 1 1 0 1 0 4
Chonan 1 0 0 5 4 3
Anyang 0 2 0 5 5 2
Suwon 0 2 0 3 3 2
Pohang 0 1 0 3 3 1
Pusan 0 1 0 0 2 1
Chonnam 0 1 1 5 6 1
Ulsan 0 0 1 4 5 0
Chonbuk 0 0 0 0 0 0
Senegal cholera outbreak kills five .
DAKAR 1996-08-22
An outbreak of cholera has killed five people in the central Senegal town of Kaolack , where health authorities have recorded 291 cases since August 11 , a medical official said on Thursday .
Doctor Masserigne Ndiaye said medical staff were overwhelmed with work . "
People are rushing to the hospital as soon as the first symptoms appear , that 's why we have fewer deaths , " he told Reuters by telephone from the town , 160 km ( 100 miles ) southeast of the Senegalese capital Dakar .
Nigerian general takes over Liberia ECOMOG force .
MONROVIA 1996-08-22
Nigerian Major General Sam Victor Malu took over on Thursday as commander of the ECOMOG peacekeeping force in Liberia , two days after the start of the latest ceasefire in the six-year civil war .
Malu replaced another Nigerian major general , John Inienger , who told officers at the handover ceremony that peace was now at hand for Liberia after six years of fighting and more than a dozen failed accords .
" The search for peace in Liberia has been difficult , challenging and sometimes painful .
Peacekeepers were harassed , killed and taken hostage , " he said .
" It is difficult but I want to assure you that peace is in sight . "
United Nations military observers travelling to the western town of Tubmanburg on Wednesday to monitor the ceasefire were delayed by shooting along the highway , U.N. special representative Anthony Nyakyi said .
They finally went ahead with an escort from the ULIMO-J faction .
Faction leaders who agreed a new peace deal in the Nigerian capital Abuja on Saturday have accused each other of breaking the ceasefire .
The latest peace deal foresees the disarmament of an estimated 60,000 combatants and sets a target date of May 30 next year for elections .
The ECOMOG force , currently 10,000 strong , was sent to Liberia by the Economic Community of West African States in 1990 at the height of the fighting .
Guinea calls two days of prayer .
CONAKRY 1996-08-22
The West African state of Guinea declared Thursday and Friday days of national prayer .
A government statement , broadcast repeatedly by state radio , said the two days of prayer were " for the dead , for peace and prosperity in Guinea , the victory of the new government and the health of the head of state " .
The precise reason for the call was not immediately clear .
Guinea 's president , Lansana Conte , vice-president of the Organisation of the Islamic Conference , left for Kuwait on August 16 to prepare the next OIC summit in Pakistan in 1997 .
Koranic reading sessions and prayers were to be held in the farming town of Badi-Tondon , near his home about 60 km ( 40 miles ) from the capital Conakry .
Conte , an army general , survived a February army pay revolt which at the time he described as a veiled attempt to topple him .
He has since named a prime minister for the first time since early in his rule and ordered a crackdown on corruption .
Conte seized power in 1984 after the death of veteran Marxist leader Ahmed Sekou Toure .
He won elections in 1993 .
South African answers U.S. message in a bottle .
JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-22
A South African boy is writing back to an American girl whose message in a bottle he found washed up on President Nelson Mandela 's old prison island .
But Carlo Hoffmann , an 11-year-old jailer 's son who found the bottle on the beach at Robben Island off Cape Town after winter storms , will send his letter back by ordinary mail on Thursday , the post office said .
It will be sent for free .
Danielle Murray from Sandusky , Ohio , the same age as her new penfriend , asked for a reply from whoever received the message she flung on its journey months ago on the other side of the Atlantic Ocean .
Rottweiler kills South African toddler .
JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-22
A rottweiler dog belonging to an elderly South African couple savaged to death their two-year-old grandson who was visiting , police said on Thursday .
The dog attacked Louis Booy in the front garden of his grandparents ' house in Vanderbijlpark near Johannesburg on Tuesday .
His bloody body was lying in the garden when his parents arrived in the afternoon to pick him up .
It was unclear where the grandparents were at the time .
Dogs fierce enough to scare off burglars are becoming increasingly popular in the crime-infested Johannesburg area .
INDICATORS - Hungary - updated Aug 22 .
BUDAPEST 1996-08-22
The latest indicators :
CPI ( pct ) July +0.4m / m ; 23.0yr / yr ( June +0.9;+23.6 )
PPI ( pct ) June +0.7 m / m;+21.5yr / yr ( May +1.7;+22.0 )
Industry output ( pct ) June - 7.8 m / m;-0.2yr / yr ( May +7.3;-3.6 )
Current account Jan-May - $ 738 million ( Jan-April - $ 748 million )
NBH trade balance Jan-May - $ 934 million ( Jan-April - $ 774 million )
MIT trade balance Jan-June - $ 1.45 bln ( Jan-May - $ 1.24 bln )
Gross foreign debt May $ 27,246.5 million ( April $ 28,716.8 million )
Net foreign debt May $ 14,390.7 million ( April $ 15,704.3 million )
Unemployment ( pct ) July 10.8 pct ( June 10.6 pct )
Budget deficit ( HUF ) Jan-July 102 bln ( Jan-June 122 bln )
T-bill yields % ( 1mo ) 22.95 ( 3mo ) 23.02 ( 6mo ) 23.53 ( 1yr ) 24.40
Government bond yields : ( 2-yr 1998 / J ) 25.49,(3-yr 1999 / c ) 24.44
The NBH is BBB-minus by Duff & Phelps , IBCA and Thomson BankWatch , BB-plus by S&P , BA1 by Moody 's Investors Service , BBB+ by the Japan Credit Rating Agency .
The NBH trade data is based on cash flow , MIT data on customs statistics .
-- Budapest newsroom ( 36 1)266 2410
Fifty Russians die in clash with rebels-Interfax .
MOSCOW 1996-08-22
At least 50 Russian servicemen have been killed in a battle with separatist rebels which erupted in the Chechen capital Grozny on Thursday and continued after Russia and the rebels agreed a truce , Interfax news agency said .
Interfax quoted Russian military command in Chechnya as saying that about 200 interior ministry forces , sent on reconaisance mission , clashed with rebels at Minutka Square .
The Interfax report could not be independently confirmed .
Moscow peacemaker Alexander Lebed and rebel chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov signed an agreement earlier on Thursday under which the two sides would cease all hostilities at noon ( 0800 GMT ) on Friday .
Interfax made clear that the interior ministry detachment had been sent on the mission before the truce deal had been signed at the local equivalent of 1500 GMT .
But fierce fighting still raged at 1600 GMT , Interfax said .
It quoted a source in the Russian command in Chechnya as saying that the servicemen were outnumbered by the rebels .
Polish schoolgirl blackmailer wanted textbooks .
GDANSK , Poland 1996-08-22
A Polish schoolgirl blackmailed two women with anonymous letters threatening death and later explained that she needed money for textbooks , police said on Thursday .
" The 13-year-old girl tried to extract 60 and 70 zlotys ( $ 22 and $ 26 ) from two residents of Sierakowice by threatening to take their lives , " a police spokesman said in the nearby northern city of Gdansk on Thursday .
He said the women reported the blackmail letters and police caught the girl on Wednesday as she tried to pick up the cash at the Sierakowice railway station .
" Interviewed in the presence of a psychologist , she said she wanted to use the money for school books and clothes , " spokesman Kazimierz Socha told Reuters .
He said the case of the girl , from a poor family that had never been in trouble with the law , would go before a special court dealing with underage offenders .
Czech CNB-120 index rises 1.2 pts to 869.3 .
PRAGUE 1996-08-22
The CNB-120 index , a broad daily measure of Czech equities , rose 1.2 points on Thursday to 869.3 , the Czech National Bank ( CNB ) said .
Eight of the ten sectoral indices rose , with the banking index rising the most , up 14.4 points to 1,294.5 .
-- Prague Newsroom , 42-2-2423-0003
Russians , rebels sign deal in Chechnya .
NOVYE ATAGI , Russia 1996-08-22
Russian President Boris Yeltsin 's security supremo Alexander Lebed and Chechen rebel chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov signed a deal on Thursday aimed at ending three weeks of renewed fighting in the region .
The final contents of the document negotiated in this village south of the Chechen capital Grozny have not been officially disclosed .
Itar-Tass news agency said it provided for the disengagement of Russian and rebel forces in Chechnya .
Lebed aide says Russian-Chechen talks going well .
NOVYE ATAGI , Russia 1996-08-22
Talks between Russia 's Alexander Lebed and Chechen separatist leaders were going well on Thursday and the two sides were working out a detailed schedule on how to stop the war , a Lebed aide said .
Press spokesman Alexander Barkhatov told reporters the negotiations , being held at this rebel-held village some 20 km ( 12 miles ) south of the Chechen capital Grozny , were progressing briskly and being conducted in a good mood .
He said a document would be completed in an hour 's time for signature by the two sides , who were working on a " day-by-day schedule to stop the war in Chechnya . "
Yeltsin shown on Russian television .
MOSCOW 1996-08-22
Russian television showed a brief clip of Boris Yeltsin on Thursday , with the president laughing and smiling as he spoke to nominee health minister Tatyana Dmitrieva .
It was the first time the president had been shown on television since he was inaugurated for a second term in office on August 9 .
He returned to the Kremlin on Thursday after a two-day break in the lakelands of northwestern Russia .
PRESS DIGEST - Bosnia - Aug 22 .
SARAJEVO 1996-08-22
These are the leading stories in the Sarajevo press on Thursday .
Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy .
OSLOBODJENJE
- The Bosnian federation launches a common payment system on Friday .
Under the new system taxes and customs may be paid in the Bosnian dinar , the Croatian kuna or the Deutsche mark until a new Bosnian currency is introduced .
- The president of the Bosnian Association for Refugees and Displaced Persons , Mirhunisa Komarica says many survivors of the 1995 massacre in the Bosnian town of Srebrenica are languishing as forced laborers in Serbian mines .
According to Komarica , 2,400 male residents of Srebrenica work in the Trepca mine and 1,900 work in a mine in Aleksandrovac .
DNEVNI AVAZ
- Slovenian police briefly detain two Bosnian opposition leaders in Ljubljana and cancel opposition political rallies in Ljubljana and Maribor .
-- Sarajevo newsroom , +387-71-663-864 .
Grozny quiet overnight after raids .
ALKHAN-YURT , Russia 1996-08-22
The city of Grozny , pounded by Russian planes and artillery for hours on Wednesday , calmed down overnight , although sporadic explosions and shooting could still be heard .
Reuters correspondent Lawrence Sheets , speaking from the nearby village of Alkhan-Yurt , said he had heard little from Grozny since Wednesday evening 's arrival of Russian security chief Alexander Lebed , who said he " came with peace " .
A couple of helicopters flew over the city early on Thursday morning , but did not appear to be firing at anything .
Lebed said on Wednesday he had clinched a truce with Chechen separatists and he promised to halt a threatened bombing assault on Grozny , which the rebels have held since August 6 .
Boat passengers rescued off Colombian coast .
BOGOTA , Colombia 1996-08-22
Colombia 's Coast Guard on Thursday rescued 12 people lost for three days in an open boat off the Pacific coast , officials said .
The boat had been missing since Monday afternoon when it left the tiny island of Gorgona off Colombia 's southwest coast with sightseers for a return trip to Narino province , near the border with Ecuador .
The boat ran out of fuel and did not have a radio to call for help , Navy spokesman Lt. Italo Pineda said .
He said 11 passengers and one boatman survived on coconuts and rainwater during 65 hours lost at sea .
The boat was towed to the port city of Buenaventura .
Argentine July raw steel output up 14.8 pct vs ' 95 .
BUENOS AIRES 1996-08-22
Argentine raw steel output was 355,900 tonnes in July , 14.8 percent higher than in July 1995 and up 1.9 percent from June , Steel Industry Center said Thursday .
Primary iron output was 297,700 tonnes , 14.5 percent more than last July and 0.1 percent more than in June .
Hot laminate production was 349,000 tonnes , 3.2 percent up from July 1995 and 0.8 percent up from June .
Production of cold laminates was 120,500 tonnes , 4.2 percent higher than the same month last year and 11 percent higher than in June .
-- Jason Webb , Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0655
Peru 's guerrillas kill one , take 8 hostage in jungle .
LIMA , Peru 1996-08-21
Peruvian guerrillas killed one man and took eight people hostage after taking over a village in the country 's northeastern jungle region , anti- terrorist police sources said on Wednesday .
For three hours on Tuesday , around 100 members of the Maoist rebel group Shining Path took control of Alomella Robles , a small village about 345 miles ( 550 km ) northeast of Lima , the sources said .
Some guerrillas made villagers listen to propaganda speeches in the village centre , others forced passing motorists out of their cars and daubed their vehicles with slogans .
By Wednesday , the whereabouts of the eight hostages was still not known , the sources said .
In recent months the Shining Path , severely weakened since the 1992 capture of its leader Abimael Guzman , has been stepping up both its military and propaganda activities .
Peru 's guerrilla conflicts have cost at least 30,000 lives and $ 25 billion in damage to infrastructure since 1980 .
Former Surinam rebel leader held after shooting .
PARAMARIBO , Surinam 1996-08-21
Flamboyant former Surinamese rebel leader Ronny Brunswijk was in custody on Wednesday charged with attempted murder , police said .
Brunswijk turned himself into police after Freddy Pinas , a Surinamese-born visitor from the Netherlands , accused Brunswijk of trying to kill him on Sunday after a bar-room brawl in the small mining town of Moengo , about 56 miles ( 90 km ) east of Paramaribo , said police spokesman Ro Gajadhar .
Pinas , showing cuts and bruises on his face , told reporters the former head of the feared Jungle Command had tried and failed to shoot him after Pinas objected to Brunswijk 's advances toward his wife .
Pinas said Brunswijk then ordered his bodyguards to beat him up .
Brunswijk , 35 , denied the charges and said he had merely defended himself when Pinas attacked him with a bottle .
It was the second time Brunswijk had been charged with attempted murder in less than two years .
In 1994 he served two months in prison for shooting a thief in the buttocks .
Brunswijk led a rebel group of about 1,000 in a 1986 uprising against the regime of military strongman Desi Bouterse .
The conflict , which killed more than 500 and caused thousands to flee to neighbouring French Guiana in the late 1980s , eventually paved the way to democratic elections in 1991 .
Despite numerous problems with authorities , Brunswijk went on to become a successful businessman with mining and logging interests .
He also manages and occasionally plays for one of the leading local soccer teams .
Noisy saw leads Thai police to heroin hideaway .
BANGKOK 1996-08-22
A Hong Kong carpenter was arrested in the Thai seaside town of Pattaya after police seized 18 kg ( 39.7 pounds ) of heroin following complaints by residents of a noisy saw , police said on Thursday .
Cheung Siu Man , 40 , was arrested late on Wednesday after police searched a house and found heroin in bags and hidden in hollow spaces in wooden planks , police said .
The suspect said he was hired to make a wooden box from the planks in order to hide the heroin .
Police went to the house after receiving complaints of sawing during the night over the course of several days .
When they arrived to investigate , police saw people escaping from the back door so they decided to search the house .
The seized heroin has an estimated street value of about 300 million baht ( $ 12 million ) , police said .
Officials are now hunting for the suspect 's collaborators , police said .
Cheung was being detained pending formal charges , police said .
Australia foreign minister arrives in China .
BEIJING 1996-08-22
Australian Foreign Minister Alexander Downer arrived in Beijing on Thursday for a four-day visit that follows rising friction between the two nations in recent weeks .
Downer was to meet Chinese Foreign Minister Qian Qichen and sign an agreement on an Australian consulate in Hong Kong , an official of the Australian embassy in Beijing said .
China will resume sovereignty over Hong Kong , a British colony , in mid-1997 .
Relations between China and Australia have been strained in recent weeks because of Australia 's plan to sell uranium to China 's rival Taiwan .
Other issues affecting ties include plans by an Australian cabinet minister to visit Taiwan , a security pact between Canberra and Washington and a possible visit to Australia next month by Tibet 's exiled spiritual leader the Dalai Lama .
Downer is the first Australian minister to visit China since the new conservative government took office in Canberra in March .
Palestinians accuse PA of banning books .
NABLUS , West Bank 1996-08-22
A West Bank bookseller charged on Thursday that the Palestinian Information Ministry has forced him to sign an undertaking not to distribute books written by critics of Israeli-PLO self-rule deals .
" They made me sign an undertaking not to sell the books to anyone at the risk of legal action .
One official told me ' you have to either destroy the books or return them to Amman ' , " Daoud Makkawi , owner of the Nablus-based al-Risala bookshop , told Reuters .
He said ministry officials made him sign this a few weeks ago after he brought about a dozen copies from Jordan of a book by Edward Said , a prominent scholar at New York City 's Columbia University .
Said , a U.S. citizen of Palestinian origin , has been an outspoken critic of the 1993 Israeli-PLO self-rule deal and has written at least two books on the accord .
On Wednesday a bookseller in the West Bank town of Ramallah said police about a month ago confiscated several copies of two of Said 's books on the Israel-PLO self-rule deals .
Palestinian Information Ministry Director-General Mutawakel Taha denied that ministry officials forced anyone to sign any undertaking and insisted that the Palestinian Authority has no plans to censor books .
" There is no strategy to ban books or to suppress freedom of expression in any form whatsoever , " Taha told Reuters .
But Taha said that the absence of relevent legislations may have resulted in some mistakes by some security officials .
" This may explain some mistakes against some journalists and writers , " he said .
Daoud said books by other authors , including British Journalist Patrick Seale , were also banned .
He said that security officials often visit his shop to make sure he was not selling the books .
" I think this is a bad beginning .
If we have confidence , why should we be afraid of the other opinion ? "
Daoud said .
Thousands of books were banned from sale in the West Bank and Gaza Strip by the Israeli military authorities before the Jewish state handed over parts of the two areas to the PLO under a self-rule deal in 1994 .
Egypt blames Istanbul control tower for accident .
CAIRO 1996-08-22
The chairman of national carrier EgyptAir on Thursday blamed the control tower at Istanbul airport for the EgyptAir plane accident .
Twenty people were injured on Wednesday when the EgyptAir Boeing 707 overshot the runway , caught fire , hit a taxi and skipped across a road onto a railway line .
Chairman Mohamed Fahim Rayyan told a news conference at Cairo airport : " The control tower should have allocated the plane another runway , instead of the one the plane landed on . "
" The one it landed on is 2,250 metres ( 2,460 yards ) long while the other one if more than 3,000 metres ( 3,300 yards ) long and is less steep , " he added .
He said a Turkish civil aviation authority official had made the same point and he noted that a Turkish plane had a similar accident there in 1994 .
The EgyptAir pilot blamed Turkish airport staff for misleading him .
The landing took place after a rainstorm .
" Its not an accident .
It 's very wet .
The brake action is very poor and the tower said it 's medium .
That 's wrong , " the pilot told private Ihlas news agency in English .
Egypt wants nothing to do with Sudanese rulers .
CAIRO 1996-08-22
The Egyptian government will have nothing more to do with the Sudanese government because it continues to shelter and support Egyptian militants , President Hosni Mubarak said in a speech on Thursday .
Egypt says the Sudanese government helped the Moslem militants who tried to kill Mubarak in Addis Ababa last year .
It sponsored last week 's U.N. Security Council resolution threatening a ban on Sudanese flights abroad if Khartoum does not hand over three men accused in the Addis Ababa incident .
The sanctions will come into effect in November if Sudan fails to extradite the men , but Sudan says it cannot hand them over to Ethiopia for trial because they are not in Sudan .
" We are still eager that nothing should affect the Sudanese people but we will not deal with the current regime or the Turabi front or whatever , " Mubarak told a group of academics .
Hassan al-Turabi is the leader of the National Islamic Front , the political force behind the Sudanese government .
" I do n't want to go into more details than that but there are more details and they are bitter .
There are terrorists they are sheltering and they make Sudanese passorts for them and they get paid by them , " Mubarak said .
He did not say if Egypt would go so far as to break relations , a step it has been reluctant to take , ostensibly because it would affect ordinary Sudanese .
Turkish shares shed gains in profit-taking .
ISTANBUL 1996-08-22
Turkish shares ended lower on Thursday , shedding gains of earlier in the week amid profit-taking sales , brokers said .
The IMKB-100 lost 0.19 percent or 123.89 points to end at 64,178.78 .
Gains so far this week have totalled 2.92 percent .
Daily volume dropped to 7.2 trillion lira from Wednesday 's 7.8 trillion lira .
" Profit-taking sales in the afternoon showed the latest gains of the index were actually a reaction rise .
I expect the market to go as far down as 63,000 tomorrow if sales continue , " said Burcin Mavituna from Interbank .
Brokers said profit taking sales had come especially as the index approached the 65,000 resistance level .
They said the index could also rise towards 65,000 if the cheap share prices attracted buyers .
The market had its first resistance at 67,000 if it pierced 65,000 , they added .
The session 's most active shares were those of Isbank gained 300 lira to 8,600 .
Shares of utility Cukurova lost 3,000 lira to 67,000 .
The 85-share industrial index lost 0.47 percent to 70,848.86 and the 15-share financial index rose by 0.55 percent to 55,929.89 .
Of the 218 shares traded , gainers outdid losers by 100 to 64 and 54 shares were stable .
-- Istanbul Newsroom , +90-212-275 0875 SA
Miss Universe hides behind veil of silence .
Kieran Murray
LAS CRUCES , N.M. 1996-08-22
Miss Universe , Venezuela 's Alicia Machado , left New Mexico on Thursday , refusing to answer questions about her weight or claims she was told to either go on a crash diet or give up her title .
Machado , 19 , flew to Los Angeles after slipping away from the New Mexico desert town of Las Cruces , where she attended the 1996 Miss Teen USA pageant on Wednesday .
While Machado was not a contestant here , she came under intense scrutiny following reports she was given an ultimatum by Los Angeles-based Miss Universe Inc. to drop 27 pounds ( 12 kg ) in two weeks or risk losing her crown .
In Venezuela , her mother told Reuters that Machado had a swollen face when she left home two weeks ago because she had her wisdom teeth extracted .
Marta Fajardo insisted her daughter , who weighed 112 pounds ( 51 kg ) when she won the Miss Universe title in Las Vegas in May , had perfectly normal eating habits .
" Everybody has their own addiction to something or other but it 's not as if she eats cakes like crazy , " she said .
Organisers flatly denied ever threatening Machado but immediately put her under wraps and blocked access to her .
Dressed in a black strapless evening gown at Wednesday 's pageant , Machado was clearly heavier than the contestants but still won rave reviews after her brief appearance on stage .
" Are you kidding ?
She 's fantastic , " said Nikki Campbell , 28 , who went to the pageant . "
She looked great .
Very sexy . "
Machado 's publicists said on Thursday she was scheduled to stay in Los Angeles for promotional work with sponsors before returning to Venezuela on Sept .
5 .
Beauty queens are high-profile personalities in Venezuela and Machado 's alleged weight problem made front page news this week .
It was an official of the Miss Venezuela Organisation who first said Machado had been told to lose weight fast .
People close to her said she then eased up on her diet and indulged her passion for pasta and cake , but it was not clear how many pounds she gained and most people who saw her said she was still a long way from being fat .
Martin Brooks , president of Miss Universe Inc , said he spoke with Machado to assure her that organisers were not putting pressure on her .
" She 's fine with it .
She wished , as we all did , that it had n't happened but she 's spiritually and mentally terrific .
There 's no problem whatsoever , " he told Reuters .
He said the lifestyle associated with being Miss Universe could make routine exercise difficult .
" The problem is they travel so much and are so busy that the ability to have any type of regimented routine workout does n't exist .
I dont know if Alicia is working out .
We have n't talked about it because it has n't been an issue , " he said .
Kevorkian attends third suicide in week .
PONTIAC , Mich .
1996-08-22
Dr. Jack Kevorkian attended his third suicide in less than a week on Thursday , bringing the body of a 40-year-old Missouri woman suffering from multiple sclerosis to a hospital emergency room , doctors said .
Dr Robert Aranosian , emergency room director at Pontiac Osteopathic Hospital , said Kevorkian brought in the body of Patricia Smith , of Lees Summit , Mo .
, at midday and told doctors that she had been paralysed by the disease .
It was his second assisted-suicide in 36 hours and the 37th that he has acknowledged attending since starting his crusade for doctor assisted suicide in 1990 .
Kevorkian 's lawyer , Geoffrey Fieger , said those attending Smith 's death included her husband , David , a police officer , her father , James Poland , and Kevorkian .
It was the first known time that a police officer has been president at the suicide of one of Kevorkian 's patients .
He offered no details about the cause of Smith 's death or the location .
She was a nurse who had " rapidly progressing multple sclerosis . "
On Tuesday night , Kevorkian attended the death of Louise Siebens , a 76-year-old Texas woman with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis , or Lou Gehrig 's disease .
On August 15 , Kevorkian helped Judith Curren , a 42-year-old Massachusetts nurse , who suffered from chronic fatigue syndrome , a non-terminal illness , to end her life .
Fairview , Texas , $ 1.82 million deal Baa1 - Moody 's .
NEW YORK 1996-08-22
Moody 's Investors Service -
Rating Announcement As of 08/21/96 .
Issuer : Fairview Town
State : TX
Rating : Baa1
Sale Amount : 1,820,000
Expected Sale Date : 08/27/96
-- U.S. Municipal Desk , 212-859-1650
Defiant U.S. neo-Nazi jailed by German court .
Andrew Gray
HAMBURG , Germany 1996-08-22
A Hamburg court sentenced U.S. neo-Nazi leader Gary Lauck on Thursday to four years in prison for pumping banned extremist propaganda into Germany from his base in the United States .
Lauck , from Lincoln , Nebraska , yelled a tirade of abuse at the court after his conviction for inciting racial hatred .
" The struggle will go on , " the 43-year-old shouted in German before being escorted out by security guards .
Lauck 's lawyer vowed he would appeal against the court 's decision , arguing that his client should have been set free because he had not committed any offence under German law .
The German government hailed the conviction as a major victory in the fight against neo-Nazism .
Lauck 's worldwide network has been the main source of anti-Semitic propaganda material flowing into Germany since the 1970s .
" Lauck possessed a well-oiled propaganda machine , honed during more than 20 years , " presiding judge Guenter Bertram told the court .
" He set up a propaganda cannon and fired it at Germany . "
said Bertram , who also read out extracts from Lauck 's material praising Hitler as " the greatest of all leaders " and describing the Nazi slaughter of millions of Jews as a myth .
Eager to put Lauck behind bars quickly and avoid a long and complex trial , prosecutor Bernd Mauruschat limited his charges to offences since 1994 .
He had demanded a five-year jail term but said he was satisfied with the court 's sentence .
Publishing and distributing neo-Nazi material is illegal in Germany but Lauck 's defence team had argued that U.S freedom of speech laws meant he was free to produce his swastika-covered books , magazines , videos and flags in his homeland .
Interior Minister Manfred Kanther said in a statement he " welcomed the prosecution and conviction of one of the ringleaders of international neo-Nazism and biggest distributers of vicious racist publications " .
" It is high time he was behind bars , " the opposition Social Democrats said in a statement .
Lauck , dressed in a sober blue suit and sporting his trademark Hitleresque black moustache , showed no sign of emotion as Bertram spent more than an hour reading out the verdict and explaining the court 's decision .
But as Lauck was about to be led away , he turned to reporters and blurted out a virtually incomprehensible quick-fire diatribe against the court .
" Neither the National Socialists ( Nazis ) nor the communists dared to kidnap an American citizen , " he shouted , in an oblique reference to his extradition to Germany from Denmark . "
That 's the truth . "
His attorney , Hans-Otto Sieg , told reporters outside the courtroom that the judges had not explained how a German court could judge someone for actions carried out in the United States .
Bertram said Lauck was obsessed by Nazism and devoted his life to leading his National Socialist German Workers ' Party Foreign Organisation ( NSDAP-AO ) , which derives its name from the full German title of Hitler 's Nazi party .
During the three-month trial , the court dealt mainly with issues of the NSDAP-AO 's " NS Kampfruf " ( " National Socialist Battle Cry " ) magazine , filled with references to Aryan supremacy and defamatory statements about Jews .
The court rejected Sieg 's argument that Lauck 's extradition from Denmark , where he was arrested in March last year at the request of German authorities , was illegal .
Lauck was also convicted of disseminating the symbols of anti-constitutional organisations .
He will probably be free in around two and a half years .
The court ruled that the 15 months he has spent in custody since his arrest should be subtracted from his prison term .
UN official says Iraqi deal will occur " soon " .
UNITED NATIONS 1996-08-22
A senior U.N. official said on Thursday he expected arrangements to implement the Iraqi oil-for-food deal could be completed " quite soon . "
" I am reluctant to speculate but we are doing the preparations and the secretary-general is anxious to start the program , " said Undersecretary-General Yasushi Akashi .
" It might be sooner than you think , " he told reporters after briefing the Security Council on arrangements for monitors needed to carry out the agreement .
Akashi is head of the Department of Humanitarian affairs .
His deputy earlier speculated at least 10 days .
Suspected killers of bishop dead -- Algeria TV .
PARIS 1996-08-22
Algerian security forces have shot dead three Moslem guerrillas suspected of killing a leading French bishop in western Algeria , the Algerian state-run television said on Thursday .
Security forces also arrested four other men sought for giving support to the slain Moslem rebels , the television said .
The television , which did not say when the security forces killed the rebels , said the four arrested men confessed details of the assassination of the French Roman Catholic Bishop Pierre Claverie .
The 58-year-old Claverie was killed in August 1 in a bomb blast at his residence in the western Algerian city of Oran , hours after he met visiting French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette in Algiers .
An estimated 50,000 Algerians and more than 110 foreigners have been killed in Algeria 's violence pitting Moslem rebels against the Algerian government forces since early 1992 , when the authorities cancelled a general election in which radical Islamists took a commanding lead .
German flown cargo January-July rise 3.8 percent .
FRANKFURT 1996-08-22
The following table shows total flown air cargo volumes in tonnes handled at international German airports January-July 1996 .
The figures exclude trucked airfreight according to the German airports association ADV .
Berlin ( total ) 17,844 up 5.9 pct
- Tegel 10,896 up 3.1
- Tempelhof 202 down 60.0
- Schoenefeld 6,746 up 16.8
Bremen 1,453 up 13.1
Dresden 792 up 11.4
Duessseldorf 31,347 down 4.4
Frankfurt 768,269 up 1.5
Hamburg 21,240 down 3.5
Hannover 6,030 up 15.3
Koeln ( Cologne ) 182,887 up 11.8
Leipzig / Halle 1,806 up 45.6
Munich 44,525 up 11.8
Muenster / Osnabrueck 382 up 28.2
Nuremberg 25,929 up 17.8
Saarbruecken 626 up 28.3
Stuttgart 10,655 up 11.7
TOTAL 1,113,785 up 3.8
- Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 161 542 7706 Fax+44 171 542 5017
Paribas repeats buy on Aegon after results .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-22
Summary of Aug 22 research .
Company-------------Price---Broker----------------
Aegon 83.40 Paribas
COMMENT : " Not only did Aegon surprise with earnings of 711 million guilders , which were above the top of the expected range , it also forecast a similar performance in the second half . "
Reiterates previous " buy " recommendation after results .
Estimates ( Dfl ) : EPS P / E Dividend
1996 5.83 13.8 2.75
1997 6.59 12.2 3.10
-- Amsterdam newsroom , +31 20 504 5000 ( Fax +31 20 504 5040 )
Clinton 's Ballybunion fans invited to Chicago .
DUBLIN 1996-08-22
U.S. President Bill Clinton had to drop the resort of Ballybunion from a whirlwind Irish tour last year .
So Ballybunion is going to America instead .
Two residents of the Atlantic resort , where Clinton was to have played golf with the Irish Foreign Minister Dick Spring , have been invited to the Democratic party convention in Chicago on August 26-29 .
They have been asked to bring with them the placards they waved when Clinton addressed Ireland at a packed ceremony in Dublin city centre on December 1 , last year .
They read : " Ballybunion backs Clinton . "
" The Democratic party have requested we bring our placards with us .
We will be guests of the Kennedys , " said Frank Quilter , one of the two who have been invited to Chicago .
Clinton made a triumphant Irish tour to back a Northern Ireland peace process but was forced to drop Ballybunion from a packed schedule at the last minute .
Bonn says Moscow has promised to observe ceasefire .
BONN 1996-08-22
Germany said on Thursday it had received assurances from the Russian government that its forces would observe the latest ceasefire in Chechnya .
Foreign Ministry spokesman Martin Erdmann said top Bonn diplomat Wolfgang Ischinger had been assured by senior Russian officials that the ultimatum to storm and take the Chechen capital of Grozny was not valid .
" The Russian side confirmed that the ceasefire is in place and they will keep to it , " Erdmann told Reuters after speaking by telephone to Ischinger , who had met the officials on a two-day visit to Moscow .
He returned to Bonn on Thursday .
Ischinger is the political director of Bonn 's foreign ministry .
Ischinger said he met three Russian deputy foreign ministers and a vice defence minister , who confirmed Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov 's pledge that Moscow would seek a political solution under the aegis of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe ( OSCE ) .
" The ultimatum ( to storm Grozny ) is no longer an issue , " he said quoting Ischinger , who had been sent to Moscow by German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel as his personal envoy to urge an end to Moscow 's military campaign in the breakaway region .
Ischinger said the threat of a major assault to take Grozny had been the unauthorised initiative of the commanding general and not Moscow 's intention .
The officials had been positive about Kinkel 's request on Wednesday that President Boris Yeltsin 's security chief Alexander Lebed should , on his return to Moscow , meet Tim Goldiman , the OSCE representative responsible for Chechnya , he said .
India says sees no arms race with China , Pakistan .
NEW DELHI 1996-08-22
India said on Thursday that its opposition to a global nuclear test ban treaty did not mean New Delhi intended to enter into an arms race with neighbouring Pakistan and China .
Foreign Minister I.K. Gujral was asked at a news conference if India 's decision to block adoption of the accord in Geneva would lead to an arms race with Pakistan and China .
" I do n't see that possibility because India is not entering into any arms race , " he said . "
Our not signing a new treaty does not mean we are going in for any new kind of weapons , particularly nuclear . "
China , along with Britain , France , Russia and the United States , is a declared nuclear power .
India carried out a nuclear test in 1974 but says it has not built the bomb .
Experts believe both India and Pakistan could quickly assemble nuclear weapons .
Gujral said he did not expect India 's veto of the Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty ( CTBT ) to damage bilateral ties with other nations .
" I do not visualise its straining our bilateral relations with any country .
The text has already been blocked , " he said .
Gujral said India would re-examine its position if the treaty , particularly a clause providing for its entry into force , was modified .
Asked what India would do if the pact were forwarded to the United Nations General Assembly , Gujral said : " That bridge I will cross when I come to it . "
In a written statement released at the news conference , Gujral reiterated India 's objections to the treaty , under negotiation at the Conference on Disarmament in Geneva .
" It is a sad fact that the nuclear weapon states show no interest in giving up their nuclear hegemony , " the statement said .
Gujral said India had national security concerns that made it impossible for New Delhi to sign the CTBT .
" Our security concerns oblige us to maintain our nuclear option , " he said , adding that India had exercised restraint in not carrying out any nuclear tests since the country 's lone test blast in 1974 .
He said : " We cannot accept constraints on our option as long as nuclear weapon states continue to rely on their nuclear arsenals for their security " .
Britain says death of its citizen will sour ties .
DHAKA 1996-08-22
A British minister expressed his government 's official disquiet on Thursday at the recent death of a British citizen of Bangladeshi origin at Dhaka airport .
" I have told Bangladesh leaders that British goverment has attached serious importance to the resolution of the tragic death of Siraj Mia , " Under-Secretary of State for Foreign and Commonwealth Affairs Liam Fox Fox , told reporters .
Siraj Mia died at Dhaka airport on May 9 during interogation by customs officials after arriving from London .
His body bore multiple injuries , and his relatives complained that he was murdered .
A post-mortem report suggested he might have been tortured .
But customs authorities said the passenger was drunk and died of loss of blood from a deep cut in his wrist after he hit a glass sheet .
Fox , who arrived in Bangladesh on Tuesday on four-day visit , said Britain wanted Dhaka to act seriously on the case .
" This is one of the reasons of my visit here ...
this is an important issue in our relationship " , said Fox , who is due to leave for Nepal on Friday .
Fox said the incident had strained relations between the two governments .
He said the Mia 's issue had been raised in the House of Commons .
Fox said he had brought up the issue at every meeting he had had with government leaders in Dhaka .
He said the Bangladesh government had assured him it was taking the matter seriously .
" The British government wants a thorough investigation and a just outcome , " he said .
Fox said the British government wanted an end to the alleged harassment of its nationals at Dhaka airport by customs officials .
Bangladesh 's Criminal Investigation Department has charged two immigration officials in connection with Mia 's killing .
Mia , a father of five children , had a restaurant business in a London suburb .
India fears attempts to disrupt Kashmir polls .
SRINAGAR , India 1996-08-22
India 's Home ( interior ) Minister accused Pakistan on on Thursday of planning to disrupt state elections in troubled Jammu and Kashmir state .
" It seems that from across the border there is going to be a planned attempt to disrupt the elections , " Inderjit Gupta told reporters in the state capital Srinagar .
The local polls next month will be the first since 1987 in the state , clamped under direct rule from New Delhi since 1990 .
India has often accused Pakistan of abetting militancy in the valley , a charge Islamabad has always denied .
Gupta said there might be an increase in the number of people infiltrating the Kashmir valley to create disturbance in the region .
" We noticed among the people who come from across the border , there is a growing number of foreign mercenaries , " Gupta said .
India and Pakistan have fought two of their three wars over the troubled region of Kashmir since independence from Britain in 1947 .
Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda 's centre-left government hopes the elections will help restore normality and democratic rule in Jammu and Kashmir , where more than 20,000 people have died in insurgency-related violence since 1990 .
Over a dozen militant groups are fighting New Delhi 's rule in the state .
Dhaka stocks end up on gains by engineering , banks .
DHAKA 1996-08-22
Dhaka stocks edged up on sharply higher volume as engineering and cash shares gained amid buying by both small and institutional investors , brokers said .
The Dhaka Stock Exchange ( DSE ) all-share price index rose 8.05 points or 0.7 percent to 1,156.79 on a turnover of 146.2 million taka .
Of the total 119 issues traded 71 closed higher , 44 ended lower and four remained unchanged .
.
National Bank rose 12.71 taka to 228.7 , Eastern Cables gained 20.37 to 677.98 and Apex Tannery lost 22.72 to 597 .
Brokers said the stocks recovered early losses to edge up at close because of institutional support and short-covering ahead of Friday weekend .
India RBI chief sees cut in cash reserve ratio .
NEW DELHI 1996-08-22
The Reserve bank of India governor C. Rangarajan said on Thursday that he expected the cash reserve ratio ( CRR ) maintained by banks to be reduced over the medium term .
" Over the medium term , yes , " he told Reuters after addressing industrialists in the capital .
He denied having said in a recent newspaper interview that the CRR could be raised if necessary .
He said he was only trying ( in that newspaper report ) to explain the theoretical position on the use of the CRR by central banks to manage money supply .
Rangarajan explained that the cash reserve ratio was an instrument that central banks could use to regulate money supply by reducing or increasing the ratio .
But in the current context , the government stood by an earlier commitment to reduce it over a period of time , he said in response to a question .
-- New Delhi newsroom , +91-11-3012024
Two pct India current account deficit viable - RBI .
BOMBAY 1996-08-22
The Reserve Bank of India Governor Chakravarty Rangarajan said on Thursday that a current account deficit of two percent of gross domestic product ( GDP ) was sustainable given the currrent rate of growth .
" The current account deficit of around two percent of GDP is a sustainable level of deficit given the expected real growth rate and the trends in imports and exports , " Rangarajan said in an address to business leaders in New Delhi .
Rangarajan said a current account deficit of two percent brought about by a 16-17 percent annual growth in exports and a 14-15 percent rise in imports along with an increase in non-debt flows could lead to a reduction in the debt-service ratio to below 20 percent over the next five years .
-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000
Mother Teresa devoted to world 's poor .
CALCUTTA 1996-08-22
Mother Teresa , known as the Saint of the Gutters , won the Nobel Peace Prize in 1979 for bringing hope and dignity to millions of poor , unwanted people with her simple message : " The poor must know that we love them . "
While the world heaps honours on her and even regards her as a living saint , the nun of Albanian descent maintains she is merely doing God 's work .
" It gives me great joy and fulfilment to love and care for the poor and neglected , " she said . "
The poor do not need our sympathy and pity .
They need our love and compassion . "
The diminutive Roman Catholic missionary was on respiratory support in intensive care in an Indian nursing home on Thursday after suffering heart failure .
But an attending doctor said Mother Teresa , who turns 86 next Tuesday , was conscious and in stable condition .
The task Mother Teresa began alone in 1949 in the slums of densely-populated Calcutta , and grew to touch the hearts of people around the world .
When in 1979 she was told she had won the Nobel Peace Prize , she said characteristically : " I am unworthy . "
The world disagreed , showering more than 80 national and international honours on her including the Bharat Ratna , or Jewel of India , the country 's highest civilian award .
Her health began to deteriorate in 1989 when she was fitted with a heart pacemaker .
A year later , the Vatican announced she was stepping down as Superior of her Missionaries of Charity order .
More than 100 delegates flew in from around the world to elect a successor .
They could not agree , so asked her to stay on .
She agreed .
In 1991 , Mother Teresa was treated at a California hospital for heart disease and bacterial pneumonia .
In 1993 , she fell in Rome and broke three ribs .
In August the same year , while in New Delhi to receive yet another award , she developed malaria , complicated by her heart and lung problems .
Last April she fractured her left collar bone .
But her increasing frailty , arthritis and failing eyesight has not stopped her travels around the world to mingle with the poor and desperate .
Mother Teresa was born Agnes Goinxha Bejaxhiu to Albanian parents in Skopje , in what was then Serbia , on August 27 , 1910 .
She attended a government school and was already deeply religious by the time she was 12 .
At the age of 18 she became a Loretto nun , hoping to work at the Order 's Calcutta mission .
She was sent to Loretto Abbey in Dublin and from there to India to begin her novitiate and teach geography at a convent school in Calcutta .
She said her divine call to work among the poor came in September , 1946 . "
The message was quite clear , " she told one interviewer . "
I was to leave the convent and help the poor while living among them .
It was an order .
I knew where I belonged . "
The Vatican and the mother superior in Dublin approved and after intensive training as a nurse with American missionaries she opened her first Calcutta slum school in December 1949 .
She took the name of Teresa , after France 's Saint Therese of the Child Jesus .
In India she was simply called Mother .
Mother Teresa set up her first home for the dying in a Hindu rest house in Calcutta after she saw a penniless woman turned away by a city hospital .
Named " Nirmal Hriday " ( Tender Heart ) , it was the first of a chain of 150 homes for dying , destitute people , admitting nearly 18,000 a year .
Her Missionaries of Charity , a Roman Catholic religious order she founded in 1949 , now runs about 300 homes for unwanted children and the destitute in India and abroad .
In 1994 a British television documentary called the myth around Mother Teresa a mixture of " hyperbole and credulity " .
Catholics around the world rose to her defence .
RTRS - FOCUS-News forecasts alien-led profit boost .
Bernard Hickey
SYDNEY 1996-08-22
Media baron Rupert Murdoch 's News Corp Ltd reported lower than expected 1995/96 profits on Thursday , but forecast that the hit film " Independence Day " would help increase profits by at least 20 percent in 1996/97 .
" From an earnings perspective , the current fiscal year has begun with great promise due to the hit motion picture ' Independence Day , ' " News Corp said in a statement announcing its results for the year to June 30 , 1996 .
It said moderating paper prices and solid orders for advertising at its Fox Broadcasting television network in the United States would also help boost profits in the 1996/97 year . "
A budgeted profit increase of at least 20 percent for the full year currently appears very attainable , " News Corp said .
The bullish comments for the coming year soothed analysts and most shareholders , who were disappointed by the lower than expected profit for 1995/96 .
News announced pre-abnormals net profit for the year fell six percent to A$ 1.26 billion ( US$ 995 million ) and earnings per share dropped to 40 cents from 46 cents .
Analysts had on average expected a pre-abnormals profit of A$ 1.343 billion .
" The year just gone was disappointing , but the outlook for the current year looks good , " First Pacific media analyst Lachlan Drummond said .
News Corp said strong performances in U.S. television and British newspapers were offset by lower profits from News Corp 's magazine and publishing divisions and further hefty losses from its Asian Star TV operations .
Higher newsprint prices hit profits hard . "
Throughout the group , higher paper prices increased costs by over US$ 300 million , " it said .
News Corp said British newspaper operating profits rose 10 percent for the year , as higher cover prices at The Sun and The Times and higher advertising volumes offset increased newsprint costs .
Advertising revenues at The Times grew 20 percent .
Analysts said sharply lower earnings from News Corp 's book publishing division and its U.S. magazines had been the major surprises in the results for 1995/96 .
News Corp said revenue gains at its magazines and inserts division were offset by higher paper prices and lower sales at the U.S. TV Guide .
News said dramatically lower earnings from the British arm of its Harper-Collins publishing division more than offset healthy results from its U.S. operation .
It said the demise of the Net Book Agreement had hurt the British operations , and weak performances from the San Francisco unit of Harper-Collins had not helped .
The minimum price setting expired last September when three publishers pulled out .
But it was the bullish profit forecast for 1996/97 that took the spotlight in the market , with some analysts saying 20 percent may even be an understatement .
" If they 're saying at least 20 percent , then their internal forecasts are probably saying 25 or 30 percent , " said one Sydney media analyst who declined to be named .
News Corp 's shares were down eight cents at A$ 6.39 at 2.00 p.m. ( 0400 GMT ) in a soft market .
( A$ 1 = US$ 0.79 )
-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800
RTRS - Budget cuts to boost Australia savings - RBA .
CANBERRA 1996-08-22
The Australian government 's plans to slash its budget deficit should make a useful contribution to national savings , the Reserve Bank of Australia ( RBA ) said in its annual report .
" The government 's announced plans to balance the budget , if realised , would make a useful contribution to raising national savings , " the RBA said .
The bank said there were concerns fiscal consolidation would unduly restrict growth , but evidence was ambiguous .
In its 1996/97 budget announced on Tuesday , the Australian Coalition government announced an underlying budget deficit of A$ 5.65 billion , and pledged to return the underlying budget balance to surplus by 1998/99 .
The budget deficit was A$ 10.3 billion in 1995/96 .
-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800
" Determined and credible efforts to rein in unsustainable fiscal positions ( are ) often rewarded by rising confidence , giving favourable effects on economic activity even in the short term , " it said .
" More generally , the long-term effects of fiscal consolidation are clearly positive , with higher saving tending to promote economic growth by raising investment and lowering long-term real interest rates , " the RBA said .
BNZ cuts NZ fixed home lending rates .
WELLINGTON 1996-08-22
Bank of New Zealand said on Thursday it was cutting its fixed home lending rates .
The rates are :
New rate old rate
Six month rate 10.5 pct 10.75
One year 10.5 pct 10.95
Two year 10.5 pct 11.25
Three year 10.5 pct 11.25
BNZ said it was responding to lower wholesale rates .
Fixed business and farm lending rates rates were left unchanged although they were under review .
-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746
Power NZ ODV up 8 pct at NZ$ 524 million .
WELLINGTON 1996-08-22
Power New Zealand said on Thursday that the Optimised Deprival Value ( ODV ) of its network at March 31 , 1996 has been set at $ 524.2 million , an increase of eight percent on its $ 486.5 million valuation a year earlier .
The company said the increase reflected the value of extensions to the network to meet economic growth in its supply area and an increase in the estimated lifespan of the network .
It said the increase was consistent with the approach followed by other power companies and reflected the company 's new levels of preventative maintenance and equipment upgrading .
The revaluation was undertaken to meet the disclosure
requirements of the Ministry of Commerce .
-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746
Thais hunt for Australian jail breaker .
BANGKOK
Thailand has launched a manhunt for an Australian who escaped from a high security prison in Bangkok while awaiting trial on drug possession charges , officials said on Thursday .
Daniel Westlake , 46 , from Victoria , made the first sucessful escape from Klongprem prison in the northern outskirts of the capital on Sunday night .
He was believed by prison officials to still be in Thailand .
" We have ordered a massive hunt for him and I am quite confident we will get him soon , " Vivit Chatuparisut , deputy director general of the Correction Department , told Reuters .
Westlake , arrested in December 1993 and charged with heroin trafficking , sawed the iron grill off his cell window and climbed down the prison 's five-metre ( 15-foot ) wall on a rope made from bed sheets , Vivit said .
The corrections department was probing the escape and had ordered all foreign inmates chained to prevent more breakouts .
There are 266 Westerners , including six Australians , in the prison , most awaiting trial on drugs charges .
There also are about 5,000 Thai inmates in Klongprem , a prison official said .
Tokyo Soir - 1996 parent forecast .
TOKYO 1996-08-22
Year to December 31 , 1996
( in billions of yen unless specified )
LATEST ACTUAL
( Parent ) FORECAST YEAR-AGO
Sales 26.00 26.70
Current 400 million 329 million
Net 250 million 84 million
EPS 11.61 yen 3.92 yen
Ord div 10.00 yen 10.00 yen
NOTE - Tokyo Soir Co Ltd is a specialised manufacturer of women " s formal wear .
Ka Wah Bank sets HK$ 43 mln FRCD .
HONG KONG 1996-08-22
Ka Wah Bank 's HK$ 43 million floating rate certificate of deposit issue has been privately placed , sole arranger HSBC Markets said .
The facility has a tenor of six months .
It pays a coupon of 15 basis points over the six-month Hong Kong Interbank Offered Rate .
Other details are not available .
The deposit date is September 5 , 1996 .
Clearing is through the Hong Kong Central Moneymarkets Unit .
-- Hong Kong Newsroom ( 852 ) 2847 4039
Malaysia bans nitrofuran usage in chicken feed .
KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-22
Malaysia has banned the use of nitrofuran , an antibiotic , in chicken feed and veterinary applications because it believes the drug could cause cancer , the health ministry said on Thursday .
" It is hoped that livestock breeders and feedmillers will abide by the laws and respect the cabinet decision in the interest of consumer safety , " Health Minister Chua Jui Meng was quoted as saying by the national Bernama news agency .
Chua said offenders could face a two-year prison sentence and a maximum fine of 5,000 ringgit ( $ 2000 ) .
" The ban takes effect immediately , " he added .
INDONESIAN STOCKS - factors to watch - August 22 .
JAKARTA 1996-08-22
Following are some of the main factors likely to affect Indonesian stocks on Thursday :
** Security was tight in Jakarta ahead of a trial involving ousted Indonesian Democratic Party leader Megawati Sukarnoputri .
Around 200 police and troops were stationed outside the court in central Jakarta but there was no sign of demonstrators .
** The Dow Jones industrial average closed down 31.44 points at 5,689.82 on Wednesday , ending a three-session winning streak as investors took profits and tobacco stocks took a beating .
MARKETS :
** The Jakarta composite index rose 2.60 points , or 0.48 percent , to 542.20 points on Wednesday on the back of bargain-hunting in selected big-capitalised stocks and secondliners .
** On Thursday , the Indonesian rupiah was at 2,343.00 / 43.50 in early trading against an opening of 2,342.75 / 43.50 .
STOCKS TO WATCH
** Packaging manufacturer Super Indah Makmur on announcement of a tender offer by PT VDH Teguh Sakti , a wholly-owned subsidiary of Singapore-listed Van Der Horst .
** Privately-owned Bank Duta on market talk that it is obtaining fresh syndicated loans , a management reshuffle and fresh equity injection .
** Ciputra Development on reports of a plan to build property projects worth $ 2 billion in Jakarta and Surabaya .
Key stock and currency market movements at 1600 GMT .
LONDON 1996-08-23
The following table shows the latest close of key indices* on major world stock exchanges , the day 's change in points and the indices ' 1996 closing highs and lows ( with dates ) .
Also shown are the London closing values of the German mark , the Japanese yen , the British pound and gold bullion ( previous day 's closes in brackets ) :
AUG 23 DAY 'S CHANGE 1996 HIGH 1996 LOW
CLOSE IN POINTS
NEW YORK 5,710.53 - 22.94 5,778.00 5,032.94
( midday ) ( May 22 ) ( Jan 10 )
LONDON 3,907.5 +16.4 3,907.5 3,632.3
( Aug 23 ) ( Jul 16 )
TOKYO 21,228.80 - 134.44 22,666.80 19,734.70
( Jun 26 ) ( Mar 13 )
FRANKFURT 2,555.16 - 2.10 2,583.49 ) 2,284.86
( Jul 5 ) ( Jan 2 )
PARIS 2,020.82 +3.06 2,146.79 1,897.85
( Apr 30 ) ( Jan 11 )
SYDNEY 2,292.9 +18.3 2,326.00 2,096.10
( Apr 26 ) ( Jul 17 )
HONG KONG 11,424.64 - 54.13 11,594.99 10,204.87
( Feb 16 ) ( Jan 2 )
- - - -
FOREIGN EXCHANGE / GOLD BULLION CLOSE IN LONDON
Dollar / mark ...
1.4871 ( 1.4935 )
Dollar / yen ....
108.50 ( 108.43 )
Pound / dollar ..
$ 1.5520 ( $ 1.5497 )
Gold ( ounce ) ..
$ 387.50 ( $ 386.95 )
- - - -
*INDICES USED AND THEIR ALL-TIME CLOSING HIGHS
New York Dow Jones industrial average -- 5,778.00 ( May 22/96 )
London FTSE-100 index -- 3,907.5 ( Aug 23/96 )
Tokyo Nikkei average -- 38,915.87 ( Dec 29/89 )
Frankfurt DAX-3O index -- 2,583.49 ( Jul 5/96 )
Paris CAC-40 General index -- 2,355.93 ( Feb 2/94 )
Sydney Australian All-Ordinaries index -- 2,340.6 ( Feb 3/94 )
Hong Kong Hang Seng index -- 12,201.09 ( Jan 4/94 )
Ukraine hails peace as marks five-year independence .
Rostislav Khotin
KIEV 1996-08-23
Ukraine celebrates five years of independence from Kremlin rule on Saturday , hailing civil and inter-ethnic peace as its main post-Soviet achievement .
Ukraine 's declaration of independence in 1991 , backed nine-to-one by a referendum in December of that year , effectively dealt a death blow to the Soviet empire and ended more than three centuries of rule from Moscow .
Ukraine , with a Russian community of 11 million people -- the world 's largest outside Russia -- has avoided conflicts like those in Russia 's Chechnya , neighbouring Moldova , and the former Soviet republics of Georgia , Azerbaijan and Tajikistan .
" Ukraine 's biggest achievements for five years are the preservation of civil peace and inter-ethnic harmony , " President Leonid Kuchma said in televised statement this week .
" Unlike many other post-Soviet countries we were able to deal with conflict situations in a peaceful and civilised way . "
But independence was initially accompanied by hyper-inflation and economic collapse , although there are signs of a turnaround .
Inflation -- a hyper-inflationary 10,300 percent a year in 1993 -- was a respectable 0.1 percent a month in June and July and the economy has just begun to grow .
Kuchma told a solemn ceremony at the Ukraina Palace on Friday that " there was a turning point " in reforms and that he expected a rise in the standard of living in the near future .
" There is no doubt that economic growth has already started , " said Adelbert Knobl , head of the International Monetary Fund 's mission in Ukraine . "
The national bank and the government have every reason to be proud of their efforts . "
Central bank officials said on Thursday that a much-postponed hryvna currency would " definitely " be introduced before the end of this year .
It will replace the interim karbovanets currency , which was introduced at par to the Russian rouble in 1992 but now trades at almost 33 karbovanets per rouble .
Ukraine has repeatedly promised to introduce the hryvna but had to postpone the plans because of economic problems .
Proud of its record in promptly joining both the Council of Europe and NATO 's Partnership for Peace , Ukraine caused a foreign policy wrangle this week , offending China by allowing a Taiwanese minister to appear on a public , if unofficial visit .
China cancelled a visit by a top-level delegation in protest .
Kiev 's Foreign Minister Hennady Udovenko said Beijing was overreacting .
But Ukraine , seeing itself as a bridge between Russia and the rapidly Westernising countries of eastern Europe , is looking West as well as East .
" The strategic aim of European integration should not in any way damage Ukraine 's interests in post-Soviet areas .
Relations with Russia , which is our main partner , have great importance , " Kuchma said .
" But Ukraine cannot be economically oriented on Russia , even though those in some circles push us to do that . "
Kuchma has said Kiev wants membership of the European Union , associate membership of the Western European Union defence grouping and to move closer to NATO .
A message from the West this week from U.S. President Bill Clinton congratulated Ukraine on the anniversary , promising to support market reforms and praising Ukraine as a " stabilising factor " in a united Europe .
Oldest Albania book disappears from Vatican - paper .
TIRANA 1996-08-23
A 16th-century document , the earliest complete example of written Albanian , has disappeared from the Vatican archives , an Albanian newspaper said on Friday .
Gazeta Shqiptare said the " Book of Mass ' , by Gjon Buzuku , dating from 1555 and discovered in 1740 in a religious seminary in Rome , was the first major document published in the Albanian language .
" We Albanians , sons of Buzuku , believed our language had a written document but now we do not have it any more , " lamented scholar Musa Hamiti , told of the loss by the Vatican library .
Tirana 's national library has three copies of the " Book of Mass ' . "
There is nothing left for us but to be grateful to civilisation for inventing photocopies , " Gazeta Shqiptare said .
Russia to clamp down on barter deals .
MOSCOW 1996-08-23
Russian officials , keen to cut capital flight , will adopt tight measures to cut barter deals in foreign trade to a minimum , a customs official said on Friday .
" We have always been concerned about barter deals with other countries , viewing them as a disguised kind of capital flight from Russia , " Marina Volkova , deputy head of the currency department at the State Customs Committee , told Reuters .
Volkova said last year goods had been exported under many Russian barter deals , with nothing imported in return .
She said the cost of such unimported goods was $ 1.10 billion in 1995 .
Barter deals were worth $ 4.9 billion last year , or about eight percent of all Russian exports estimated at $ 61.5 billion , she said .
" The cost of exported goods is too often understated , so the actual share of barter deals in Russian exports and the amount of unimported goods may be even higher , " Volkova said .
A few days ago Russian President Boris Yeltsin issued a decree on state regulation of foreign barter deals , and Volkova said this " could substantially improve the situation " .
In line with the decree , which will come into force on November 1 , all Russian barter traders will be obliged to import goods worth the cost of their exports within 180 days .
" If traders are late , they will have to pay fines worth the cost of their exported goods , " Volkova said .
Understating the cost of exported goods could still be a loophole for barter dealers , but Volkova said the authorities are currently " tackling the technicalities of the issue " .
Barter has always been a feature of the Soviet Union 's foreign trade , but Yeltsin 's decrees liberalising foreign trade in 1991-1992 has given barter a new impetus .
A few years ago , barter deals accounted for up to 25-30 percent of Russian exports because " thousands ( of ) trade companies which popped up preferred barter in the absence of reliable Russian banks and money transfer systems " , Volkova said .
" Now many Russian banks are strong and can make various sorts of money tranfers , while incompetent traders are being ousted by more experienced ones .
But the current share of barter deals in Russian exports is still high , " she said .
-- Dmitry Solovyov , Moscow Newsroom , +7095 941 8520
Viacom plans " Mission " sequel - report .
LOS ANGELES 1996-08-22
Paramount Pictures is going ahead with a sequel to the Tom Cruise blockbuster , " Mission : Impossible " and hopes to release it in the summer of 1998 , Daily Variety reported in its Friday edition .
The big-screen version of the spy TV series has grossed $ 175 million domestically since opening May 22 , and $ 338 million overseas so far .
It 's the biggest success for Viacom Inc-owned Paramount since 1994 's " Forrest Gump " .
However , many critics complained its plot was incomprehensible .
Cruise will reprise his roles as star and co-producer , and will soon meet Academy Award-winning screenwriter William Goldman , who will write the script , the report said .
It said " Mission : Impossible " director Brian De Palma would have first crack at the sequel , though no deals have been made yet .
Goldman , whose Oscars were for " Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid " and " All the President 's Men " , earlier this summer criticised some of the season 's blockbusters .
However , he singled out " Mission : Impossible " as an especially entertaining movie , Daily Variety said .
CRICKET - CRAWLEY FORCED TO SIT AND WAIT .
LONDON 1996-08-23
England batsman John Crawley was forced to endure a frustrating delay of over three hours before resuming his quest for a maiden test century in the third test against Pakistan on Friday .
Heavy overnight rain and morning drizzle ruled out any play before lunch on the second day but an improvement in the weather prompted the umpires to announce a 1415 local time ( 1315 GMT ) start in the event of no further rain .
Crawley , unbeaten on 94 overnight in an England total of 278 for six , was spotted strumming a guitar in the dressing-room as the Oval ground staff took centre stage .
There were several damp patches on the square and the outfield and it was still raining when the players took an early lunch at 1230 local time ( 1130 GMT ) .
When brighter weather finally arrived , the umpires announced a revised figure of 67 overs to be bowled with play extended to at least 1900 local time ( 1800 GMT ) .
MOTOR RACING - BELGIAN GRAND PRIX PRACTICE TIMES .
SPA-FRANCORCHAMPS , Belgium 1996-08-23
Leading times
after Friday 's opening practice sessions for Sunday 's
Belgian Grand Prix motor race :
1. Gerhard Berger ( Austria ) Benetton 1 minute 53.706 seconds
2. David Coulthard ( Britain ) McLaren 1:54.342
3. Jacques Villeneuve ( Canada ) Williams 1:54.443
4. Mika Hakkinen ( Finland ) McLaren 1:54.754
5. Heinz-Harald Frentzen ( Germany ) 1:54.984
6. Jean Alesi ( France ) Benetton 1:55.101
7. Damon Hill ( Britain ) Williams 1:55.281
8. Michael Schumacher ( Germany ) 1:55.333
9. Martin Brundle ( Britain ) Jordan 1:55.385
10. Rubens Barrichello ( Brazil ) Jordan 1:55.645
11. Johnny Herbert ( Britain ) Sauber 1:56.318
12. Olivier Panis ( France ) Ligier 1:56.417
TENNIS - RESULTS AT TOSHIBA CLASSIC .
[ CORRECTED 05:30 GMT ]
CARLSBAD , California 1996-08-22
Results from the
$ 450,000 Toshiba Classic tennis tournament on Thursday ( prefix
number denotes seeding ) :
Quarter-finals
2 - Conchita Martinez ( Spain ) beat Nathalie Tauziat ( France )
6-3 6-4
Second round
5 - Gabriela Sabatini ( Argentina ) beat Asa Carlsson ( Sweden )
6-1 7-5
Katarina Studenikova ( Slovakia ) beat 6 - Karina Habsudova
( Slovakia ) 7-6 ( 7-4 ) 6-2
( Corrects that Habsudova is sixth seed ) .
SOCCER - ENGLISH FIRST DIVISION RESULTS .
LONDON 1996-08-23
Results of English first division
soccer matches on Friday :
Portsmouth 1 Queens Park Rangers 2
Tranmere 3 Grimsby 2
SOCCER - SCOTTISH THIRD DIVISION RESULT .
GLASGOW 1996-08-23
Result of a Scottish third
division soccer match on Friday :
East Stirling 0 Albion 1
CRICKET - ENGLISH COUNTY CHAMPIONSHIP SCORES .
LONDON 1996-08-23
Close of play scores in four-day
English County Championship cricket matches on Friday :
Third day
At Weston-super-Mare : Durham 326 ( D. Cox 95 not out ,
S. Campbell 69 ; G. Rose 7-73 ) .
Somerset 298-6 ( M. Lathwell 85 ,
R. Harden 65 ) .
Second day
At Colchester : Gloucestershire 280 ( J. Russell 63 , A. Symonds
52 ; A. Cowan 5-68 ) .
Essex 194-0 ( G. Gooch 105 not out , D. Robinson
72 not out ) .
At Cardiff : Kent 255-3 ( D. Fulton 64 , M. Walker 59 , C. Hooper
52 not out ) v Glamorgan .
At Leicester : Leicestershire 343-8 ( P. Simmons 108 , P. Nixon
67 not out ) v Hampshire .
At Northampton : Sussex 389 ( N. Lenham 145 , V. Drakes 59 ,
A. Wells 51 ; A. Penberthy 4-36 ) .
Northamptonshire 160-4 ( K. Curran
79 not out ) .
At Trent Bridge : Nottinghamshire 392-6 ( G. Archer 143 not
out , M. Dowman 107 ) v Surrey .
At Worcester : Warwickshire 310 ( A. Giles 83 , T. Munton 54 not
out , W. Khan 52 ; R. Illingworth 4-54 , S. Lampitt 4-90 ) .
Worcestershire 10-0 .
At Headingley : Yorkshire 529-8 declared ( C. White 181 ,
R. Blakey 109 not out , M. Moxon 66 , M. Vaughan 57 ) .
Lancashire
162-4 ( N. Fairbrother 53 not out ) .
CRICKET - POLLOCK HOPES FOR RETURN TO WARWICKSHIRE .
LONDON 1996-08-23
South African all-rounder Shaun Pollock , forced to cut short his first season with Warwickshire to have ankle surgery , has told the English county he would like to return later in his career .
Pollock , who returns home a month early next week , said : " I would like to come back and play county cricket in the future and I do n't think I would like to swap counties . "
Explaining his premature departure was unavoidable , Pollock said : " I have been carrying the injury for a while and I hope that by having the surgery now I will be able to last out the new season back home . "
CRICKET - ENGLAND V PAKISTAN FINAL TEST SCOREBOARD .
LONDON 1996-08-23
Scoreboard on the second day of
the third and final test between England and Pakistan at The
Oval on Friday :
England first innings
M. Atherton b Waqar Younis 31
A. Stewart b Mushtaq Ahmed 44
N. Hussain c Saeed Anwar b Waqar Younis 12
G. Thorpe lbw b Mohammad Akram 54
J. Crawley b Waqar Younis 106
N. Knight b Mushtaq Ahmed 17
C. Lewis b Wasim Akram 5
I. Salisbury c Inzamam-ul-Haq b Wasim Akram 5
D. Cork c Moin Khan b Waqar Younis 0
R. Croft not out 5
A. Mullally b Wasim Akram 24
Extras ( lb-12 w-1 nb-10 ) 23
Total 326
Fall of wickets : 1-64 2-85 3-116 4-205 5-248 6-273 7-283
8-284 9-295
Bowling : Wasim Akram 29.2-9-83-3 , Waqar Younis 25-6-95-4 ,
Mohammad Akram 12-1-41-1 , Mushtaq Ahmed 27-5-78-2 , Aamir Sohail
6-1-17-0
Pakistan first innings
Saeed Anwar not out 116
Aamir Sohail c Cork b Croft 46
Ijaz Ahmed not out 58
Extras ( lb-1 nb-8 ) 9
Total ( for one wicket ) 229
Fall of wicket - 1-106
To bat : Inzamam-ul-Haq , Salim Malik , Asif Mujtaba , Wasim
Akram , Moin Khan , Mushtaq Ahmed , Waqar Younis , Mohammad Akam
Bowling ( to date ) : Lewis 9-1-49-0 , Mullally 9-3-28-0 , Croft
17-3-42-1 , Cork 7-1-38-0 , Salisbury 14-0-71-0
CRICKET - ENGLAND 326 ALL OUT V PAKISTAN IN THIRD TEST .
LONDON 1996-08-23
England were all out for 326 in their first innings on the second day of the third and final test against Pakistan at The Oval on Friday .
Score : England 326 ( J. Crawley 106 , G. Thorpe 54 .
Waqar Younis 4-95 )
SOCCER - SPONSORS CASH IN ON RAVANELLI 'S SHIRT DANCE .
LONDON 1996-08-23
Middlesbrough 's Italian striker Fabrizio Ravanelli is to wear his team sponsor 's name on the inside of his shirt so it can be seen when he scores .
Every time he finds the net , the grey-haired forward pulls his shirtfront over his head as he runs to salute the fans , and Middlesbrough 's sponsors want to cash in on the spectacle .
" Having seen Ravanelli celebrate his goals ...
we thought it would be fun to have ( the name ) on the inside of his shirt , " a spokesman for the sponsors said .
" It will give the fans something else to look at besides his chest . "
Ravanelli aggravated a foot injury in the 1-0 defeat at Chelsea on Wednesday and was given only an even chance of playing at Nottingham Forest on Saturday by his manager Bryan Robson .
TENNIS - AUSTRALIANS ADVANCE AT CANADIAN OPEN .
TORONTO 1996-08-22
It was Australia Day at the $ 2 million Canadian Open on Thursday as three Aussies reached the quarter-finals with straight-set victories .
Unseeded Patrick Rafter recorded the most noteworthy result as he upset sixth-seeded American MaliVai Washington 6-2 6-1 in just 50 minutes .
Todd Woodbridge , who defeated Canadian Daniel Nestor 7-6 ( 7-2 ) 7-6 ( 7-4 ) , and Mark Philippoussis , a 6-3 6-4 winner over Bohdan Ulihrach of the Czech Republic , also advanced and will meet in Friday 's quarter-finals .
Third-seeded Wayne Ferreira of South Africa defeated Tim Henman of Britain 6-4 6-4 after a three-hour evening rain delay and fifth-seeded Thomas Enqvist of Sweden won his third-round match , eliminating Petr Korda of the Czech Republic 6-3 6-4 .
Ferreira and Enqvist play in a Friday night quarter-final .
Two Americans , seventh seed Todd Martin and unseeded Alex O'Brien , will meet on Friday after winning matches on Thursday .
Martin overcame Cedric Pioline of France 2-6 6-2 6-4 and O'Brien beat Mikael Tillstrom of Sweden 6-3 2-6 6-3 .
" If you really look at the match , " said the 12th-ranked Washington after losing to the 70th-ranked Rafter , " I never really got a chance to play because he was serving big and getting in close to the net .
" He was also able to handle my serve pretty easily because my ( first ) service percentage was only in the 40s .
Put those two things together and you get a loss . "
Rafter missed 10 weeks after wrist surgery earlier this year and the time away from tennis has given him a new perspective .
" Before when I was on tour , I always felt I had to be in bed by 9:30 or 10 o'clock and I had to be up at a certain time , " Rafter said . "
Now I can go to bed at at midnight or wake up at seven in the morning .
I just do n't have as many set routines and it 's made me a happier person . "
Martin was pleased with his victory over Pioline , his first in five meetings with the 11th-ranked Frenchman . "
It 's always difficult to win a match when you lose the first set , especially against someone you have never beaten , " he said .
" I got more aggressive in the second and third sets and the wind picked up and that also affected things because Cedric definitely went off a little bit . "
The 26-year-old O'Brien , who won the ATP Tour stop in New Haven last week , has now won 18 of his last 20 matches , dating back to qualifying rounds in Los Angeles in late July .
He ranks 76th after being 285th four weeks ago .
" I feel I 'm hitting the ball well even though I 'm having more mental letdowns than I did last week , " O'Brien said . "
But I 'm still competing well . "
" I got a lot of first serves in , " said Enqvist about his victory over Korda . "
I did n't miss that many shots and he was making the mistakes . "
Still marvelling at an exciting 64-stroke rally he won in the last game of his second-round match against Javier Sanchez of Spain on Tuesday , Enqvist joked , " Today against Petr there were about 64 strokes in the whole match .
It was mostly short points . "
TENNIS - RESULTS AT CANADIAN OPEN .
TORONTO 1996-08-22
Results from the Canadian Open
tennis tournament on Thursday ( prefix number denotes seeding ) :
Third round
3 - Wayne Ferreira ( South Africa ) beat Tim Henman ( Britain ) 6-4
6-4
4 - Marcelo Rios ( Chile ) beat Daniel Vacek ( Czech Republic ) 6-4
6-3
5 - Thomas Enqvist ( Sweden ) beat Petr Korda ( Czech Republic )
6-3 6-4
Patrick Rafter ( Australia ) beat 6 - MaliVai Washington ( U.S. )
6-2 6-1
7 - Todd Martin ( U.S. ) beat 9 - Cedric Pioline ( France ) 2-6 6-2
6-4
Mark Philippoussis ( Australia ) beat Bohdan Ulihrach ( Czech
Republic ) 6-3 6-4
Alex O'Brien ( U.S. ) beat Mikael Tillstrom ( Sweden ) 6-3 2-6
6-3
Todd Woodbridge ( Australia ) beat Daniel Nestor ( Canada ) 7-6
( 7-2 ) 7-6 ( 7-4 )
RUGBY UNION - MULDER OUT OF SECOND TEST .
JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-23
Centre Japie Mulder has been ruled out of South Africa 's team for the second test against New Zealand in Pretoria on Saturday .
Mulder missed the first test in Durban with back spasms and failed a fitness check on Thursday .
But new Springbok skipper Gary Teichmann has recovered from a bruised thigh and is ready to play , coach Andre Markgraaff said .
Mulder 's absence means that Northern Transvaal centre Andre Snyman should win his second cap alongside provincial colleague Danie van Schalkwyk .
Wing Pieter Hendriks is expected to retain his place , following speculation that Snyman would be picked out of position on the wing .
The line-up would not be announced until shortly before the start , Markgraaff said .
BADMINTON - MALAYSIAN OPEN BADMINTON RESULTS .
KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-23
Results in the Malaysian
Open badminton tournament on Friday ( prefix numbers denote
seedings ) :
Men 's singles , quarter-finals
2 - Ong Ewe Hock ( Malaysia ) beat 5/8 - Hu Zhilan ( China ) 15-2 15-10
9/16 - Luo Yigang ( China ) beat Jason Wong ( Malaysia ) 15-5 15-6
Ijaya Indra ( Indonesia ) beat P. Kantharoopan ( Malaysia ) 15-6 5-4
9/16 - Chen Gang ( China ) beat 9/16 - Hermawan Susanto ( Indonesia )
15-9 15-7
TENNIS - INJURED CHANDA RUBIN OUT OF U.S. OPEN .
NEW YORK 1996-08-23
Promising 10th-ranked American Chanda Rubin has pulled out of the U.S. Open Tennis Championships with a wrist injury , tournament officials announced .
The 20-year-old Rubin , who was to be seeded 11th , is still suffering from tendinitis of the right wrist that has kept her sidelined in recent months .
Rubin 's misfortune turned into a very lucky break for eighth-seeded Olympic champion Lindsay Davenport .
Davenport had drawn one of the toughest first-round assignments of any of the seeded players in 17th-ranked Karina Habsudova of Slovakia .
But as the highest-ranked non-seeded player in the tournament , Habsudova will be moved into Rubin 's slot in the draw , while Davenport will now get a qualifier in the first round , according to U.S. Tennis Association officials .
Rubin is the third notable withdrawal from the women 's competition after 12th-ranked former Australian Open champion Mary Pierce and 20th-ranked Wimbledon semifinalist Meredith McGrath pulled out earlier this week with injuries .
Men 's Australian Open champion Boris Becker will also miss the year 's final Grand Slam with a wrist injury .
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE STANDINGS AFTER THURSDAY 'S GAMES .
NEW YORK 1996-08-23
Major League Baseball
standings after games played on Thursday ( tabulate under won ,
lost , winning percentage and games behind ) :
AMERICAN LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
NEW YORK 72 54 .571 -
BALTIMORE 67 59 .532 5
BOSTON 64 64 .500 9
TORONTO 59 69 .461 14
DETROIT 45 82 .354 27 1/2
CENTRAL DIVISION
CLEVELAND 76 51 .598 -
CHICAGO 69 60 .535 8
MINNESOTA 63 64 .496 13
MILWAUKEE 60 68 .469 16 1/2
KANSAS CITY 58 71 .450 19
WESTERN DIVISION
TEXAS 74 54 .578 -
SEATTLE 65 61 .516 8
OAKLAND 62 68 .477 13
CALIFORNIA 59 68 .465 14 1/2
FRIDAY , AUGUST 23 SCHEDULE
SEATTLE AT BOSTON
MILWAUKEE AT CLEVELAND
CALIFORNIA AT BALTIMORE
OAKLAND AT NEW YORK
TORONTO AT CHICAGO
DETROIT AT KANSAS CITY
TEXAS AT MINNESOTA
NATIONAL LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
ATLANTA 79 47 .627 -
MONTREAL 68 58 .540 11
NEW YORK 59 69 .461 21
FLORIDA 58 69 .457 21 1/2
PHILADELPHIA 52 76 .406 28
CENTRAL DIVISION
HOUSTON 68 60 .531 -
ST LOUIS 67 60 .528 1/2
CHICAGO 63 62 .504 3 1/2
CINCINNATI 63 62 .504 3 1/2
PITTSBURGH 54 73 .425 13 1/2
WESTERN DIVISION
SAN DIEGO 70 59 .543 -
LOS ANGELES 67 60 .528 2
COLORADO 66 62 .516 3 1/2
SAN FRANCISCO 54 71 .432 14
FRIDAY , AUGUST 23 SCHEDULE
CINCINNATI AT FLORIDA ( doubleheader )
CHICAGO AT ATLANTA
ST LOUIS AT HOUSTON
PITTSBURGH AT COLORADO
NEW YORK AT LOS ANGELES
PHILADELPHIA AT SAN DIEGO
MONTREAL AT SAN FRANCISCO
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE RESULTS THURSDAY .
NEW YORK 1996-08-23
Results of Major League
Baseball games played on Thursday ( home team in CAPS ) :
American League
BOSTON 2 Oakland 1
Seattle 10 BALTIMORE 3
California 12 NEW YORK 3
Toronto 1 CHICAGO 0 ( in 6 1/2 )
Detroit 10 KANSAS CITY 3
Texas 11 MINNESOTA 2
National League
COLORADO 10 St Louis 5
Cincinnati 3 ATLANTA 2 ( in 13 )
Pittsburgh 8 HOUSTON 6
LOS ANGELES 8 Philadelphia 5
Montreal 5 SAN FRANCISCO 4
BASEBALL - SORRENTO HITS SLAM AS SEATTLE ROUTS ORIOLES .
BALTIMORE 1996-08-22
Former Oriole Jamie Moyer allowed two hits over eight scoreless innings before tiring in the ninth and Paul Sorrento added his third grand slam of the season as the Seattle Mariners routed Baltimore 10-3 Thursday .
Moyer ( 10-2 ) , who was tagged for a pair of homers by Mike Devereaux and Brady Anderson and three runs in the ninth , walked none and struck out two .
Norm Charlton retired the final three batters to seal the victory .
With one out in the fifth Ken Griffey Jr and Edgar Martinez stroked back-to-back singles off Orioles starter Rocky Coppinger ( 7-5 ) and Jay Buhner walked .
Sorrento followed by hitting a 1-2 pitch just over the right-field wall for a 7-0 advantage .
Right fielder Bobby Bonilla was after the ball , which was touched by fans at the top of the scoreboard in right .
" Things fell in for us , " said Sorrento , who has six career grand slams and hit the ninth of the season for the Mariners .
" We have over a month left .
We 've got to make up some ground . "
In the American League wild-card race , the Mariners are three games behind the White Sox , two behind Baltimore and two ahead of the Red Sox heading into Boston for a weekend series .
Moyer retired 11 straight batters between the third and seventh innings and threw two or fewer pitches to 11 of the 29 batters he faced .
" I made some bad pitches at the end but I 'm not going to dwell on it .
We won the game , " said Moyer .
Coppinger ( 7-5 ) was tagged for eight runs and 10 hits in 4 1/3 innings .
Orioles manager Davey Johnson missed the game after being admitted to a hospital with an irregular heartbeat .
Bench coach Andy Etchebarren took his place .
In Boston , Troy O'Leary homered off the right-field foul pole with one out in the bottom of the ninth and the Red Sox climbed to the .500 mark for the first time this season with their fourth straight victory , 2-1 over the Oakland Athletics .
Boston has won 15 of its last 19 games .
Boston 's Roger Clemens ( 7-11 ) was one out away from his second straight shutout when pinch-hitter Matt Stairs tripled over the head of centre fielder Lee Tinsley on an 0-2 pitch and pinch-hitter Terry Steinbach dunked a broken-bat single into right to lift Oakland into a 1-1 tie .
The run broke Clemens ' 28-inning shutout streak , longest in the majors this season .
He pitched his fourth complete game , allowing eight hits with two walks and 11 strikeouts .
Reliever Mark Acre ( 0-1 ) took the loss .
In New York , Garret Anderson and Gary DiSarcina drove in two runs apiece in a five-run first inning and Jim Edmonds highlighted a six-run sixth with a bases-loaded double as the California Angels coasted to a 12-3 victory over the Yankees in the rubber game of their three-game series .
The Angels battered Kenny Rogers ( 10-7 ) for five runs in the first .
The Yankees have allowed at least two runs in the first inning in six straight games , getting outscored 21-1 in the first inning in that span .
Chuck Finley ( 12-12 ) snapped a four-game losing streak .
In Kansas City , Travis Fryman doubled in the go-ahead run in the fifth and Melvin Nieves and Damion Easley belted two-run homers as the Detroit Tigers claimed a 10-3 win over the Royals , handing them their fifth straight loss .
The Tigers won their third straight and halted a seven-game road losing streak behind Justin Thompson ( 1-2 ) , who earned his first major-league win .
Tim Belcher ( 12-8 ) was tagged for six runs and nine hits in eight innings .
At Minnesota , Ken Hill allowed two runs en route to his sixth complete game of the season and Rusty Greer added three hits , including a homer , and two RBI as the red-hot Texas Rangers routed the Twins 11-2 .
The Rangers , who won for the 11th time in their last 13 games , have scored 45 runs in their last five contests .
Hill ( 14-7 ) allowed 10 hits .
He has yielded just seven runs in his last four starts , covering 33 1/3 innings .
In Chicago , Erik Hanson outdueled Alex Fernandez , and Jacob Brumfield drove in Otis Nixon with the game 's only run in the sixth inning as the Toronto Blue Jays blanked the White Sox 1-0 in a game shortened to six innings due to rain .
Toronto won its fifth straight and handed the White Sox their seventh loss in nine games .
Hanson ( 11-15 ) allowed three hits , walked three and struck out four to snap a personal three-game losing streak .
Fernandez ( 12-8 ) scattered six hits .
SOCCER - SPORTING START NEW SEASON WITH A WIN .
LISBON 1996-08-23
Sporting 's Luis Miguel Predrosa scored the first goal of the new league season as the Lisbon side cruised to a 3-1 away win over SC Espinho on Friday .
Predrosa drilled a right-foot shot into the back of the net after 24 minutes to set Sporting on the way to victory .
Although Espinho 's Nail Besirovic put the home side back on terms in the 35th minute , Sporting quickly restored their lead .
Jose Luis Vidigal scored in the 38th minute and Mustapha Hadji added the third in the 57th .
The game was brought forward from Sunday when reigning champions Porto and Lisbon rivals Benfica play their first games of the season .
SOCCER - PORTUGUESE FIRST DIVISION RESULT .
LISBON 1996-08-23
Result of a Portuguese first
division soccer match on Friday :
Espinho 1 Sporting 3
SOCCER - ST PAULI TAKE POINT WITH LATE FIGHTBACK .
BONN 1996-08-23
Hamburg side St Pauli , tipped as prime candidates for relegation , produced a stunning second-half fightback to draw 4-4 in their Bundesliga clash with Schalke on Friday .
Schalke , who finished third last season , raced to a 3-1 lead at halftime .
St Pauli pulled a goal back through Andre Trulsen but Schalke striker Martin Max restored his team 's two-goal cushion shortly afterwards .
Christian Springer put St Pauli back in touch in the 64th minute and three minutes later they were level , thanks to a penalty from Thomas Sabotzik .
In the night 's only other match , Hamburg beat Hansa Rostock 1-0 , Karsten Baeron scoring the winner after some dazzling build-up from in-form midfielder Harald Spoerl .
The win put Hamburg in second place in the German first division after three games , though that may change after the other sides play on Saturday .
ATHLETICS - SALAH HISSOU BREAKS 10,000 METRES WORLD RECORD .
BRUSSELS 1996-08-23
Morocco 's Salah Hissou broke the men 's 10,000 metres world record on Friday when he clocked 26 minutes 38.08 seconds at the Brussels grand prix on Friday .
The previous mark of 26:43.53 was set by Ethiopia 's Haile Gebreselassie in the Dutch town of Hengelo in June last year .
SOCCER - GERMAN FIRST DIVISION SUMMARIES .
BONN 1996-08-23
Summaries of Bundesliga matches on Friday :
Hansa Rostock 0 Hamburg 1 ( Baeron 64th min ) .
Halftime 0-0 .
Attendance 18,500 .
St Pauli 4 ( Driller 15th , Trulsen 54th , Springer 64th , Sobotzik 67th penalty ) Schalke 4 ( Max 11th , Thon 34th , Wilmots 38th , Springer 64th ) .
1-3 .
19,775 .
SOCCER - FRENCH LEAGUE SUMMARY .
PARIS 1996-08-23
Summary of a French first division match on Friday .
Nancy 0 Paris St Germain 0 .
Attendance : 15,000 .
SOCCER - FRENCH LEAGUE RESULT .
PARIS 1996-08-23
Result of a French first division match on Friday .
Nancy 0 Paris St Germain 0
SOCCER - GERMAN FIRST DIVISION RESULTS .
BONN 1996-08-23
Results of German first division
soccer matches on Friday :
St Pauli 4 Schalke 4
Hansa Rostock 0 Hamburg 1
ATHLETICS - MASTERKOVA BREAKS SECOND WORLD RECORD IN 10 DAYS .
Adrian Warner
BRUSSELS 1996-08-23
Russia 's double Olympic champion Svetlana Masterkova smashed her second world record in just 10 days on Friday when she bettered the mark for the women 's 1,000 metres .
After breaking the world record for the women 's mile in Zurich last Wednesday , the Olympic 800 and 1,500 metres champion clocked two minutes 28.98 seconds over 1,000 at the Brussels grand prix meeting .
The Russian ate up the ground in a swift last lap to shave 0.36 seconds off the previous best of 2:29.34 set by Mozambique 's Maria Mutola in the same stadium in August last year .
Former world 800 champion Mutola pushed Masterkova all the way , finishing second in 2:29.66 .
But it was the Russian who picked up the bonus of $ 25,000 for the historic run in front of a capacity 40,000 crowd .
Masterkova dominated the middle-distance races at the recent Atlanta Games following her return to competition this season after a three-year maternity break .
In her first mile race at the richest meeting in Zurich last Wednesday , she slashed 3.05 seconds off the previous record .
The record of four minutes , 12.56 seconds in Zurich earned Masterkova a bonus of $ 50,000 plus one kilo of gold .
After Friday 's performance the Russian will have earned well over $ 100,000 in less than a fortnight , taking her appearance money into account .
Brussels organisers had laid a new track for the meeting comparable to the surface at the Atlanta Games but put down on a softer surface .
Masterkova clearly enjoyed it .
Mutola looked threatening in the final 200 metres but the Russian found an extra gear to power home several strides ahead , pointing at the time on the clock with delight as she crossed the line .
ATHLETICS - WOMEN 'S 1,000 METRES WORLD RECORD EVOLUTION .
BRUSSELS 1996-08-23
Evolution of the women 's 1,000
metres world record ( tabulated under time , name / nationality ,
venue , date ) :
2:30.67 Christine Wachtel ( Germany ) Berlin 17.8.90
2:29.34 Maria Mutola ( Mozambique ) Brussels 25.8.95
2:28.98 Svetlana Masterkova ( Russia ) Brussels 23.8.96
ATHLETICS - MASTERKOVA BREAKS WOMEN 'S WORLD 1,000 RECORD .
BRUSSELS 1996-08-23
Russian Svetlana Masterkova broke the women 's world 1,000 metres record on Friday when she clocked an unofficial two minutes 28.99 seconds at the Brussels grand prix .
The previous mark of 2:29.34 was set by Mozambique 's Maria Mutola here on August 25 last year .
The time was officially adjusted to 2:28.98 .
GOLF - GERMAN OPEN SECOND ROUND SCORES .
STUTTGART , Germany 1996-08-23
Leading second round
scores in the German Open golf championship on Friday ( Britain
unless stated ) :
128 Ian Woosnam 64 64
129 Robert Karlsson ( Sweden ) 67 62
130 Fernando Roca ( Spain ) 66 64 , Ian Pyman 66 64
131 Carl Suneson 65 66 , Stephen Field 66 65
132 Miguel Angel Martin ( Spain ) 66 66 , Raymond Russell 63 69 ,
Thomas Gogele ( Germany ) 67 65 , Paul Broadhurst 62 70 ,
Diego Borrego ( Spain ) 69 63
133 Ricky Willison 69 64 , Stephen Ames ( Trinidad and Tobago )
68 65 , Eamonn Darcy ( Ireland ) 65 68
134 Robert Coles 68 66 , David Williams 67 67 , Thomas Bjorn
( Denmark ) 66 68 , Pedro Linhart ( Spain ) 67 67 , Michael
Jonzon ( Sweden ) 67 67 , Roger Chapman 72 62 , Jonathan Lomas
67 67 , Francisco Cea ( Spain ) 68 66
135 Terry Price ( Australia ) 67 68 , Paul Eales 67 68 , Wayne
Riley ( Australia ) 64 71 , Carl Mason 69 66 , Barry Lane
68 67 , Bernhard Langer ( Germany ) 64 71 , Gary Orr 67 68 ,
Mats Lanner ( Sweden ) 64 71 , Jeff Hawksworth 67 68 , Des
Smyth ( Ireland ) 66 69 , David Carter 66 69 , Steve Webster
69 66 , Jose Maria Canizares ( Spain ) 67 68 , Paul Lawrie
66 69
ATHLETICS - MITCHELL UPSTAGES TRIO OF OLYMPIC SPRINT CHAMPIONS .
Adrian Warner
BRUSSELS 1996-08-23
American Dennis Mitchell upstaged a trio of past and present Olympic 100 metres champions on Friday with a storming victory at the Brussels grand prix .
Sporting his customary bright green outfit , the U.S. champion clocked 10.03 seconds despite damp conditions to take the scalp of Canada 's reigning Olympic champion Donovan Bailey , 1992 champion Linford Christie of Britain and American 1984 and 1988 champion Carl Lewis .
Mitchell also beat world and Olympic champion Bailey at the most lucrative meeting in the sport in Zurich last week .
The American , who finished fourth at the Atlanta Games , was fast out of his blocks and held off Bailey 's late burst in the final 20 metres before heading off for a lap of celebration .
The Canadian was second in 10.09 with Lewis third in 10.10 , ahead of Atlanta bronze medallist Ato Boldon who clocked 10.12 in fourth .
Christie , competing in what is expected to be his last major international meeting , finished fifth in 10.14 .
Lewis , making a rare appearance in Europe in a sprint race , left the track with a slight limp .
American Olympic high hurdles champion Allen Johnson defied the wet conditions to produce a brilliant 12.92 seconds in the 110 metres race , just 0.01 outside the world record held by Britain 's Colin Jackson .
Johnson ran the same time at the U.S. Olympic trials in Atlanta in June to become the second equal fastest hurdler of all time with American Roger Kingdom .
He seemed to relish the new track at the Brussels meeting , dominating the race from start to finish with a slight wind at his back .
Jackson , the only man to have run faster , could not live with his speed , taking second in 13.24 seconds .
The rain was pelting down when the women 's high hurdlers stepped up for their 100 metres race .
But Sweden 's Olympic high hurdles champion Ludmila Engquist , who crashed out of last week 's meeting in Zurich after hitting a hurdle , also kept her footing perfectly to win in a fast 12.60 seconds .
Olympic silver medallist Brigita Bukovec of Slovenia could finish only fifth in the race in 12.95 .
Jamaican Commonwealth champion Michelle Freeman took second in 12.77 ahead of Cuban Aliuska Lopez .
The Zurich fall cost Engquist a shot at a jackpot of 20 one-kg gold bars which can be won by athletes who clinch their events at all of the Golden Four series in Oslo , Zurich , Brussels and Berlin .
Seven athletes went into Friday 's penultimate meeting of the series with a chance of winning the prize and American men 's 400 metres hurdles champion Derrick Adkins kept his hopes alive in the competition by winning his event in 47.93 .
American Olympic champion Gail Devers clocked a swift 10.84 seconds on her way to victory in the women 's 100 metres , the second fastest time of the season and 0.10 seconds faster than her winning time in Atlanta .
Jamaican veteran Merlene Ottey , who beat Devers in Zurich after just missing out on the gold medal in Atlanta after a photo finish , had to settle for third place in 11.04 .
American world champion Gwen Torrence , the bronze medallist in Atlanta , was second in 11.00 .
It was a costly defeat for Ottey since it threw her out of the race for the Golden Four jackpot .
ATHLETICS - BRUSSELS GRAND PRIX RESULTS .
BRUSSELS 1996-08-23
Leading results in the Brussels
Grand Prix athletics meeting on Friday :
Women 's discus
1. Ilke Wyludda ( Germany ) 66.60 metres
2. Ellina Zvereva ( Belarus ) 65.66
3. Franka Dietzsch ( Germany ) 61.74
4. Natalya Sadova ( Russia ) 61.64
5. Mette Bergmann ( Norway ) 61.44
6. Nicoleta Grasu ( Romania ) 61.36
7. Olga Chernyavskaya ( Russia ) 60.46
8. Irina Yatchenko ( Belarus ) 58.92
Women 's 100 metres hurdles
1. Ludmila Engquist ( Sweden ) 12.60 seconds
2. Michelle Freeman ( Jamaica ) 12.77
3. Aliuska Lopez ( Cuba ) 12.85
4. Dionne Rose ( Jamaica ) 12.88
5. Brigita Bukovec ( Slovakia ) 12.95
6. Yulia Graudin ( Russia ) 12.96
7. Julie Baumann ( Switzerland ) 13.36
8. Patricia Girard-Leno ( France ) 13.36
9. Dawn Bowles ( U.S. ) 13.53
Men 's 110 metres hurdles
1. Allen Johnson ( U.S. ) 12.92 seconds
2. Colin Jackson ( Britain ) 13.24
3. Emilio Valle ( Cuba ) 13.33
4. Sven Pieters ( Belgium ) 13.37
5. Steve Brown ( U.S. ) 13.38
6. Frank Asselman ( Belgium ) 13.64
7. Hubert Grossard ( Belgium ) 13.65
8. Jonathan N'Senga ( Belgium ) 13.66
9. Johan Lisabeth ( Belgium ) 13.75
Women 's 5,000 metres
1. Roberta Brunet ( Italy ) 14 minutes 48.96 seconds
2. Fernanda Ribeiro ( Portugal ) 14:49.81
3. Sally Barsosio ( Kenya ) 14:58.29
4. Paula Radcliffe ( Britain ) 14:59.70
5. Julia Vaquero ( Spain ) 15:04.94
6. Catherine McKiernan ( Ireland ) 15:07.57
7. Annette Peters ( U.S. ) 15:07.85
8. Pauline Konga ( Kenya ) 15:11.40
Men 's 100 metres
1. Dennis Mitchell ( U.S. ) 10.03 seconds
2. Donovan Bailey ( Canada ) 10.09
3. Carl Lewis ( U.S. ) 10.10
4. Ato Boldon ( Trinidad ) 10.12
5. Linford Christie ( Britain ) 10.14
6. Davidson Ezinwa ( Nigeria ) 10.15
7. Jon Drummond ( U.S. ) 10.16
8. Bruny Surin ( Canada ) 10.30
Men 's 400 metres hurdles
1. Derrick Adkins ( U.S. ) 47.93 seconds
2. Samuel Matete ( Zambia ) 47.99
3. Rohan Robinson ( Australia ) 48.86
4. Torrance Zellner ( U.S. ) 49.06
5. Jean-Paul Bruwier ( Belgium ) 49.24
6. Dusan Kovacs ( Hungary ) 49.31
7. Calvin Davis ( U.S. ) 49.49
8. Laurent Ottoz ( Italy ) 49.61
9. Marc Dollendorf ( Belgium ) 50.36
Women 's 100 metres
1. Gail Devers ( U.S. ) 10.84 seconds
2. Gwen Torrence ( U.S. ) 11.00
3. Merlene Ottey ( Jamaica ) 11.04
4. Mary Onyali ( Nigeria ) 11.09
5. Chryste Gaines ( U.S. ) 11.18
6. Zhanna Pintusevich ( Ukraine ) 11.27
7. Irina Privalova ( Russia ) 11.28
8. Natalia Voronova ( Russia ) 11.28
9. Juliet Cuthbert ( Jamaica ) 11.31
Women 's 1,500 metres
1. Regina Jacobs ( U.S. ) 4 minutes 01.77 seconds
2. Patricia Djate ( France ) 4:02.26
3. Carla Sacramento ( Portugal ) 4:02.67
4. Yekaterina Podkopayeva ( Russia ) 4:04.78
5. Margret Crowley ( Australia ) 4:05.00
6. Leah Pells ( Canada ) 4:05.64
7. Sarah Thorsett ( U.S. ) 4:06.80
8. Sinead Delahunty ( Ireland ) 4:07.27
3,000 metres steeplechase
1. Joseph Keter ( Kenya ) 8 minutes 10.02 seconds
2. Patrick Sang ( Kenya ) 8:12.04
3. Moses Kiptanui ( Kenya ) 8:12.65
4. Gideon Chirchir ( Kenya ) 8:15.69
5. Richard Kosgei ( Kenya ) 8:16.80
6. Larbi El Khattabi ( Morocco ) 8:17.29
7. Eliud Barngetuny ( Kenya ) 8:17.66
8. Bernard Barmasai ( Kenya ) 8:17.94
Men 's 400 metres
1. Michael Johnson ( U.S. ) 44.29 seconds
2. Derek Mills ( U.S. ) 44.78
3. Anthuan Maybank ( U.S. ) 44.92
4. Davis Kamoga ( Uganda ) 44.96
5. Jamie Baulch ( Britain ) 45.08
6. Sunday Bada ( Nigeria ) 45.21
7. Samson Kitur ( Kenya ) 45.34
8. Mark Richardson ( Britain ) 45.67
9. Jason Rouser ( U.S. ) 46.11
Men 's 200 metres
1. Frankie Fredericks ( Namibia ) 19.92 seconds
2. Ato Boldon ( Trinidad ) 19.99
3. Jeff Williams ( U.S. ) 20.21
4. Jon Drummond ( U.S. ) 20.42
5. Patrick Stevens ( Belgium ) 20.42
6. Michael Marsh ( U.S. ) 20.43
7. Ivan Garcia ( Cuba ) 20.45
8. Eric Wymeersch ( Belgium ) 20.84
9. Lamont Smith ( U.S. ) 21.08
Women 's 1,000 metres
1. Svetlana Masterkova ( Russia ) 2 minutes 28.98 seconds
( world record )
2. Maria Mutola ( Mozambique ) 2:29.66
3. Malgorzata Rydz ( Poland ) 2:39.00
4. Anja Smolders ( Belgium ) 2:43.06
5. Veerle De Jaeghere ( Belgium ) 2:43.18
6. Eleonora Berlanda ( Italy ) 2:43.44
7. Anneke Matthijs ( Belgium ) 2:43.82
8. Jacqueline Martin ( Spain ) 2:44.22
Women 's 200 metres
1. Mary Onyali ( Nigeria ) 22.42 seconds
2. Inger Miller ( U.S. ) 22.66
3. Irina Privalova ( Russia ) 22.68
4. Natalia Voronova ( Russia ) 22.73
5. Marina Trandenkova ( Russia ) 22.84
6. Chandra Sturrup ( Bahamas ) 22.85
7. Zundra Feagin ( U.S. ) 23.18
8. Galina Malchugina ( Russia ) 23.25
Women 's 400 metres
1. Cathy Freeman ( Australia ) 49.48 seconds
2. Marie-Jose Perec ( France ) 49.72
3. Falilat Ogunkoya ( Nigeria ) 49.97
4. Pauline Davis ( Bahamas ) 50.14
5. Fatima Yussuf ( Nigeria ) 50.14
6. Maicel Malone ( U.S. ) 50.51
7. Hana Benesova ( Czech Republic ) 51.71
8. Ann Mercken ( Belgium ) 53.55
Men 's 3,000 metres
1. Daniel Komen ( Kenya ) 7 minutes 25.87 seconds
2. Khalid Boulami ( Morocco ) 7:31.65
3. Bob Kennedy ( U.S. ) 7:31.69
4. El Hassane Lahssini ( Morocco ) 7:32.44
5. Thomas Nyariki ( Kenya ) 7:35.56
6. Noureddine Morceli ( Algeria ) 7:36.81
7. Fita Bayesa ( Ethiopia ) 7:38.09
8. Martin Keino ( Kenya ) 7:38.88
Men 's discus
1. Lars Riedel ( Germany ) 66.74 metres
2. Anthony Washington ( U.S. ) 66.72
3. Vladimir Dubrovshchik ( Belarus ) 64.02
4. Virgilius Alekna ( Lithuania ) 63.62
5. Juergen Schult ( Germany ) 63.48
6. Vassiliy Kaptyukh ( Belarus ) 61.80
7. Vaclavas Kidikas ( Lithuania ) 60.92
8. Michael Mollenbeck ( Germany ) 59.24
Men 's triple jump
1. Jonathan Edwards ( Britain ) 17.50 metres
2. Yoelvis Quesada ( Cuba ) 17.29
3. Brian Wellman ( Bermuda ) 17.05
4. Kenny Harrison ( U.S. ) 16.97
5. Gennadi Markov ( Russia ) 16.66
6. Francis Agyepong ( Britain ) 16.63
7. Rogel Nachum ( Israel ) 16.36
8. Sigurd Njerve ( Norway ) 16.35
Men 's 1,500 metres
1. Hicham El Guerrouj ( Morocco ) three minutes 29.05 seconds
2. Isaac Viciosa ( Spain ) 3:33.00
3. William Tanui ( Kenya ) 3:33.36
4. Elijah Maru ( Kenya ) 3:33.64
5. Marcus O'Sullivan ( Ireland ) 3:33.77
6. John Mayock ( Britain ) 3:33.94
7. Laban Rotich ( Kenya ) 3:34.12
8. Christophe Impens ( Belgium ) 3:34.13
Women 's high jump
1. Stefka Kostadinova ( Bulgaria ) 2.03 metres
2. Inga Babakova ( Ukraine ) 2.03
3. Alina Astafei ( Germany ) 1.97
4. Tatyana Motkova ( Russia ) 1.94
5. Svetlana Zalevskaya ( Kazakhstan ) 1.91
6. Yelena Gulyayeva ( Russia ) 1.88
7. Hanna Haugland ( Norway ) 1.88
8 equal .
Olga Boshova ( Moldova ) 1.85
Nele Zilinskiene ( Lithuania ) 1.85
Men 's 10,000 metres
1. Salah Hissou ( Morocco ) 26 minutes 38.08 seconds ( world
record )
2. Paul Tergat ( Kenya ) 26:54.41
3. Paul Koech ( Kenya ) 26:56.78
4. William Kiptum ( Kenya ) 27:18.84
5. Aloys Nizigama ( Burundi ) 27:25.13
6. Mathias Ntawulikura ( Rwanda ) 27:25.48
7. Abel Anton ( Spain ) 28:18.44
8. Kamiel Maase ( Netherlands ) 28.29.42
9. Worku Bekila ( Ethiopia ) 28.42.23
10. Robert Stefko ( Slovakia ) 28:42.26
SOCCER - JORGE CALLS UP SIX PORTO PLAYERS FOR WORLD CUP QUALIFIER .
LISBON 1996-08-23
Portugal 's new coach Artur Jorge called up six players from league champions Porto on Friday in an 18-man squad for the opening World Cup qualifier against Armenia on August 31 .
Midfielder Paulo Sousa , recently transferred to Borussia Dortmund from Italy 's Juventus , is the only leading member of the Portuguese side from this year 's European championships who will not make the trip .
It will be Jorge 's first game in charge of the national squad since taking over from Antonio Oliveira , who now coaches Porto , at the end of Euro 96 .
Squad :
Goalkeepers - Vitor Baia , Rui Correia .
Defenders - Jorge Costa , Paulinho Santos , Helder Cristovao , Carlos Secretario , Dimas Teixeira , Fernando Couto .
Midfielders - Jose Barroso , Luis Figo , Rui Barros , Rui Costa , Oceano Cruz , Ricardo Sa Pinto .
Forwards - Domingos Oliveira , Joao Vieira Pinto , Jorge Cadete , Antonio Folha .
SOCCER - VOGTS KEEPS FAITH WITH EURO ' 96 CHAMPIONS .
BONN 1996-08-23
Trainer Berti Vogts kept faith with his entire European championship winning squad for Germany 's first match since their title victory , a friendly in Poland .
Vogts picked no new players for the squad for the September 4 game in Zabrze .
Instead on Friday he nominated all 23 Euro ' 96 veterans including Bremen 's Jens Todt , called up before the final by special UEFA dispensation .
He will , however , have to do without the Dortmund trio of libero Matthias Sammer , midfielder Steffen Freund and defender Rene Schneider , who were all formally nominated despite being injured .
" This squad is currently the basis of my planning for the 1998 World Cup , " Vogts said . "
We 'll have to see which other players produce good league performances to play themselves into the squad . "
Squad :
Goalkeepers - Oliver Kahn , Andreas Koepke , Oliver Reck
Defenders - Markus Babbel , Thomas Helmer , Juergen Kohler , Stefan Reuter , Matthias Sammer , Rene Schneider
Midfielders - Mario Basler , Marco Bode , Dieter Eilts , Steffen Freund , Thomas Haessler , Andreas Moeller , Mehmet Scholl , Thomas Strunz , Jens Todt , Christian Ziege
Forwards - Oliver Bierhoff , Fredi Bobic , Juergen Klinsmann , Stefan Kuntz .
SOCCER - EUROPEAN CUP DRAWS FOR AEK , OLYMPIAKOS , PAO .
ATHENS 1996-08-23
Following are the European soccer
draws for the UEFA cup and the cup 's winners cup involving Greek
teams that took place today in Geneva :
x-AEK Athens ( Greece ) v Chemlon Humenne ( Slovakia )
x-Olympiakos v Ferencvaros ( Hungary )
x-PAO v Legia Warsaw ( Poland )
x indicates seeded teams .
-- Dimitris Kontogiannis , Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4
SOCCER - EURO CLUB COMPETITION FIRST ROUND DRAWS .
GENEVA 1996-08-23
Draws for the first round of the European club soccer competitions made on Friday ( x denotes seeded team ) :
UEFA Cup Lyngby ( Denmark ) v x-Club Brugge ( Belgium ) Casino Graz ( Austria ) v Ekeren ( Belgium ) Besiktas ( Turkey ) v Molenbeek ( Belgium ) Alania Vladikavkaz ( Russia ) v x-Anderlecht ( Belgium )
Cup Winners ' Cup x-Cercle Brugge ( Belgium ) v Brann Bergen ( Norway )
CRICKET - SRI LANKA AND AUSTRALIA SAY RELATIONS HAVE HEALED .
COLOMBO 1996-08-23
Sri Lanka and Australia agreed on Friday that relations between the two teams had healed since the Sri Lankans ' acrimonious tour last year .
The Sri Lankans were first found guilty then cleared of ball tampering and off-spinner Muttiah Muralitharan was called for throwing during a controversial three-test series in Australia .
" Our concern is to get out there and play proper cricket , " Sri Lanka captain Arjuna Ranatunga told a news conference on the eve of a warmup match between the World Cup champions and a World XI team scheduled for Saturday .
" What happened is history . "
Australian team manager Cam Battersby said he agreed with Ranatunga .
" I believe relations between the two teams will be excellent , " Batterby said .
The Australians are making their first visit to the Indian Ocean island since boycotting a World Cup fixture in February after a terrorist bomb in Colombo .
Australia have been promised the presence of commandos , sniffer dogs and plainclothes policemen to ensure a limited overs tournament is trouble-free .
The tournament , starting on August 26 , also includes India and Zimbabwe .
Battersby said he was satisfied with the security arrangements .
Sri Lankan officials said they expected heavy rain which washed out a warmup match on Friday should cease by Saturday .
Australia , led by wicketkeeper Ian Healy , opened their short tour of Sri Lanka with a five-run win over the country 's youth team on Thursday .
PRESS DIGEST - ANGOLA - AUG 23 .
LUANDA 1996-08-23
These are the leading stories in the Angolan press on Friday .
Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy .
- - - -
JORNAL DE ANGOLA
- The Angolan Chief of State addressed a letter to UN Security Council proposing dates for the conclusion of the peace process in Angola .
He proposed definite dates , August 25 for return of Unita generals to the joint army , September 5 for the beginning of the formation of the Government of National Unity and Reconciliation .
Until this date the free circulation of peoples and goods should be guaranteed , the government administration installed in all areas and the Unita deputies should occupy their places in the National Assembly .
The president justified his proposal by the delays verified in the peace process , including the fact that areas under Unita control or occupation have not been effectively demilitarised , where the Unita military forces have been substituted by their so-called police .
- President Dos Santos proposes the establishment by UN Security Council of definitive and final timetable for the tasks and obligations under the Lusaka Agreement and the sending of a mission of SC , as soon as possible , to supervise the execution of the agreement .
FORECAST - S.AFRICAN COMPANY RESULTS CONSENSUS .
JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-23
Analysts estimates of major
South African company results expected next week include the
following ( all figures cents per share ) :
DAY--COMPANY----PERIOD--CONSENSUS----RANGE-------PVS
MON Gencor YR EPS 93.12 92.0-94.5 73.8
MON Gencor YR DIV 25.75 25.0-27.0 20.0
MON Primedia YR EPS N / A 149.1
MON Primedia YR DIV N / A 123.2
MON Distillers YR EPS N / A 71.8
MON Distillers YR DIV N / A 49.0
TUE Iscor YR EPS 29.7 26.0-32.0 38.0
TUE Iscor YR DIV 15.0 14.5-16.5 16.5
TUE McCarthy YR EPS 125.3 112.0-149.0 93.2
TUE McCarthy YR DIV 36.8 32.0-43.0 28.0
WED Imphold YR EPS 172.7 170.4-175.0 115.1
WED Imphold YR DIV 67.5 66.6-68.4 45.0
THU M&R YR EPS 113.0 112.1-113.4 126.0
THU M&R YR DIV 31.7 10.5-42.3 47.0
THU JD Group YR EPS 143.7 138.0-149.0 111.2
THU JD Group YR DIV 41.8 41.0-42.5 33.0
ooOOoo
-- Johannesburg newsroom , +27 11 482 1003
Ulster Petroleums Ltd Q2 net profit falls .
CALGARY 1996-08-23
1996 1995
Shr C$ 0.04 C$ 0.08
Net 1,196 2,232
Cash flow / shr 0.39 0.41
Revs 20,167 18,623
6 MONTHS
Shr C$ 0.12 C$ 0.15
Net 3,674 4,271
Cash flow / shr 0.86 0.81
Revs 41,752 35,711
( All data above 000s except per share numbers )
-- Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8100
Nigerian terms jeopardize Commonwealth trip-Canada .
OTTAWA 1996-08-23
Commonwealth ministers concerned about human rights in Nigeria may cancel a planned trip there because of government restrictions on their mission , Canadian Foreign Minister Lloyd Axworthy said on Friday .
" The reaction of the regime there is such that many of us feel that the mission under the present circumstances should n't go ahead , " Axworthy said .
Commonwealth foreign ministers will meet in London on Wednesday to discuss what to do , he added .
Mid-tier golds up in heavy trading .
TORONTO 1996-08-23
Investors gave into gold fever Friday morning , with heavy trading in a handful of Toronto-based gold companies .
TVX Gold Inc was up C$ 0.30 to C$ 11.55 in trading of 780,000 shares , while Kinross Gold Corp gained C$ 0.25 to C$ 11 in volume of 720,000 shares .
And Scorpion Minerals Inc , a junior gold exploration company with five Indonesian mining properties , was up C$ 0.50 to C$ 6 , with about 120,000 shares changing hands .
TVX and Kinross rose after recent buy recommendations from U.S. brokers , analysts said .
But Scorpion was raising a lot of eyebrows after it issued a release Friday morning saying it was not aware of any developments that could have affected the stock .
The company was formed this year and a couple of analysts have been on their properties , said one analyst .
Exploration results are expected soon .
-- Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8100
RESEARCH ALERT - Unitog Co upgraded .
- Barrington Research Associates Inc said Friday it upgraded Unitog Co to a near-term outperform from a long-term outperform rating .
- Analyst Alexander Paris said he expected consistent 20 percent earnings growth after an estimated gain of 18 percent for 1996 .
- The stock closed unchanged at 27 , down from a recent high of 30 .
-- Chicago newsdesk , 312-408-8787
Buffett raises Property Capital stake .
WASHINGTON 1996-08-23
Omaha billionaire Warren Buffett said Friday he raised his stake in Property Capital Trust to 8.0 percent from 6.7 percent .
In a filing with the Securities and Exchnage Commission , Buffett said he bought 62,900 additional common shares of the Boston-based real estate investment trust at prices ranging from $ 7.65 to $ 8.02 a share .
The purchases increased his holding in the company to 725,900 shares , which was purchased for a total of $ 6.2 million , he said .
Buffett , who is well-known as a long-term investor , is chairman of Berkshire Hathaway Inc , a holding company through which he holds investments in several large U.S. companies .
Colombia , U.S. reach aviation agreement .
MIAMI 1996-08-23
The U.S. and Colombian governments reached an agreement that will allow AMR Corp 's American Airlines to operate three round-trip flights between New York and Bogota , the Department of Transportation said Friday .
Under the agreement , which followed talks in Miami this week , AMR also will be allowed to shift up to four of the weekly flights it now operates between Miami and Colombia to its New York gateway .
The United States also will be able to designate one new all-cargo carrier for service between the two nations after two years .
Colombia was permitted to add a single additional round-trip flight to its current New York service , although it will not be able to do so while under Category Two ( Conditional ) status under the Federal Aviation Administration 's International Aviation Safety program .
Colombia would be allowed to add new service when its safety assessment has been improved , the department said .
With the exception of the new services just agreed to , the governments of the two nations have agreed to maintain their current level of routes and airlines for the next 2-1/2 years , the agreement said .
The agreement resolved a dispute that arose in June when Colombia turned down American 's request to operate flights between New York and Bogota , a denial that prompted the United States to charge that the Colombians were breaking a bilateral aviation agreement and to propose sanctions against one of two Colombian airlines , Avianca and ACES .
Clean tanker fixtures and enquiries - 1754 GMT .
LONDON 1996-08-23
LATEST FIXTURES
- MIDEAST GULF / RED SEA
Konpolis 75 1/9 Mideast / Indonesia W112.5 KPC .
TBN 30 6/9 Mideast / W.C. India W200 , E.C.India W195 IOC .
- ASIA PACIFIC
Petrobulk Rainbow 28 24/8 Okinawa / Inchon $ 190,000 Honam .
- MED / BLACK SEA
TBN 30 15/9 Constanza / Inia $ 700,000 IOC .
- UK / CONT
Port Christine 36,5 3/9 Pembroke / US W145 Stentex .
- WESTERN HEMISPHERE
Kpaitan Stankov 69 31/8 St Croix / USAC W125 Hess .
AP Moller 30 31/8 Caribs / Japan $ 875,000 BP .
Tiber 29 2/9 Caribs / options W265 Stinnes .
------------------------------------------------------------
- MIDDAY FIXTURES
- MIDEAST GULF / RED SEA
Tenacity 70 24/08 Mideast / South Korea W145 Samsung .
SKS Tana 70 03/09 Mideast / Japan W145 CNR .
Northsea Chaser 55 12/09 Mideast / Japan W167.5 Jomo .
Sibonina 55 13/09 Red Sea / Japan W160 Marubeni .
- ASIA / PACIFIC
Neptune Crux 30 02/09 Singapore / options $ 185,000 Sietco .
World Bridge 30 03/09 South Korea / Japan rnr CNR .
Fulmar 30 28/08 Ulsan / Yosu $ 105,000 LG Caltex .
- MED / BLACK SEA
Hemina 33 05/09 Eleusis / UKCM W155 CNR .
-- London Newsroom , +44 171 542 8980
CRICKET - PAKISTAN 229-1 V ENGLAND - close .
Saeed Anwar not out 116
Aamir Sohail c Cork b Croft 46
Ijaz Ahmed not out 58
Extras 9
Fall of wicket - 1-106
To bat - Inzamam-ul-Haq , Salim Malik , Asif Mujtaba , Wasim Akram , Moin Khan , Mushtaq Ahmed , Waqar Younis , Mohammad Akam
England 326 all out
RTRS - Golf : Norman sacks his coach after disappointing season .
SYDNEY 1996-08-23
World number one golfer Greg Norman has sacked his coach Butch Harmon after a disappointing season .
" Butch and I are finished , " Norman told reporters on Thursday before the start of the World Series of Golf in Akron , Ohio .
Norman , a two-time British Open champion , parted ways with his long-time mentor after drawing a blank in this year 's four majors , winning two tournaments worldwide .
The blonde Australian opened with a level par round of 70 in Akron , leaving him four shots adrift of the leaders , Americans Billy Mayfair and Paul Goydos and Japan 's Hidemichi Tanaki .
On Wednesday Norman described this year as his worst on the professional circuit since 1991 , when he failed to win a tournament .
" My application this year has been strange , " Norman said . "
Maybe I have n't been as keyed up as I should have been . "
" Sometimes you do n't have it in your head to play .
Maybe this was one of those years where I was there , but I was n't 100 percent there , and you have to be 100 percent to perform , " he said .
-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800
Soccer - Arab team breaks new ground in Israel .
Ori Lewis
TAIBE , Israel 1996-08-23
For the first time in Israeli history , an Arab team will take the field when the National League soccer season starts on Saturday .
Hapoel Taibe fields four Jewish players and two foreign imports -- a Pole and a Romanian .
The rest of the side is made up mainly of Moslem Arabs .
The club , founded in 1961 , has a loyal following in Taibe , an Arab town of 28,000 in the heart of Israel .
But away from their home ground , they face unfriendly crowds who taunt the players with racist abuse .
" The very first thing we thought about after we knew we would be promoted was the game against Betar Jerusalem , " said Taibe supporter Karem Haj Yihye .
Two weeks ago Taibe , coached by Pole Wojtek Lazarek , met Betar , a club closely associated with the right-wing Likud party , for the first time in a Cup match in Jerusalem .
Chants from the crowd of " Death to the Arabs " , and bottle-throwing during the game marred the match which ended in a goalless draw .
One Taibe supporter required hospital treatment for cuts and bruises after a stone struck his head as he was driving from the stadium .
" We 're used to hearing the taunts of " Death to the Arabs ' , " said Sameh Haj Yihye , a Taibe resident who studies at Jerusalem 's Hebrew University . "
But we know that these are only words , nobody has died from hearing them and it only makes us support our team more vehemently . "
The dusty town of Taibe lacks the amenities of Jewish communities and many Israeli Arabs have long complained of state discrimination .
" There are no parks or empty areas of land around here , so when we want to play a friendly game of soccer we all load up in the car and travel to Tel Aviv , " 60 km ( 36 miles ) away , Sameh Haj Yihye said .
The town 's ramshackle 2,500-seat ground is accessible only by two dirt tracks .
" We plan to build a 10,000-seat stadium , but it may well be situated elsewhere , " said club chairman Abdul Rahman Haj Yihye . "
We will discuss this with the mayor and hopefully a new or refurbished ground will be completed by the start of the new year . "
In the meantime , Taibe will play all their heavily policed home matches at the Jewish coastal town of Netanya .
" We are Israelis , there is no question about that , " said Karem Haj Yihye , a hotel waiter .
" We do n't have any connection with the Palestinians , they live over there , " he said , pointing to the West Bank seven km ( four miles ) to the east .
" We do n't feel our club represents Palestinian Arabs , " said club chairman Abdul Rahman . "
We are trying to do all we can to run a professional outfit , we are pleased at any support we get , but do not go out looking to represent the whole Arab world . "
Soccer - Kennedy and Phelan both out of Irish squad .
DUBLIN 1996-08-23
Two players have withdrawn from the Republic of Ireland squad for the 1998 World Cup qualifying match against Liechenstein on August 31 , the Football Association of Ireland said in a statement on Friday .
The F.A.I. statement said that Liverpool striker Mark Kennedy and Chelsea defender Terry Phelan were both receiving treatment for injuries and would not be travelling to Liechenstein for the game .
No replacements had been named .
-- Damien Lynch , Dublin Newsroom +353 1 6603377
Soccer - Manchester United face Juventus in Europe .
GENEVA 1996-08-23
European champions Juventus will face English league and cup double winners Manchester United in this season 's European Champions ' League .
The draw made on Friday pitted Juventus , who beat Dutch champions Ajax Amsterdam 4-2 on penalties in last year 's final , against Alex Ferguson 's European hopefuls in group C .
The other two teams in the group are last season 's Cup Winners ' Cup runners-up Rapid Vienna and Fenerbahce of Turkey .
Juventus meet United in Turin on September 11 , with the return match at Old Trafford on November 20 .
United have dominated the premier league in the 1990s , winning three English championships in four years , but have consistently failed in Europe , crashing out of the European Cup to Galatasaray of Turkey and Spain 's Barcelona at their last two attempts .
They have not lifted a European Trophy since 1991 when they beat Barcelona in the Cup Winners ' Cup final , and their one and only European Cup triumph was way back in 1968 , when they beat Benfica of Portugal 4-1 at Wembley .
Juventus have won the European Cup twice .
Before conquering Ajax last year they beat United 's big English rivals Liverpool in the ill-fated 1985 final in the Heysel stadium in Brussels .
Nigeria police kill six robbery suspects .
LAGOS 1996-08-23
Nigerian police shot dead six robbery suspects as they tried to escape from custody in the northern city of Sokoto , the national news agency reported on Friday .
The News Agency of Nigeria ( NAN ) quoted police spokesman Umar Shelling as saying the six were killed on Wednesday .
They had been arrested last week for stealing 800,000 naira ( $ 10,000 ) from a sheep merchant .
Rwandan group says expulsion could be imminent .
NAIROBI 1996-08-23
Repatriation of 1.1 million Rwandan Hutu refugees announced by Zaire and Rwanda on Thursday could start within the next few days , an exiled Rwandan Hutu lobby group said on Friday .
Innocent Butare , executive secretary of the Rally for the Return of Refugees and Democracy in Rwanda ( RDR ) which says it has the support of Rwanda 's exiled Hutus , appealed to the international community to deter the two countries from going ahead with what it termed a " forced and inhuman action " .
Orthodox church blown up in southern Croatia .
ZAGREB 1996-08-23
Saboteurs blew up a Serb orthodox church in southern Croatia on Friday with a blast which also damaged four nearby homes , the state news agency Hina reported .
HINA said the church in the small village of Karin Gornji , 30 km ( 19 miles ) north of Zadar , was destroyed by the morning attack .
It did not report any casualties .
Zadar police said in a statement they had launched an investigation and were doing their best to find the perpetrators .
HINA said it was the first time an orthodox church had been blown up in the Zadar hinterland , where a large number of Serbs lived before the 1991 war over Croatia 's independence from the Yugoslav federation .
The area was part of the self-styled state of Krajina proclaimed by minority Serbs in 1991 and recaptured by the Croatian army last year .
Up to 200,000 Serbs fled to Bosnia and Yugoslavia , leaving Krajina vacant and depopulated .
Hungary 's gross foreign debt rises in June .
BUDAPEST 1996-08-23
Hungary 's gross foreign debt rose to $ 27.53 billion in June from $ 27.25 billion in May , the
National Bank of Hungary ( NBH ) said on Friday .
FIGURES IN $ MILLION June 1996 May 1996
Gross foreign debt 27,535.5 27,246.5
International reserves and
other foreign assets 13,256.5 12,855.7
Net foreign debt 14,278.9 14,390.7
Net foreign debt of the
government and NBH 9,510.9 10,056.4
-- Budapest newsroom ( 36 1 ) 266 2410
Germany , Poland tighten cooperation against crime .
WARSAW 1996-08-23
Germany and Poland agreed on Friday to tighten cooperation between their intelligence services in fighting international organised crime , PAP news agency reported .
Interior Minister Zbigniew Siemiatkowski and Bernd Schmidbauer , German intelligence co-ordinator in Helmut Kohl 's chancellery , sealed the closer links during talks in Warsaw .
Ministry spokesman Ryszard Hincza told the Polish agency the services would work together against mafia-style groups , drug smuggling and illegal trade in arms and radioactive materials .
Russians , Chechens say observing Grozny ceasefire .
GROZNY , Russia 1996-08-23
Rebel fighters and Russian soldiers said a ceasefire effective at noon ( 0800 GMT ) on Friday was being generally observed , although scattered gunfire echoed through the Chechen capital Grozny .
The Russian army said earlier it was preparing to withdraw from the rebel-dominated southern mountains of the region as part of the peace deal reached with separatists on Thursday .
" There has been some shooting from their side but it has been relatively quiet , " said fighter Aslan Shabazov , a bearded man wearing a white t-shirt and camoflage trousers .
Soon after he spoke another burst of gunfire rocked the courtyard where the rebels had set up their base and a captured Russian T-72 tank roared out to investigate .
The separatists , who swept into Grozny on August 6 , still control large areas of the centre of town , and Russian soldiers are based at checkpoints on the approach roads .
" The ceasefire is being observed , " said woman soldier Svetlana Goncharova , 35 , short dark hair poking out from under a peaked camouflage cap .
A few helicopters flew overhead , firing off flares , but there was no shooting from the air .
The truce , the latest of several , was agreed in talks on Thursday between Russian peacemaker Alexander Lebed and rebel chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov .
The two also agreed to set up joint patrols in Grozny , but Goncharova said she was sceptical about whether this could work .
" We have to try it , but I doubt if this is possible with the separatists , " she said .
WEATHER - Conditions at CIS airports - August 23 .
MOSCOW 1996-08-23
No closures of airports in the Commonwealth of Independent States are expected on August 24 and August 25 , the Russian Weather Service said on Friday .
-- Moscow Newsroom +7095 941 8520
Granic arrives to sign Croatia-Yugoslavia treaty .
BELGRADE 1996-08-23
Yugoslavia and Croatia were poised on Friday to sign a landmark normalisation treaty ending five years of tensions and paving way for stabilisation in the Balkans .
Croatian Foreign Minister Mate Granic landed at Belgrade airport aboard a Croatian government jet on Friday morning for talks with his Yugoslav counterparts and a signing ceremony expected around noon ( 1000 GMT ) .
On Thursday the Yugoslav government endorsed the text of the agreement on normalising relations between the two countries , the Yugoslav news agency Tanjug said .
" The government assessed the agreement as a crucial step to resolving the Yugoslav crisis , ensuring the restoration of peace in former Yugoslavia , " it said .
Last-minute talks this week on the legal fine print finally cleared the way for a treaty based on mutual recognition within internationally recognised borders and the establishment of diplomatic relations , diplomats said .
The pact ends five years of hostility after Croatia 's secession from federal Yugoslavia .
Western powers regard diplomatic normalisation between Croatia and Serbia , twin pillars of the old multinational federal Yugoslavia , as a crucial step towards a lasting peace in the Balkans .
Ecuador president to lunch with ethnic Indians .
QUITO , Ecuador 1996-08-23
Ecuador 's President Abdala Bucaram has announced he will hold regular lunches in his presidential palace for members of the country 's different ethnic groups as of next week .
" It was about time for the Indians , the blacks and the mixed-bloods to begin eating in the palace with their president because this is not a palace exclusively for the potentates and ambassadors and protocol , " Bucaram said late on Thursday .
" In these weekly lunches we are going to get to know the problems of the Indian , mixed-race , black and peasant sectors , " he said .
He has invited 35 Indian leaders to lunch next Tuesday .
Bucaram , who was elected on a populist platform last month , also plans to create a ministry for ethnic cultures .
The Andean nation 's population of 11.4 million is 47 percent indigenous .
Brazil to use hovercrafts for Amazon travel .
BRASILIA 1996-08-22
Hovercrafts will soon be plying the waters of the Amazon in a bid to reduce the difficulties of transportation on the vast Brazilian waterway , the government said on Thursday .
Two Russian-built hovercrafts , capable of carrying up to 50 tons each , will begin ferrying passengers and cargo up and down the huge river from its mouth at Belem by the end of the year , Brazil 's Amazon Affairs Department said in a statement .
The use of riverways in the region has been made a priority under a government plan for the Amazon and the high-speed hovercraft will help reduce the time involved in travelling often massive distances , it said .
HK 's Tsang to visit Indonesia , New Zealand .
HONG KONG 1996-08-23
Hong Kong Financial Secretary Donald Tsang will visit Indonesia and New Zealand from August 25 to 31 , the government said on Friday .
In Jakarta , Tsang will meet President Suharto , Minister of Finance Mar'ie Muhammad , Minister of Foreign Affairs Ali Alatas and Minister of Trade and Industry Tungky Ariwibowo .
On his New Zealand leg from August 29 , Tsang will meet Prime Minister Jim Bolger , Deputy Prime Minister Don McKinnon and Minister of Finance Bill Birch .
Jordan expels Iraqi diplomat after bread riots .
Rana Sabbagh
AMMAN 1996-08-23
Jordan , which has blamed Iraq for bread riots last week , has asked an Iraqi diplomat to leave , official and diplomatic sources said on Friday .
The main Friday prayers in southern Jordan that were the starting point for the riots a week ago passed peacefully under tight security imposed by the army with only brief demonstrations reported .
Adel Ibrahim , the Iraqi embassy 's press attache , was asked to leave " because he was carrying out duties incompatible with diplomatic norms " , one source told Reuters , implying he was accused of spying .
Ibrahim told Reuters by telephone from his embassy office in Amman that he " had not been notified " of any explusion order .
The government declined official comment .
Ibrahim 's assistant , Hussein Khalaf , was expelled earlier this year for similar reasons amid rising tension in bilateral ties after King Hussein began calling for change in Baghdad following top Iraqi defections in August 1995 .
Iraq retaliated then by expelling a junior administrator working in the Jordanian embassy in Baghdad but has continued its policy of trying to avoid public conflicts with Jordan -- its only secure route to the rest of the world .
Jordan has accused Iraq and a local pro-Baghdad party for the country 's worst unrest in seven years which erupted after it almost doubled the prices of bread last week under radical economic reforms agreed with the International Monetary Fund .
In Karak , where two days of riots flared last Friday , a few hundred young men lingered outside Omari mosque on leaving , shouting slogans for about 15 minutes .
" Disperse , abstain from forming groups and help maintain order , " army officers , who has enforced a loose curfew since the riots , told the crowd through loudspeakers .
The men shouted " Allahu Akbar " ( God is Greatest ) as a former Islamist deputy , Ahmed Kafawin , told soldiers the crowd would not cause trouble .
He had earlier mounted the mosque 's pulpit to demand release of detainees , an end to raids on houses and the cancelling of the bread price rises .
Armoured cars had patrolled streets in Karak , traditional bastion of communist ideology and Baath socialism that swept the region in the 1950s , and guarded entrances to the hill-top city famed for its Crusader castle before the prayers .
There was also heavy security in the crowded centre of Amman , where smaller clashes had erupted last Saturday , but Friday prayers at the main mosque ended quietly as police in full riot gear looked on .
The Jordanian Arab Socialist Baath Party , which has one deputy in the 80-seat lower house of parliament , has denied involvement in unrest which it blamed on government policies and rising economic hardship .
Government attempts to link the rioting to foreign influence has been treated with derision by those in the streets who blame the protests on severe economic hardships .
Turkey says killed 17 Kurd rebels in clashes .
ANKARA 1996-08-23
Turkish troops have killed 17 Kurdish rebels in recent clashes in the southeast of the country , the state-run Anatolian news agency said on Friday .
Two security officials and two state-paid village guards were killed in the fighting with Kurdistan Workers Party ( PKK ) guerrillas , the agency quoted the emergency rule governor 's office as saying .
Eight of the rebels were killed in Van province , five in Sirnak and four in Hakkari .
The agency did not say when the clashes took place .
More than 20,000 people have died in the PKK 's 12-year-old fight for independence or autonomy in southeastern Turkey .
Three people , including two village guards , died when a mine planted by PKK rebels exploded on a road in the southeast , Anatolian reported earlier .
It said a taxi carrying the guards , members of a mostly Kurdish militia which fights the PKK , hit the mine in the province of Diyarbakir .
U.S. says Iraqi Kurds agree ceasefire .
WASHINGTON 1996-08-23
Leaders of Iraq 's two main Kurdish factions agreed on Friday to end six days of fighting and to attend U.S.-mediated peace talks next month , the State Department said .
Spokesman Glyn Davies said in a statement that the agreement followed direct U.S. contacts with Massoud Barzani , leader of the Kurdistan Democratic Party ( KDP ) , and Jalal Talabani , leader of the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan ( PUK ) .
Davies said the two leaders " have agreed to cease the fighting ( and ) return their forces to the positions held before the current fighting began " on August 17 .
He did not give a specific time for the ceasefire but said the United States looked forward to " immediate implementation " .
The two party leaders had also agreed to meet U.S. Assistant Secretary for Near Eastern Affairs Robert Pelletreau in September " to solidify the cease-fire and to pursue reconciliation " , Davies said .
His statement gave no venue or precise date for the meeting .
The United States has already called on the Kurdish factions to hold peace talks in London .
The KDP said Thursday night it had repelled an attack by thousands of PUK fighters , killing , wounding or capturing about 400 opposing guerrillas .
The fighting has threatened a U.S.-led peace plan to unite the mountainous Kurdish region in northern Iraq against President Saddam Hussein .
One teen left dead by attack on U.S. slumber party .
CHESAPEAKE , Va .
1996-08-23
A knife-wielding neighbour apparently intent on sexual assault invaded a teenage slumber party on Friday , killing one girl and wounding three others , police said .
At about 4 a.m. EDT ( 0800 GMT ) , a group of teenaged girls were having the overnight party in the Camelot subdivision of this eastern Virginia city , when a man entered the house , wielding a knife , threatening to sexually assault the girls .
Detective Richard Black of the Chesapeake Police Department , said a neighbour , Curtis Lee White II , 19 , was arrested in the attack , but had not been charged by late morning on Friday .
There were apparently no adults at the party as the father of the family who lived in the house was out of town and the mother died more than a year ago , Black said .
The detective said details were sketchy , but two of the teenagers were reportedly downstairs watching television when White allegedly entered the house and told the girls to take off their clothes .
He said a male teenager sleeping upstairs reportedly heard the commotion and came downstairs and confronted White , who allegedly stabbed him more than once .
The other teenagers also confronted the assailant and three girls , all under 18 , were stabbed , one fatally .
" At least two of them were sexually molested , " Black said .
He said all of the wounded teenagers were taken to a hospital but none of the injuries were considered life-threatening .
Police said the girl who died was identified as Michelle Harper .
Her age was not given .
Glickman says USDA monitoring aflatoxin in Texas .
WASHINGTON 1996-08-23
Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman said the department was monitoring reports of aflatoxin found in corn in parts of Texas .
" We 're always concerned about aflatoxin but we 're on top of it , " Glickman told reporters after addressing a USDA-sponsored farmers ' market .
" That 's a perennial problem .
It may be a little more problematic because of cold , wet conditions but we 're on top of it , " the secretary said .
Asked about reports Egypt has set new levels for a vomitoxin in its purchase of U.S. wheat , the secretary said " I do n't know anything about it " but added that USDA officials were " looking at it . "
Mass .
governor has trouble winning home support .
BOSTON 1996-08-23
The 12-year-old daughter of Republican Gov .
William Weld is working to stop his bid to win a U.S. Senate seat because she does n't want to leave Massachusetts .
Weld conceded his 12-year-old daughter , Franny , is " a foot soldier " for Democratic incumbent Sen .
John Kerry , even though she is n't old enough to vote .
Weld , speaking on WBUR-FM radio on Thursday , said he was facing a revolt from his daughter in part because she does not want to leave Cambridge , Massachusetts , and move to Washington .
He also said Franny Weld 's best friend , Tracy Roosevelt , might have something to do with her politics .
Tracy is the great-granddaughter of Democratic former President Franklin Roosevelt , and support for Democrats runs in the family .
The Roosevelts are good friends of Weld and his wife , Susan Roosevelt Weld , a descendant of former President Theodore Roosevelt , who won the presidency as a Republican .
Lufthansa cargo Q2 load factor up 1.7 pct .
FRANKFURT 1996-08-23
The following table shows Lufthansa Cargo AG second quarter 1996 results , based on figures published by Deutsche Lufthansa AG in-house newspaper
Lufthanseat .
Available freight-tonne kilometres ( million ) 2,389 up 4 pct
Revenue freight-tonne kilometres ( million ) 1,600 up 7 pct
Freight load factor 67.0 up 1.7 pct pts
Revenue from transport ( Dm million ) 820 up 2 pct
Revenue from other services ( Dm million ) 14 down 26 pct
Staff costs ( Dm million ) 116 up 8 pct
Fuel costs ( Dm million ) 69 up 20 pct
Flight-related fees ( Dm million ) 125 up 17 pct
- Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax+44 171 542 5017
WSC-India Rice Weather , Aug 23 .
SUMMARY- Showers 0.25-1.30 inch ( 6-33 mm ) and locally heavier through much of India , 75 percent coverage .
Isolated showers 0.20-0.70 inch ( 5-18 mm ) in the north .
Highs 82-96F ( 28-36C ) .
CROP IMPACT- Conditions remain favorable for the development of rice in the region .
FORECAST-
TODAY ...
Showers and rain 0.25-1.00 inch ( 6-25 mm ) and locally heavier through most of central and south central India , up to 0.75 inch ( 19 mm ) in 75 percent of north central India , and only isolated up to 0.50 inch ( 13 mm ) elsewhere over India .
Highs 82-96F ( 28-36C ) .
TONIGHT ...
Variable clouds in southern India with showers .
Partly cloudy in northern India with a few light showers .
Lows 68-76F ( 20-24C ) .
TOMORROW ...
Little change from today 's weather expected .
OUTLOOK ...
Numerous to scattered showers and thunderstorms in southern and central India , and isolated showers to the north Sunday through Tuesday .
Temperatures near normal .
Source : Weather Services Corporation
Washington to curb Tamil support in U.S. - Sri Lanka .
COLOMBO 1996-08-23
Sri Lanka said on Friday the United States had promised to stamp out any illegal activities on U.S. soil directed against the island 's government .
The Sri Lankan foreign ministry said in a statement : " The United States government sympathised with the current predicament Sri Lanka was facing . "
The statement said the U.S. government " would do all within its prevailing legal framework to prevent the use of American soil to perpetrate violence against the democratic government of Sri Lanka " .
It said the U.S. State Department 's coordinator for counter terrorism , Philip Wilcox , had expressed Washington 's support for the government when he visited Colombo this week .
Colombo has said it believes Tamil rebels , fighting a 13-year war for independence against the government , finance their military activity through funds extorted from expatriate Sri Lankans in western countries such as the United States .
U.S. embassy officials in Colombo were not immediately available to comment on the report .
Colombo estimates more than 50,000 people have been killed in the war between government forces and the Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam rebels in the island 's north and east .
Nepal 's king leaves on week-long visit to China .
KATHMANDU 1996-08-23
King Birendra left Nepal on Friday for a week-long visit to China , his eighth since ascending the throne in 1972 , officials said .
The constitutional monarch , who last visited China in 1993 , was scheduled to meet Chinese President Jiang Zemin and Premier Li Peng during his visit , they said .
Foreign ministry officials gave no details of the issues the king , who was accompanied by Foreign Minister Prakash Chandra Lohani , would discuss with Chinese leaders .
The Himalayan kingdom , sandwiched between China and India , has traditionally sought to maintain close cooperation with its giant neighbours , and an equal distance from the two .
The 50-year old monarch was accompanied by Queen Aishwarya on a flight to the Tibetan capital of Lhasa .
The king will visit Chongqing before arriving in the Chinese capital , Beijing , early next week , officials said .
Nepal man held for keeping child servant in chains .
KATHMANDU 1996-08-23
Nepali police said on Friday they arrested a man who allegedly kept a child servant bound in chains so that he would not run away when his employer was out to work .
Madhusudan Munakarmi was arrested on Thursday after his neighbours informed police about the plight of 12-year old Dhiraj K.C. , who told police his employer used to tie him up with iron chains and locks concealed under his clothes .
The neighbours in Kathmandu called the police when they saw Dheeraj , employed by the man for the past nine months , limping because of the chains .
" I feared he would flee from work or steal my belongings , " the Kathmandu Post newspaper quoted Munakarmi as saying after his arrest .
If convicted , he faces a maximum of three years in jail under Nepal 's child protection laws .
OPTIONS - Euro debt vols seen regrouping after fall .
LONDON 1996-08-23
Implied volatility of European bond and interest rate options should stabilise around current levels until early next week after falling before and after this week 's German-led cut in interest rates , traders said .
" Volatility has come off a lot .
We 're looking for it to stabilise now , " said one Euromark options trader at a U.S. bank .
A trader at a Japanese bank said Euromark volatility now stood at 14.00 for September contract , 16.75 for December , 19.50 for March and 21.25 for June .
This compared with midweek levels , before the welter of interest rate cuts , of 18.50 for September , 20.00 for December , 22.00 for March and 23.5 for June , he said .
At 1347 GMT , December Euromark futures were trading at 96.78 , two basis points down on the day .
He said the sell-off in June vols might have been overdone , which could offer value at current levels .
He said caps and floors would be well bid after the round of interest rate cuts due to the fact these rates should stay low at the short end .
The size of the Bundesbank 's repo rate cut , to 3.00 percent from 3.30 percent , took markets by surprise .
" Volatility has a bid to it -- longer-dated volatility more than short-dated because the event people were buying for has passed and now perhaps people will sell some short dated vol and buy some long dated vol , " he said .
" Long dated volatility has been low this year , so it is still at levels which are not historically high .
" It is not a dangerous level to own vol. You are not going to lose a lot and you could make quite a bit . "
He said volatility levels should be stable until markets reassess the situation after a long weekend in Britain .
Paribas Capital Markets OTC options specialist Robert Coughlan said that if volatility continued lower for the rest of Friday in over-the-counter 10-year Bunds , it should be higher next Tuesday .
He said the absence on holiday of many market makers was a main factor behind falls this week in volatility in high-yielding markets such as Italy , Spain and Sweden .
Coughlan said the market had more downside than upside potential , but a fall was not likely to be of significant size .
" I recommend people sell strangles in a number of markets -- in Germany and France in particular .
" With high-yielding markets Italy will be a lot more vulnerable in September on economic and political fronts , so I would use current the low level of vol to buy options .
" So sell options on Bunds and France to enhance yield and buy options on Italy , " Coughlan said ..
-- Stephen Nisbet , International Bonds +44 171 542 6320
Goldman Sachs sets warrants on Continental .
LONDON 1996-08-23
Goldman Sachs & Co Wertpapier GmbH has issued a total of five million American-style call warrants , on Continental AG , lead manager Goldman Sachs & Co said .
One warrant controls one share .
STRIKE PRICE 25.00 DEM PREMIUM 10.12 PCT
ISSUE PRICE 2.42 DEM GEARING 10.29 X
EXERCISE PERIOD 02.SEP.96-21.NOV.97 PAYDATE 30.AUG.96
LISTING DDF FFT STG MIN EXER LOT 100
SPOT REFERENCE 24.90 DEM
-- Reuter London Newsroom +44 171 542 7658
Legal challenge to Diana delayed by jail term .
LONDON 1996-08-23
A British photographer branded a stalker by Princess Diana has been forced to postpone a legal challenge to a ban on approaching her because he 's been jailed for criminal damage , his lawyer said on Friday .
Martin Stenning started a 12-week jail sentence on Thursday just as he was preparing to contest an injunction obtained by Diana banning him from coming within 300 metres ( yards ) of her .
" We were in the process of preparing a detailed affidavit responding to the Princess 's affadavit and expected to go to court in the next couple of weeks , " said Stenning 's lawyer , Benedict Birnberg . "
But everything has been put on ice now . "
Birnberg told Reuters that the challenge to the injunction would be delayed until Stenning was released .
Stenning threw a brick through the window of a van in February after an argument with a driver when he was working as a motorcycle dispatch rider .
Stenning , who has previous convictions , is expected to appeal against the sentence .
Magistrates also ordered him to pay compensation of 182 pounds ( $ 282 ) .
The freelance photographer was branded a stalker by Diana , whose divorce from heir-to-the-throne Prince Charles is due to become final next week , after persistently trailing her on his motorcycle .
In an affidavit , the princess said that in chasing her Stenning had got so close that he twice smashed into her car and pushed her when she tried to remove the film from his camera .
Stenning has rejected Diana 's claims and said he was being made a scapegoat to scare off press photographers .
Jordan expels Iraqi diplomat .
AMMAN 1996-08-23
Jordan has asked an Iraqi diplomat to leave the kingdom for carrying out duties incompatible with diplomatic norms , an official source said on Friday .
The move came after Amman blamed Iraq and a pro-Baghdad local political party for last week 's worst unrest in seven years after a government decision to double prices of bread .
The government declined comment .
" Jordan has asked Mr. Adel Ibrahim , the Iraqi embassy 's press attache , to leave because he was carrying out duties incompatible with diplomatic norms , " the source told Reuters .
He said Ibrahim was still in Amman .
The Jordanian Arab Socialist Baath Party has denied involvement in unrest which it blamed on government policies and rising economic hardship .
The riots , which shook Jordan for two days , broke out after last Friday 's main prayers in the southern town of Karak and spread to Amman .
Kurd rebels to free Turkish soldier prisoners .
DOHUK , Iraq 1996-08-23
Turkish Kurd guerrillas said on Friday they would free seven Turkish soldiers they hold in northern Iraq under a tentative Islamist peace bid .
" ...For the sake of safety we are asking for their family members or the authorities to come and pick them up , " Kurdistan Workers Party ( PKK ) central committee member Riza Altun told journalists near the Iraqi city of Dohuk .
PKK guerrillas would accompany the soldiers , captured last spring in one of Turkey 's frequent cross-border drives , until they could be handed over , he said .
Their release has been negotiated by Islamist writer Ismail Nacar as part of a wider effort , partly backed by Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan , to find a political solution to Turkey 's Kurdish problem .
Erbakan has encouraged Nacar 's bid but has ruled out direct talks with the rebels .
The PKK often uses bases in northern Iraq in its fight for autonomy or independence in southeast Turkey .
More than 20,000 people have died in 12 years of fighting between the guerrillas and Turkish forces .
SOLIDERE shares mixed on market .
BEIRUT 1996-08-23
SOLIDERE shares were mixed on Friday on the privately-operated Beirut Secondary Market ( BSM ) .
A shares -- distributed to former holders of property rights in the Beirut central district SOLIDERE is rebuilding -- closed at $ 104.625 unchanged from Thursday .
B shares -- issued in a $ 650-million subscription in January 1994 -- rose to $ 106.5 from $ 106.375 a day earlier .
Turnover on BSM , which trades only SOLIDERE shares , was 8,049 shares from Thursday 's 8,757 and value was $ 850,968 from $ 918,288 .
On the official Beirut Stock Exchange , only 1,185 Ciments Libanais shares were traded at $ 1.1875 compared with 2,036 shares traded on Thursday at the same price .
There was no trade in any of the three other listed companies : Ciments Blancs , Eternit and Uniceramic .
The BLOM Stock Index which covers both markets rose 0.04 percent to 903.09 and the LISPI index rose 0.02 percent to 81.58 .
- Beirut editorial ( 961 1 ) 864148 353078 861723
Zenith lands $ 1 billion contract , plans $ 100 million plant .
Susan Nadeau
CHICAGO 1996-08-22
A consortium of telephone companies and The Walt Disney Co .
said Thursday it had signed a $ 1 billion contract with Zenith to make digital televison set-top boxes for its home entertainment service .
The announcement of the contract for 3 million set-top boxes gave new hope to Zenith , which has struggled with years of losses .
" This really indicates we 're back in the business , " William Luehrs , president of the Glenview , Ill.-based company 's Networks Services Division , said in a telephone interview . "
Anytime somebody gets the opportunity to enter the next era with such a big bang has got to be seen as a strong message to the industry . "
Following the announcement , Zenith 's stock soared $ 5.50 to $ 16.875 on the New York Stock Exchange .
The consortium , called Americast , said the contract was part of its strategy to develop and market the next generation in home entertainment .
In addition to Disney , Americast 's partners are phone companies Ameritech Corp. , BellSouth Corp. , GTE Corp. and SBC Communications .
Americast said Southern New England Telecommunications Corp. has signed a letter of intent to join the group , which plans to provide a home entertainment service similar to cable television .
Zenith also said it planned to build a new $ 100 million plant in Woodridge , Ill .
, to make picture tubes for 32- and 35-inch screen TV sets .
The company currently buys the tubes from competitors .
The new plant , which is dependent on obtaining financing , will create about 280 new jobs , Zenith said .
The contract calls for production of the set-top boxes over five years .
Luehrs said manufacturing will begin and revenue will start to roll in during the first half of next year .
The boxes will be made on a build-to-order basis .
Zenith will convert its Chihuahua , Mexico , analogue set-top box plant to manufacture the digital boxes .
Luehrs declined to say when the operation was expected to be profitable .
Americast will provide the boxes to subscribers as part of the service .
Its service is being introduced in selected markets across the United States .
Luehrs said digital technology in set-top boxes is only the beginning and said the technology will eventually show up in retail consumer electronics .
" We 'll build a lot of these devices into television sets , for digital television , " he said . "
Although that is not where this particular contract is headed , the fact that there is a strong Zenith presence will pay us dividends in the future . "
Zenith has been plagued by generally soft conditions in the colour television industry , reporting full-year losses since 1989 .
Last month , it reported a second-quarter loss of $ 33.2 million , or 51 cents a share , vs. a loss of $ 45.3 million , or 97 cents a share , a year earlier .
Last November , South Korea-based LG Electronics Inc. bought a majority stake in Zenith .
Robert Gutenstein , an analyst for Kalf , Voorhis & Co .
, said the contract was " not unique , but it 's big . "
" Digital is coming , it 's economic and the question is what will make the consumer happy and at what price . "
Natural Law Party says it can meditate problems away .
WASHINGTON 1996-08-22
From the people who brought you hundreds of " yogic fliers " who claimed to defy nature by levitating comes The Natural Law Party , a minor political party that nominated a presidential candidate on Thursday .
At a hotel convention here , the party associated with the Transcendental Meditation ( TM ) movement named physicist John Hagelin as its presidential nominee for the Nov. 5 election .
The party is running on a platform claiming it can ward off problems before they occur through techniques such as mass meditation that would reduce stress , crime , terrorism and even wars .
" Social stress can be reduced and problems such as crime and violence will automatically decrease , " said a party paper .
Many party members are practitioners of TM , which involves meditating to a repeated word or phrase , called a mantra .
Some advanced TM followers contend they can actually mediate to such a point that they fly .
But in a demonstration of " yogic flying " several years ago , critics said the people were merely bouncing off the ground from a sitting position .
Huge Windows 95 sales fail to meet expectations .
Martin Wolk
SEATTLE 1996-08-22
A year after its massively publicized introduction , Microsoft Corp. 's Windows 95 computer operating system has fallen short of the most optimistic expectations for the software giant and the industry .
Even though more than 40 million copies of Windows 95 have been sold , making it the fastest-selling new software ever , it would have been impossible for any product to live up to the unprecedented hype of the Aug. 24 , 1995 launch , when stores around the world opened at midnight to greet long lines of customers .
The Redmond , Wash.-based company spent tens of millions of dollars promoting the product with stunts that included buying the entire print run of the Times of London and lighting New York 's Empire State building in a Windows color scheme .
But the product , delivered eight months late , has fallen short of its sales potential in part because Microsoft delivered a mixed message to business customers , analysts said .
" It did n't do as well as it could have , " said Rob Enderle , an analyst with Giga Information Group .
Scores of software and hardware companies that had hoped for a big boost in sales were disappointed when only a brief spike materialized .
" People who were expecting major coat-tails were somewhat disappointed , " said Scott Winkler , an analyst with Gartner Group .
" It 's not as though it has n't had an impact , " he said . "
It just has n't had the huge earth-shattering impact some people were looking for . "
Symantec Corp. , which had been among the most bullish of software companies at the time of the Windows 95 launch , ended up posting disappointing financial results when retail sales of the operating system fell short of its projections .
Touchstone Software Corp. had to pay $ 1.3 million in cash and stock to settle a shareholders lawsuit brought after the company 's sales failed to meet expectations tied to the Windows 95 launch .
Many software developers apparently saw their crucial holiday season sales suffer last year because store shelves were jammed with blue-and-white boxes of Windows 95 , resulting in a shortage of space for seasonal products , said Ann Stephens , president of PC Data Inc .
To be sure , sales of Windows 95 and the accompanying Office 95 upgrade drove Microsoft sales up 46 percent last year to a record $ 8.67 billion and cemented the company 's status as the industry 's dominant company .
Microsoft executives say they are thrilled with the sales figures , and industry analysts estimate that by sometime next year , the installed base of Windows 95 will surpass that of the older version of Windows , now used on about 100 million computers worldwide .
But Enderle said the figure could have been even higher if Microsoft had done a better job of handling the huge demand for technical support from customers who were frustrated trying to install the system .
He and other analysts said corporate America adopted a go-slow approach because Microsoft already was promoting the new version of its high-end Windows NT operating system , expected to be available in stores in the next several weeks .
" Microsoft sent a lot of signals that NT was going to be the answer , " Winkler said . "
Many people began to believe that Windows 95 was being downplayed . "
But now that Windows NT 4.0 has been launched , Winkler and others believe only a relatively small proportion of corporate users will elect to pay the added software and hardware costs needed to use it instead of Windows 95 .
" Windows 95 is going to do great , " he said . "
The mistake people made was in thinking it was going to be a fast , sweeping change rather than a slow , building change . "
U.S. says still committed to Cuba migration pacts .
WASHINGTON 1996-08-22
The United States said on Thursday it remained committed to migration accords with Cuba and would continue to repatriate intercepted Cuban migrants who attempted to enter U.S. territory illegally .
A State Department statement appeared in part a response to Cuban complaints that Washington was jeopardising the accords by failing to return some of the Cubans involved in recent illegal migration incidents .
" The United States reiterates its full commitment to the implementation " of the accords signed by the two countries in 1994 and 1995 , said the statement by spokesman Glyn Davies .
" The United States will continue to return Cuban migrants intercepted at sea who seek to enter the United States or the Guantanamo Naval Base illegally , " it said .
Washington would also take " prompt and effective law enforcement action " against alien smuggling and hijackings from Cuba , it added .
Davies told reporters the statement would be distributed in the Cuban exile community in Miami " to remind everyone of the importance of abiding by the accords and avoiding dangerous attempts to cross the straits " from Cuba to Florida .
Havana 's complaints centred on an incident in which a boatload of emigrants capsized in the Florida Straits last week and two recent aircraft hijackings from Cuba .
Sixteen of those picked up from the boat were returned to Cuba but eight were taken to the United States and three to Guantanamo Bay , a U.S. base on Cuba , until they emigrated to another nation .
The most recent hijacking , last Friday , involved three hijackers and the pilot of a small aircraft .
Davies said on Tuesday the pilot could soon return to Cuba but U.S. authorities planned to try the hijackers .
In an incident on July 7 , a Cuban interior ministry official hijacked a commercial plane and sought aylum at Guantanamo Bay .
Davies said he knew of no plans to return the man to Cuba .
Wis .
says is first state to apply for new welfare .
CHICAGO 1996-08-22
In keeping with its pioneering image in the area of welfare , Wisconsin was the first state to submit an administrative plan under the nation 's new welfare law , Gov .
Tommy Thompson said Thursday .
According to a new release from the governor , Wisconsin submitted a plan to the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services for administration of the new block grant system for welfare just minutes after President Bill Clinton signed the measure into law Thursday .
" As the nation 's leader in welfare reform , Wisconsin is far ahead of the curve and ready to go under this new system , " Thompson said .
Still , the governor said the new law does not go as far as the state 's own welfare reform program , dubbed W-2 .
He said that despite the new law , Wisconsin will still require federal waivers allowing the working poor to acquire health care coverage from the state , a 60-day residency requirement for participation in the welfare program , and child support collections to go directly to custodial parents .
The nation 's new welfare reform law limits eligibility , gives states more power and ends direct federal aid for poor children .
-- Karen Pierog , 312-408-8647
Snoozing Vietnamese man takes slow train to Alaska .
ANCHORAGE , Alaska 1996-08-22
A Vietnamese man who tried to take a snooze in a railway boxcar in Canada found himself locked in and bound for Alaska with no food or water .
Officials in the port of Whittier said on Thursday that they found Tuan Quac Phan , 29 , dehydrated , famished and terrified after sailing to Alaska from Canada in the boxcar loaded on a barge , a trip that takes about five days .
Sgt .
Dan Jewell of the Whittier , Alaska police department described Phan as " extremely cooperative " . "
Seeing me in my uniform , he kept saying , Jail better .
Jail better . '
"
Phan 's accidental journey started last week in Prince Rupert , British Columbia , where he was searching for a fishing job , Jewell said .
" He had climbed up in this boxcar to get out of the weather and to get some sleep , " Jewell said . "
The next thing you know , the boxcar is coupled up and loaded up to a barge and headed north . "
Police found Phan late on Monday when the boxcar , which was transporting lumber , was opened at Whittier , a port in western Prince William Sound .
Officials fed Phan some soup , gave him medical care , kept him overnight and then fed him a large breakfast .
State , federal agents probe Arkansas church fires .
Steve Barnes
LITTLE ROCK , Ark .
1996-08-22
State and federal agents on Thursday sifted through the rubble of two predominantly black Arkansas churches that burned within minutes of one another late Tuesday and early Wednesday .
Both churches were in the Mississippi delta region of Arkansas , about 90 miles ( 145 kms ) southeast of Little Rock , and were located within three miles of one another .
" We 're investigating with the idea that both fires may be arson , but that has n't been conclusively established , " said Wayne Jordan , a spokesman for the Arkansas State Police .
Agents of the F.B.I. and the Bureau of Alcohol , Tobacco and Firearms were also at the scene , Jordan said .
Mount Zion Missionary Baptist Church and St. Matthews Missionary Baptist Church were both frame structures , each near Turner , Arkansas , a small community surrounded by cotton and soybean fields .
" This is rural Arkansas .
I 'm surprised anyone could even find us out here , " said Fannie Johnson , a member of St. Matthew 's , who said she believed arson was to blame .
Others connected with the two churches said they shared that suspicion , although all said they knew of no motive and no racial tension in the area .
" It 's sad someone would have that kind of spite in their heart , " said Rev. Jerome Turner , pastor of Mount Zion Missionary Baptist Church .
Arkansas has been spared the loss of predominantly black churches to arson , a wave that has claimed an estimated 30 houses of worship across the south in the past several months .
A black church near Camden , Arkansas , about 100 miles ( 161 kms ) south of Little Rock , burned in July , but federal agents have not determined the cause .
RESEARCH ALERT - Royal Oak initiated .
-- EVEREN Securities Inc said Friday it initiated coverage of Royal Oak Mines Inc with an outperform rating .
-- It set earnings estimates of $ 0.08 a share for fiscal 1996 , $ 0.13 for 1997 , $ 0.40 for 1998 and $ 0.43 for 1999 .
-- " Based on our simulated production , income and cash flow models , common shares of Royal Oak are at a significant discount to the industry averages , " EVEREN said .
-- The short-term price objective is $ 5 a share and the long-term objective is $ 9 .
-- Royal Oak shares were down 1/16 at 3-11/16 .
Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787
SunGard to buy CheckFree unit .
SAN MATEO , Calif. 1996-08-23
SunGard Shareholder Systems Inc , a subsidiary of SunGard Data Systems Inc , said it had entered into a definitive agreement to buy the Securities Products Business unit of CheckFree Corp .
The company said in a statement on Friday the deal was expected to be finalized in September .
Terms were not disclosed .
The purchase is not expected to have a material effect o SunGard 's financial condition or results of operations .
-- New York newsroom , ( 212 ) 859-1610
Alpha Techs closes Lockhart purchase .
NEW YORK 1996-08-23
Alpha Technologies Group Inc said it had closed on its agreement to acquire Lockhart Industries Inc .
The company said in a statement late on Thursday that it issued 280,556 shares of common stock for the stock of Lockhart .
These shares are subject to post-closing adjustments .
Lockhart , based in Paramount , Calif. , is a designer and manufacturer of sophisticated thermal management products .
-- New York newsroom , ( 212 ) 859-1610
Analysts hold Dutch PTT estimates .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-23
Dutch post and telecoms group Koninklijke PTT Nederland NV 's ( Dutch PTT ) first half results came marginally below most analysts ' forecasts , giving scant grounds to adjust full year estimates , analysts said on Friday .
PTT earlier announced an 8.5 percent rise in net profit for the first six months of 1996 to 1.209 billion guilders , a hair 's breadth below the 1.210-1.236 billion forecast range .
" They were pretty much in line with our estimate of 1.210 billion , " said Peter Roe , at Paribas in London . "
As we expected volume growth was quite good ...
there 's really no reason to change our forecast and our largely positive view on the stock . "
" Coming just a million guilders under the forecast range is n't overwhelmingly surprising , " said ING analyst Steven Vrolijk , who is continuing to look for a nine to 10 percent rise in 1996 earnings .
" They 've got a very sound domestic business which is doing very well , we remain positive on the stock , " said Roe . "
We think it 's a solid performer in the Dutch market . "
Roe said he was sticking by his forecast of a 2.45 billion guilder net for 1996 .
Dutch PTT earlier on Friday repeated a forecast it would improve on 1995 's 2.26 billion guilder net profit for the whole year of 1996 .
By 1403 GMT the shares were down 1.70 guilders to 61.00 guilders , falling in a weaker Amsterdam bourse .
-- Keiron Henderson , Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000
Boskalis upgrades 1996 outlook .
[ CORRECTED 13:12 GMT ]
PAPENDRECHT , Netherlands 1996-08-23
Dredging group Koninklijke Boskalis Westminster NV said on Friday it expected higher turnover and profits for the second half of 1996 ( corrects from the full year 1996 ) .
" An improvement is expected in capacity utilisation , turnover and profits , " the company said in a statement .
The world 's largest dredger said in March that it was uncertain whether it could hold 1996 full-year profit steady at the previous year 's 70.9 million guilders , but added long-term prospects were good .
Boskalis reported 1996 first-half net profit fell to 27.5 million guilders from a year-earlier 41.4 million .
Greek president dissolves parliament for snap vote .
ATHENS 1996-08-23
Greek President Costis Stephnopoulos signed a decree on Thursday ordering the dissolution of the 300-seat parliament ahead of snap elections on September 22 .
" The President of the Republic Costis Stephanopoulos signed the decree for the dissolution of parliament , " a presidency statement said .
Socialist Prime Minister Costas Simitis announced the snap poll on Thursday citing problems with the economy , the country 's convergence with the European Union and tense relations with neighbouring Turkey .
Elections were originally scheduled to be held in October next year .
Libyan man murdered in Malta .
VALLETTA 1996-08-23
A Libyan man has been found stabbed to death in Malta , police said on Friday .
They said the body of Amer Hishem Ali Mohammed , 23 , was found in a pool of blood in Sliema , seven km ( four miles ) from Valletta , on Wednesday morning .
He appeared to have been killed on Tuesday night , suffering at least eight stab wounds .
Police Commissioner George Grech said police were investigating the possibility that Mohammed had links to an Islamic militant group as reported by the local press .
" What we know is that he was a fervant religious man , we cannot exclude anything in investigations " he said .
Deutsche Bahn H1 pre-tax profit up 17.5 pct .
FRANKFURT 1996-08-23
Six months to June 30
( in millions of marks unless stated )
Group pre-tax profit 188 vs 160
Group sales 14,600 up 3.3 pct
NOTE - Full name of the state-owned German railway company is Deutsche Bahn AG .
The company is earmarked for eventual privatisatio
also covers snap FAT8222
Revenue from long-distance passenger
traffic 2,500 up 6.4 pct
Revenue from commuter traffic 5,400 up 4.6 pct
Revenue from freight traffic 3,200 down 5.1 pct
Group workforce on June 30 300,962 down 3.7 oct
NOTE - Sales , profit compare with first half of 1995 , workforce compares with Dec 31 .
-- Frankfurt Newsroom , +49 69 756525
Sea lion paparazzi to keep tabs on whales .
LONDON 1996-08-22
U.S. marine biologists have trained a pair of sea lions to tag and photograph elusive whales as they cruise through the Pacific depths , New Scientist magazine reported on Thursday .
James Harvey and Jennifer Hurley of the Moss Landing Marine Laboratories in California say their sea lions , natural companions of many species of whale , can go where no man or woman has ever gone before .
" Any diver knows that when a whale gets going you ca n't keep up , " Harvey told the magazine . "
That is why we know only about five percent of what whales do . "
The sea lions -- 17-year-old Beaver and nine-year-old Sake -- have undergone six years of training for their mission .
Beaver once worked for the U.S. Navy and Sake is an amusement park veteran .
Harvey said they could accurately tag whales with a radio transmitter , and could also swim all the way around one of the giant mammals , filming it with a video camera .
Their first assignment , later this year , will be documenting humpback whale migration off Monterey , California .
The article did not spell out exactly how the sea lions manage to tag the whales but said in training they were taught to stick a radio transmitter on to a plastic model of a whale using suction cups .
RTRS - Australia Senate jeopardises rate cut - Howard .
CANBERRA 1996-08-23
Australian Prime Minister John Howard said the possibility of lower interest rates was being jeopardised by Parliament 's upper house where opposition parties planned to scrutinise the 1996/97 budget .
" Every time the Senate hacks away at the budget , they hack away at the lower interest rate environment , " Howard told reporters on Thursday night after attending a Liberal Party function .
Senior ministers have repeatedly warned since the fiscally-tight budget was handed down on Tuesday night that the chance of lower official rates could be hampered in the Senate .
The budget contained sharp spending cuts in areas such as the labour market to reduce the deficit to about A$ 5.6 billion .
The conservative government 's plan for reform of the industrial relations environment and to partially sell Telstra has also been opposed by parties in the Senate such as the Greens and Australian Democrats as well as the official opposition , the Labor Party .
Official cash rates were last cut on July 31 to 7.0 percent .
-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800
RTRS - Toyota Australia workers to return to work .
MELBOURNE 1996-08-23
Over 2,000 striking workers voted on Friday to return to work on Monday at Toyota Australia 's Melbourne assembly line , ending a two-week stoppage .
RTRS - Niugini shares surge on bid talk .
SYDNEY 1996-08-23
Shares in gold miner Niugini Mining Ltd surged 38 cents to A$ 3.75 early on Friday following confirmation on Thursday from Battle Mountain Gold that it was considering acquiring the 49.6 percent of Niugini it did not already own .
Niugini Mining Ltd said on Thursday that Battle Mountain had initiated talks about acquiring the shares in Niugini it does not already own . "
Battle Mountain are set to take out the minorities there soon , " said a Sydney broker .
Niugini holds copper and gold mining interests in Australia , Chile and Papua New Guinea , where it has a 17.2 percent stake in the Lihir gold project .
By 11.25 a.m. ( 0025 GMT ) , Niugini Mining shares were at A$ 3.65 , up 28 cents on turnover of 108,288 shares .
-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373 1800
South Korean students throw " irreplaceable " rocks .
SEOUL 1996-08-23
Students at South Korea 's Yonsei University threw more than just ordinary rocks at riot police -- some were samples that the geology department had taken 30 years to collect , newspapers reported on Friday .
Geology prefessors were quoted as saying that their collection of 10,000 rocks , gathered from across the nation and abroad , were irreplaceable .
" These are not like missing window panes or broken desks .
They are lost forever , " said one professor .
The students staged a violent nine-day demonstration at the university to demand unification with North Korea .
Police ended the protest on Tuesday after storming the campus .
S. Korean won ends up on dollar position unwinding .
SEOUL 1996-08-23
The won rose against the dollar on Friday as banks unwound dollar positions on the belief that the won would continue to strengthen , dealers said .
The won closed at 818.10 , after opening at 819.10 .
It ranged from 817.60 to 819.30 .
" The dollar is overbought at the moment , " said a western bank dealer . "
The central bank 's insistent intervention just above the 820 level convinced players that it is serious about supporting the won .
So some foreign banks began unwinding their dollar positions . "
Orii - 96/97 group forecast .
TOKYO 1996-08-23
Year to May 31 , 1997
( in billions of yen unless specified )
LATEST ACTUAL
( Group ) FORECAST YEAR-AGO
Sales 8.70 8.67
Current prft 7 mln loss 371 mln
Net nil loss 447 mln
EPS nil yen loss 48.61 yen
NOTE - Orii Corp makes automation equipment .
Orii - 95/96 group results .
TOKYO 1996-08-23
Year to May 31 , 1996
( Group ) ( in billions of yen unless specified )
Sales 8.67 vs 9.33
Operating loss 286 million vs loss 48 million
Current loss 371 million vs loss 278 million
Net loss 447 million vs loss 350 million
EPS loss 48.61 yen vs loss 38.11 yen
Diluted EPS - vs -
NOTE - Orii Corp makes automation equipment .
China copper stocks owned by state reserve - trade .
Lynne O'Donnell
HONG KONG 1996-08-23
Up to 100,000 tonnes of copper held in Shanghai bonded warehouses , confounding the world market as to its source and ultimate fate , probably belongs to China 's strategic state reserve , industry sources said on Friday .
Around 40,000 tonnes of the copper have already been moved to warehouses near the northern port of Yingkou , where some of the strategic stockpile was stored , they said .
Just who owns the copper is a question that has kept traders and industry analysts guessing since the metal was channelled into Shanghai by the China National Nonferrous Metals Import and Export Corp ( CNIEC ) in June and July .
It was unclear whether or not the 40,000 tonnes had cleared customs -- which would provide some concrete indication that the strategic reserve , administered directly by the central government 's State Planning Commission , owned the copper .
Traders have said the reserve could negotiate concessions on duties -- three percent import tax and 17 percent value-added tax -- that made the copper prohibitively expensive otherwise .
But one source , the head of a Hong Kong trading house , said it made no difference if the copper was customs cleared or not .
" If they spend all this money moving the copper to Yingkou , it will be sitting there for years , " he said .
" Once it arrives in Yingkou , it is subject to monitoring by the State Planning Commission , which has to give permission for any more movement ; it is out of the hands of traders , " he said .
Mystery has surrounded the Shanghai stockpile in recent months , with traders unsure not only of who owns it , but of its exact size and what its owner planned to do with it .
Trading sources generally agreed it would be cost-effective to take the copper back into a depleted central reserve as it had already served its purpose in taking advantage of long-term backwardation on the London Metal Exchange ( LME ) .
A backwardation occurs when the spot price of a metal is higher than the forward price .
CNIEC lent around 85,000 tonnes of copper onto the LME between April and June 1995 on behalf of the state reserve , running the state stockpile down to 115,000 tonnes from 200,000 tonnes previously .
Traders in Asia said CNIEC could well have lent it to the market at around US$ 2,700 a tonne , and then paid somewhere between $ 2,200 and $ 2,400 a tonne when it started taking the metal back earlier this year .
This would have cleared CNIEC a healthy profit , which could then have been used to finance storage and other costs .
Word that CNIEC had offered the copper to European trading houses in a series of secret meetings unnerved an already jittery market .
Industry analysts Bloomsbury Minerals Economics ( BME ) said on Wednesday the motivation of the owners of the 85,000 tonnes , " whoever they are , is the most important short-term fundamental " in an already tight world market .
BME repeated in its latest review rumours of involvement by Sumitomo Corp , with CNIEC said to be helping the Japanese trader unload its copper positions after it revealed in June losses of $ 1.8 billion in a decade of unauthorised deals .
Sumitomo and CNIEC have made no comments on the talk and Chinese traders said they know nothing of such an arrangement .
Traders in Shanghai said on Thursday they were unaware of movements out of the Shanghai bonded warehouses .
They reported more arrivals that were probably spot purchases .
They also expressed concern that the tonnage in bonded warehouses would move onto the domestic market .
But these concerns were irrelevant , a Singapore trader said , despite a forecast that domestic Chinese copper demand could hit one million tonnes this year .
As with many commodities , " there is a desire ( by the Chinese government ) to keep a stockpile of the metal , " he said . "
You do n't keep it to help industry , you keep it in case of emergency . "
-- Hong Kong newsroom ( 852 ) 2843-6470
Companion Marble posts 1st final result .
HONG KONG 1996-08-23
Year ended March 31
( in million HK$ unless stated )
Shr ( H.K. cents ) 14.0
Dividend ( H.K. cents ) nil
Exceptional items nil
Net 56.06
Turnover 531.52
Company name Companion Marble ( Holdings ) Ltd
Books close N / A
Dividend payable N / A
NOTE - Marble and granite products distributor Companion Marble , a spinoff of construction materials concern Companion Building Material ( Holdings ) Ltd , was listed on the Stock Exchange on April 25 , 1996 .
-- Hong Kong News Room ( 852 ) 2843 6368
Softbank to procure $ 900 mln via forex by Sept 5 .
TOKYO 1996-08-23
Softbank Corp said on Friday that it would procure $ 900 million through the foreign exchange market by September 5 as part of its acquisition of U.S. firm , Kingston Technology Co .
" It is in the contract that we pay ( Kingston ) $ 900 million by September 5 , " he said , adding that Softbank had already started making forward transactions to buy dollars .
On August 15 , computer software retailer Softbank said it would buy 80 percent of Kingston , the world 's largest maker of memory boards , for about $ 1.5 billion in the latest in a series of high-profile acquisitions it has made in the United States .
Shanghai Post and Telecomm net down .
SHANGHAI 1996-08-23
Half-year ended June 30 , 1996
( in millions of yuan unless stated )
Turnover 115.259 vs 123.157
Net profit 20.318 vs 22.828
Net asset per share 3.02 yuan ( no comparative figure )
Earnings per share 0.14 yuan ( no comparative figure )
Company name : Shanghai Posts and Telecommunications Equipment Co
Note : the figures were unaudited .
Promodes set to sell German assets - paper .
PARIS 1996-08-23
German retailer Promodes is in advanced talks about selling its German assets and the retailer 's board might decide as soon as Tuesday to sell the assets to Spar AG , Les Echos newspaper said on Friday .
It said investment bank Rothschild & Cie was an intermediary in the talks and added that unlisted German retailers Metro , Rewe and Lidl were also still in discussions .
Promodes has in Germany its Promo hypermarket unit with 36 Continent superstores , which is 1995 generated 4.7 percent of total Promodes sales .
The French group entered the German market in 1990 , buying
In June , Promodes signed an outline agreement to sell its Specia unit -- which runs 100 Dia stores in France -- to Germany 's Aldi .
Promodes was not immediately available for comment .
-- Paris newsroom +33 1 4221 5452
PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - August 23 .
DUBLIN 1996-08-23
Following are highlights of stories in the Irish press on Friday .
Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy .
IRISH INDEPENDENT
- Ireland 's biggest mortgage lender Irish Permanent ended weeks of stalemate when it announced it was increasing its mortgage lending rate by a quarter of a percentage point .
- Two investors who claim to be owed nearly one million Irish pounds by fund manager Tony Taylor believe they may have lost their money .
- A second Japanese trawler was under arrest on Thursday night as the Irish Navy and Air Corps continued a cat and mouse game with up to 40 vessels off the Irish coast .
- The Irish Department of Enterprise and Employment has widened its probe into Taylor Asset Managers to include the investigation of investments of 10 more investors .
- Irish exploration company Ivernia and its South African partner Minorco have received planning permission from the local county council for a major lead and zinc mine at Lisheen , County Tipperary .
- Building materials firm CRH refused to comment on reports that it is about to pay 180 million pounds stering for U.S. stone and concrete business Tilcon Inc .
IRISH TIMES
- Mortgage lending rates are on the way up with banks and building societies poised to add around a quarter of a percentage point to their main variable rates of interest .
- Members of a County Antrim Protestant family who were driven into exile by by loyalist paramilitaries two years ago returned yesterday to live in Northern Ireland in defiance of the threat hanging over them .
- Talks will resume next Tuesday in an attempt to avoid a major strike in Irish retail chain Dunnes Stores .
- Top dealers in the London office of U.S. bankers Merrill Lynch are transferring to Dublin .
- The Irish plastics industry called on the government to support incineration to deal with plastics not suitable for recycling .
Ford China JV posts 77 percent net drop in H1 96 .
SHANGHAI 1996-08-24
A Chinese truck maker in which Ford Motor Co has a 20 percent stake said it posted a 77 percent drop in post-tax profits in the first half of 1996 .
Jiangling Motors Corp , in a statement in Saturday 's edition of the China Securities newspaper , said net profit in the period was 3.385 million yuan , down from 14.956 million in the same 1995 period .
Turnover fell to 937.891 million yuan from 1.215 billion , while net assets per share were 1.88 yuan , unchanged , and earnings per share fell to 0.005 yuan from 0.02 yuan , the statement said .
In the first half , the company said it produced 8,333 vehicles and sold 9,018 , but it did not explain the difference .
It blamed the drop in profits on a weak vehicle market and said as its engine plant had only just started trial production , the company 's results would not improve in the short-term .
Ford owns 138.643 million shares in the firm .
The majority shareholder , with 51 percent , or 353.24 million shares , is Jiangling Motors Group .
The company , in the southern province of Jiangxi , had about eight percent of China 's light truck market in 1994 .
( $ 1 = 8.3 yuan )
TENNIS - RESULTS AT HAMLET CUP .
COMMACK , New York 1996-08-24
Results from the
Waldbaum Hamlet Cup tennis tournament on Saturday ( prefix
number denotes seeding ) :
Semifinals :
Martin Damm ( Czech Republic ) beat Adrian Voinea ( Romania ) 5-7
7-5 7-5
5 - Andrei Medvedev ( Ukraine ) beat Karol Kucera ( Slovakia ) 7-6
( 7-0 ) 6-3
TENNIS - RESULTS AT TOSHIBA CLASSIC .
CARLSBAD , Calif. 1996-08-24
Results from the $ 450,000 Toshiba Classic tennis tournament on Saturday ( prefix number denotes seeding ) :
Semifinals :
1 - Arantxa Sanchez Vicario ( Spain ) beat 3 - Jana Novotna ( Czech Republic ) 1-6 , 6-2 6-3
4 - Kimiko Date ( Japan ) beat 2 - Conchita Martinez ( Spain ) 6-2 7-5 .
RALLYING - KANKKUNEN IN COMMAND AS MCRAE ROLLS OUT .
JYVASKYLA , Finland 1996-08-24
Finland 's Juha Kankkunen produced an impressive performance in his Toyota on Saturday to open up a 37 seconds lead after six stages of the 1,000 Lakes Rally , sixth round of the world championship .
On a weekend overshadowed by Friday 's fatal accident , four times world champion Kankunnen emerged from the first five of Saturday 's 10 stages with a commanding advantage over his country 's latest prospect , Marcus Gronholm , also in a Toyota .
World championship leader Tommi Makinen in his Mitsubishi was third but current world champion Colin McRae ended a bad week by crashing out .
After being fined $ 250,000 by the sports governing body on Tuesday , the British driver rolled his Subaru 6.5 km into stage six .
He and co-driver Derek Ringer were unhurt but team boss David Richards was furious with them .
" It 's not unfortunate , it 's incompetent , " he declared .
Kankkunen has set an astonishing pace for a driver who has not rallied for three months .
" If you do a lot of something , sometimes it 's good to have a break .
It 's not bad for an old man ! "
said the 37-year-old veteran .
Ford had a poor morning with Spaniard Carlos Sainz losing 90 seconds through turbo trouble while Belgian Bruno Thiry dropped four minutes when a transmission shaft snapped .
MOTOR RACING - BELGIAN GRAND PRIX GRID POSITIONS .
SPA-FRANCORCHAMPS , Belgium 1996-08-24
Grid positions
for Sunday 's Belgian Grand Prix motor race after final
qualifying on Saturday :
1. Jacques Villeneuve ( Canada ) Williams 1 minute 50.574
seconds ( average speed 226.859 kph )
2. Damon Hill ( Britain ) Williams 1:50.980
3. Michael Schumacher ( Germany ) Ferrari 1:51.778
4. David Coulthard ( Britain ) McLaren 1:51.884
5. Gerhard Berger ( Austria ) Benetton 1:51.960
6. Mika Hakkinen ( Finland ) McLaren 1:52.318
7. Jean Alesi ( France ) Benetton 1:52.354
8. Martin Brundle ( Britain ) Jordan 1:52.977
9. Eddie Irvine ( Britain ) Ferrari 1:53.043
10. Rubens Barrichello ( Brazil ) Jordan 1:53.152
Add grid :
11. Heinz-Harald Frentzen ( Germany ) Sauber 1:53.199
12. Johnny Herbert ( Britain ) Sauber 1:53.993
13. Mika Salo ( Finland ) Tyrrell 1:54.095
14. Olivier Panis ( France ) Ligier 1:54.220
15. Pedro Diniz ( Brazil ) Ligier 1:54.700
16. Jos Verstappen ( Netherlands ) Arrows 1:55.150
17. Ukyo Katayama ( Japan ) Tyrrell 1:55.371
18. Ricardo Rosset ( Brazil ) Arrows 1:56.286
19. Pedro Lamy ( Portugal ) Minardi 1:56.830
Did not qualify ( times did not meet qualifying standard ) :
20. Giovanni Lavaggi ( Italy ) Minardi 1:58.579
RALLYING - BELGIAN SPECTATOR DIES IN FINNISH RALLY .
JYVASKYLA , Finland 1996-08-24
A Belgian man died and 31 people were injured after an accident in Friday 's opening phase of the world championship 1,000 Lakes Rally .
The unnamed victim died during the night , a hospital spokesman said on Saturday .
Danish driver Karsten Richardt had ploughed into the crowd during the two-kilometre first stage held in the host city of Jyvaskyla .
Richardt 's Mitsubishi skidded down an escape road and ploughed into a cordoned-off area for spectators .
A second Belgian was also seriously injured but the hospital spokesman said his life was not in danger .
The stage was suspended but the four-day rally resumed on Saturday .
A woman was killed before last year 's event when she walked in front of a car practising on the course .
TENNIS - RESULTS AT TOSHIBA CLASSIC .
CARLSBAD , California 1996-08-24
Results from the
$ 450,000 Toshiba Classic tennis tournament on Friday ( prefix
number denotes seeding ) :
Quarterfinals :
1 - Arantxa Sanchez Vicario ( Spain ) beat Katarina Studenikova
( Slovakia ) 6-3 6-3
3 - Jana Novotna ( Czech Republic ) beat Sandrine Testud ( France )
2-6 7-6 ( 7-4 ) 6-3 .
4 - Kimiko Date ( Japan ) beat 5 - Gabriela Sabatini ( Argentina )
6-4 6-1
TENNIS - RESULTS AT HAMLET CUP .
COMMACK , New York 1996-08-23
Results from the
Waldbaum Hamlet Cup tennis tournament on Friday ( prefix number
denotes seeding ) :
Quarterfinals :
Adrian Voinea ( Romania ) beat Thomas Johansson ( Sweden ) 7-6
( 7-4 ) 6-2
5 - Andrei Medvedev ( Ukraine ) beat Jonathan Stark ( U.S. ) 7-6
( 7-4 ) 4-6 6-3
Martin Damm ( Czech Republic ) beat Michael Joyce ( U.S. ) 5-7
6-2 6-3
Karol Kucera ( Slovakia ) beat 1 - Michael Chang ( U.S. ) 6-4 6-4
GOLF - THUNDERSTORMS FORCE SUSPENSION OF SECOND ROUND IN AKRON .
AKRON , Ohio 1996-08-23
Thunderstorms forced the suspension of the World Series of Golf after just five players in the 43-man field had completed the second round on Friday .
Play initially was interrupted for more than 3-1/2 hours before resuming for two hours .
But play was finally suspended for the day when the storm continued .
The 38 players are schedeled to resume their rounds on Saturday morning before the third round begins .
GOLF - SCORES AT WORLD SERIES OF GOLF .
AKRON , Ohio 1996-08-23
Scores from the $ 2.1
million NEC World Series of Golf after the second round was
suspended due to rain on Friday with 38 of the 43 players yet
to finish their rounds on the 7,149 yard , par 70 Firestone C.C
course ( players U.S. unless noted ) :
- 5 Paul Goydos through 2 holes
- 5 Billy Mayfair through 2
- 4 Greg Norman ( Australia ) through 8
- 4 Hidemichi Tanaka ( Japan ) through 3
- 3 Steve Stricker through 3
- 2 Phil Mickelson through 7
- 2 Mark Brooks through 3
- 1 Hal Sutton through 11
- 1 John Cook through 5
- 1 Tim Herron through 4
- 1 Justin Leonard through 3
0 Steve Jones through 7
0 Nick Faldo ( Britain ) through 5
0 Davis Love through 5
+1 Fred Couples through 15
+1 Fred Funk through 9
+1 Scott Hoch through 9
+1 Ernie Els ( South Africa ) through 8
+2 D.A. Weibring through 12
+2 Clarence Rose through 9
+2 Duffy Waldorf through 4
+3 Jim Furyk through 16
+3 Corey Pavin through 14
+3 Craig Stadler through 14
+3 Brad Bryant through 12
+3 Tom Lehman through 11
+3 Sven Struver ( Germany ) through 10
+3 Alexander Cejka ( Germany ) through 10
+3 Anders Forsbrand ( Sweden ) through 5
+4 Willie Wood through 17
+4 Costantino Rocca ( Italy ) through 15
+4 Stewart Ginn ( Australia ) through 13
+5 Wayne Westner ( South Africa ) 77 68
+5 Sigeki Maruyama ( Japan ) through 17
+5 Mark O'Meara through 15
+5 Loren Roberts through 9
+6 Scott McCarron 76 70
+7 Satoshi Higashi ( Japan ) through 16
+7 Paul Stankowski through 15
+8 Craig Parry ( Australia ) through 13
+9 Tom Watson 79 70
+11 Seiki Okuda ( Japan ) 81 70 ( through 18 )
+11 Steve Schneiter 77 74 ) through 18 )
RUGBY LEAGUE - EUROPEAN SUPER LEAGUE RESULTS / STANDINGS .
LONDON 1996-08-24
Results of European Super League
rugby league matches on Saturday :
Paris 14 Bradford 27
Wigan 78 Workington 4
Standings ( tabulated under played , won , drawn , lost , points
for , against , total points ) :
Wigan 22 19 1 2 902 326 39
St Helens 21 19 0 2 884 441 38
Bradford 22 17 0 5 767 409 34
Warrington 21 12 0 9 555 499 24
London 21 11 1 9 555 462 23
Sheffield 21 10 0 11 574 696 20
Halifax 21 9 1 11 603 552 19
Castleford 21 9 0 12 548 543 18
Oldham 21 8 1 12 439 656 17
Leeds 21 6 0 15 531 681 12
Paris 22 3 1 18 398 795 7
Workington 22 2 1 19 325 1021 5
CRICKET - ESSEX POISED TO STEP UP TITLE CHALLENGE .
LONDON 1996-08-24
Essex are set to step up their English county championship challenge with a fifth consecutive victory after new-ball pair Neil Williams and Mark Ilott sent Gloucestershire reeling on Saturday .
Williams seized two wickets in two deliveries and left-armer Ilott also captured two as Gloucestershire , 252 behind on first innings , slumped to 27 for four at the close on the third day of the four-day game at Colchester .
Essex , who started the current round of matches in fifth place 20 points behind leaders Derbyshire with a game in hand , could go top if they complete victory on Monday 's last day and other results favour them .
Williams thrust Essex on course for success by dispatching Matt Windows and Andrew Symonds in his second over , before Ilott removed Dominic Hewson and Tim Hancock to reduce Gloucestershire to 17 for four at one stage .
The visitors had started the day optimistically by sending back former England captain Graham Gooch when he added just six to his overnight 105 , but Essex went on to make 532 for eight before declaring .
Captain Paul Prichard plundered 88 from 73 deliveries , hitting 15 fours and one six .
Second-placed Kent were frustrated by rain which prevented any play at Cardiff , where they have reached 255 for three in their first innings against Glamorgan , while third-placed Surrey are facing an uphill task against Nottinghamshire .
Surrey slipped to 88 for four in reply to Notts ' commanding first innings of 446 for nine declared at Trent Bridge , before Alistair Brown struck a 55-ball half-century .
Brown 's 56 not out , containing eight fours and three sixes , lifted Surrey to 128 for four on a rain-curtailed day .
Fourth-placed Leicestershire had Hampshire on the ropes at Leicester before rain intervened .
Pace trio David Millns ( 2-24 ) , Gordon Parsons ( 3-20 ) and Vince Wells ( 2-19 ) had Hampshire reeling at 81 for seven in reply to the home county 's first innings of 353 .
Yorkshire rekindled their title hopes after three successive defeats by taking the upper hand against arch-rivals Lancashire at Old Trafford .
Facing Yorkshire 's 529 for eight declared , Lancashire were forced to follow on 206 behind after being bowled out for 323 , paceman Darren Gough polishing off the innings with a burst of three wickets for one run in 17 deliveries .
Lancashire then reached 210 for five at the close -- just four ahead -- after Neil Fairbrother hit 55 in 60 balls to add to his first innings of 86 .
CRICKET - ENGLAND V PAKISTAN FINAL TEST SCOREBOARD .
LONDON 1996-08-24
Scoreboard on the third day of the
third and final test between England and Pakistan at The Oval on
Saturday :
England first innings 326 ( J. Crawley 106 , G. Thorpe 54 ; Waqar
Younis 4-95 )
Pakistan first innings ( overnight 229-1 )
Saeed Anwar c Croft b Cork 176
Aamir Sohail c Cork b Croft 46
Ijaz Ahmed c Stewart b Mullally 61
Inzamam-ul-Haq c Hussain b Mullally 35
Salim Malik not out 2
Asif Mujtaba not out 1
Extras ( b-4 lb-3 nb-11 ) 18
Total ( for four wickets ) 339
Fall of wickets : 1-106 2-239 3-334 4-334
To bat : Wasim Akram , Moin Khan , Mushtaq Ahmed , Waqar Younis ,
Mohammad Akam
Bowling ( to date ) : Lewis 12-1-76-0 , Mullally 22-6-56-2 ,
Croft 29-6-64-1 , Cork 14.3-4-45-1 , Salisbury 17-0-91-0
CRICKET - ENGLISH COUNTY CHAMPIONSHIP SCORES .
LONDON 1996-08-24
Close of play scores in four-day
English County Championship cricket matches on Saturday :
Final day
At Weston-super-Mare : Match abandoned as a draw - rain .
Durham 326 ( D. Cox 95 not out , S. Campbell 69 ; G. Rose 7-73 ) .
Somerset 298-6 ( M. Lathwell 85 , R. Harden 65 ) .
Somerset 9 points ,
Durham 8 .
Third day
At Colchester : Gloucestershire 280 and 27-4 .
Essex 532-8
declared ( G. Gooch 111 , R. Irani 91 , P. Prichard 88 , D. Robinson 72 ;
M. Alleyne 4-80 ) .
At Cardiff : Kent 255-3 ( D. Fulton 64 , M. Walker 59 , C. Hooper
52 not out ) v Glamorgan .
No play - rain .
At Leicester : Leicestershire 353 ( P. Simmons 108 , P. Nixon 67 ;
S. Renshaw 4-56 , J. Bovill 4-102 ) .
Hampshire 81-7 .
At Northampton : Sussex 389 and 112 ( C. Ambrose 6-26 ) .
Northamptonshire 361 ( K. Curran 117 , D. Ripley 66 not out ) and
42-3 .
At Trent Bridge : Nottinghamshire 446-9 declared ( G. Archer
143 , M. Dowman 107 , W. Noon 57 ; B. Julian 4-104 ) .
Surrey 128-4
( A. Brown 56 not out ) .
At Worcester : Warwickshire 310 ( A. Giles 83 , T. Munton 54 not
out , W. Khan 52 ; R. Illingworth 4-54 , S. Lampitt 4-90 ) .
Worcestershire 205-9 ( K. Spiring 52 ) .
At Headingley : Yorkshire 529-8 declared ( C. White 181 ,
R. Blakey 109 not out , M. Moxon 66 , M. Vaughan 57 ) .
Lancashire 323
( N. Fairbrother 86 , M. Watkinson 64 ; D. Gough 4-53 ) and 210-5
( N. Speak 65 not out , N. Fairbrother 55 ) .
SOCCER - SCOTTISH LEAGUE RESULTS .
GLASGOW 1996-08-24
Results of Scottish league soccer
matches on Saturday :
Premier division
Hibernian 0 Dunfermline 0
Kilmarnock 1 Celtic 3
Raith 0 Motherwell 3
Rangers 1 Dundee United 0
Playing Sunday :
Aberdeen v Hearts
Division one
Airdrieonians 0 East Fife 0
Clydebank 1 Stirling 0
Dundee 2 Greenock Morton 1
Falkirk 1 Partick 0
St Mirren 0 St Johnstone 3
Division two
Berwick 0 Stenhousemuir 6
Brechin 1 Ayr 1
Hamilton 2 Clyde 0
Queen of the South 2 Dumbarton 1
Stranraer 1 Livingston 2
Division three
Alloa 1 Arbroath 1
Cowdenbeath 1 Monstrose 0
Forfar 3 Inverness 1
Ross County 1 Queen 's Park 2
Played Friday :
East Stirling 0 Albion 1
SOCCER - OUT-OF-SORTS NEWCASTLE CRASH 2-1 AT HOME .
LONDON 1996-08-24
Newcastle 's early season teething problems continued on Saturday when they lost 2-1 at home to premier league pacesetters Sheffield Wednesday .
England striker Alan Shearer gave Kevin Keegan 's talent-laden side the lead from the penalty spot after 13 minutes after Wednesday 's Yugoslav Dejan Stefanovic pulled down Colombian forward Faustino Asprilla .
But two minutes later Wednesday equalised through Peter Atherton , who found space in the penalty area to meet Mark Pembridge 's free kick with a precise glancing header .
Guy Whittingham stole three points for the Yorkshire side with a goal 10 minutes from time .
To add to Newcastle 's misery , England striker Les Ferdinand was stretchered off in the second half .
Wednesday , who escaped relegation on the final day of last season , have now won their first three games of the season .
Elsewhere , title hopefuls Liverpool were held 0-0 at home by newly-promoted Sunderland , and in London , the tie between Tottenham Hotspur and Everton also ended goaless .
Frenchman Frank LeBoeuf and Italian Gianluca Vialli scored their first premier league goals as Chelsea beat Coventry 2-0 , and managerless Arsenal won by the same scoreline at Leicester .
Last season 's league and Cup winners Manchester United host 1995 champions Blackburn on Sunday .
SOCCER - ENGLISH LEAGUE RESULTS .
LONDON 1996-08-24
Results of English league soccer
matches on Saturday :
Premier league
Aston Villa 2 Derby 0
Chelsea 2 Coventry 0
Leicester 0 Arsenal 2
Liverpool 0 Sunderland 0
Newcastle 1 Sheffield Wednesday 2
Nottingham Forest 1 Middlesbrough 1
Tottenham 0 Everton 0
West Ham 2 Southampton 1
Playing Sunday :
Manchester United v Blackburn
Playing Monday :
Leeds v Wimbledon
Division one
Bolton 3 Norwich 1
Charlton 1 West Bromwich 1
Crystal Palace 3 Oldham 1
Ipswich 5 Reading 2
Oxford 5 Southend 0
Sheffield United 4 Birmingham 4
Stoke 2 Manchester City 1
Swindon 1 Port Vale 1
Wolverhampton 1 Bradford 0
Played Friday :
Portsmouth 1 Queen 's Park Rangers 2
Tranmere 3 Grimsby 2
Playing Sunday :
Barnsley v Huddersfield
Division two
Brentford 3 Luton 2
Bristol City v Blackpool late kickoff
Burnley 2 Walsall 1
Chesterfield 1 Bury 2
Peterborough 2 Crewe 2
Preston 0 Bristol Rovers 0
Rotherham 1 Shrewsbury 2
Stockport 0 Notts County 0
Watford 0 Millwall 2
Wrexham 4 Plymouth 4
Wycombe 1 Gillingham 1
York 1 Bournemouth 2
Division three
Barnet 1 Wigan 1
Cardiff 1 Brighton 0
Carlisle 0 Hull 0
Chester 1 Cambridge 1
Darlington 4 Swansea 1
Exeter 2 Scarborough 2
Hartlepool 2 Fulham 1
Hereford 1 Doncaster 0
Lincoln 1 Leyton Orient 1
Northampton 3 Mansfield 0
Rochdale 0 Colchester 0
Scunthorpe 1 Torquay 0
Add Division two
Bristol City 0 Blackpool 1
CRICKET - PAKISTAN 318-2 V ENGLAND -- LUNCH .
LONDON 1996-08-24
Pakistan were 318 for two at lunch on the third day of the third and final test at The Oval on Saturday in reply to England 's 326 all out .
Score : England 326 ( J. Crawley 106 , G. Thorpe 54 .
Waqar Younis 4-95 ) .
Pakistan 318-2 ( Saeed Anwar 169 not out , Ijaz Ahmed 61 ) .
TENNIS - RESULTS AT CANADIAN OPEN .
TORONTO 1996-08-23
Results from the Canadian Open
tennis tournament on Friday ( prefix numbers denotes seedings ) :
Quarterfinals
3 - Wayne Ferreira ( South Africa ) beat 5 - Thomas Enqvist
( Sweden ) 7-5 6-2
4 - Marcelo Rios ( Chile ) beat Patrick Rafter ( Australia ) 0-6
7-6 ( 7-4 ) 6-1
7 - Todd Martin ( U.S. ) beat Alex O'Brien ( U.S. ) 6-4 6-4
Todd Woodbridge ( Australia ) beat Mark Philippoussis
( Australia ) 7-5 6-4
RUGBY UNION - NEW ZEALAND WIN FIRST SERIES IN SOUTH AFRICA .
PRETORIA , South Africa 1996-08-24
New Zealand made history on Saturday when they completed their first series victory in South Africa with a 33-26 victory in the second test .
The win gave the All Blacks an unbeatable 2-0 lead in the three-test series .
Each side scored three tries and the Springboks outscored the All Blacks 15-12 in the second half but still suffered a fourth successive defeat against their old enemies .
Two tries from wing Jeff Wilson in the first quarter gave New Zealand a 24-11 lead before tries from flanker Ruben Kruger and scrum-half Joost van der Westhuizen in the space of two minutes narrowed the gap to a single point at 23-24 .
The Springboks would have gone ahead had not fly-half Joel Stransky 's conversion hit an upright and New Zealand only scrambled to safety through a fine penalty from replacement fly-half Jon Preston and a drop goal by number eight Zinzan Brooke .
RUGBY UNION - NEW ZEALAND DEFEAT SOUTH AFRICA 33-26 .
PRETORIA , South Africa 1996-08-24
New Zealand beat South Africa 33-26 ( halftime 21-11 ) in the second test on Saturday .
Scorers :
South Africa - Tries : Hannes Strydom , Ruben Kruger , Joost van der Westhuizen .
Penalties : Joel Stranksy ( 3 ) .
Conversion : Stranksy .
New Zealand - Tries : Jeff Wilson ( 2 ) , Zinzan Brooke .
Penalties : Simon Culhane , Jon Preston ( 2 ) .
Conversions : Culhane ( 3 ) .
Drop goal : Zinzan Brooke .
New Zealand lead the three-test series 2-0 .
SOCCER - YUGOSLAV LEAGUE RESULTS / STANDINGS .
BELGRADE 1996-08-24
Results of Yugoslav league
soccer matches played on Saturday :
Division A
Cukaricki 0 Hajduk 2
Becej 2 Borac 0
Mladost ( L ) 0 Zemun 0
Rad 1 Buducnost ( P ) 0
Standings ( tabulated under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , against , points ) :
Becej 3 2 1 0 5 1 7
Partizan 2 2 0 0 6 2 6
Vojvodina 2 2 0 0 4 1 6
Red Star 2 2 0 0 3 1 6
Mladost ( L ) 3 1 1 1 6 4 4
Rad 3 1 1 1 2 2 4
Hajduk 3 1 0 2 3 3 3
Cukaricki 3 1 0 2 5 6 3
Buducnost 3 1 0 2 3 5 3
Zemun 3 0 2 1 2 3 2
Proleter 2 0 1 1 1 4 1
Borac 3 0 0 3 0 8 0
Division B
Sutjeska 3 Sloboda 2
Loznica 0 Obilic 1
OFK Kikinda 1 Radnicki ( N ) 0
Spartak 1 Buducnost ( V ) 2
OFK Beograd 2 Mladost ( BJ ) 2
Standings :
Obilic 3 3 0 0 8 1 9
Loznica 3 2 0 1 7 3 6
Sutjeska 3 2 0 1 6 3 6
OFK Kikinda 3 2 0 1 4 1 6
Buducnost ( V ) 3 2 0 1 4 3 6
Spartak 3 1 1 1 3 3 4
Zeleznik 2 1 0 1 4 4 3
OFK Beograd 3 0 3 1 4 4 3
Radnicki 3 1 0 2 5 6 3
Sloboda 3 0 1 2 4 8 1
Mladost ( BJ ) 3 0 1 2 2 6 1
Rudar 2 0 0 2 0 6 0
SOCCER - POLISH FIRST DIVISION RESULTS .
WARSAW 1996-08-24
Results of Polish first division
soccer matches on Saturday :
Amica Wronki 3 Hutnik Krakow 0
Sokol Tychy 5 Lech Poznan 3
Rakow Czestochowa 1 Stomil Olsztyn 4
Wisla Krakow 1 Gornik Zabrze 0
Slask Wroclaw 3 Odra Wodzislaw 1
GKS Katowice 1 Polonia Warsaw 0
Zaglebie Lubin 2 LKS Lodz 1
Legia Warsaw 3 GKS Belchatow 2
BASKETBALL - PHILIPPINE PRO-LEAGUE RESULTS .
MANILA 1996-08-24
Results of semi-final round games on Friday in the Philippine Basketball Association second conference , which includes American players :
Alaska Milk beat Purefoods Hotdogs 103-95 ( 34-48 half-time )
Ginebra San Miguel beat Shell 120-103 ( 65-56 )
BASEBALL - RESULTS OF S. KOREAN PRO-BASEBALL GAMES .
SEOUL 1996-08-24
Results of South Korean
pro-baseball games played on Friday .
Samsung 13 Hyundai 3
Haitai 5 Hanwha 4
OB 4 Lotte 2
Ssangbangwool 1 LG 0
Standings after games played on Friday ( tabulate under won ,
drawn , lost , winning percentage , games behind first place )
W D L PCT GB
Haitai 62 2 40 .606 -
Ssangbangwool 56 2 47 .543 6 1/2
Hanwha 55 1 47 .539 7
Hyundai 54 5 47 .533 7 1/2
Samsung 47 5 53 .471 14
Lotte 43 5 52 .455 15 1/2
LG 44 5 56 .443 17
OB 40 5 59 .407 20 1/2
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE STANDINGS AFTER FRIDAY 'S GAMES .
NEW YORK 1996-08-24
Major League Baseball
standings after games played on Friday ( tabulate under won ,
lost , winning percentage and games behind ) :
AMERICAN LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
NEW YORK 73 54 .575 -
BALTIMORE 67 60 .528 6
BOSTON 64 65 .496 10
TORONTO 60 69 .465 14
DETROIT 46 82 .359 27 1/2
CENTRAL DIVISION
CLEVELAND 76 52 .594 -
CHICAGO 69 61 .531 8
MINNESOTA 64 64 .500 12
MILWAUKEE 61 68 .473 15 1/2
KANSAS CITY 58 72 .446 19
WESTERN DIVISION
TEXAS 74 55 .574 -
SEATTLE 66 61 .520 7
OAKLAND 62 69 .473 13
CALIFORNIA 60 68 .469 13 1/2
SATURDAY , AUGUST 24TH SCHEDULE
SEATTLE AT BOSTON
MILWAUKEE AT CLEVELAND
CALIFORNIA AT BALTIMORE
TORONTO AT CHICAGO
OAKLAND AT NEW YORK
DETROIT AT KANSAS CITY
TEXAS AT MINNESOTA
NATIONAL LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
ATLANTA 80 47 .630 -
MONTREAL 69 58 .543 11
NEW YORK 59 70 .457 22
FLORIDA 59 70 .457 22
PHILADELPHIA 53 76 .411 28
CENTRAL DIVISION
ST LOUIS 68 60 .531 -
HOUSTON 68 61 .527 1/2
CINCINNATI 64 63 .504 3 1/2
CHICAGO 63 63 .500 4
PITTSBURGH 55 73 .430 13
WESTERN DIVISION
SAN DIEGO 70 60 .538 -
LOS ANGELES 68 60 .531 1
COLORADO 66 63 .512 3 1/2
SAN FRANCISCO 54 72 .429 14
SATURDAY , AUGUST 24TH SCHEDULE
CHICAGO AT ATLANTA
ST LOUIS AT HOUSTON
NEW YORK AT LOS ANGELES
MONTREAL AT SAN FRANCISCO
CINCINNATI AT FLORIDA
PITTSBURGH AT COLORADO
PHILADELPHIA AT SAN DIEGO
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE RESULTS FRIDAY .
NEW YORK 1996-08-24
Results of Major League
Baseball games played on Friday ( home team in CAPS ) :
American League
BOSTON 6 Seattle 4
Milwaukee 6 CLEVELAND 5 ( 11 innings )
California 2 BALTIMORE 0
NEW YORK 5 Oakland 3
Toronto 4 CHICAGO 2
Detroit 3 KANSAS CITY 2
MINNESOTA 9 Texas 2
National League
Cincinnati 6 FLORIDA 5 ( 1ST GM )
FLORIDA 8 Cincinnati 3 ( 2ND GM )
ATLANTA 4 Chicago 3
St Louis 1 HOUSTON 0
Pittsburgh 5 COLORADO 3
LOS ANGELES 7 New York 5
Philadelphia 7 SAN DIEGO 4
Montreal 10 SAN FRANCISCO 8
SOCCER - PORTUGUESE FIRST DIVISION RESULT .
LISBON 1996-08-24
Result of a Portuguese first
division soccer match on Saturday :
Belenenses 2 Boavista 4
SOCCER - DISAPPOINTING AJAX SLUMP 2-0 AT HEERENVEEN .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-24
Dutch champions Ajax Amsterdam faltered in their second league match of the season on Saturday losing 2-0 away at Heerenveen .
Ajax , who had a dismal series of pre-season results before beating NAC of Breda in their opening game , had the best of an entertaining first half but failed to break the deadlock .
Eight minutes after the interval , Heerenveen 's Romeo Wouden broke through the Amsterdam defence , left defender John Veldman standing and curled the ball beyond goalkeeper Edwin van der Sar into the Ajax net .
Ajax , without injured defenders Marcio Santos and Winston Bogarde and strikers Jari Litmanen and Marc Overmars , then stepped up the pace and looked certain to equalise .
But they left gaps at the back and on 73 minutes Danish striker Jon Dahl Tomasson rushed out of his own half , beat the Ajax defence and lobbed van der Sar .
The defeat means Ajax 's main title contenders PSV Eindhoven , who beat the champions 3-0 in the traditional league curtain-raiser , can go three points clear of their rivals if they beat Groningen on Sunday .
SOCCER - BELGIAN FIRST DIVISION RESULTS .
BRUSSELS 1996-08-24
Results of Belgian first
division matches on Saturday :
Standard Liege 3 Molenbeek 0
Anderlecht 2 Lokeren 2
Cercle Brugge 2 Mouscron 2
Antwerp 1 Lommel 4
Ghent 3 Aalst 2
Lierse 4 Charleroi 0
Sint Truiden 3 Ekeren 1
SOCCER - LEADING FRENCH LEAGUE SCORERS .
PARIS 1996-08-24
Leading goalscorers in the French
first division after Saturday 's matches :
3 - Anto Drobnjak ( Bastia ) , Xavier Gravelaine ( Marseille ) .
2 - Miladin Becanovic ( Lille ) , Enzo Scifo ( Monaco ) ,
Vladimir Smicer ( Lens ) , Christopher Wreh ( Guingamp ) .
SOCCER - FRENCH LEAGUE SUMMARIES .
PARIS 1996-08-24
Summaries of French first division
matches on Saturday :
Nantes 0 Lens 1 ( Smicer 52nd ) .
Halftime 0-0 .
Attendance 16,000 .
Nice 1 ( Debbah 39th ) Bastia 1 ( Drobnjak 82nd ) .
1-0 .
6,000 .
Lille 3 ( Boutoille 47th , Becanovic 79th pen , 82nd ) ) Rennes 1
( Guivarc'h 60th pen .
) 0-0 .
6,000 .
Bordeaux 0 Auxerre 0 .
30,000 .
Marseille 1 ( Gravelaine 24th ) Metz 2 ( Traore 65th , Bombarda
69th ) .
1-0 .
20,000 .
Strasbourg 1 ( Zitelli 80th ) Le Havre 0 .
0-0 .
15,000
Caen 1 ( Bancarel 70th ) Lyon 1 ( Caveglia 89th ) .
0-0 .
9,000 .
Guingamp 2 ( Wreh 15th , 42nd ) Monaco 1 ( Scifo 35th ) .
2-1 .
7,000 .
Montpellier 0 Cannes 1 ( Charvet 8th ) .
0-1 .
10,000 .
Played on Friday :
Nancy 0 Paris St Germain 0 .
15,000 .
SOCCER - FRENCH LEAGUE STANDINGS .
PARIS 1996-08-24
Standings in the French soccer
league after Saturday 's matches ( tabulate under played , won ,
drawn , lost , goals for , goals against , points ) :
Lens 3 3 0 0 6 1 9
Bastia 3 2 1 0 4 1 7
Paris Saint-Germain 3 2 1 0 3 0 7
Auxerre 3 2 1 0 3 0 7
Cannes 3 2 1 0 4 2 7
Lille 3 2 0 1 4 3 6
Bordeaux 3 1 2 0 2 1 5
Monaco 3 1 1 1 5 3 4
Marseille 3 1 1 1 5 4 4
Metz 3 1 1 1 3 3 4
Lyon 3 1 1 1 4 4 4
Guingamp 3 1 1 1 2 2 4
Rennes 3 1 0 2 4 6 3
Strasbourg 3 1 0 2 1 3 3
Montpellier 3 0 2 1 1 2 2
Nantes 3 0 1 2 2 5 1
Nancy 3 0 1 2 2 5 1
Nice 3 0 1 2 2 5 1
Le Havre 3 0 1 1 1 3 1
Caen 3 0 1 2 1 5 1
SOCCER - FRENCH LEAGUE RESULTS .
PARIS 1996-08-24
Results of French first division
matches on Saturday :
Nantes 0 Lens 1
Nice 1 Bastia 1
Lille 3 Rennes 1
Bordeaux 0 Auxerre 0
Marseille 1 Metz 2
Strasbourg 1 Le Havre 0
Caen 1 Lyon 1
Guingamp 2 Monaco 1
Montpellier 0 Cannes 1
Played on Friday :
Nancy 0 Paris St Germain 0
SOCCER - DUTCH FIRST DIVISION RESULTS / STANDINGS .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-24
Result of Dutch first division
soccer match played on Saturday :
Graafschap Doetinchem 3 RKC Waalwijk 2
Willem II Tilburg 0 Fortuna Sittard 1
NAC Breda 1 Sparta Rotterdam 0
Heerenveen 2 Ajax Amsterdam 0
Standings ( tabulated under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , against , points ) :
Graafschap Doetinchem 2 1 1 0 4 3 4
Fortuna Sittard 2 1 1 0 1 0 4
PSV Eindhoven 1 1 0 0 4 1 3
Twente Enschede 1 1 0 0 3 1 3
Vitesse Arnhem 1 1 0 0 2 0 3
Heerenveen 2 1 0 1 3 3 3
NAC Breda 2 1 0 1 1 1 3
Ajax Amsterdam 2 1 0 1 1 2 3
Utrecht 1 0 1 0 2 2 1
Feyenoord Rotterdam 1 0 1 0 1 1 1
Roda JC Kerkrade 1 0 1 0 1 1 1
Volendam 1 0 1 0 1 1 1
Groningen 1 0 1 0 0 0 1
RKC Waalwijk 2 0 1 1 4 5 1
Sparta Rotterdam 2 0 1 1 0 1 1
Willem II Tilburg 2 0 1 1 0 1 1
AZ Alkmaar 1 0 0 1 0 2 0
NEC Nijmegen 1 0 0 1 1 4 0
SOCCER - SUMMARIES OF GERMAN FIRST DIVISION MATCHES .
BONN 1996-08-24
Summaries of German first division
matches played on Saturday :
Bochum 1 ( Jack 66th minute ) Arminia Bielefeld 1 ( Molata 59th ) .
Halftime 0-0 .
Attendance 25,000
Borussia Moenchengladbach 1 ( Andersson 22nd ) Karlsruhe 3
( Haessler 33rd , Dundee 45th , Keller 90th ) .
1-2 .
20,000
Stuttgart 2 ( Balakow 50th , Bobic 61st ) Werder Bremen 1 ( Votava
68th ) .
0-0 .
32,000
1860 Munich 1 ( Schwabl 38th ) Borussia Dortmund 3 ( Zorc
59th-pen , Moeller 73rd , Heinrich 90th ) .
1-0 .
50,000
Bayer Leverkusen 0 Fortuna Duesseldorf 1 ( Seeliger 47th ) .
0-0 .
18,000
Freiburg 1 ( Zeyer 52nd ) Cologne 3 ( Gaissmayer 9th , Polster
86th , 90th ) .
0-1 .
22,500
SOCCER - RESULTS OF GERMAN FIRST DIVISION MATCHES .
BONN 1996-08-24
Results of German first division
soccer matches played on Saturday :
Bochum 1 Arminia Bielefeld 1
Borussia Moenchengladbach 1 Karlsruhe 3
Stuttgart 2 Werder Bremen 1
1860 Munich 1 Borussia Dortmund 3
Bayer Leverkusen 0 Fortuna Duesseldorf 1
Freiburg 1 Cologne 3
Played on Saturday :
St Pauli 4 Schalke 4
Hansa Rostock 0 Hamburg 1
Bundesliga standings after Saturday 's games ( tabulate under
played , won , drawn , lost , goals for , goals against , points ) :
Cologne 3 3 0 0 7 1 9
VfB Stuttgart 2 2 0 0 6 1 6
Borussia Dortmund 3 2 0 1 9 5 6
Hamburg 3 2 0 1 7 3 6
Bayer Leverkusen 3 2 0 1 7 4 6
VfL Bochum 3 1 2 0 3 2 5
Karlsruhe 2 1 1 0 5 3 4
Bayern Munich 2 1 1 0 3 2 4
St Pauli 3 1 1 1 7 7 4
1860 Munich 3 1 0 2 3 5 3
Freiburg 3 1 0 2 5 10 3
Fortuna Duesseldorf 3 1 0 2 1 7 3
Hansa Rostock 3 0 2 1 3 4 2
Arminia Bielefeld 3 0 2 1 2 3 2
Borussia Moenchengladbach 3 0 2 1 1 3 2
Schalke 3 0 2 1 4 8 2
Werder Bremen 3 0 1 2 4 6 1
MSV Duisburg 2 0 0 2 1 4 0
SOCCER - AUSTRIA FIRST DIVISION RESULTS / STANDINGS .
VIENNA 1996-08-24
Results of Austria first division
soccer matches played on Saturday :
Rapid Vienna 0 FC Linz 0
GAK 2 Austria Vienna 2
Admira / Wacker 0 Sturm Graz 3
Linzer ASK 1 FC Tirol Innsbruck 3
Standings ( tabulated under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , against , points ) :
FC Tirol Innsbruck 6 4 2 0 13 5 14
Austria Vienna 6 4 2 0 9 5 14
SV Salzburg 5 3 2 0 4 1 11
Sturm Graz 6 2 3 1 8 5 9
GAK 6 1 3 2 8 10 6
Rapid Wien 5 0 5 0 3 3 5
SV Ried 5 1 1 3 6 5 4
Linzer ASK 5 0 3 2 4 8 3
Admira / Wacker 6 0 3 3 5 10 3
FC Linz 6 0 2 4 1 9 2
CRICKET - RAIN BRINGS PREMATURE END TO SRI LANKA MATCH .
COLOMBO 1996-08-24
The one-day match between Sri Lanka and a World XI was abandoned on Saturday because of rain .
Scores : World XI 102-0 ( M. Waugh 39 not out , S. Tendulkar 56 not out ) off 21.4 overs v Sri Lanka .
British hostage in Chechnya describes ordeal .
LONDON 1996-08-24
A British aid worker , held hostage in Chechnya for nearly four weeks , said on Saturday a cocked Kalashnikov had been thrust into his mouth at one point during his ordeal .
Michael Penrose , a 23-year-old worker with the group Action Against Hunger , described his ordeal to a news conference when he arrived back in Britain from Moscow .
" The worst period of physical manhandling was during that time when we were beaten with Kalashnikovs and at one point I had a Kalashnikov held to the back of my throat -- cocked , " he said .
" For the first period we were held in a small room with no bed or anything .
We had very little food and sometimes went two or three days without eating . "
Gunmen seized Penrose , who comes from Swerford in southern England , Frenchman Frederic Malardeau and six other hostages from their car in Grozny , the capital of Chechnya , on July 27 .
The assailants had demanded a ransom of 300,000 pounds ( $ 465,000 ) but no money was paid by the charity when they were released on Wednesday .
The hostages were held in a house in or near Grozny which was bombarded regularly .
" During the last 15 days of being held , the fighting in Grozny was very close .
At first it was street fighting outside the house and then we came under very heavy shelling and bombardment from conventional weapons like tanks , artillery and grenade launchers , " he said .
Penrose had been working for the charity which provides food to civilians for only a few weeks before he was captured .
When asked if he would return to the mountainous region where rebels have been fighting Russian troops for full independence , Penrose said : " Not for the time being .
I do n't think it 's safe for me .
But maybe in the future , depending on the circumstances . "
Princess Diana send message to Mother Teresa .
LONDON 1996-08-24
Britain 's Princess Diana has sent a message to seriously ill Mother Teresa , the nun to whom she has turned several times for spiritual guidance .
Diana 's office said on Saturday the princess had sent a message to the Nobel Peace Prize-winning missionary as news broke this week of her battle against heart problems and malaria .
A spokeswoman declined to release details of the message .
Diana first met the Albanian-born missionary in Rome in 1992 .
She said afterwards that the meeting had fulfilled her " dearest wish " and the two women have met several times since .
The princess , who has carved out a major role for herself as a helper of the sick and needy , is said to have turned to Mother Teresa for guidance as her marriage crumbled to heir to the British throne Prince Charles .
The 85-year-old nun said in the past that she was praying for the couple , whose divorce is expected to become final next week .
Doctors caring for Mother Teresa in a Calcutta hospital said on Saturday that her fever had fallen and her malaria was under control but she remained on a respirator in intensive care .
CRICKET - PAKISTAN 339-4 V ENGLAND - close .
Saeed Anwar c Croft b Cork 176
Aamir Sohail c Cork b Croft 46
Ijaz Ahmed c Stewart b Mullally 61
Inzamam-ul-Haq c Hussain b Mullally 35
Salim Malik not out 2
Asif Mujtaba not out 1
Extras 18
Fall of wicket - 1-106 2-239 3-334 4-334
To bat - Wasim Akram , Moin Khan , Mushtaq Ahmed , Waqar Younis , Mohammad Akam
England 326 all out
Soccer - Nijmeh beat Nasr 1-0 .
TRIPOLI , Lebanon 1996-08-24
Nijmeh of Lebanon beat Nasr of Saudi Arabia 1-0 ( halftime 1-0 ) in their Asian club championship second round first leg tie on Saturday .
Scorer : Issa Alloush ( 45th minute ) .
Attendance : 10,000 .
Adventurers start Canadian wilderness race .
PEMBERTON , British Columbia 1996-08-24
About 350 adventurers from nine countries set out on Saturday to climb , raft , bike and run in a 323-mile ( 517-km ) endurance race through the Canadian wilderness .
The event , called the Eco-Challenge , is part of a growing sport known as adventure racing in which competitors test their limits for days over a perilous wilderness course .
" I 'm looking forward to this race .
I think it will be more physically challenging and we 'll have to go up against more diverse situations due to the terrain , " said Dr. Michael Stroud , a veteran Eco-Challenge participant .
The Eco-Challenge has been staged twice before -- in Utah and Maine last year -- and is modelled on similar races overseas .
The 70 teams in this year 's race will will trek glaciers , climb mountains , whitewater raft , horseback ride , canoe and mountain bike along the grueling course .
This year 's race , the route of which was keep a secret until Friday evening , is being held near Pemberton , British Columbia , about 100 miles ( 160 km ) northeast of Vancouver .
The area is filled with treacherous mountain peaks , ice fields and frigid waters .
Organisers expect about two-thirds of the participants to drop out or be disqualified before the finish .
The hardy ones are expected to complete the course in about six days , with first-place finishers receiving $ 10,000 in prize money .
In the Eco-Challenge , competitors race in teams of five which must include both men and women .
Team members must remain within 100 yards ( metres ) of each other at all times and finish together .
With racers carrying about 40 pounds ( 18 kg ) of gear on their backs , broken bones , sunstroke , dehydration and exhaustion are common .
Cholera kills 21 in southern Nigeria .
LAGOS 1996-05-28
An outbreak of cholera has killed 21 people in a week at Ubimini in oil-rich southern Nigeria , the News Agency of Nigeria reported on Saturday .
The chairman of the local council , Damian Ejiohuo , said drugs had been rushed to the area to quell the disease and the community needed a safer source of drinking water to prevent future outbreaks .
Epidemics are common in rural areas of Nigeria where piped water is not usually available .
Malawi 's ex-president Banda says he 's feeling well .
BLANTYRE 1996-08-24
Malawi 's frail former president , Kamuzu Banda , said on Saturday in a rare public interview that he was feeling well despite his advanced years .
" I feel all right and I eat everything that is put on the table .
And that means I am all right , " he told reporters invited to his home .
Banda , a vegetarian teetotaller believed to be 97 , walked unaided but supporting himself on a walking stick .
He clutched a fly whisk which for a long time symbolised his obsession with power .
His health was the subject of much recent speculation .
Malawi 's undisputed ruler for three decades , he lost power in the first all-party elections in 1994 .
He spent a year under house arrest and was tried but acquitted last year on charges of ordering the murder of four opponents in 1983 .
Zimbabwe fires striking civil servants .
Emelia Sithole
HARARE 1996-08-24
The Zimbabwean government fired thousands of workers on Saturday for defying an order to end a strike which has crippled essential services and disrupted international and domestic flights .
The Public Service Commission ( PSC ) said in a statement that the workers -- including nurses , junior doctors , mortuary attendants , customs officers and firefighters -- would be barred from entering their workplaces on Monday .
" All civil servants who did not return to work at their normal working hours , and remained working for the full working day on 23 August 1996 , have been summarily dismissed ...
with immediate effect , " it said in a statement .
Union officials from the Public Service Association ( PSA ) were unavailable for comment .
Public Service , Labour and Social Welfare Minister Florence Chitauro told state radio her ministry had already begun recruiting other people to replace the strikers , sub-contracting some of the work to private firms .
The government had been threatening to fire the workers since the strike began on Tuesday , saying it was illegal .
But the strikers ignored the threat and vowed to stay on the streets until their demands for wage rises of 30 to 60 percent were met .
The stoppage has left essential services stretched with many hospitals handling only emergency cases under senior doctors with the help of army medical personnel and the Red Cross .
It has also disrupted flights .
Some internal services were cancelled , leaving tourists at the Victoria Falls resort stranded , and flights abroad were delayed .
The PSA said 80 percent of the country 's 180,000 civil servants took part in the strike which is a rare challenge to President Robert Mugabe , who has been in power since independence from Britain in 1980 .
Opposition parties , civic organisations and private-sector unions have expressed support for the action and denounced the government 's pay rises of up to eight percent for its workers .
Civil servants earn on average Z$ 1,000 ( $ 100 ) a month .
They say their pay has not kept up at all with inflation , currently running at 22 percent .
Rwanda says Zaire expels 28 Rwandan refugees .
KIGALI 1996-08-24
Rwanda said on Saturday that Zaire had expelled 28 Rwandan Hutu refugees accused of being " trouble-makers " in camps in eastern Zaire .
Captain Firmin Gatera , spokesman for the Tutsi-dominated Rwandan army , told Reuters in Kigali that 17 of the 28 refugees handed over on Friday from the Zairean town of Goma had been soldiers in the former Hutu army which fled to Zaire in 1994 after being defeated by Tutsi forces in Rwanda 's civil war .
Zairean Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo said on Thursday in a visit to Rwanda that his country would expell all the refugees back to Rwanda but he gave no timeframe .
Zaire is home to 1.1 million Rwandan Hutu refugees who fled three months of civil war in 1994 .
Many had taken part in the genocide that year of one million people , mostly Tutsis , and refuse to go home for fear of reprisal at the hands of the new Tutsi-dominated government in Kigali .
Gatera said the refugees were handed over following a deal made at a meeting between the governor of Zaire 's north Kivu region and his counterpart in the Rwandan border town of Gisenyi .
" After a meeting between the governor of north Kivu and the prefect of Gisenyi , 28 prisoners ( refugees ) were handed over to Rwandan authorities on Friday , " Gatera said . "
Out of these 17 were former soldiers .
These people are now in Gisenyi prison , " Gatera added .
Revered skull of S. Africa king is Scottish woman 's .
JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-24
A limelight-loving South African chief was in disgrace on Saturday after a prized skull he brought home from Scotland was identified as belonging not to his sacred tribal ancestor , but to a middle-aged white woman .
A forensic scientist who examined the supposed skull of 19th century King Hintsa , a chief of President Nelson Mandela 's Xhosa tribe killed in battle by the British , said it was in fact the cranium of a European woman .
Chief Nicholas Gcaleka , dressed in animal skins and full tribal regalia , journeyed to a wintry Scotland in February on a hugely publicised quest to find Hintsa 's skull .
The witchdoctor said ancestors had appeared to him in a dream and ordered him to return the head , said to have been carried off as a colonial trophy by the officer who shot and allegedly beheaded Hintsa after a battle in 1835 .
But Gcaleka ran into trouble as soon as he returned to South Africa with a skull he found in a cottage in a lonely Highland forest near Inverness .
He said the spirit of a hurricane had guided him there .
Members of the Xhosa royal family , branding Gcaleka a charlatan , confiscated the head and sent it for tests to a forensic scientist , who examined the shape of the skull and the hole that he determined had not come , as supposed , from a bullet .
" It can be stated beyond reasonable doubt that this skull is not that of the late king , " the scientist said in a statement .
Sudan arrests opposition sewing machine smugglers .
KHARTOUM 1996-08-24
Sudanese police have arrested three people trying to smuggle sewing machines and army clothing to Sudanese opposition groups in Eritrea , an official newspaper reported on Saturday .
The government-owned al-Ingaz al-Watani said the smugglers were caught in Banat in the eastern state of Kassala , on the border with Eritrea , and had confessed they were on their way to " the so-called alliance forces which have been undertaking subversive operations on the eastern border " .
Authorities in Kassala said opposition forces based in Eritrea have been laying landmines and stealing vehicles and other goods to smuggle them across the border into Eritrea .
Sudan accuses the Eritrean authorities of providing support to Sudanese opposition elements based in Eritrea .
Eritrea cut diplomatic ties with Sudan in 1994 , accusing it of training rebels to make raids into Eritrea .
The exiled National Democratic Alliance , a Sudanese umbrella opposition group , has its headquarters in the Eritrean capital Asmara .
It uses the former Sudanese embassy .
Albanian Socialists start landmark reform congress .
TIRANA 1996-08-24
Albania 's opposition Socialist Party began a two-day congress on Saturday to discuss major jettisoning its links with almost half a century of Stalinist dictatorship in the Balkan country .
" The congress will approve new concepts that will turn the party into a Social-Democratic and electoral party , not a class and ideological one , " the Socialist Zeri i Popullit daily said in an editorial .
Jailed Socialist leader Fatos Nano made the first call for change in July , a month after the party 's chief opponents , the conservative Democrats of President Sali Berisha , almost swept the board in a disputed general election .
The Socialists , reformed heirs to the communists , pulled out of the poll saying it was a sham .
Acting Socialist leader Servet Pellumbi has said he too will urge the party to scrap the ideas of Karl Marx at the congress .
The pro-reform stance of some of the party leadership initially caused a storm and triggered the resignation last month of the party 's Secretary-General Gramoz Ruci .
More recently political commentators have reported a growing consensus , however , and a rift at the meeting looks increasingly unlikely .
Nicaraguan president to go to U.S. for medical care .
MANAGUA , Nicaragua 1996-08-23
Nicaraguan President Violeta Chamorro was due to fly to the United States on Saturday for a medical check-up to determine if surgery was needed on the lower part of her spinal column , the government said on Friday .
Chamorro has complained of lower back pain since her trip to Taiwan in May , when the pain forced her to go to Taipei University Hospital for an examination .
Chamorro , 66 , suffers from osteoporosis , a disease that weakens the bones , and has repeatedly flown to Washington for treatment by her longtime doctor , Sam Wilson .
Nepal wo n't help split Tibet , king tells China .
BEIJING 1996-08-24
King Birendra of Nepal has told China his nation will not become the tool of people who want Tibetan independence from Beijing , the official China Daily newspaper said on Saturday .
King Birendra , in Tibet at the start of a one-week unofficial visit to China , said the Nepalese government had " maintained a sharp vigilance against such intentions " , the newspaper said .
Nepal shares a long mountain border with the restive Himalayan region , where opposition to Beijing 's four-decade rule is widespread .
Chinese official media has often accused foreign forces , notably the United States , of seeking to support Tibetan independence activists .
King Birenda told Gyaicain Norbu , chairman of the Tibetan government , that Nepal would not " become a tool for others to split Tibet " , the newspaper said .
Gyaicain told the royal visitor increased cooperation between Nepal and Tibet was possible in the fields of trade , tourism , communications and sports , it said .
It gave no details .
Iran hangs two men for drug trafficking .
TEHRAN 1996-08-24
Iran has hanged two drug traffickers in the southern city of Shiraz , the evening newspaper Resalat reported on Saturday .
The two Iranian men were arrested in July with 419 kilograms ( 924 lbs ) of opium after they opened fire on police and killed a pedestrain and wounded four , the newspaper quoted a police commander as saying .
Resalat said the executions were ordered by the Islamic Revolutionary Court .
It did not say when they took place .
One of the men , who killed the pedestrian , was hanged at the site of the crime and the other was executed in Adel prison in Shiraz , the newspaper said .
Possession of 30 grammes ( just over an ounce ) of heroin or five kg ( 11 lb ) of opium is punishable by death in Iran .
More than 1,000 people have been executed in drug-related cases since the law took effect in 1989 .
Iran has an estimated one million drug addicts and is a key transit route for drugs , mostly opium , smuggled to Europe through Afghanistan and Pakistan -- the so called " Golden Crescent . "
Main Tunisian opposition party ousted from HQ .
TUNIS 1996-08-24
Tunisia 's main opposition party on Saturday announced that it had been ousted from its headquarters building by a court decision for failing to pay the rent .
Mohamed Ali Khalfallah , spokesman for the Movement of Socialist Democrats ( MDS ) said that a bailiff who was accompagnied by policemen , on Saturday ordered the party to leave the building .
" We were not allowed a delay to enable us to transfer the movement 's goods and documents , " Khalfallah added in a statement .
The building is state property .
The MDS was represented in court and admitted owing money for rent but did not give details .
MDS this year lost its president and vice-president , both of whom were tried and given jail sentences .
MDS president Mohamed Moada was sentenced last February to 11 years in jail on charges of having secret contacts with Libyan agents and receiving money from Tripoli .
Vice-president Khemais Chammari last July was sentenced to five years in prison on a charge of disclosing secrets of judicial proceedings in Moada 's affair .
To replace Moada , the MDS after the trial named Khalfallah as " coordinator " but Ismail Boulahya , the last of the MDS founding members still politically active , claimed the title of president , causing a new split within the movement .
MDS was founded in 1978 by a group led by Ahmed Mestiri , who withdrew from politics in 1992 .
Succeeding him as head of the movement , Moada , an Arab nationalist , ousted liberals led by MDS secretary-general Mustapha Ben Jaafar in 1993 .
Kurdish group says two killed in Iraqi shelling .
NICOSIA 1996-08-24
An Iraqi Kurdish guerrilla group on Saturday accused Iraqi government forces of killing two civilians in shelling in northern Iraq , the Iranian news agency IRNA reported .
IRNA said it was monitoring a report from a radio station affiliated to the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan ( PUK ) .
" Iraqi army heavily shelled the Kanie Karzhala camp , west of Arbil , on Friday ...
Two civilians were killed in the Iraqi bombing , " IRNA quoted the radio report as saying .
The PUK-run radio on Friday said Iraqi heavy artillery was pounding its positions in Kurdish-controlled northern Iraq but it gave no details of casualties .
There was no independent confirmation of the reports .
The rival Kurdistan Democratic Party ( KDP ) , which accuses Iran of supporting the PUK , said on Thursday that its forces had halted an Iranian-backed attack by thousands of PUK fighters .
The United States said in Washington on Friday that it had brokered a ceasefire to end six days of fighting between the two main Kurdish factions and persuaded them to attend U.S.-mediated peace talks next month .
The clashes , shattering a ceasefire negotiated last year by Washington , had threatened a U.S.-led peace plan to unite the Kurdish region against Iraqi President Saddam Hussein .
U.S. , British and French planes have been patrolling the skies of northern Iraq since shortly after the 1991 Gulf War to shield Iraq 's Kurds from any attack by Iraqi troops .
Iran accuses Iraq of ceasefire violations .
NICOSIA 1996-08-24
Iran has accused Iraq of violating the ceasefire ending their 1980-88 war some 32 times between the end of March and May 31 this year , the Iranian news agency IRNA reported on Saturday .
Iran 's deputy representative to the United Nations , Majid Takht Ravanchi , made the allegations in a letter to U.N. Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali on Friday , the agency said .
" The Islamic Republic of Iran has reported some 32 new cases of ceasefire violations by the Iraqi regime between March 31 and May 31 , 1996 , " it reported from New York .
It said violations included constructing observation posts , installing mortars and anti-aircraft cannons , setting up tents , penetrating Iranian territory , and firing rifle grenades towards Iranian territory .
The eight-year war between the two countries ended with a U.N.-sponsored ceasefire .
PRESS DIGEST - Iraq - Aug 24 .
BAGHDAD 1996-08-24
These are some of the leading stories in the official Iraqi press on Saturday .
Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy .
JUMHOURIYA
- Istanbul chamber of commerce urges Ankara to resume trade with Iraq .
- Offers from Arab and foreign companies to supply Iraq with goods .
- Four ships unload tonnes of Iraq-bound sugar at Jordan 's Aqaba .
- Editorial blames U.S. for latest flare-up of fighting between Kurdish rebels in northern Iraq .
- Black market booms in the shadow of state-run supermarkets .
- Parliament completes draft law on protection of river waters in Iraq .
QADISSIYA
- Iraq denounces violation of airspace by U.S. warplanes .
IRAQ
- Editorial lambasts Jalal Talabani , leader of a Kurdish rebel faction in the north , for liaising with Iran in its fight against rivals .
BABEL
- Blaming Iraq for riots in Jordan is a dirty game .
Clinton campaign busy making " news " .
Laurence McQuillan
WASHINGTON 1996-08-24
President Bill Clinton has served notice he intends to be busy " making news " -- or at least doing things that look and sound like it in a campaign year .
With Democrats gathering in Chicago to start a convention on Monday to nominate him for a second term as president , Clinton plans a steady parade of events designed to highlight his leadership and dim the glow of the just-concluded Republican conclave that gave a boost to rival Bob Dole .
After a week of carefully orchestrated events signing into law bills passed by the Republican-controlled Congress , Clinton used his Saturday radio address to the nation to proudly " announce " a development in the war on crime .
" Sixty days ago I directed the attorney general to draw up a plan for a national registry of sex offenders , " Clinton said . "
That plan has now reached my desk . "
" Today I am pleased to announce that we are following through on our commitment to keep track of these criminals , not just in a single state but wherever they go , " he said .
Actually , creation of such a registry was underway without Clinton lifting a finger .
Attorney General Janet Reno 's report -- all nine pages of it , including footnotes -- offers only the interim services of the FBI until a formal registry on sex offenders has been established .
Two months ago , Clinton announced he wanted an interim effort established .
Now , 60 days later , he had a chance to talk about it again .
It is an example of Clinton 's strategic planning as he heads into the stretch drive for the Nov. 5 presidential election .
Such things do not happen by chance in the Clinton White House , they are part of his political chess game .
In the past week Clinton signed into law an increase in the minimium wage , a bill that makes it easier for someone with a pre-existing health problem to change jobs , and sweeping changes overhauling the nation 's welfare system .
" America can look back on a week of remarkable achievement , " Clinton said , without even a passing reference to the Republican majority in the House and Senate .
" America is on the right track offering more opportunity , demanding more responsibility , building a stronger community , the sense of shared values and stronger families , " he said in striking the theme of his coming week .
According to a senior campaign official , Clinton " will be making a lot of news in the coming week -- something different each day . "
Clinton departs on Sunday on a four-day train trip through West Virginia , Kentucky , Ohio , Michigan and Indiana while fellow Democrats are gathered in Chicago .
" He 'll make news during the day ... and then at night the attention will go to the convention , " said the campaign official . "
We think it 'll work really well . "
Although officials decline to say just what each day 's " news " will be , the intent is to put a focus on Clinton himself and not just those attending the party 's convention .
Each day of the trip will have a late start , so that network television correspondents will be able to do live reports for morning programmes .
Campaign officials then hope the day 's " news " event will be showcased on evening television news shows as a lead-in for that night 's convention programme .
" We 'll be concentrating ... on supporting the president as he is on the trip and making significant public policy statements related to some of his plans for the future , " said White House Press Secretary Mike McCurry .
McCurry said that when Clinton delivers his acceptance address on Thursday night to fellow Democrats and a national television audience , he will " set out a road map " for the nation 's future -- one the president hopes guides him back to the White House for four more years .
Hurricane expected to veer north of Caribbean .
MIAMI 1996-08-24
Hurricane Edouard grew stronger on Saturday as it swirled across the Atlantic Ocean , but forecasters at the National Hurricane Center said the storm would likely swing north and miss the Caribbean .
" Edouard is getting stronger and stronger , and it already has winds of 105 mph ( 185 kph ) , " said hurricane forecaster Lixion Avila .
" But the good news is that all our computer models indicate Edouard is going to turn to the west-northwest on Sunday and miss the islands , " he added .
At 11 a.m. EDT ( 1500 GMT ) , Edouard was 1,130 miles east of the Lesser Antilles and moving west at 14 mph ( 25 kph ) .
Its exact position was latitude 14.5 north , longitude 44.2 west .
France hands suspected ETA member to Spain .
PARIS 1996-08-24
France on Saturday handed a suspected member of the Basque separatist group ETA to Spanish authorities , French Interior Ministry officials said .
Ignacio Olascoaga Mugica , who had just ended a prison sentence in France , is suspected of having taken part in several guerrilla attacks in Spain .
ETA ( Basque Homeland and Freedom ) has killed about 800 people in its campaign for an independent Basque state since the 1960s .
German troops to remain in Bosnia for 1997--Ruehe .
BONN 1996-08-24
Defence Minister Volker Ruehe said that German troops would stay on in Bosnia next year as part of an international force to ensure the establishment of peace , a newspaper reported on Saturday .
The current NATO-led peace force ( IFOR ) in Bosnia is due to return home at the end of the year .
But Ruehe told Bild am Sonntag in an interview that a " new and different mandate " for the troops would be agreed on for next year after the current mandate expires in December .
" After the ( Bosnian ) elections ( on September 14 ) the troops will start being reduced from the beginning of October from 60,000 to about 20,000 .
A completely new and different mandate will be agreed for next year , " Ruehe said .
" The defence ministers will begin negotiations for this at the beginning of September at a NATO meeting , " he told the newspaper in an interview , excerpts of which were released ahead of publication on Sunday .
" But we must avoid giving the impression this peace deployment in former Yugoslavia is being perceived in the long run as an occupation .
On the other hand we must prevent any return of war and massacres " he said .
Italian comics hope independence-joke 's on Bossi .
ORVIETO , Italy 1996-08-24
A group of Italian comics hope the joke will be on separatist leader Umberto Bossi next month when they lead the ancient Etruscan town of Orvieto in a mock split from Rome .
Orvieto mayor Stefano Cimicchi said the comics , including popular actor Roberto Benigni , would declare Orvieto " capital of Etruria " on September 15 -- the day Bossi plans a march across the north in favour of independence from Rome .
" We will then proceed with the annexation of Sardinia , Corsica and Cyprus , " Cimicchi told reporters on Saturday .
He said the city council would be " ironically present " when the comics made their proclamation on the same day Bossi has threatened to declare the birth of Padania , the name he has given to northern Italy .
Orvieto , located in Umbria between Rome and Florence , was once the capital of Etruria , an ancient federation of 12 Etruscan towns .
" We want to pop some air out of this balloon of tension that has been blown up around September 15 , " Cimicchi said .
" We want to help turn down the rhetoric in a country that borders former Yugoslavia yet in which people are still talking about secession , " he added .
Bossi has intensified his separatist rhetoric since his Northern League party 's good showing in last April 's general election , when it took 10 percent of the vote nationally .
He has recently dropped a drive for federalism , saying secession from Rome 's wasteful and centralised bureaucracy is the only solution for northerners .
Italian farmer says he mutilated four women .
VERONA , Italy 1996-08-24
An Italian farmer accused of multiple homocide has confessed to mutilating the bodies of four women after having sex with them , the Italian news agency ANSA reported on Saturday .
It quoted the lawyer of Gianfranco Stevanin as saying the 35-year-old farmer confessed on Friday to a Verona magistrate that he had killed and mutilated the women .
ANSA said Stevanin was unable to recall how he had killed the women , remembering only that he had found them " lifeless in his arms " after having sadmasochistic sex with them .
Stevanin , arrested in 1994 and jailed for three years for assaulting an Austrian prostitute , is accused of murdering five women , three of whose bodies were found near his villa outside Verona between July and December 1995 .
Two of the corpses were identified but not the third , found headless and decomposed in a sack in a nearby canal .
Lawyer Cesare dal Maso told ANSA that Stevanin confessed to beheading and dumping the body of a fourth woman in the nearby Adige river .
Dal Maso declined to comment on the alleged fifth murder , saying only that " the interrogations are not over yet " with investigators .
It said investigators believed Stevanin had suffocated them by putting plastic bags on their heads .
Stevanin was first sentenced for assault but investigators began digging in the garden of his villa after the first body was found by a passer-by .
Belgium asks how paedophile suspect eluded police .
Jeremy Lovell
BRUSSELS 1996-08-24
Belgian police searched two more houses on Saturday for bodies in a child-sex scandal of murder , kidnapping and pornography that has sent a shockwave of revulsion throughout Europe .
Recriminations built up over how the scandal 's central figure , convicted child rapist Marc Dutroux , managed to prey on children unhindered for so long .
In just over a week two young girls have been found dead , from starvation , two have been freed from a dungeon-like secret compartment and an international hunt has started for at least two others .
On Saturday investigators with dogs trained to find bodies searched one house at Ransart and one at Mont-sur-Marchienne -- both suburbs of the southern city of Charleroi .
Both houses are owned by Dutroux .
Belgian media speculated that Dutroux , charged with abduction and illegal imprisonment of children , must have had high level protection to molest youngsters .
They put forward no proof to support the speculation , but seized on a comment by chief prosecutor Michel Bourlet on Belgian television on Friday night that he would chase down everyone involved in the case " if I am allowed to " .
Bourlet said between 300 and 400 paedophile porn video tapes had been seized , some of which featured Dutroux .
Dutroux was charged a week ago after police rescued two young girls from a concrete dungeon in the basement of one of the six houses he owns in and around Charleroi .
Just a day later the national euphoria at the rescue turned to disgust as Dutroux led police to the bodies of two eight-year-old girls in another of his houses .
Julie Lejeune and Melissa Russo , had been kidnapped in June last year .
Dutroux said they starved to death nine months later .
He also admitted kidnapping two other girls , An Marchal and Eefje Lambrecks , a year ago .
The fate of the girls is unknown , but there has been speculation they were sold into prostitution in Slovakia or the Czech Republic where Dutroux was a frequent visitor .
Belgian police have visited Bratislava and will visit Prague .
Five other people have been arrested including Dutroux 's second wife Michelle Martin , charged as an accomplice .
The others have been charged with abduction and illegal imprisonment of children or are suspected of criminal association .
Dutch police are also holding a 74-year old Dutchman in connection with the disappearance of An and Eefje , although a spokesman said no direct link had yet been established .
At least part of the speculation in the Belgian media of high-level protection for Dutroux and his accomplices is based on leaked documents cataloguing a high degree of police bungling , incompetence and indifference .
Among the revelations are the fact that the gendarmerie was running a surveillance operation codenamed " Othello " against Dutroux in 1995 -- when both Julie and Melissa and An and Eefje were kidnapped .
They show that the gendarmes were aware that Dutroux was building cells in some of his houses for holding children , yet this information was either not passed on to other police forces searching for the missing girls or was overlooked when it was .
They also show that police investigating a theft visited Dutroux late last year at the house where Julie and Melissa were being held but accepted his word that the children 's cries they could hear came from neighbours .
Justice Minister Stefaan De Clerck has admitted that mistakes were made and ordered an inquiry at the same time as stressing there were no indications of a cover-up .
There is also widespread disbelief that no one appeared to question how Dutroux , an unemployed father of three with no visible means of support , managed to own six houses .
Death toll of Algeria bomb put at seven-newspaper .
PARIS 1996-08-24
An Algerian newspaper on Saturday put at seven -- two women and five children -- the death toll of a bomb blast in a market west of Algiers on Friday .
Algerian security forces said on Friday three women and two children were killed and five people wounded when a home-made bomb exploded at a market in the coastal town of Bou Haroun , 65 km ( 40 miles ) west of Algiers .
The security forces also said a man carrying an explosive device also died after it went off prematurely .
El-Watan paper said the blast killed seven -- a mother and her 25-year-old daughter , four young boys and a five-year-old girl .
Several people were also wounded , it said .
The explosion was the latest in series of bomb attacks in Algeria 's four-year-old civil strife .
The government-appointed watchdog , Human Rights National Observatory , was quoted this month by local newspapers as saying about 1,400 civilians have died in bomb attacks blamed on Moslem rebels in the past two years .
An estimated 50,000 Algerians and more than 110 foreigners have been killed in violence pitting Moslem rebels against government forces since early 1992 , when the authorities cancelled a general election in which radical Islamists had taken a commanding lead .
Malta police seize cannabis among chilli sauce .
VALLETTA 1996-08-24
Police in Malta said on Saturday they had seized 7.5 tonnes of cannabis concealed in a shipment of chilli sauce on its way from Singapore to Romania .
Police commissioner George Grech said the cannabis was found on Friday packed in 500 boxes hidden behind chilli sauce in a container that arrived at Malta Freeport a week ago .
The container was on its way to Romania via the former Yugoslavia from Singapore and was the biggest drugs haul in Malta , police said .
No street value was given for the cannabis .
Czech coach in fatal crash in Austria .
VIENNA 1996-08-24
A Czech coach crashed and burst into flames on a southern Austrian motorway early on Saturday , killing one person and injuring 15 , police said .
Austrian television said the coach , which was carrying 45 , was en route from the Czech Republic to Italy when the accident occurred near Steinberg , 200 km southwest of Vienna .
Most Spaniards back talks with Basque rebels--poll .
MADRID 1996-08-24
Most Spaniards would support government talks with the illegal Basque separatist group ETA if the rebels renounced violence permanently , a survey published in daily El Mundo on Saturday said .
While 57 percent of the population supported negotiations with ETA ( Basque Homeland and Freedom ) , 30 percent opposed it , the survey by the state-controlled Centre for Sociological Studies ( CIS ) found .
But 80 percent said ETA had shown little interest in achieving peace in the Basque country when it offered a one-week truce in July while continuing to hold prison officer Jose Antonio Ortega Lara , kidnapped in January .
The problem of terrorism had neither worsened nor improved since the conservative Popular Party ( PP ) came to power in May , according to 56 percent of those questioned , while 22 percent said it had worsened .
The survey questioned 2,496 people between July 17 and 21 and has a margin of error of plus or minus two percent .
Thirty killed as floods plunge Lahore into chaos .
ISLAMABAD 1996-08-24
At least 30 people have been killed and about 100 injured in the flood-hit Pakistani city of Lahore , newspapers reported on Saturday .
They said 461 mm ( 18 inches ) of rain had drenched the Punjab provincial capital in 36 hours , turning streets into rivers , knocking out power , water and telephone services , disrupting air and rail traffic , and sweeping away houses and cars .
Newspapers quoted witnesses as saying they had seen bodies floating in the streets .
Among the dead were five members of the religious Jamaat-i-Islami party who drowned while trying to remove books from a basement library .
They said thousands of people had been made homeless after a breach opened in the city canal , inundating residential areas .
Army troops were called in to evacuate residents of low-lying areas to higher ground .
Officials said the Ravi and Chenab rivers , which both flow through Punjab , were in high flood and emergency services backed by troops were on full alert .
Internet Startup funded to develop Java software .
MOUNTAIN VIEW , Calif. 1996-08-25
A small team of engineers from Sun Microsystems Inc. 's JavaSoft unit said Sunday they have formed a new company , dubbed Internet Startup , to build Java infrastructure software .
The fledgling company , established in a ground-floor office here over the last two weeks , has received venture financing from Bessemer Venture Partners of Menlo Park , Calif ..
David Cowan , Internet Startup founder and acting chief executive , is a general partner of Bessemer .
The startup company 's acting chairman is Jim Bidzos , the president of RSA Data Security , a unit of Security Dynamics Technologies Inc. as well as chairman of VeriSign .
Internet Startup , which opened its doors with about half a dozen initial employees , combines experience at JavaSoft , Apple Computer Inc. , and Oracle Systems .
" Java portends dramatic changes in the way we use the Internet , " said Hong Bui , vice president of engineering of the new company after serving as a senior engineer at JavaSoft .
Java is a computer programming language introduced by Sun Microsystems in mid-1995 which has immediately captured the attention of the industry for its ability to operate across virtually all computer system in a relatively secure manner .
Just last week , Sun Microsystems and the Silicon Valley venture capital giant Kleiner Perkins Caufield & Byers said they had completed financing of a $ 100 million fund managed by Kleiner Perkins to fund startups developing Java technologies .
Java has been licensed by nearly 50 organisations , ranging from Microsoft Corp. and International Business Machines Corp. to the Taiwan government .
Prasad Wagle , another former senior JavaSoft engineer who is among the founding engineers at Internet Startup , said the new company aims to build software infrastructure using Java to make networked applications ubiquitious .
One feature of the Java language is that small software programmes , known as " applets " because they are small applications , can be downloaded from the server computers at the centre of networks onto individual computers for use .
In this model , individual computer users can always gain access to the latest programmes and do not need to store more software than they are currently using on their computers at any one time , also saving costs of memory and storage .
Chris Zuleeg , a veteran of Apple and a former JavaSoft marketing manager , is vice president of marketing at Internet Startup , whose Web site is www.internetstartup.com .
Bessemer has funded numerous Internet pioneers , including PSI Net , VeriSign and Individual .
GOLF - MICKELSON WINS FOURTH TITLE OF YEAR IN AKRON .
AKRON , Ohio 1996-08-25
Phil Mickelson birdied two of the last three holes to win World Series of Golf by three strokes over Billy Mayfair on Sunday .
It was the fourth tournament title this year for Mickelson , who shot an even-par 70 , after being tied for the lead with Billy Mayfair with three holes to play .
Along with Mayfiar at 277 for the tournament were Steve Stricker , who had a 68 , and Duffy Waldorf , with a 66 .
" It was very hard to sleep last night because there was so much I could accomplish with this win , " said Mickelson , who had a three-stroke lead entering the third round . "
This was a win I wanted very , very much . "
Mickelson 's victory gave him a 10 year exemption to the PGA Tour .
The $ 378,000 first place check brings Mickelson back to the top of the money list with $ 1,574,799 won this year .
" This is a major championship golf course , and for me to perform well on this style of course is a big step up for me in my career and my performance in future majors , " he said .
Mickelson three-stroke lead was cut to two when Mayfair birdied the course 's only easy hole , the par five second hole , while Mickelson three-putted for par from 25 feet .
On the back nine Mickelson began driving erratically , and poor tee shots resulted in bogeys on the , eighth , 12th and 13th holes , bringing Mickelson back to four under par , tied with Mayfair , who had parred 14 straight holes after the birdie on no.2 .
Mickelson then set up a tap in birdie on the 16th , sending a wedge shot to 18 inches .
He had another birdie on the 17th , where he his a 6-iron to six feet .
Mayfair bogeyed the 17th , missing a five foot par putt , and dropped from solo second place to a three way tie for second .
It was the second successive year in which Mayfair has finished runner up in this tournament .
He lost to Greg Norman in sudden death last year .
The defending champion was in contention , two behind Mickelson for much of the day , until he bogeyed the 13th and 14th holes .
GOLF - SCORES AT THE WORLD SERIES OF GOLF .
AKRON , Ohio 1996-08-24
Scores after the final
round of the $ 2.1 million NEC World Series of Golf at
Firestone C.C , 7149 yards , par 70 ( players U.S. unless noted ) :
274 Phil Mickelson 70 66 68 70
277 Duffy Waldorf 70 70 71 66 , Steve Stricker 68 72 69 68 ,
Billy Mayfair 66 71 70 70
278 Greg Norman ( Australia ) 70 68 69 71
280 Alexander Cejka ( Germany ) 72 71 71 66 , Davis Love 70 74
67 69
281 John Cook 70 69 71 71
282 Corey Pavin 73 70 70 69
283 Tom Lehman 72 69 74 68 , Fred Funk 72 70 73 68 , Mark
Brooks 69 69 74 71 , Nick Faldo ( Britain ) 70 71 68 74
284 D.A. Weibring 73 69 74 68 , Tim Herron 70 67 75 72 , Mark
O'Meara 73 71 69 71 , Jim Furyk 75 69 67 73 , Justin Leonard 69
70 71 74
285 Loren Roberts 72 73 71 69 , Hal Sutton 72 69 74 70 , Fred
Couples 73 68 72 72 , Craig Stadler 73 72 67 73
286 Hidemichi Tanaka ( Japan ) 66 75 75 70 , Steve Jones 70 69
76 71 , Paul Goydos 66 75 74 71 , Ernie Els ( South Africa ) 71 71
71 73
287 Costantino Rocca ( Italy ) 74 71 75 67 , Clarence Rose 72 71
72 72 , Craig Parry ( Australia ) 73 75 67 72 , Willie Wood 75 69
69 74
288 Shigeki Maruyama ( Japan ) 75 71 70 72 , Anders Forsbrand (
Sweden ) 70 75 71 72
289 Scott Hoch 71 68 77 73
290 Tom Watson 79 70 68 73
292 Wayne Westner ( South Africa ) 77 68 73 74 , Sven Struver (
Germany ) 72 72 72 76
294 Satoshi Higashi ( Japan ) 75 72 74 73 , Scott McCarron 76 70
74 74
295 Stewart Ginn ( Australia ) 73 72 77 73
298 Steve Schneiter 77 74 76 71 , Paul Stankowski 74 75 74 75 ,
Seiki Okuda ( Japan ) 81 70 72 75
301 Brad Bryant 73 72 77 79
TENNIS - RESULTS AT HAMLET CUP .
COMMACK , New York 1996-08-24
Results at the Hamlet
Cup tennis tournament on Sunday ( prefix number denotes
seedings :
Finals , singles
5 - Andrei Medvedev ( Ukraine ) beat Martin Damm ( Czech
Republic ) 7-5 6-3
Finals , doubles
Luke Jensen and Murphy Jensen ( U.S. ) beat Alexander Volkov
( Russia ) and Handrik Dreekmann ( Germany ) 6-3 7-6 ( 7-5 )
TENNIS - RESULTS AT TOSHIBA CLASSIC .
CARLSBAD , California 1996-08-25
Results from the
$ 450,000 Toshiba Classic tennis tournament on Sunday ( prefix
number denotes seeding ) :
Finals :
4 - Kimiko Date ( Japan ) beat 1 - Arantxa Sanchez Vicario ( Spain )
3-6 6-3 6-0 .
RALLYING - LEADING POSITIONS IN 1,000 LAKES RALLY .
JYVASKLYA , Finland 1996-08-25
Leading positions on
Sunday after 23 special stages in the 1,000 Lakes Rally , sixth
round of the world championship :
1. Tommi Makinen ( Finland ) Mitsubishi Lancer three hours
eight minutes one second
2. Juha Kankkunen ( Finland ) Toyota Celica 12 seconds
behind
3. Marcus Gronholm ( Finland ) Toyota Celica 2:09
4. Jarmo Kytolehto ( Finland ) Ford Escort 2:23
5. Kenneth Eriksson ( Sweden ) Subaru Impreza 2:39
6. Carlos Sainz ( Spain ) Ford Escort 3:03
MOTOCROSS - SWEDISH 500CC GRAND PRIX RESULTS .
LANDSKRONA , Sweden 1996-08-25
Leading results in the
Swedish 500cc motocross Grand Prix on Sunday :
First race
1. Joel Smets ( Belgium ) Husaberg
2. Peter Johansson ( Sweden ) Husqvarna
3. Gert Jan Van Doorn ( Netherlands ) Honda
4. Jacky Martens ( Belgium ) Husqvarna
5. Peter Dirkx ( Belgium ) KTM
6. Danny Theybers ( Belgium ) Honda
Second race
1. Shayne King ( New Zealand ) KTM
2. Martens
3. Theybers
4. Johan Boonen ( Belgium ) Husqvarna
5. Dietmar Lalcher ( Germany ) Honda
6. Claus Manne Nielsen ( Denmark ) KTM
Overall on day :
1. Martens 30 points
2. Shayne King 28
3. Smets 27
4. Theybers 25
5. Van Doorn 24
6. Johansson 17
World championship standings ( after 11 of 12 rounds ) :
1. Shayne King 323 points
2. Smets 290
3. Johansson 236
4. Lacher 219
5. Darryll King ( New Zealand ) Honda 178
6. Van Doorn 176
MOTOCROSS - GERMAN 125CC GRAND PRIX RESULTS .
HOLZGERLINGEN , Germany 1996-08-25
Leading results in
the German 125cc motocross Grand Prix on Sunday :
First race
1. Sebastien Tortelli ( France ) Kawasaki
2. Bob Moore ( U.S. ) Yamaha
3. Luigi Seguy ( France ) TM
4. Andi Kanstinger ( Germany ) Honda
5. Nicolas Charlier ( France ) Kawasaki
6. Erik Camerlengo ( Italy ) Yamaha
Second race
1. Tortelli
2. Moore
3. Alex Belometti ( Italy ) Honda
4. Frederic Vialle ( France ) Yamaha
5. Collin Dugmore ( South Africa ) Honda
6. Camerlengo
Overall on day :
1. Tortelli 40 points
2. Moore 34
3. Seguy 24
4. Vialle 22
5. Camerlengo 20
6. Belometti 19
Final world championship standings :
1. Tortelli 432 points
2. Paul Malin ( Britain ) Yamaha 317
3. Vialle 293
4. Seguy 192
5. Michele Fanton ( Italy ) Kawasaki 160
6. Dugmore 152
MOTOR RACING - LEADING PLACINGS IN POKKA 1,000 KM RACE .
SUZUKA , Japan 1996-08-25
Leading placings in
Sunday 's Pokka 1,000 km motor race , seventh round of the
International Endurance GT championship :
1. Ray Belim ( Britain ) / James Weaver ( Britain ) / J.J.Lehto
( Finland ) Gulf McLaren FI GTR 171 laps - 6 hours 18 minutes
48.637 seconds ( average speed 158.82 kph )
2. Anders Olofsson ( Sweden ) / Luciano della Noce ( Italy ) Ennea
Ferrari F40 170 laps
3. Andy Ballace ( Britain ) / Olivier Grouillard ( France ) Harrods
McLaren FI GTR 169
4. Thomas Bscher ( Germany ) / Peter Kox ( Netherlands ) West McLaren
F1 GTR 168
5. Fabien Giroix ( France ) / Jean-Denis Deletraz ( Switzerland )
Muller McLaren F1 GTR 167
6. Lindsay Owen-Jones ( Britain ) / Pierre-Henri Raphanel
( France ) / David Brabham ( Australia ) Gulf McLaren F !
GTR
7. Jean-Marc Gounon ( France ) / Eric Bernard ( France ) / Paul
Belmondo ( France ) Ennea Ferrari F40 167
8. Bruno Eichmann ( Germany ) / Gerd Ruch ( Germany ) / Ralf Kelleners
( Germany ) GT2 Roock Porsche 911 164
9. Stephane Ortelli ( France ) / Bob Wollek ( France ) / Franz Konrad
( Austria ) GT2 Konrad Porsche 911 164
10. Cor Euser ( Netherlands ) / H. Wada ( Japan ) / N. Furuya ( Japan ) GT2
Marcos LM600 162
Fastest lap : Gounon , 2 minutes 03.684 seconds ( 170.680 kph )
Championship standings after seven rounds :
1. Belim , Weaver 156 points
2. Eichmann , Ruch 116
3. Bscher 112
4. Gounon , Bernard , Belmondo 98
5. Olofsson , della Noce 93
6. Owen-Jones , Raphanel 82
ATHLETICS - LEADING RESULTS AT SHEFFIELD INTERNATIONAL MEETING .
SHEFFIELD , England 1996-08-25
Leading results at an
international meeting on Sunday :
Women 's triple jump
1. Sarka Kasparkova ( Czech Republic ) 14.84 metres
2. Ashia Hansen ( Britain ) 14.78
3. Rodica Matescu ( Romania ) 14.18
Women 's 400 metres hurdles
1. Deon Hemmings ( Jamaica ) 55.13 seconds
2. Anne Marken ( Belgium ) 55.90
3. Susan Smith ( Ireland ) 56.00
Women 's javelin
1. Isel Lopez ( Cuba ) 61.36
2. Louise McPaul ( Australia ) 60.66
3. Silke Renk ( Germany ) 60.66
Women 's 200 metres
1. Cathy Freeman ( Australia ) 22.53
2. Falilat Ogunkoya ( Nigeria ) 22.58
3. Juliet Cuthbert ( Jamaica ) 22.77
100 metres hurdles
1. Dionne Rose ( Jamaica ) 12.83
2. Michelle Freeman ( Jamaica ) 12.91
3. Gillian Russell ( Jamaica ) 12.95
Women 's 800 metres
1. Charmaine Crooks ( Canada ) two minutes 00.42 seconds
2. Inez Turner ( Jamaica ) 2:01.98
3. Margaret Crowley ( Australia ) 2:02.40
Men 's pole vault
1. Trond Bathel ( Norway ) 5.60
2. Pat Manson ( U.S. ) 5.60
3. Tim Lobinger ( Germany ) 5.50
Men 's javelin
1. Tom Pukstys ( U.S. ) 86.82
2. Steve Backley ( Britain ) 82.20
3. Nick Nieland ( Britain ) 81.12
Women 's 400 metres
1. Marcel Malone ( U.S. ) 51.50
2. Kim Graham ( U.S. ) 52.17
3. Phylis Smith ( Britain ) 52.53
Men 's 200 metres
1. Jeff Williams ( U.S. ) 20.45
2. Doug Turner ( Britain ) 20.48
3. John Regis ( Britain ) 20.63
Men 's high jump
1. Charles Austin ( U.S. ) 2.30
2. Tim Forsyth ( Australia ) 2.30
3. Patrik Sjoberg ( Sweden ) 2.25
Men 's 800 metres
1. Verbjorn Rodal ( Norway ) 1:44.93
2. Benson Koech ( Kenya ) 1:45.96
3. Vincent Malakwen ( Kenya ) 1:46.18
Men 's mile
1. William Tanui ( Kenya ) 3:54.57
2. John Mayock ( Britain ) 3:54.60
3. Tony Whiteman ( Britain ) 3:54.87
Men 's 400 metres
1. Roger Black ( Britain ) 45.05
2. Mark Richardson ( Britain ) 45.38
3. Derek Mills ( U.S. ) 45.48
Men 's 100 metres
1. Osmond Ezinwa ( Nigeria ) 10.06
2. Ian Mackie ( Britain ) 10.17
3. Linford Christie ( Britain ) 10.19
MOTOR RACING - BELGIAN GRAND PRIX RESULT .
SPA-FRANCORCHAMPS , Belgium 1996-08-25
Result of
Sunday 's Belgian Grand Prix motor race :
1. Michael Schumacher ( Germany ) Ferrari 1 hour 28 minutes
15.125 seconds ( average speed 208.442 kph )
2. Jacques Villeneuve ( Canada ) Williams 5.602 seconds
behind
3. Mika Hakkinen ( Finland ) McLaren 15.710
4. Jean Alesi ( France ) Benetton 19.125
5. Damon Hill ( Britain ) Williams 29.179
6. Gerhard Berger ( Austria ) Benetton 29.896
7. Mika Salo ( Finland ) Tyrrell 1:00.754
8. Ukyo Katayama ( Japan ) Tyrrell 1:40.227
9. Ricardo Rosset ( Brazil ) Arrows one lap
10. Pedro Lamy ( Portugal ) Minardi one lap
Did not finish :
11. David Coulthard ( Britain ) McLaren 37 laps completed
12. Martin Brundle ( Britain ) Jordan 34
13. Eddie Irvine ( Britain ) Ferrari 29
14. Rubens Barrichello ( Brazil ) Jordan 29
15. Pedro Diniz ( Brazil ) Ligier 22
16. Jos Verstappen ( Netherland ) Arrows 11
Did not start ( failed to complete one lap ) :
Olivier Panis ( France ) Ligier
Johnny Herbert ( Britain ) Sauber
Heinz-Harald Frentzen ( Germany ) Sauber
Fastest lap : Berger 1:53.067 ( 221.857 kph )
MOTOR RACING - SCHUMACHER WINS BELGIAN GRAND PRIX .
SPA-FRANCOCHAMPS 1996-08-25
Michael Schumacher of
Germany , driving a Ferrari , won the Belgian Grand Prix motor
race on Sunday .
Canada 's Jacques Villeneuve finished second in his Williams
and Mika Hakkinen of Finland was third in a McLaren .
Frenchman Jean Alesi came fourth in his Benetton with
Britain 's Damon Hill fifth in a Williams and Gerhard Berger of
Austria sixth in the other Benetton .
World drivers ' championship standings ( after 13 rounds ) :
1. Damon Hill ( Britain ) 81 points
2. Jacques Villeneuve ( Canada ) 68
3. Michael Schumacher ( Germany ) 39
4. Jean Alesi ( France ) 38
5. Mika Hakkinen ( Finland ) 23
6. David Coulthard ( Britain ) 18
7. Gerhard Berger ( Austria ) 17
8. Olivier Panis ( France ) 13
9. Rubens Barrichello ( Brazil ) 12
10. Eddie Irvine ( Britain ) 9
11. Heinz-Harald Frentzen ( Germany ) 6
12. Mika Salo ( Finland ) 5
13. Johnny Herbert ( Britain ) 4
14. Martin Brundle ( Britain ) 3
15 equal .
Jos Verstappen ( Netherlands ) 1
Pedro Diniz ( Brazil ) 1
Constructors ' championship :
1. Williams 149 points
2. Benetton 55
3. Ferrari 48
4. McLaren 41
5. Jordan 15
6. Ligier 14
7. Sauber 10
8. Tyrrell 5
9. Footwork 1
RALLYING - LEADING POSITIONS IN 1,000 LAKES RALLY .
JYVASKYLA , Finland 1996-08-25
Leading positions
after six of Sunday 's 12 special stages in the 1,000 Lakes
Rally , sixth round of the world championship :
1. Juha Kankkunen ( Finland ) Toyota Celica 2 hours 30 minutes
52 seconds
3. Tommi Makinen ( Finland ) Mitsubishi Lancer 8 seconds
behind
2. Marcus Gronholm ( Finland ) Toyota Celica 1:46
4. Jarmo Kytolehto ( Finland ) Ford Escort 1:56
5. Kenneth Eriksson ( Sweden ) Subaru Impreza 2:05
6. Thomas Radstrom ( Sweden ) Toyota Celica 2:23
MOTORCYCLING - WORLD SUPERBIKE CHAMPIONSHIP RESULTS .
SUGO , Japan 1996-08-25
Leading results from round
nine of the superbike world championship on Sunday :
First race
1. Yuuchi Takeda ( Japan ) Honda 38 minutes 30.054 seconds
2. Noriyuki Haga ( Japan ) Yamaha 38:30.140
3. Wataru Yoshikawa ( Japan ) Yamaha 38:32.353
4. Troy Corser ( Australia ) Ducati 38:34.436
5. John Kocinski ( U.S. ) Ducati 38:36.306
6. Aaron Slight ( New Zealand ) Honda 38:41.756
7. Norihiko Fujiwara ( Japan ) Yamaha 38:43.253
8. Carl Fogarty ( Britain ) Honda 38:49.595
9. Akira Ryo ( Japan ) Kawasaki 38:50.269
10. Shiya Takeishi ( Japan ) Kawasaki 38:52.271
Fastest lap : Haga 147.159 kph .
Second race
1. Takuma Aoki ( Japan ) Honda 38:18.759
2. Kocinski 38:19.313
3. Haga 38:32.040
4. Slight 38:32.149
5. Fogarty 38:32.719
6. Fujiwara 38:33.595
7. Ryo 38:34.682
8. Takeishi 38:34.999
9. Yoshikawa 38:35.297
10. Corser 38:42.015
Fastest lap : Aoki 147.786 kph
World championship standings ( after nine rounds ) :
1. Slight 280 points
2. Corser 269
3. Kocinski 254
4. Fogarty 236
5. Colin Edwards ( U.S. ) Yamaha 176
6. Pier Francesco Chili ( Italy ) Ducati 175
7. Simon Crafar ( New Zealand ) Kawasaki 132
8. Anthony Gobert ( Australia ) Kawasaki 117
9. Yoshikawa 107
10. Neil Hodgson ( Britain ) Ducati 82
Revised placings for second race after the disqualification
of Japanese rider Noriyuki Haga for using an illegal carburettor
part :
1. Takuma Aoki ( Japan ) Honda 38:18.759
2. Kocinski 38:19.313
3. Slight 38:32.149
4. Fogarty 38:32.719
5. Fujiwara 38:33.595
6. Ryo 38:34.682
7. Takeishi 38:34.999
8. Yoshikawa 38:35.297
9. Corser 38:42.015
10. Keiichi Kitigawa ( Japan ) Suzuki 38:42.333
Fastest lap : Aoki 147.786 kph
Revised world championship standings ( after nine rounds ) :
1. Slight 283 points
2. Corser 270
3. Kocinski 254
4. Fogarty 238
5. Colin Edwards ( U.S. ) Yamaha 176
6. Pier Francesco Chili ( Italy ) Ducati 175
7. Simon Crafar ( New Zealand ) Kawasaki 133
8. Anthony Gobert ( Australia ) Kawasaki 117
9. Yoshikawa 108
10. Neil Hodgson ( Britain ) Ducati 82
MOTORCYCLING - JAPANESE WIN BOTH ROUND NINE SUPERBIKE RACES .
SUGO , Japan 1996-08-25
Teenager Yuuichi Takeda , racing in only his first season , outclassed the big names to win the first race in round nine of the world superbike championship on Sunday .
Takeda , 18 , showed poise far beyond his years to overtake Australian Ducati rider Troy Corser , last year 's championship runner-up , with four of the 25 laps left .
Honda 's Takeda was pursued past Corser by the Yamaha duo of Noriyuki Haga and Wataru Yoshikawa with Haga briefly taking the lead in the final chicane on the last lap .
But Takeda found one more spurt of power to just take the flag first with Haga second and Yoshikawa third .
Haga had the consolation of recording the fastest lap at 147.159 kph .
Corser , who crashed during practice on Friday , limped in fourth , four seconds behind Takeda with championship leader Aaron Slight of New Zealand 11 seconds behind the winner .
In the second race , Takeda again challenged strongly until the fifth lap from the end when he crashed while running second to eventual race winner Takuma Aoki .
Aoki , the elder brother of reigning 125cc world champion Haruchika , had a race-long duel with John Kocinski of the United States on a Ducati before taking the chequered flag .
Kocinski led for the early laps before he was passed first by Aoki , who recorded the fastest lap of 147.786 kph , and then by Takeda .
With Takeda out of the race , Kocinski regained second place but he could not overtake Aoki .
Haga again was the unlucky rider finishing third ahead of Slight with Corser in 10th place .
But the strong showing by the Japanese riders did not alter the championship table with Slight still leading on 280 points , followed by Corser with 269 and Kocinski with 254 .
RUGBY LEAGUE - EUROPEAN SUPER LEAGUE RESULTS / STANDINGS .
LONDON 1996-08-25
Results of European Super League
rugby league matches on Sunday :
Halifax 64 Leeds 24
London 56 Castleford 0
Standings :
Wigan 22 19 1 2 902 326 39
St Helens 21 19 0 2 884 441 38
Bradford 22 17 0 5 767 409 34
London 22 12 1 9 611 462 25
Warrington 21 12 0 9 555 499 24
Halifax 22 10 1 11 667 576 21
Sheffield 22 10 0 12 599 730 20
Oldham 22 9 1 12 473 681 19
Castleford 22 9 0 13 548 599 18
Leeds 22 6 0 16 555 745 12
Paris 22 3 1 18 398 795 7
Workington 22 2 1 19 325 1021 5
CRICKET - POLLOCK CONCLUDES WARWICKSHIRE CAREER WITH FLOURISH .
LONDON 1996-08-25
South African fast bowler Shaun Pollock concluded his Warwickshire career with a flourish on Sunday by taking the final three wickets during the county 's Sunday league victory over Worcestershire .
Pollock , who returns home on Tuesday for an ankle operation , took the last three wickets in nine balls as Worcestershire were dismissed for 154 .
After an hour 's interruption for rain , Warwickshire then reached an adjusted target of 109 with 13 balls to spare and record their fifth win in the last six games .
Warwickshire are currently in fourth position behind Yorkshire , Nottinghamshire and Surrey .
Yorkshire captain David Byas completed his third Sunday league century as his side swept clear at the top of the table , reaching a career best 111 not out against Lancashire .
Lancashire 's total of 205 for eight from 40 overs looked reasonable before Byas put their attack to the sword , collecting his runs from just 100 balls with three sixes and nine fours .
Yorkshire eventually reached their target with only four wickets down and 7.5 overs to spare .
SOCCER - HINCHCLIFFE CALLED INTO ENGLAND SQUAD .
LONDON 1996-08-25
England manager Glenn Hoddle called up uncapped Everton defender Andy Hinchcliffe on Sunday to the national squad for the opening World Cup qualifier against Moldova next weekend .
Left-back Hinchcliffe , 27 , replaces Tottenham 's Darren Anderton who has a recurring groin problem .
CRICKET - ENGLAND 326 AND 74-0 ; PAKISTAN 521-8 DECLARED .
LONDON 1996-08-25
England were 74 for no wicket in
their second innings at the close of the fourth day of the third
and final test at The Oval on Sunday .
Scores : England 326 and 74-0 ; Pakistan 521-8 declared .
SOCCER - ENGLISH PREMIER LEAGUE SUMMARY .
LONDON 1996-08-25
Summary of an English premier
league soccer match on Sunday :
Manchester United 2 ( Cruyff 39th minute , Solskjaer 70th )
Blackburn 2 ( Warhurst 34th , Bohinen 51st ) .
Halftime 1-1 .
Attendance 54,178 .
SOCCER - ENGLISH LEAGUE RESULTS / STANDINGS .
LONDON 1996-08-25
Results of English league soccer
matches on Sunday :
Premier league
Manchester United 2 Blackburn 2
Standings ( ( tabulated under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , against , points ) :
Sheffield Wednesday 3 3 0 0 6 2 9
Chelsea 3 2 1 0 3 0 7
Arsenal 3 2 0 1 4 2 6
Aston Villa 3 2 0 1 4 2 6
Manchester United 3 1 2 0 7 4 5
Sunderland 3 1 2 0 4 1 5
Liverpool 3 1 2 0 5 3 5
Everton 3 1 2 0 4 2 5
Tottenham 3 1 2 0 3 1 5
Nottingham Forest 3 1 1 1 5 5 4
West Ham 3 1 1 1 3 4 4
Leicester 3 1 1 1 2 3 4
Newcastle 3 1 0 2 3 4 3
Middlesbrough 3 0 2 1 4 5 2
Derby 3 0 2 1 4 6 2
Leeds 2 0 1 1 3 5 1
Southampton 3 0 1 2 2 4 1
Blackburn 3 0 1 2 2 5 1
Coventry 3 0 1 2 1 6 1
Wimbledon 2 0 0 2 0 5 0
Division one
Barnsley 3 Huddersfield 1
Standings :
Bolton 3 2 1 0 5 2 7
Barnsley 2 2 0 0 5 2 6
Wolverhampton 2 2 0 0 4 1 6
Queens Park Rangers 2 2 0 0 4 2 6
Stoke 2 2 0 0 4 2 6
Birmingham 2 1 1 0 5 4 4
Tranmere 2 1 1 0 4 3 4
Oxford 2 1 0 1 6 2 3
Ipswich 2 1 0 1 5 3 3
Bradford 2 1 0 1 3 2 3
Crystal Palace 2 1 0 1 3 2 3
Huddersfield 2 1 0 1 3 3 3
Norwich 2 1 0 1 3 3 3
Reading 2 1 0 1 3 5 3
Manchester City 3 1 0 2 2 3 3
Port Vale 2 0 2 0 2 2 2
Sheffield United 2 0 1 1 4 5 1
West Bromwich 2 0 1 1 2 3 1
Charlton 2 0 1 1 1 3 1
Swindon 2 0 1 1 1 3 1
Southend 2 0 1 1 1 6 1
Grimsby 2 0 0 2 3 6 0
Oldham 2 0 0 2 2 5 0
Portsmouth 2 0 0 2 2 5 0
CRICKET - ENGLAND V PAKISTAN FINAL TEST SCOREBOARD .
LONDON 1996-08-25
Scoreboard on the fourth day of
the third and final test between England and Pakistan at The
Oval on Sunday :
England first innings 326 ( J. Crawley 106 , G. Thorpe 54 ; Waqar
Younis 4-95 )
Pakistan first innings ( overnight 339-4 )
Saeed Anwar c Croft b Cork 176
Aamir Sohail c Cork b Croft 46
Ijaz Ahmed c Stewart b Mullally 61
Inzamam-ul-Haq c Hussain b Mullally 35
Salim Malik not out 100
Asif Mujtaba run out 13
Wasim Akram st Stewart b Croft 40
Moin Khan b Salisbury 23
Mushtaq Ahmed c Crawley b Mullally 2
Waqar Younis not out 0
Extras ( b-4 lb-5 nb-16 ) 25
Total ( for eight wickets , declared ) 521
Fall of wickets : 1-106 2-239 3-334 4-334 5-365 6-440 7-502
8-519
Did not bat : Mohammad Akam
Bowling : Lewis 23-3-112-0 , Mullally 37.1-7-97-3 , Croft
47-10-116-2 , Cork 23-5-71-1 , Salisbury 29-3-116-1
England second innings
M. Atherton not out 26
A. Stewart not out 40
Extras ( nb-8 ) 8
Total ( for no wicket ) 74
Bowling ( to date ) : Wasim Akram 7-0-35-0 , Waqar Younis
7-1-24-0 , Mushtaq Ahmed 7-2-11-0 , Aamir Sohail 2-1-4-0
CRICKET - PAKISTAN DECLARE FIRST INNINGS AT 521-8 .
LONDON 1996-08-25
Pakistan declared their first
innings at 521-8 on the fourth day of the third and final test
against England at The Oval on Sunday .
Scores : England 326 ; Pakistan 521-8 .
SOCCER - SCOTTISH PREMIER DIVISION RESULT / STANDINGS .
GLASGOW 1996-08-25
Result of a Scottish premier
division soccer match on Sunday :
Aberdeen 4 Hearts 0
Standings ( tabulated under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , against , points ) :
Rangers 3 3 0 0 7 2 9
Celtic 3 2 1 0 9 4 7
Aberdeen 3 1 2 0 8 4 5
Motherwell 3 1 2 0 6 3 5
Hibernian 3 1 1 1 2 2 4
Hearts 2 1 0 1 3 6 3
Kilmarnock 3 1 0 2 5 7 3
Dundee United 3 0 1 2 1 3 1
Dunfermline 2 0 1 1 2 5 1
Raith 3 0 0 3 1 8 0
CRICKET - PAKISTAN 473-6 AT TEA ON FOURTH DAY THIRD TEST .
LONDON 1996-08-25
Pakistan were 473-6 at tea on the fourth day of the third and final test at The Oval on Sunday in reply to England 's 326 .
Scores : England 326 ; Pakistan 473-6 .
CRICKET - RUN-OUT GIVES LEWIS AND ENGLAND SLIM SATISFACTION .
LONDON 1996-08-25
Chris Lewis did his best to forget his controversial omission from the England one-day squad on Sunday but could not prevent Pakistan reasserting their dominance in the final test at The Oval .
A super piece of fielding by Lewis , dropped as a disciplinary measure after arriving only 35 minutes before the start on the fourth morning , provided the only bright spot for England as the touring team batted on to reach 413 for five at the interval , a lead of 87 .
The solitary wicket to fall was Asif Mujtaba , run out for 13 attempting a second run to third man where Lewis was lurking with a point to prove .
There seemed scant danger until the Surrey player swooped on to the ball and returned off balance to county team mate Alec Stewart who whipped off the bails .
Lewis , though , could not make similar waves with the ball as Salim Malik and Wasim Akram batted through the rest of the session with few alarms .
Wasim rattled along to 30 not out , outscoring his partner who was unbeaten on 24 at the break , although the weather was again threatening to play the dominant role .
Rain arrived just as the players left the field for lunch , forcing the ground-staff into action yet again .
The weather delayed the resumption for over an hour , the umpires finally announcing play would start again at 1445 local time ( 1345 GMT ) .
CRICKET - ENGLAND NAME SQUAD FOR ONE-DAY INTERNATIONALS .
LONDON 1996-08-25
The England cricket squad was announced on Sunday for the one-day international series against Pakistan starting on Thursday .
Squad : Michael Atherton ( captain ) , Alec Stewart , Graham Thorpe , Nick Knight , Graham Lloyd , Matthew Maynard , Ronnie Irani , Adam Hollioake , Robert Croft , Darren Gough , Peter Martin , Dean Headley , Alan Mullally .
TENNIS - RESULTS AT CANADIAN OPEN .
TORONTO 1996-08-25
Results from the Canadian Open
tennis tournament on Sunday ( prefix number denotes seeding ) :
Final
3 - Wayne Ferreira ( South Africa ) beat Todd Woodbridge
( Australia ) 6-2 6-4
TENNIS - RESULTS AT CANADIAN OPEN .
TORONTO 1996-08-24
Results from the Canadian Open
tennis tournament on Saturday ( prefix numbers denotes
seedings ) :
Semifinals
3 - Wayne Ferreira ( South Africa ) beat 7 - Todd Martin ( U.S. )
4-6 6-3 7-5
Todd Woodbridge ( Australia ) beat 4 - Marcelo Rios ( Chile ) 6-0
6-3
SOCCER - TOGO BEAT CONGO 1-0 IN AFRICA NATIONS CUP QUALIFIER .
LOME 1996-08-25
Togo beat Congo 1-0 ( halftime 0-0 )
in their African Nations Cup preliminary round , second leg
qualifying match on Sunday .
Scorer : Salou Bachirou ( 53rd minute )
Attendance : 18,000
Togo win 1-0 on aggregate .
SOCCER - ETHIOPIA BEAT UGANDA ON PENALTIES IN AFRICAN NATIONS CUP .
ADDIS ABABA 1996-08-25
Ethiopia and Uganda drew 1-1
( halftime 1-0 ) in their African Nations Cup preliminary round ,
second leg match on Sunday .
Attendance : 25,000
Aggregate 2-2 .
Ethiopia won 4-2 penalties .
SOCCER - YUGOSLAV LEAGUE RESULTS .
BELGRADE 1996-08-25
Results of Yugoslav league
soccer matches played on Sunday :
Division A
Vojvodina 1 Partizan 1
Crvena zvezda 3 Proleter 1
Division B
Zelesnik 0 Rudar 1
SOCCER - LEADING GOALSCORERS IN POLISH FIRST DIVISION .
WARSAW 1996-08-25
Leading goalscorers in the Polish
first division after the weekend 's matches :
7 - Bogdan Prusek ( Sokol Tychy )
5 - Slawomir Wojciechowski ( GKS Katowice )
4 - Jacek Dembinski ( Widzew Lodz ) , Marcin Mieciel
( Legia Warsaw ) , Ryszard Wieczorek ( Odra Wodzislaw )
3 - Jacek Berensztain ( GKS Belchatow ) , Marek Citko ( Widzew ) ,
Adam Fedoruk , Dariusz Jackiewicz ( both Amica Wronki ) ,
Bartlomiej Jamroz ( Hutnik Krakow ) , Tomasz Moskal
( Slask Wroclaw ) , Krzysztof Piskula ( Lech Poznan ) , Mariusz
Srutwa ( Ruch Chorzow ) , Emmanuel Tetteh ( Polonia Warszawa ) ,
Krzysztof Zagorski ( Odra )
SOCCER - ROMANIAN FIRST DIVISION RESULTS / STANDINGS .
BUCHAREST 1996-08-25
Results of first division
soccer matches played over the weekend :
A.S. Bacau 1 Ceahlaul Piatra Neamt 1
Otelul Galati 1 F.C. Arges Dacia Pitesti 0
F.C. Farul Constanta 3 Chindia Tirgoviste 1
Sportul Studentesc 4 Universitatea Craiova 2
F.C. Petrolul Ploiesti 4 Politehnica Timisoara 5
F.C. Brasov 1 F.C. National Bucharest 1
Jiul Petrosani 1 Dinamo Bucharest 0
Gloria Bistrita 0 Universitatea Cluj 1
Rapid Bucharest 0 Steaua Bucharest 2
Standings ( tabulate under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , against , points ) :
Dinamo Bucharest 4 3 0 1 6 2 9
Jiul Petrosani 4 3 0 1 6 4 9
F.C. Farul Constanta 4 2 2 0 6 2 8
Universitatea Cluj 4 2 2 0 6 4 8
A.S. Bacau 4 2 1 1 7 3 7
Politehnica Timisoara 4 2 1 1 11 9 7
F.C. National Bucharest 4 2 1 1 7 6 7
Otelul Galati 4 2 0 2 4 3 6
F.C. Chindia Tirgoviste 4 2 0 2 3 4 6
Steaua Bucharest 4 2 0 2 5 7 6
F.C. Arges Dacia Pitesti 4 1 2 1 4 2 5
Universitatea Craiova 4 1 1 2 8 6 4
Sportul Studentesc 4 1 1 2 7 9 4
Ceahlaul Piatra Neamt 4 1 1 2 2 4 4
F.C. Brasov 4 1 1 2 6 10 4
Gloria Bistrita 4 1 0 3 3 9 3
F.C. Petrolul Ploiesti 4 0 2 2 5 7 2
Rapid Bucharest 4 0 1 3 4 9 1
SOCCER - POLISH FIRST DIVISION RESULTS / STANDINGS .
WARSAW 1996-08-25
Results of Polish first division
soccer matches played over the weekend :
Amica Wronki 3 Hutnik Krakow 0
Sokol Tychy 5 Lech Poznan 3
Rakow Czestochowa 1 Stomil Olsztyn 4
Wisla Krakow 1 Gornik Zabrze 0
Slask Wroclaw 3 Odra Wodzislaw 1
GKS Katowice 1 Polonia Warsaw 0
Zaglebie Lubin 2 LKS Lodz 1
Legia Warsaw 3 GKS Belchatow 2
Widzew Lodz 3 Ruch Chorzow 0
Standings ( tabulate under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , against , points ) :
Amica Wronki 7 5 1 1 13 8 16
Legia Warsaw 7 5 1 1 13 7 16
Lech Poznan 7 5 0 2 12 9 15
Widzew Lodz 7 4 2 1 13 3 14
GKS Katowice 7 4 2 1 12 9 14
Sokol Tychy 7 4 0 3 14 15 12
Odra Wodzislaw 7 3 1 3 13 10 10
Slask Wroclaw 7 3 1 3 8 7 10
Polonia Warsaw 7 3 1 3 7 9 10
GKS Belchatow 7 3 0 4 9 9 9
Stomil Olsztyn 7 2 3 2 9 9 9
Wisla Krakow 7 2 3 2 3 4 9
Hutnik Krakow 7 3 0 4 8 10 9
Rakow Czestochowa 7 2 1 4 6 10 7
Zaglebie Lubin 7 1 3 3 10 12 6
Ruch Chorzow 7 1 2 4 7 13 5
Gornik Zabrze 7 1 1 5 6 10 4
LKS Lodz 7 0 2 5 4 13 2
SOCCER - RUSSIAN PREMIER DIVISION RESULTS / STANDINGS .
MOSCOW 1996-08-25
Results of Russian premier league
matches played on Saturday :
Alaniya Vladikavkaz 3 Zhemchuzhina Sochi 1
Baltika Kaliningrad 2 Zenit St Petersburg 0
Chernomorets Novorossiisk 2 Rostselmash Rostov 1
Lokomotiv Moscow 2 Torpedo Moscow 1
Rotor Volgograd 0 Dynamo Moscow 1
CSKA Moscow 4 Kamaz Naberezhnye Chelny 2
Lada Togliatti 1 Spartak Moscow 1
Tekstilshik Kamyshin 2 Krylya Sovetov Samara 1
Lokomotiv Nizhny Novgorod 2 Uralmash Yekaterinburg 2
Standings ( tabulate under games played , won , drawn , lost ,
goals for , goals against , points ) .
Note - if more than one team has the same number of points ,
precedence is given to the one with most wins .
If more than one
team has the same number of wins and points , precedence goes to
the side with the most successful record against the others ) .
Alaniya Vladikavkaz 24 16 5 3 48 25 53
Dynamo Moscow 25 15 7 3 43 21 52
Rotor Volgograd 23 15 5 3 42 17 50
Spartak Moscow 25 14 7 4 48 24 49
CSKA Moscow 25 13 6 6 40 27 45
Lokomotiv Nizhny Novgorod 25 11 4 10 27 35 37
Lokomotiv Moscow 25 9 9 7 30 24 36
Baltika Kaliningrad 25 8 10 7 29 26 34
Torpedo Moscow 25 8 9 8 31 33 33
Zenit St Petersburg 24 9 4 11 24 26 31
Krylya Sovetov Samara 25 8 7 10 19 29 31
Zhemchuzhina Sochi 25 8 4 13 26 38 28
Rostselmash Rostov 24 7 7 10 42 38 28
Chernomorets Novorossiisk 25 7 5 13 25 38 26
Kamaz Naberezhnye Chelny 24 5 4 15 25 42 19
Lada Togliatti 24 4 6 14 15 37 18
Tekstilshchik Kamyshin 25 3 9 13 15 30 18
Uralmash Yekaterinburg 24 3 8 13 24 43 16
AUSTRALIAN RULES-AFL RESULTS AND STANDINGS .
MELBOURNE 1996-08-25
Results of Australian Rules
matches played at the weekend .
Played Sunday :
Adelaide 14.12 ( 96 ) Collingwood 24 .
9 ( 153 )
West Coast 24 .
7 ( 151 ) Melbourne 11.12 ( 78 )
Richmond 28.19 ( 187 ) Fitzroy 5 .
6 ( 36 )
Played Saturday :
Carlton 13.18 ( 96 ) Footscray 9.12 ( 66 )
Essendon 14.16 ( 100 ) Sydney 12.10 ( 82 )
St Kilda 9 .
9 ( 63 ) Hawthorn 12 .
8 ( 80 )
Brisbane 10.11 ( 71 ) Fremantle 10.10 ( 70 )
Played Friday :
North Melbourne 14.12 ( 96 ) Geelong 16.13 ( 109 )
Standings ( tabulate under played , won , drawn , lost , points
for , against , percentage , total points ) :
Brisbane 21 15 1 5 2123 1631 130.2 62
Sydney 21 15 1 5 2067 1687 122.5 62
West Coast 21 15 0 6 2151 1673 128.6 60
North Melbourne 21 15 0 6 2385 1873 127.3 60
Carlton 21 14 0 7 2009 1844 108.9 56
Geelong 21 13 1 7 2288 1940 117.9 54
Essendon 21 13 1 7 2130 1947 109.4 54
Richmond 21 11 0 10 2173 1803 120.5 44
Hawthorn 21 10 1 10 1791 1820 98.4 42
St Kilda 21 9 0 12 1909 1958 97.5 36
Collingwood 21 8 0 13 2103 2091 100.6 32
Adelaide 21 8 0 13 2158 2183 98.9 32
Melbourne 21 7 0 14 1642 2361 69.5 28
Fremantle 21 6 0 15 1673 1912 87.5 24
Footscray 21 5 1 15 1578 2060 76.6 22
Fitzroy 21 1 0 20 1381 2778 49.7 4
RUGBY LEAGUE - AUSTRALIAN RUGBY LEAGUE RESULTS / STANDINGS .
SYDNEY 1996-08-25
Results of Australian rugby league matches played at the weekend .
Played Sunday :
Sydney Bulldogs 17 South Queensland 16 Brisbane 38 Gold Coast 10
North Sydney 46 South Sydney 4
Illawarra 42 Penrith 2
St George 20 North Queensland 24
Manly 42 Western Suburbs 12
Played Saturday :
Parramatta 14 Sydney Tigers 26
Newcastle 24 Western Reds 20
Played Friday :
Canberra 30 Auckland 6
Premiership standings ( tabulate under played , won , drawn ,
lost , points for , against , total points ) :
Manly 21 17 0 4 501 181 34
Brisbane 21 16 0 5 569 257 32
North Sydney 21 14 2 5 560 317 30
Sydney City 20 14 1 5 487 293 29
Cronulla 20 12 2 6 359 258 26
Canberra 21 12 1 8 502 374 25
St George 21 12 1 8 421 344 25
Newcastle 21 11 1 9 416 366 23
Western Suburbs 21 11 1 9 382 426 23
Auckland 21 11 0 10 406 389 22
Sydney Tigers 21 11 0 10 309 435 22
Parramatta 21 10 1 10 388 391 21
Sydney Bulldogs 21 10 0 11 325 356 20
Illawarra 21 8 0 13 395 432 16
Western Reds 21 6 1 14 297 398 13
Penrith 21 6 1 14 339 448 13
North Queensland 21 6 0 15 266 593 12
Gold Coast 21 5 1 15 351 483 11
South Sydney 21 5 1 15 304 586 11
South Queensland 21 4 0 17 210 460 8
BADMINTON - MALAYSIAN OPEN RESULTS .
KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-25
Results of finals in the
Malaysian Open badminton tournament on Sunday ( prefix numbers
denote seedings ) :
Men 's singles
2 - Ong Ewe Hock ( Malaysia ) beat Indra Wijaya ( Indonesia ) 1-15
15-1 15-7
Women 's singles
2 - Zhang Ning ( China ) beat 1 - Wang Chen ( China ) 11-7 11-8
Women 's doubles
3/4 - Marlene Thomsen / Lisbet Stuer-Lauridsen ( Denmark ) beat
3/4 - Qiang Hong / Liu Lu ( China ) 10-15 17-14 17-16
Men 's doubles
1 - Yap Kim Hock / Cheah Soon Kit ( Malaysia ) beat Lee Wan Wah / Chong
Tan Fook ( Malaysia ) 15-5 15-3
BASEBALL - RESULTS OF S. KOREAN PRO-BASEBALL GAMES .
SEOUL 1996-08-25
Results of South Korean
pro-baseball games played on Saturday .
Haitai 10 Hanwha 4
Hyundai 5 Samsung 4
Ssangbangwool 4 LG 1
OB 1 Lotte 1
Lotte 1 OB 0*
*Note - OB and Lotte played two games .
Standings after games played on Saturday ( won , drawn , lost ,
winning percentage , games behind first place )
W D L PCT GB
Haitai 63 2 40 .610 -
Ssangbangwool 57 2 47 .547 6 1/2
Hyundai 55 5 47 .537 7 1/2
Hanwha 55 1 48 .534 8
Samsung 47 5 54 .467 15
Lotte 44 6 52 .461 15 1/2
LG 44 5 57 .439 18
OB 40 6 60 .406 21 1/2
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE RESULTS SUNDAY .
NEW YORK 1996-08-25
Results of Major League
Baseball games played on Sunday ( home team in CAPS ) :
American League
BOSTON 8 Seattle 5
CLEVELAND 8 Milwaukee 5
California 13 BALTIMORE 0
Oakland 6 NEW YORK 4
CHICAGO 10 Toronto 9 ( 10 )
Texas 13 MINNESOTA 2
Detroit 7 KANSAS CITY 4
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE STANDINGS AFTER SATURDAY 'S GAMES .
NEW YORK 1996-08-25
Major League Baseball
standings after games played on Saturday ( tabulate under won ,
lost , winning percentage and games behind ) :
AMERICAN LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
NEW YORK 74 54 .578 -
BALTIMORE 68 60 .531 6
BOSTON 65 65 .500 10
TORONTO 61 69 .469 14
DETROIT 46 83 .357 28 1/2
CENTRAL DIVISION
CLEVELAND 76 53 .589 -
CHICAGO 69 62 .527 8
MINNESOTA 65 64 .504 11
MILWAUKEE 62 68 .477 14 1/2
KANSAS CITY 59 72 .450 18
WESTERN DIVISION
TEXAS 74 56 .569 -
SEATTLE 66 62 .516 7
OAKLAND 62 70 .470 13
CALIFORNIA 60 69 .465 13 1/2
SUNDAY , AUGUST 25TH SCHEDULE
SEATTLE AT BOSTON
MILWAUKEE AT CLEVELAND
CALIFORNIA AT BALTIMORE
OAKLAND AT NEW YORK
TORONTO AT CHICAGO
TEXAS AT MINNESOTA
DETROIT AT KANSAS CITY
NATIONAL LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
ATLANTA 81 47 .633 -
MONTREAL 70 58 .547 11
FLORIDA 60 70 .462 22
NEW YORK 59 71 .454 23
PHILADELPHIA 53 77 .408 29
CENTRAL DIVISION
HOUSTON 69 61 .531 -
ST LOUIS 68 61 .527 1/2
CINCINNATI 64 64 .500 4
CHICAGO 63 64 .496 4 1/2
PITTSBURGH 55 74 .426 13 1/2
WESTERN DIVISION
SAN DIEGO 71 60 .542 -
LOS ANGELES 69 60 .535 1
COLORADO 67 63 .515 3 1/2
SAN FRANCISCO 54 73 .425 15
SUNDAY , AUGUST 25TH SCHEDULE
CHICAGO AT ATLANTA
PITTSBURGH AT COLORADO
NEW YORK AT LOS ANGELES
PHILADELPHIA AT SAN DIEGO
MONTREAL AT SAN FRANCISCO
CINCINNATI AT FLORIDA
ST LOUIS AT HOUSTON
BASEBALL - ORIOLES SNEAK PAST ANGELS .
BALTIMORE 1996-08-25
Rafael Palmeiro 's two-out single in the sixth inning scored Roberto Alomar with the go-ahead run as the Baltimore Orioles rallied past the California Angels 5-4 and took over the American League 's wild-card berth on Saturday .
The Orioles trailed 4-3 when pinch-hitter Mike Devereaux led off the sixth with a triple against reliever Kyle Abbott ( 0-1 ) and scored the tying run on Alomar 's single .
After Brady Anderson sacrificed , Palmeiro hit the first pitch into right field for a single , scoring Alomar .
In Boston , former Mariner Darren Bragg 's first career grand slam in the sixth inning off reliever Randy Johnson lifted the Boston Red Sox to their fifth win in six games , a 9-5 victory over Seattle .
" Just one of those things , I was just trying to make contact , " said Bragg . "
The bases were loaded and I had two strikes .
I was just trying to put the ball in play .
I got the good part of the bat on it and it carried out . "
In Cleveland , Kevin Seitzer 's two-out single in the top of the 10th brought home David Hulse with the winning run as the Milwaukee Brewers sent the Cleveland Indians to their third straight extra-inning defeat 4-3 .
Bob Wickman ( 5-1 ) , acquired from the New York Yankees on Friday , earned the win in his Milwaukee debut despite allowing the tying run in the eighth inning .
At Minnesota , Marty Cordova and Matt Lawton hit solo homers and Frankie Rodriguez allowed six hits over seven innings to earn his first win as a starter in a month as the Minnesota Twins held on to beat the Texas Rangers 6-5 .
" Yeah , you know it 's fun , it 's always fun when you 've got a chance to go to the ballpark and win a game that 's important , " said Rodriguez . "
Every game should be important , but it 's a little more important now . "
In New York , Wally Whitehurst allowed two runs over seven innings for his first win in more than two years and Paul O'Neill 's three-run double snapped a sixth-inning tie as the New York Yankees held on for a 5-4 victory over the Oakland Athletics .
Whitehurst , promoted from Triple-A Columbus on Wednesday , allowed seven hits and struck out one without a walk .
It was his first win since defeating the St. Louis Cardinals on May 28th , 1994 when he was with the San Diego Padres .
In Kansas City , Jose Rosado came within one out of his third complete game and Michael Tucker homered and drove in three runs as the Kansas City Royals broke a six-game losing streak with a 9-2 victory over the Detroit Tigers in a battle of cellar-dwellers .
Rosado ( 5-3 ) allowed two runs -- one earned -- and seven hits over 8-2/3 innings with three walks and six strikeouts .
In his last four starts , the 21-year-old left-hander has given up only four earned runs in 29-2/3 innings .
BASEBALL - BRAVES RALLY TO BEAT CUBS .
ATLANTA 1996-08-25
Fred McGriff went 5-for-5 and homered twice , including a three-run blast with two out in the bottom of the ninth inning that lifted the Atlanta Braves to a 6-5 victory over the Chicago Cubs on Saturday .
" I was just trying to hang in there and hit it up the middle , " said McGriff about his homer in the ninth . "
I was just looking for the ball , trying to stay on it .
Brad Clontz ( 6-2 ) picked up the win in relief for Atlanta , which has won 11 of its last 13 games .
In Colorado , Mark Thompson threw an eight-hitter for his third complete game and Ellis Burks homered and drove in three runs as the Colorado Rockies beat the Pittsburgh Pirates 9-3 .
Vinny Castilla and Dante Bichette each added two RBI for Colorado , which improved the major league 's best home mark to 44-20 .
At Florida , Kevin Brown scattered seven hits over eight innings and Kurt Abbott snapped a sixth-inning tie with a two-run double as the Florida Marlins defeated the tired Cincinnati Reds 5-3 .
The Marlins won for just the third time in nine games , taking advantage of a Reds ' team that has not had a day off since August 8th and was playing its fourth game in 43 hours .
In Los Angeles , Tom Candiotti allowed two runs in seven innings and singled home the go-ahead run and Mike Piazza and Todd Hollandsworth drove in two runs apiece as the Los Angeles Dodgers defeated the New York Mets 7-5 .
Candiotti ( 8-9 ) walked one , allowed five hits and struck out a season-high eight batters for Los Angeles , which has won 10 of its last 14 games .
In San Diego , Joey Hamilton allowed two hits over seven innings and Rickey Henderson hit his major league-record 69th leadoff homer as the San Diego Padres defeated the Philadelphia Phillies 7-1 for their fifth win in six games .
Hamilton ( 12-7 ) won his second straight start , allowing just a sixth-inning run and a pair of singles .
In San Francisco , Pedro Martinez allowed two hits in eight innings and David Segui drove in two runs as the Montreal Expos shut out the San Francisco Giants 3-0 for their third straight win .
Martinez ( 11-7 ) , who lasted just 1-1/3 innings in his last start against San Diego five days ago , pitched eight-plus innings , walking four and striking out 10 .
In Houston , Orlando Miller 's two-run homer with one out in the bottom of the ninth off Todd Stottlemyre gave the Houston Astros a 3-1 win over the St. Louis Cardinals and left the teams in a virtual tie for the lead in the NL Central division .
Shane Reynolds ( 16-6 ) fired a five-hitter , walking one and striking out six .
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE RESULTS SATURDAY .
NEW YORK 1996-08-25
Results of Major League
Baseball games played on Saturday ( home team in CAPS ) :
National League
ATLANTA 6 Chicago 5
HOUSTON 3 St Louis 1
LOS ANGELES 7 New York 5
Montreal 3 SAN FRANCISCO 0
FLORIDA 5 Cincinnati 3
COLORADO 9 Pittsburgh 3
SAN DIEGO 7 Philadelphia 1
American League
BOSTON 9 Seattle 5
Milwaukee 4 CLEVELAND 3 ( 10 innings )
BALTIMORE 5 California 4
Toronto 9 CHICAGO 2
NEW YORK 5 Oakland 4
KANSAS CITY 9 Detroit 2
MINNESOTA 6 Texas 5
SOCCER - CHAMPIONS PORTO KICK OFF SEASON WITH A DRAW .
LISBON 1996-08-25
Portuguese champions Porto kicked off the season with a disappointing 2-2 home draw against Setubal and were lucky to squeeze in an equaliser in extra time .
Porto , who are fighting to take their third consecutive title this season , were 2-0 down until the 86th minute when a header by Mario Jardel found the net after a string of missed opportunities , including a penalty taken by top league scorer Domingos Oliveira in the 60th minute .
Domingos redeemed himself by netting the equaliser just into extra time .
Setubal , who put on a skilful counter-attack throughout the game , opened the scoring 16 minutes into the match when an unmarked Chiquinho Conde shot around Porto 's new Polish keeper Andrejez Wozniak .
Conde scored his second in the 70th minute .
Benfica , also playing their first game of the season at home , were held to a 1-1 draw by northern side Braga despite the fact that the visitors were reduced to 10 men in the 54th minute after Rodrigo Carneiro was sent off for a second bookable offence .
Benfica dominated the game but their lack of a first-class striker was apparent throughout and in the 30th minute they lost key Brazilian midfielder Valdo who suffered a light knee injury .
He was substituted by Paulao .
Benfica finally opened the scoring in the 81st minute with a penalty taken by Helder after Luis Baltasar tripped up captain Joao Pinto under the referee 's nose .
Braga defender Idalecio gave his team their equaliser seven minutes from the final whistle with a header into the back of the net .
SOCCER - PORTUGUESE FIRST DIVISION RESULTS .
LISBON 1996-08-25
Results of Portuguese first
division soccer matches on Sunday :
FC Porto 2 Setubal 2
Benfica 1 Braga 1
Guimaraes 4 Gil Vicente 2
SOCCER - FIORENTINA WIN WITH BATISTUTA DOUBLE .
MILAN 1996-08-25
Argentine striker Gabriel Batistuta gave Fiorentina the perfect 70th birthday present on Sunday with two goals that gave the Italian Cup winners a 2-1 Supercup victory over serie A champions Milan .
The victory , coming on the eve of the founding of the Florence club in 1926 , also marked the first time since the pre-season trophy between the Cup winners and league champions was started in 1988 that the Cup winners had won .
Batistuta gave Fiorentina the lead in the 11th minute .
Sweden 's Stefan Schwarz picked him out with a lob to the edge of the box and Batistuta did the rest , chipping veteran defender Franco Baresi and scoring at the near post .
Montenegrin midfielder Dejan Savicevic equalised for the home team , weaving past a defender , checking and firing in a left-footed shot in the 21st minute that gave young Fiorentina goalkeeper Francesco Toldo little chance .
The scored stayed level to the final minutes but with a penalty shoot out looming , Batistuta took charge .
French international midfielder Marcel Desailly fouled the Argentine , whose coach at Boca Juniors before he joined Fiorentina in 1991 was new Milan coach Oscar Tabarez , and Batistuta rammed home the free kick from 30 metres out .
The 83rd minute shot , curling over the defence and dipping in under the bar from the striker dubbed Batigol by adoring Fiorentina fans , was just reward for Fiorentina who looked a far more impressive team .
Milan 's player of the year George Weah missed a good first half opportunity but otherwise looked a little rusty while Italian team mate Roberto Baggio did not play due to injury .
New Dutch signing Edgar Davids came on late in the second half as a Milan substitute but made little impact .
The league season starts on September 8 .
SOCCER - FIORENTINA BEAT MILAN IN ITALIAN SUPERCUP .
MILAN 1996-08-25
Italian Cup winners Fiorentina beat
league champions Milan 2-1 ( halftime 1-1 ) in the pre-season
Supercoppa ( SuperCup ) in Milan on Sunday :
Scorers :
Fiorentina - Gabriel Batistuta ( 11th , 83rd )
Milan - Dejan Savicevic ( 21st )
Attendance : 29,582
SOCCER - NORWAY ELITE DIVISION RESULTS / STANDINGS .
OSLO 1996-08-25
Results of Norwegian elite division
soccer matches at the weekend :
Tromso 2 Kongsvinger 1
Valerenga 3 Skeid 0
Stabaek 4 Stromsgodset 0
Molde 1 Bodo / Glimt 2
Viking 1 Moss 0
Brann 7 Start 1
Rosenborg 7 Lillestrom 2
Standings after weekend matches ( tabulate under played , won ,
drawn , lost , goals for , against , points ) :
Rosenborg 20 14 4 2 68 21 46
Lillestrom 19 9 5 5 38 29 32
Skeid 19 10 2 7 29 30 32
Stabaek 20 7 8 5 41 34 29
Brann 19 8 5 6 40 37 29
Tromso 20 8 5 7 34 33 29
Viking 20 7 7 6 33 24 28
Molde 19 8 3 8 36 25 27
Bodo / Glimt 20 7 4 9 33 41 25
Kongsvinger 20 7 4 9 26 38 25
Stromsgodset 20 7 4 9 27 40 25
Valerenga 20 6 6 8 26 32 24
Moss 20 4 6 10 23 40 18
Start 20 3 3 14 26 56 12
SOCCER - SUMMARY OF GERMAN FIRST DIVISION MATCH .
BONN 1996-08-25
Summary of German first division
match played on Sunday :
MSV Duisberg 0 Bayern Munich 4 ( Klinsmann 15th , Zieger 24th and
90th , Witechek 59th ) .
Halftime 0-2 .
Attendance : 30,000 .
SOCCER - RESULT OF GERMAN FIRST DIVISION MATCH .
BONN 1996-08-25
Result of German first division
soccer match on Sunday :
MSV Duisberg 0 Bayern Munich 4
Bundesliga standings after Sunday 's game ( tabulate under
played , won , drawn , lost , goals for , goals against , points ) :
Cologne 3 3 0 0 7 1 9
Bayern Munich 3 2 1 0 7 2 7
VfB Stuttgart 2 2 0 0 6 1 6
Borussia Dortmund 3 2 0 1 9 5 6
Hamburg 3 2 0 1 7 3 6
Bayer Leverkusen 3 2 0 1 7 4 6
VfL Bochum 3 1 2 0 3 2 5
Karlsruhe 2 1 1 0 5 3 4
St Pauli 3 1 1 1 7 7 4
1860 Munich 3 1 0 2 3 5 3
Freiburg 3 1 0 2 5 10 3
Fortuna Duesseldorf 3 1 0 2 1 7 3
Hansa Rostock 3 0 2 1 3 4 2
Arminia Bielefeld 3 0 2 1 2 3 2
Borussia Moenchengladbach 3 0 2 1 1 3 2
Schalke 3 0 2 1 4 8 2
Werder Bremen 3 0 1 2 4 6 1
MSV Duisburg 3 0 0 3 1 8 0
SOCCER - SWISS PREMIER DIVISION RESULTS / STANDINGS .
GENEVA 1996-08-25
Results of Swiss premier division
matches played at the weekend :
Aarau 1 Young Boys 0
Grasshopper 2 Lucerne 2
Lugano 1 Basle 1
Neuchatel 3 St Gallen 0
Sion 3 Servette 1
Standings ( tabulated under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , against , points ) :
Neuchatel 8 6 1 1 12 7 19
Grasshopper 9 4 4 1 17 11 16
St. Gallen 9 4 4 1 6 5 16
Lausanne 9 4 2 3 18 13 14
Aarau 8 4 1 3 9 4 13
Sion 9 3 4 2 13 11 13
Zurich 9 2 5 2 9 9 11
Basle 8 2 3 3 12 11 9
Servette 9 2 3 4 10 12 9
Lucerne 8 1 5 2 10 11 8
Lugano 9 1 4 4 6 15 7
Young Boys 9 1 0 8 6 19 3
GOLF - LEADING PRIZE MONEY WINNERS ON EUROPEAN TOUR .
STUTTGART , Germany 1996-08-25
Leading prize money
winners on the European Tour after Sunday 's German Open ( Britain
unless stated ) :
1. Ian Woosnam 480,618 pounds sterling
2. Colin Montgomerie 429,449
3. Lee Westwood 301,972
4. Robert Allenby ( Australia ) 291,088
5. Mark McNulty ( Zimbabwe ) 254,247
6. Costantino Rocca ( Italy ) 253,337
7. Andrew Coltart 246,077
8. Wayne Riley ( Australia ) 233,713
9. Raymond Russell 229,360
10. Stephen Ames ( Trinidad ) 211,175
11. Frank Nobilo ( New Zealand ) 209,412
12. Paul McGinley ( Ireland ) 208,978
13. Paul Lawrie 207,990
14. Padraig Harrington ( Ireland ) 202,593
15. Retief Goosen ( South Africa ) 188,143
16. Jonathan Lomas 181,005
17. Paul Broadhurst 172,580
18. Peter Mitchell 170,952
19. Jim Payne 165,150
20. Russell Claydon 156,996
CYCLING - SWISS GRAND PRIX RESULT .
ZURICH 1996-08-25
Leading results in the 232-km
Swiss Grand Prix World Cup cycling race on Sunday :
1. Andrea Ferrigato ( Italy ) 5 hours 51 minutes 52 seconds
2. Michele Bartoli ( Italy )
3. Johan Museeuw ( Belgium )
4. Lance Armstrong ( U.S. )
5. Francesco Casagrande ( Italy )
6. Alessandro Baronti ( Italy )
7. Frank Vandenbroucke ( Belgium ) all same time
8. Fabio Baldato ( Italy ) 11 seconds behind
9. Maurizio Fondriest ( Italy )
10. Laurent Jalabert ( France ) both same time
Leading World Cup standings ( after 8 of 11 rounds ) :
1. Museeuw 162 points
2. Ferrigato 112
3. Bartoli 108
4. Stefano Zanini ( Italy ) 88
5. Armstrong 81
6. Baldato 77
7. Alexandre Gontchenkov ( Ukraine ) 67
8. Gabriele Colombo ( Italy ) 58
9. Andrei Tchmil ( Ukraine ) 56
10. Max Sciandri ( Britain ) 55
CYCLING - FERRIGATO SPRINTS TO SECOND STRAIGHT WORLD CUP WIN .
ZURICH 1996-08-25
Andrea Ferrigato of Italy sprinted to his second cycling World Cup win in successive weekends with victory in the Swiss Grand Prix on Sunday .
Ferrigato , winner of the Leeds Classic last Sunday with a one second win over Britain 's Max Sciandri , posted a similarly narrow margin of victory again .
The 26-year-old Italian surged past compatriot Michele Bartoli and last year 's winner and defending World Cup champion Johan Museeuw of Belgium in the final few metres of the 237km race .
All three clocked the same time of five hours 51 minutes , 52 seconds .
Former world champion Lance Armstrong of the United States was in front as the leading pack of seven riders turned into the Oerlikon velodrome for the final one lap sprint but quickly faded and settled for fourth .
The back-to-back wins vault Ferrigato from sixth to second in the overall World Cup rankings with 112 points but Museeuw continues to hold a commanding lead with 162 points after eight of the 11 rounds .
GOLF - GERMAN OPEN SCORES .
STUTTGART , Germany 1996-08-25
Briton Ian Woosnam won
the German Open golf championship on Sunday after the final
round was abandoned because of torrential rain .
Scores after three rounds ( Britain unless stated ) :
193 Ian Woosnam 64 64 65 .
199 Thomas Gogele ( Germany ) 67 65 67 , Robert Karlsson
( Sweden ) 67 62 70 , Ian Pyman 66 64 69 , Fernando Roca
( Spain ) 66 64 69 .
200 Diego Borrego ( Spain ) 69 63 68 , Miguel Angel Martin
( Spain ) 66 66 68 .
201 Stephen Ames ( Trinidad ) 68 65 68 , Roger Chapman 72 62 67 ,
Paul Broadhurst 62 70 69 , Stephen Field 66 65 70 ,
Carl Suneson ( Spain ) 65 66 70
202 Greg Turner ( New Zealand ) 70 67 65 , Heinz-Peter Thul
( Germany ) 70 67 65 , Ronan Rafferty 64 72 66 , Barry Lane
68 67 67 , David Carter 66 69 67 , Michael Jonzon ( Sweden )
67 67 68 , David Williams 67 67 68
203 Lee Westwood 66 71 66 , Gary Emerson 68 69 66 , Peter Baker
70 66 67 , Des Smyth ( Ireland ) 66 69 68 , Paul Lawrie
66 69 68 , Francisco Cea ( Spain ) 68 66 69 , Pedro Linhart
( Spain ) 67 67 69 , Jonathan Lomas 67 67 69 , Paul Eales
67 68 68 , Raymond Russell 63 69 71
SOCCER - PSV BEAT GRONINGEN 4-1 TO PULL AWAY FROM AJAX .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-25
Belgian international Luc Nilis scored twice on Sunday as PSV Eindhoven came from behind to beat Groningen 4-1 in Eindhoven .
PSV and Vitesse Arnhem are the only unbeaten teams after two rounds of the Dutch league .
Defending champions Ajax Amsterdam were defeated 2-0 loss away to Heerenveen on Saturday .
Groningen took the lead in the seventh minute when Dean Gorre intercepted a back pass from Ernest Faber to goalkeeper Ronald Waterreus and shot home .
Faber made amends in the 32nd minute when he headed in a corner to score the equaliser .
PSV took control in the second half but could not score until Groningen striker Romano Sion was sent off in the 58th minute .
Five minutes after his dimissal , Nilis gave PSV the lead and in the final 15 minutes he added another as did Zeljko Petrovic .
Vitesse Arnhem upstaged Utrecht 1-0 despite ending the match with only nine men following the dismissal of defenders Raymond Atteveld and Erwin van der Looi .
Gaston Taument scored twice and newly signed Argentine Pablo Sanchez once in Feyenoord Rotterdam 's 3-0 victory over Volendam .
SOCCER - BELGIAN FIRST DIVISION RESULTS / STANDINGS .
BRUSSELS 1996-08-25
Results of Belgian first
division soccer matches at the weekend :
Genk 1 Club Brugge 1
Harelbeke 3 Mechelen 3
Standard Liege 3 Molenbeek 0
Anderlecht 2 Lokeren 2
Cercle Brugge 2 Mouscron 2
Antwerp 1 Lommel 4
Ghent 3 Aalst 2
Lierse 4 Charleroi 0
Sint Truiden 3 Ekeren 1
Standings ( tabulated under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , against , points ) :
Ghent 4 3 1 0 9 5 10
Standard Liege 4 3 0 1 7 3 9
Club Brugge 4 2 2 0 10 4 8
Mouscron 4 2 2 0 7 4 8
Anderlecht 4 1 3 0 9 3 6
Lierse 4 1 3 0 7 3 6
Antwerp 4 2 0 2 6 10 6
Genk 4 1 2 1 6 5 5
Molenbeek 4 1 2 1 4 5 5
Harelbeke 4 1 1 2 6 7 4
Aalst 4 1 1 2 5 6 4
Lokeren 4 1 1 2 4 5 4
Ekeren 4 1 1 2 6 8 4
Lommel 4 1 1 2 5 10 4
Mechelen 4 0 3 1 6 7 3
Cercle Brugge 4 0 3 1 4 5 3
Charleroi 4 1 0 3 4 8 3
Sint Truiden 4 1 0 3 4 11 3
SOCCER - DUTCH FIRST DIVISION SUMMARIES .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-25
Summary of Dutch first division
soccer played on Sunday :
Feyenoord Rotterdam 3 ( Sanchez 27th , Taument 44th , 57th )
Volendam 0 .
Halftime 2-0 .
Attendance not given .
NEC Nijmegen 0 AZ Alkmaar 0 .
Vitesse Arnhem 1 ( Van Wanrooy 58th ) Utrecht 0 .
Halftime 0-0 .
Attendance 7,032 .
Twente Enschede 1 ( Hoogma 30th ) Roda JC Kerkrade 1 ( Roelofsen
28th ) .
Halftime 1-1 .
Attendance not given .
PSV Eindhoven 4 ( Faber 32nd , Nilis 63rd 79th , Petrovic 78th )
Groningen 1 ( Gorre 7th ) .
Halftime 1-1 .
Attendance 27,500
Played on Saturday :
Graafschap Doetinchem 3 ( Ibrahim 20th 63rd , Godee 54th ) RKC
Waalwijk 2 ( Dos Santos 38th , Van Arum 73th penalty ) .
Halftime
1-1 .
Attendance 7,000
Willem II Tilburg 0 Fortuna Sittard 1 ( Hamming 65th ) .
Halftime
0-0 .
Attendance 7,250 .
NAC Breda 1 ( Arnold 70th ) Sparta Rotterdam 0 .
Haldtime 0-0 .
Attendance 11,500 .
Heerenveen 2 ( Wouden 53rd , Dahl Tomasson 74th ) Ajax Amsterdam
0. Halftime 0-0 .
Attendance 13,500 .
SOCCER - DUTCH FIRST DIVISION RESULTS / TABLE .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-25
Result of Dutch first division
soccer match played on Sunday :
Feyenoord Rotterdam 3 Volendam 0
NEC Nijmegen 0 AZ Alkmaar 0
Vitesse Arnhem 1 Utrecht 0
Twente Enschede 1 Roda JC 1
PSV Eindhoven 4 Groningen 1
Played on Saturday :
Graafschap Doetinchem 3 RKC Waalwijk 2
Willem II Tilburg 0 Fortuna Sittard 1
NAC Breda 1 Sparta Rotterdam 0
Heerenveen 2 Ajax Amsterdam 0
Standings ( tabulate under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , goals against , points ) :
PSV Eindhoven 2 2 0 0 8 2 6
Vitesse Arnhem 2 2 0 0 3 0 6
Feyenoord Rotterdam 2 1 1 0 4 1 4
Graafschap Doetinchem 2 1 1 0 4 3 4
Twente Enschede 2 1 1 0 4 2 4
Fortuna Sittard 2 1 1 0 1 0 4
Heerenveen 2 1 0 1 3 3 3
NAC Breda 2 1 0 1 1 1 3
Ajax Amsterdam 2 1 0 1 1 2 3
Roda JC Kerkrade 2 0 2 0 2 2 2
Utrecht 2 0 1 1 2 3 1
RKC Waalwijk 2 0 1 1 4 5 1
Sparta Rotterdam 2 0 1 1 0 1 1
Willem II Tilburg 2 0 1 1 0 1 1
AZ Alkmaar 2 0 1 1 0 2 1
Volendam 2 0 1 1 1 4 1
Groningen 2 0 1 1 1 4 1
NEC Nijmegen 2 0 1 1 1 4 1
DUTCH CAPTAIN BLIND ENDS INTERNATIONAL CAREER .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-25
Dutch soccer captain Danny Blind has decided to end his international career , Ajax spokesman David Endt said on Sunday .
Endt told Dutch news agency ANP that Blind , 35 , would no longer be available for selection for the national squad .
The Ajax defender , who led the Netherlands into the quarter-finals at June 's European championship finals in England , had decided to devote his attention to playing for his Amsterdam club , Endt said .
Blind , who played in the 1990 World Cup and the 1992 European championship , was capped 42 times for the Netherlands .
CRICKET - INDIA BANS SIDHU FOR 50 DAYS .
NEW DELHI 1996-08-25
Indian opener Navjot Singh Sidhu was on Sunday given a 50-day ban from international cricket for quitting this year 's tour of England , the Press Trust of India said .
The right-handed batsman will have to forfeit half the money he was due to earn from the tour , the news agency said after a disciplinary committee set up by the Board of Control for Cricket in India met at Mohali , near the northern city of Chandigarh .
Sidhu abandoned the Indian team after the third one-day international against England at Old Trafford in Manchester on May 26 , before India began a three-test series , citing serious differences with captain Mohammed Azharuddin .
Azharuddin was sacked after the tour and replaced by Sachin Tendulkar .
Sidhu was not considered for the four-nation Singer Cup beginning in Sri Lanka this month and the Sahara Cup against Pakistan scheduled to be played in Canada next month .
Sidhu , whose ban ends on October 14 , will be free to play domestic cricket .
He will not be considered for a test match against Australia starting on October 10 in New Delhi , the United News of India said .
RUGBY LEAGUE - Australian rugby league standings .
SYDNEY 1996-08-26
Australian rugby league premiership standings after matches played at the weekend ( tabulate under played , won , drawn , lost , points for , against , total points ) :
Manly 21 17 0 4 501 181 34
Brisbane 21 16 0 5 569 257 32
North Sydney 21 14 2 5 560 317 30
Sydney City 20 14 1 5 487 293 29
Cronulla 20 12 2 6 359 258 26
Canberra 21 12 1 8 502 374 25
St George 21 12 1 8 421 344 25
Newcastle 21 11 1 9 416 366 23
Western Suburbs 21 11 1 9 382 426 23
Auckland 21 11 0 10 406 389 22
Sydney Tigers 21 11 0 10 309 435 22
Parramatta 21 10 1 10 388 391 21
Sydney Bulldogs 21 10 0 11 325 356 20
Illawarra 21 8 0 13 395 432 16
Western Reds 21 6 1 14 297 398 13
Penrith 21 6 1 14 339 448 13
North Queensland 21 6 0 15 266 593 12
Gold Coast 21 5 1 15 351 483 11
South Sydney 21 5 1 15 304 586 11
South Queensland 21 4 0 17 210 460 8
-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800
RUGBY UNION - All Blacks relive triumph .
PRETORIA , Aug 25 - Captain Sean Fitzpatrick and his All Blacks revisited the test venue today to relive some of the magic moments of yesterday 's momentous rugby victory over South Africa , NZPA reported .
Most of the test 15 who beat the Springboks 33-26 to secure New Zealand 's first-ever rugby series in South Africa stood in the middle of the empty 50,000-seat Loftus Versfeld .
Magnificent , ' ' said Fitzpatrick , New Zealand 's most capped player and the world 's most capped forward .
The players relived the moves and tries , the tackles and what might have been as the emotions of victory continued .
Zinzan Brooke , the only No 8 in test rugby to have scored a dropped goal when he kicked a three-pointer against England during last year 's World Cup , added a second to his name yesterday .
I was right here , ' ' he said standing at the spot where he had received the ball for the kick .
The maul was there and I was going to go in but I thought I should hold off because we had the ball .
When ( halfback ) Justin Marshall got the ball he was going to go on the openside where Jon Preston was so I emptied my lung at him to get the ball this way .
I just hit through and I was punching the air before the ball got there .
It cost me a few bucks at the bar . '
'
The decision to attempt a dropped goal was a spontaneous one , Brooke said .
It was just like the World Cup , the ball came and the chance was there . '
'
Centre Frank Bunce said he had never felt so exhausted during a match .
We were gutted and there was nowhere to hide , they just kept coming at you , ' ' he said .
I was gone in the first 20 minutes , completely exhausted , but you had no choice .
There was just so much riding on it .
It 's amazing just how big this ground was yesterday . '
'
Two-try winger Jeff Wilson said he was so tired that he kept asking Bunce where he should be while defending .
He told me I 'm buggered too so just hang in there ' , ' ' Wilson recalled .
About 4000 New Zealander supporters were partying into the early hours of today in the South African capital .
Messages of goodwill continued to roll into the team hotel .
All Blacks coach John Hart said Prime Minister Jim Bolger rang him today to offer his congratulations .
He thanked us on behalf of the country , which is really nice for the team , and I understand we had tremendous support at home . '
'
Australian Rules - AFL results and standings .
MELBOURNE 1996-08-26
Results of Australian Rules matches played at the weekend .
Played Sunday :
Adelaide 14.12 ( 96 ) Collingwood 24 .
9 ( 153 )
West Coast 24 .
7 ( 151 ) Melbourne 11.12 ( 78 )
Richmond 28.19 ( 187 ) Fitzroy 5 .
6 ( 36 )
Played Saturday :
Carlton 13.18 ( 96 ) Footscray 9.12 ( 66 )
Essendon 14.16 ( 100 ) Sydney 12.10 ( 82 )
St Kilda 9 .
9 ( 63 ) Hawthorn 12 .
8 ( 80 )
Brisbane 10.11 ( 71 ) Fremantle 10.10 ( 70 )
Played Friday :
North Melbourne 14.12 ( 96 ) Geelong 16.13 ( 109 )
Standings ( tabulate under played , won , drawn , lost , points for , against , percentage , total points ) :
Brisbane 21 15 1 5 2123 1631 130.2 62
Sydney 21 15 1 5 2067 1687 122.5 62
West Coast 21 15 0 6 2151 1673 128.6 60
North Melbourne 21 15 0 6 2385 1873 127.3 60
Carlton 21 14 0 7 2009 1844 108.9 56
Geelong 21 13 1 7 2288 1940 117.9 54
Essendon 21 13 1 7 2130 1947 109.4 54
Richmond 21 11 0 10 2173 1803 120.5 44
Hawthorn 21 10 1 10 1791 1820 98.4 42
St Kilda 21 9 0 12 1909 1958 97.5 36
Collingwood 21 8 0 13 2103 2091 100.6 32
Adelaide 21 8 0 13 2158 2183 98.9 32
Melbourne 21 7 0 14 1642 2361 69.5 28
Fremantle 21 6 0 15 1673 1912 87.5 24
Footscray 21 5 1 15 1578 2060 76.6 22
Fitzroy 21 1 0 20 1381 2778 49.7 4
-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800
Rugby league-Australian rugby league results .
SYDNEY 1996-08-26
Results of Australian rugby league matches played at the weekend .
Played Sunday :
Sydney Bulldogs 17 South Queensland 16 Brisbane 38 Gold Coast 10
North Sydney 46 South Sydney 4
Illawarra 42 Penrith 2
St George 20 North Queensland 24
Manly 42 Western Suburbs 12
Played Saturday :
Parramatta 14 Sydney Tigers 26
Newcastle 24 Western Reds 20
Played Friday :
Canberra 30 Auckland 6
-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800
South Africa yet to hear from apartheid enforcers .
Anton Ferreira
CAPE TOWN 1996-08-25
South Africa 's truth commission begins issuing subpoenas this week in a bid to dig beneath the political rationales and find the sinister figures who have the blood of the country 's race war on their hands .
Leaders of the major parties involved , from right-wing whites to radical blacks , appeared before Archbishop Desmond Tutu 's Truth and Reconciliation Commission last week to paint the broad picture of their actions for or against apartheid .
Most , including former president F.W. de Klerk and African National Congress Deputy President Thabo Mbeki , offered apologies for any mistakes they had made and accepted broad responsibility for the actions of their foot soldiers .
But none named those guilty of ordering or carrying out any of the gross violations of human rights which Tutu is investigating .
Human rights lawyer Brian Currin said the hearings last week were not intended as a form of confessional and that those who personally committed crimes during apartheid would testify only before a separate arm of the commission , the amnesty committee .
" I do n't think one should have expected more than what one got , " he said . "
That was not the amnesty committee where perpetrators are expected to open their hearts and souls and to tell it all . "
The commission , which has the power to grant amnesty to those who confess to abuses , has begun hearing the testimony from people already in jail for their deeds .
But others , such as self-confessed secret police hit-squad leader Dirk Coetzee , have yet to testify .
Tutu 's deputy chairman , Alex Boraine , told reporters the commission would begin issuing subpoenas to suspects who refused to appear voluntarily some time this week .
He added that former hardline apartheid president P.W. Botha could be among those called .
But Currin , who is advising several people regarded as perpetrators , said this was not the best way to achieve the commission 's aims .
" A person can be forced to appear , but the only way one is going to get to the truth in its totality is if people feel it is a good idea to go to the amnesty committee .
At the moment this is not the case . "
He cited Coetzee , who was charged with murder after confessing in media interviews to dirty tricks .
His trial is due to start in December but the truth commission intends to decide on his amnesty application before that .
Currin said the law had to be changed so all judicial prosecutions were automatically suspended for those who approached the truth commission .
Last week 's submissions to the commission by the ANC , de Klerk 's National Party and the right-wing Freedom Front of General Constand Viljoen left many South Africans unsatisfied .
Boraine said the picture was incomplete because officers of the apartheid-era security forces had yet to make their scheduled , separate submission , but one black caller to a radio talk show declared :
" This whole thing is utterly useless , it does n't help us at all .
What the people expect is to have houses , to have jobs . "
Political scientist Jannie Gagiano said he doubted that the National Party , which implemented apartheid in 1948 and began dismantling it in 1990 , felt it carried a burden of guilt and needed to be exculpated through the commission .
" Therefore I have some doubts about achieving some form of reconciliation .
One has to feel a bit guilty to feel the need for reconciling yourself to a historical adversary , " he said .
Professor Tom Lodge of the University of the Witwatersrand demurred , saying :
" In the irritation , in the jokes , in the anger that white South Africans express about the commission , I think there 's a moral uneasiness , and I think that 's healthy .
Responsibility is percolating downwards . "
Moslem refugees seek to vote in Serb-held town .
Samir Arnaut
MATUZICI , Bosnia 1996-08-25
Thousands of Moslem refugees denounced Bosnia 's elections as a farce on Sunday because Serb incomers would be able to vote in their old home town , cementing partition of the country .
They said they were ready to force their way back across post-war ethnic lines to Serb-held Doboj , one of several towns where NATO troops fear violence involving refugees determined to vote where they once lived .
The refugees , rallying in Matuzici on government territory two km from Doboj in northeast Bosnia , waved banners calling the polls a farce staged by the United Nations and the European Union . "
We demand to vote in Doboj , " other banners said .
Bosnia 's Moslem-led central government and many displaced Moslems are angered by a key provision of the Western-organised September 14 elections allowing people to vote in post-war " new places of residence . "
As a result , separatist Serb authorities have packed former Moslem majority towns with refugees of their own or registered other Serbs to vote there .
Critics say that what was billed as an electoral process to reintegrate Bosnia as a single , multi-ethnic state is shaping up as a referendum on partition , de facto or de jure .
" Only our physical presence in Doboj will mean that the Dayton peace treaty has truly been implemented , " Edhem Efendija Camdzic , Doboj 's Islamic imam-in-exile , told the refugees .
" The main point of this rally is to highlight to the world powers what misfortune they brought upon us , " said Reuf Mehemdagic , head of Doboj municipality-in-exile .
" Eleven thousand Serbs who came from elsewhere to Doboj will vote there .
How can we then expect the reintegration of Bosnia ?
But no one will stop us from returning to our homes . "
Mirhunisa Komarica , a government refugee official , said : " We want to vote where we were thrown out from .
This is a protest of warning and the next step is entering our town using all means possible , so let them shoot . "
Bosnian Vice President Ejup Ganic , a Moslem , told the refugees : " We have a message for the Serbs who are now in our homes not to plan the future of their children there because there will be no good fortune in that . "
To loud applause , he added : " We will enter Doboj , untie the Doboj knot and ensure free movement for all .
We have to enter Doboj to free the Serbs from their own ( separatist ) politics . "
The Dayton peace accords guaranteed refugees the right to return to their homes and ensured freedom of movement across ethnic lines .
But local police , controlled by nationalist parties in Moslem , Serb and Croat sectors of Bosnia , and civilian mobs have turned ceasefire lines into virtually impassable borders .
The majority of refugees from Bosnia 's 1992-95 war are Moslems from the Serb-controlled north and east .
NATO-led peace troops beefed up their presence in the Doboj area on Sunday to deter any sudden emotional attempt by the refugees to cross the Inter-Entity Boundary Line into Doboj .
But the crowd dispersed without incident .
Moslems and Serbs have scuffled several times along the line in the past when Moslem refugees tried to surge into the town .
Eight killed in Moscow casino blaze .
MOSCOW 1996-08-25
Eight people died on Sunday in a blaze at a Moscow casino which the fire service said might have been started deliberately , Interfax news agency said .
The number of casinos has soared in Moscow since the collapse of communism .
The mayor has said he wants to cut their number to five as part of a war against organised crime .
President Boris Yeltsin signed a decree on fighting crime in July and handed wide-ranging powers to security chief Alexander Lebed , currently engaged in making peace in breakaway Chechnya .
Russian troops start pullout , but not in Grozny .
SHATOI , Russia 1996-08-25
Russian troops began to pull out from southern Chechnya on Sunday under a ceasefire agreement between Russian security chief Alexander Lebed and rebel leaders .
But in the capital Grozny , the commander of Russian Interior Ministry forces in Chechnya , General Anatoly Shkirko , told Interfax news agency he was delaying a pullout of troops there after a group of Chechens disarmed an armoured column .
Reuters cameraman Liutauras Stremaitis said a column of around 40 vehicles , including tanks , armoured personnel carriers , artillery cannons and lorries , escorted by Chechen rebels , pulled out of the village of Shatoi towards the border , around 50 km ( 31 miles ) to the north .
In Grozny , Shkirko told Interfax he was suspending the pullout of troops from the capital until weapons seized by the Chechens were returned .
Chechen rebel spokesman Movladi Udugov confirmed the weapons had been seized but that it was a maverick group of Chechens .
He said later that the rebels had handed them over .
The pullout of the Russian troops is a key element of the peace plan brokered by Lebed , which aims to end the 20-month Chechnya conflict .
Leftist Mexican armed group says troops in capital .
MEXICO CITY 1996-08-25
The leftist Popular Revolutionary Army ( EPR ) in a published report on Sunday said it operated throughout Mexico , including the capital , and denied government assertions it was isolated to one state .
Commanders " Vicente " and " Oscar " , guarded by a dozen EPR gunmen , said in an interview with La Jornada outside Mexico City that the armed group was committed to overthrowing the government .
" They ( government officials ) want to present us before public opinion as a local problem , as just being from Guerrero and as irrational radicals , " Commander Oscar told La Jornada .
They said the ERP , whose fighters first appeared wearing military fatigues and brandishing assault rifles in the southwestern state of Guerrero on June 28 , had a 23,000-strong membership , but this could not be confirmed independently .
La Jornada also reported on Sunday that the Mexican Army has discovered a 37-page , EPR manual detailing guerrilla tactics and strategies .
It quoted the manual as saying : " The objective of the Basic Course on War is to provide for combatants of the EPR basic military knowledge for the armed conflict against the police and military apparatus of the bourgeoisie . "
It was the second time armed " commanders " of the EPR have granted interviews outside Guerrero state , an extremely poor and volatile region where leftist protesters often have clashed violently with authorities .
Unlike the better known and unrelated Zapatista rebels in southeastern Chiapas state , the EPR has never taken on the army in direct combat , according to official reports .
There have only been a few skirmishes in Guerrero in which a handful of police , soldiers and civilians have been killed or injured .
Ten people gunned down in northwest Colombia .
BOGOTA , Colombia 1996-08-25
Unidentified gunmen dragged 10 men out ot their homes in a rural area of Colombia 's northwest province of Antioquia and shot them to death , authorities said on Sunday .
Police said the killings occurred on Saturday morning in the municipality of Anza but news of the massacre only reached the provincial capital of Medellin early on Sunday .
Anza is only 20 miles ( 30 km ) west of Medellin , but there are no roads linking it directly to the city .
Police initially said leftist Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia ( FARC ) rebels were prime suspects in the killings .
But gunmen of the left and right have killed with impunity across Antioquia for years , and there were unconfirmed reports that the latest bloodshed was the work of a right-wing paramilitary group .
Port of Tauranaga year profit climbs .
WELLINGTON 1996-08-26
Year to June 30 .
( million NZ$ unless stated )
Net profit 9.050 vs 6.03
Two Thai border police wounded by Burma gunmen .
MAE SOT , Thailand 1996-08-25
Two Thai border policemen were seriously wounded on Sunday when members of a Burmese rebel splinter faction ambushed their patrol in northwest Thailand , security officers said .
The two were wounded in the early hours of Sunday when some 30 members of the Democratic Karen Buddhist Army ( DKBA ) ambushed their patrol on the Thai side of the border with Burma , to the north of the town of Mae Sot .
The Thai army commander in the area , Col Suvit Maenmuan , told reporters the DKBA , which is allied with the Rangoon military government and based in southeast Burma , had recently stepped up cross-border infiltration .
Suvit said the motive for their intrusions was not clear but he had ordered reinforcements to beef up security along the porous frontier .
The DKBA was formed in late 1994 by hundreds of guerrillas who split from the anti-Rangoon Karen National Union ( KNU ) and allied themselves with Burmese government army , their former enemies .
DKBA members have since launched intermittent cross-border attacks on Karen refugee camps in Thailand , where the majority of inhabitants are KNU supporters , and on Thai villages and police posts near the border .
Bangkok has complained to Rangoon about the raids but Burmese military authorities say they have no contol over the faction .
Thai army commanders reject the explanation , saying they have evidence the Burmese army supplies and directs the renegade ethnic minority splinter faction .
U.S. F-14 catches fire while landing in Israel .
JERUSALEM 1996-08-25
A U.S. fighter plane blew a tyre and caught fire while landing on Sunday at Israel 's Ben Gurion airport , an airport spokesman said .
" A U.S. F-14 military plane while landing at Ben Gurion airport blew a wheel and a fire broke out , " said spokesman Yehiel Amitai , adding that the two pilots on board were not injured .
" Airport officials declared an emergency situation at the highest level and the fire brigade put out the flames while the plane was landing , " he said .
Egypt hopes jars will reveal secrets of mummies .
CAIRO 1996-08-25
Archaeologists in Egypt have found pots used by ancient Egyptians in burial rites that they say may reveal the secrets of mummification .
Mohammed Saleh , director of the Egyptian Museum , told Reuters television a U.S. team found the pots , some of which contain human intestines , in a tomb built into the rocks while digging in Dahshour , a village 40 km ( 25 miles ) south of Cairo .
Dahshour is the site of Egypt 's second largest pyramid , built for the pharaoh Seneferu more than 4,500 years ago .
Saleh said the team -- from New York 's Metropolitan Museum -- found four Canopic jars and two unguent jars in the tomb , which belongs to an unidentifed person who lived during the 12th Dynasty ( 1991-1786 BC ) in the Middle Kingdom .
" This finding is important because one of the jars still contains substances and materials used in the conservation of mummies and the conservation of the intestines and all the things which were in the cavity of a person we have not identified yet , " Saleh said .
" We hope that the analysis of such substances and liquids will reveal some secrets of the mummification process and materials used in this process , " he added .
Saudi Arabia executes Pakistani man .
DUBAI 1996-08-25
Saudi Arabia executed on Sunday a Pakistani man accused of belonging to an armed gang of robbers , Saudi television reported .
It quoted an Interior Ministry statement as saying Shabir Ahmad Muhammad Jalil was executed in Mecca .
He was the 26th person executed this year in the kingdom .
Saudi Arabia beheads convicted drug smugglers , rapists , murderers and other criminals .
PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Aug 25 .
AMMAN 1996-08-25
These are some of the leading stories in the Jordanian press on Sunday .
Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy .
JORDAN TIMES
- King : Jordan is entering a new era .
No going back on democracy ; attempts to tamper with security and stability will not be tolerated .
Information Minister Marwan Muasher says there is evidence that " some official parties in Iraq " were behind the disturbances in the south .
- King to visit Bahrain soon .
- Government asks senior Iraqi " diplomat " to leave , reviews status of others .
- Japanese foreign minister arrives for talks on peace process , bilateral ties .
AL RAI
- Prime Minister Abdul-Karim al-Kabariti says government commited to lifting ceiling of democracy .
- Saudi Prince Sultan telephones prime minister .
- Jordan releases 32 from southern town of Karak .
- Jordan expresses anger at conduct of some Iraqi diplomats in Amman which are incompatible with diplomatic traditions .
AD DUSTOUR
- Kabariti and parliament speaker meet to discuss ways to reactivate parliament 's legislative role .
AL ASWAQ
- State security court starts investigating suspects in unrest .
Netanyahu , Weizman consult on Arafat invitation .
JERUSALEM 1996-08-25
Israeli President Ezer Weizman , weighing a possible meeting with Yasser Arafat , consulted on Sunday with Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu , a spokesman said .
Weizman and Netanyahu met at the president 's official Jerusalem residence and planned to speak to the media at the end of their talks , the prime minister 's spokesman said .
Earlier , the director of the president 's office denied a report in Israel 's Yedioth Ahronoth newspaper that Weizman had already invited Arafat to his private home for talks in the coming week on the future of the Israel-PLO peace process .
But the official , Aryeh Shumer , said it was only fitting that Weizman and Arafat should talk after the Palestinian leader sent the Israeli president a letter which Yedioth Ahronoth reported contained an emotional appeal to save the peace proces .
The newspaper said Netanyahu , who is cool to meeting Arafat himself , opposed talks between Weizman and the Palestinian president .
After Moslem suicide bombers killed 59 people in Israel in February and March , Weizman called for peace efforts with the PLO to be suspended .
Shumer said his current position was that the peace process must continue .
PRESS DIGEST - Israel - Aug 25 .
JERUSALEM 1996-08-25
These are some of the leading stories in Israeli newspapers on Sunday .
Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy .
HAARETZ
- Palestinian President Arafat opens civilian struggle against Israel , calls on Palestinians to build in self-rule areas .
- Seven ministers and governor of Bank of Israel will visit the United States at the end of September and in October .
- Israel bans plane donated by the Netherlands to Arafat to land at Gaza airport .
- Former prime minister Peres to Morocco today .
YEDIOTH AHRONOTH
- Israeli President Weizman invited Palestinian President Arafat to meet him at his private residence .
- Netanyahu opposes transit camps for foreign workers facing expulsion .
- Foreign Minister Levy to visit Egypt soon .
MAARIV
- Palestinian Authority has taken over education in East Jerusalem .
- Syrian armoured columns on the move in Lebanon .
- Shimon Peres to Morocco , will stay at king 's private residence .
JERUSALEM POST
- Palestinian Minister Erekat says Israel-PLO talks will begin by September 2 .
- Prime minister names former general Avraham Tamir to staff after failing to establish national security council .
- Cabinet puts off decision on foreign workers .
- Internal Security Minister Kahalani warns cabinet of increase in organised crime .
Voting begins in second round of Lebanese election .
TRIPOLI , Lebanon 1996-08-25
Voting began on Sunday in north Lebanon in the second round of parliamentary elections with 580,000 voters eligible to choose 28 members of the 128-member parliament .
A thin trickle of voters began casting their ballots in this northern port city for the five rival lists of candidates as polling stations opened at 7 a.m. ( 0400 gmt ) .
Israeli president invites Arafat to home - paper .
JERUSALEM 1996-08-25
Israeli President Ezer Weizman has invited Yasser Arafat to meet him at his private home , Israel 's biggest newspaper said on Sunday .
The Yedioth Ahronoth daily reported that Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu , who has said he has no desire to hold talks with the Palestinian president , opposes the meeting due to be held this coming week .
The newspaper said Weizman scheduled the meeting at his private residence in the central Israeli village of Caesarea after Arafat sent him an emotional appeal " to save the peace process " .
Netanyahu met Weizman last Tuesday and voiced his opposition , Yedioth said .
" I am prepared to postpone the meeting under one condition -- that you give me a commitment right now to meet Arafat yourself within 10 days , " the paper quoted Weizman as telling Netanyahu .
It said Netanyahu had yet to give Weizman an answer .
The office of Israeli president is largely ceremonial .
But Weizman , a former defence minister and an architect of Israel 's peace treaty with Egypt , has spoken out frequently on the peace process with the Palestinians -- at times urging the former Labour government to slow it down .
Corporate America taking new view on compensation .
Anne Murray
NEW YORK 1996-08-23
Corporate America is planning major changes in employee compensation in the next few years , according to a recent study .
What it comes down to is this : If you 're highly skilled , you 'll benefit nicely .
But if you 're not and cannot contribute to your employer 's goals , you 'll be paid less .
The survey , conducted in late 1995 and the early part of this year by management consulting firm Towers Perrin , showed that the focus will be on an employee 's overall value to the company 's bottom line -- rather than how well an employee performs a specific task .
Presently , for example , if an accountant 's job involves doing five specific tasks , he or she can expect a certain salary , said Sandra O'Neal , a Towers Perrin principal .
In the future , the accountant will be evaluated solely on " knowledge , skill and abilities , " she said .
In addition to using accounting skills , the accountant will also have to be creative , work well in a team , be sensitive to customer needs and set productivity goals .
" The good news is , if you 're highly skilled and have many abilities , you 'll be paid more , " said O'Neal .
" The bad news is , if you 're not skilled and ca n't contribute to a team , to customer service and the organisation 's goals , you 'll be paid less . "
Of the 750 mid-to-large size corporations surveyed , 81 percent had undergone a major restructuring in the last three years , and more than two-thirds reported that productivity and profits were up as result .
Next on the agenda for these firms is developing a new compensation structure , and 78 percent report that they are considering a new , skills-based plan for both management and non-management employees .
This coming shift , O'Neal said , " is not just isolated or a fad .
It 's an inexorable change . "
After World War II , corporations adopted a " military model " creating hierarchical organisations where " the concept of defined tasks worked great , " she said .
But as the economy became global , customers were more demanding and problems became more complex .
" Multi-layers kept management at a distance from its customers , " O'Neal said .
Now organisations must change to stay competitive .
O'Neal says firms will place a greater emphasis on teams and team performance in giving raises .
If your team does well , you 'll do well .
If it does n't do well , do n't expect a raise .
Is this fair to an employee who can go the distance but is on a team that ca n't keep up ?
" That 's an important question we used to ask a lot , " said O'Neal . "
It 's not a question we ask any more .
The more important question is -- ' Do we have results ? '
"
To get those results , 27 percent of the companies surveyed plan to eliminate base pay increases in favour of cash bonuses and incentives , such as employee and team award programmes and education .
Companies that can change their culture and view employees as business partners will do well , O'Neal said .
For example , the survey rated some participants in the survey as " high-performing " companies , based on their return on equity above 16 percent .
Those companies also said they already offer employees variable pay and business education , give their managers more control over pay decisions and celebrate employee and team success .
" They respect employees more , they trust employees more and they value their employees more , " O'Neal said .
" The key to success at high-performance companies is engaging employees in a business partnership .
It will improve a company 's bottom line . "
Belgian police arrest detective in Dutroux affair .
Geert de Clercq
NEUFCHATEAU , Belgium 1996-08-25
Investigators arrested a senior police detective on Sunday in connection with their inquiries into Belgium 's child sex scandal , Public Prosecutor Michel Bourlet said .
" Georges Zicot was arrested and will be charged with truck theft , insurance fraud and document forgery , " Bourlet told a news conference .
He said there had been searches at three sites on Sunday , including one at the Charleroi judicial police headquarters where Zicot worked .
Zicot , 45 , is a specialist in tackling vehicle theft .
Belgian media reported that he had been questioned twice in the past two years about thefts but released both times .
He was promoted to chief detective earlier this year .
Bourlet said two other people had also been arrested .
One was Gerard Pignon , the owner of a warehouse where stolen vehicles were allegedly stored .
The other was insurer Thierry Dehaan .
Bourlet said the investigation into the vehicle theft ring would be added to the inquiry into the paedophile sex scandal in which five other people have already been arrested .
He said the connection was through Bernard Weinstein , an accomplice of convicted child rapist Marc Dutroux -- the central figure in the paedophile scandal that has sent shockwaves across Europe .
Weinstein was found dead last weekend alongside the bodies of eight-year-olds Julie Lejeune and Melissa Russo in a house belonging to Detroux , who said they starved to death earlier this year , nine months after being abducted in June 1995 .
Two other girls have been rescued and police are hunting for at least two more who Dutroux has admitted kidnapping a year ago .
" Dutroux has admitted killing Weinstein after a disagreement between the accomplices in an affair of truck theft , " Bourlet said .
Another four people were also questioned at the weekend but had not been detained , Bourlet added .
Anne Thily , public prosecutor in the eastern city of Liege where Julie and Melissa lived , said this was a major case involving some 50 investigators -- including two from the U.S. Federal Bureau of Investigation .
French 1997 budget due around September 10 - Juppe .
BREGANCON , France 1996-08-25
Prime Minister Alain Juppe said on Sunday the draft 1997 budget and plans for funding the social security system would be pubished around September 10 .
" The texts are practically ready , " he told reporters after a weekend of talks with President Jacques Chirac in a Riviera fortress .
The budget had been widely expected a week or so later .
-- Paris newsroom +331 4221 5452
19 die as bus falls in river in Pakistani Kashmir .
MUZAFFARABAD , Pakistan 1996-08-25
A bus fell from a mountain road into a river in Pakistan-ruled Azad ( free ) Kashmir on Sunday , killing at least 19 people and injuring 11 , police said .
They said dead included five refugees from the Indian-ruled part of Kashmir , where Moslem militants have waged a separatist revolt since early 1990 .
The police said 14 of the 45 passengers on the bus died instantly when the vehicle fell into Kunar river from a narrow road leading from the state capital Muzaffarabad to the nearby Pakistani town of Garhi Habibullah northwest .
Five people died later in hospital .
North Afghan highway opening put off , radio says .
ISLAMABAD 1996-08-25
The planned reopening of Afghanistan 's main northern Salang highway as a result of peace talks with an opposition alliance has been put off until Wednesday , official Kabul Radio said on Sunday .
The embattled Afghan government said last week that the Kabul-Salang highway would be opened on Monday or Tuesday following talks with the Supreme Coordination Council alliance led by Jumbish-i-Milli movement of powerful opposition warlord General Abdul Rashid Dostum .
The radio said on Sunday the postponement of the opening had been made due to " precautions " .
It did not elaborate .
The Salang highway , Afghanistan 's main route to Central Asia , has been controlled by Dostum since he began fighting President Burhanuddin Rabbani 's government in Kabul in January 1994 in alliance with Hezb-i-Islami party leader Gulbuddin Hekmatyar , then prime minister but rival to the president .
Hekmatyar rejoined the government as prime minister last June under a peace pact with Rabbani and has since been trying to persuade other opposition factions to follow suit .
Earlier this month , Jumbish denied a Kabul government statement that the two sides had agreed to a ceasefire in the north .
Students burn Hasina effigy , battle police .
Anis Ahmed
DHAKA 1996-08-25
Students backed by opposition parties battled police and burned an effigy of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina during a strike in the north Bangladeshi town of Bogra on Sunday .
The strikers barricaded streets , attacked the local office of the ruling Awami League , fought running battles with police and set alight hundreds of copies of the popular " Janakantha " newspaper , alleging it was pro-government .
Police used batons and teargas to try to disperse students who were throwing stones and home-made bombs , witnesses said .
The strike , called by the main opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party ( BNP ) , to denounce the deaths of four students killed by police over the last few days , coincided with a visit to the area by Hasina .
Local officials said one policeman was killed by gunshots during clashes with pro-opposition students on Thursday .
Hasina told a cross section of people at the Bogra police headquarters on Sunday that the government had already suspended three police officers and ordered a judicial probe into the violent incidents .
The prime minister offered financial grants to the families of those killed , ordered the best possible medical care for the injured and urged Bogra residents to call off the strike .
Opposition legislators walked out of parliament in Dhaka on Sunday denouncing " unprecedented police barbarity " against opposition students and supporters .
They renewed their call for the resignation of Home ( Interior ) Minister Rafiqul Islam .
Hundreds of police raided the Dhaka university on Sunday , arresting nearly 30 outsiders who had been living in student dormitories and seizing weapons , university officials said .
Police stormed ten residence halls on the campus , flushed out people at gunpoint and searched their baggage .
They seized revolvers , sawn-off rifles , shotguns and knives .
The students were later allowed to return .
The swoop followed the resignation of the university 's Vice-Chancellor Dr. Emajuddin Ahmed on Saturday over the deteriorating law and order situation on the campus .
Authorities closed down the 28,000-student university on Wednedsay following gunbattles between students and police .
Police said they fought armed activists from the BNP , headed by former prime minister Begum Khaleda Zia .
Hasina told police the home ministry had already given a " blanket order " to arrest terrorists and possessors of illegal firearms irrespective of their political identities .
Nearly 100 students have been injured in the clashes in Dhaka and Bogra , police told reporters .
16 die as bus crashes in Pakistani Kashmir .
MUZAFFARABAD , Pakistan 1996-08-25
At least 16 people were killed and several injured on Sunday when a bus fell from a mountain road into a ravine on a river bank in Pakistan-ruled Azad ( free ) Kashmir , police said .
They said 14 out of 45 passengers on the bus died instantly when the vehicle fell from the narrow road while on its way from the state capital Muzaffarabad to the nearby Pakistani town of Garhi Habibullah in the northwest .
Two died later in hospital .
FEATURE - Fertile Ukraine faces drought of cash and rain .
Irene Marushko
BATKIVSHCHYNA COLLECTIVE FARM , Ukraine 1996-08-26
Four shiny new green-and-yellow John Deere combines parked at this 1,750-hectare ( 4,325-acre ) farm in the grain-growing regions south of Kiev do n't fill its chief agronomist with enthusiasm .
" They did a good job this year , but they need good diesel and good engine oil , " said Ivan Odnosum . "
God help us if there is a breakdown , " he said of the machinery , loaned to the farm after the Ukrainian government bought it earlier this year .
The country 's grain harvest this year is forecast to fall by more than 23 percent to only 28 million tonnes and two harsh factors are to blame .
A drought scoured the steppes in May and June , stunting the growing wheat .
And the farming sector , making the painful transition from Soviet central planning to a market economy simply has no money .
Ukraine 's black soil is so fertile that a diplomat described it as " rich enough to grow rubber boots " .
But recently Ukraine has been losing its reputation as a breadbasket of Europe , earned in the years before brutal forced collectivisation under Soviet dictator Josef Stalin .
" The wheat will not be of a good quality this year , " said Hryhory Borsuk , a scientist at the Mironivka Wheat Institute , run by the Ukrainian Academy of Agrarian Sciences .
" The temperature on the ground reached 62 decrees Celsius ( 143.60 Fahrenheit ) this summer .
We 've never seen anything so bad , " he said in an interview in his office , unlit since the government cut off electricity because of unpaid power bills .
The harvest is gathered in the dry areas , but rainfall in Western Ukraine has delayed harvesting there .
While Mironivka 's scientists , some unpaid for months , carry on developing new strains of wheat resistant to Ukraine 's extreme continental climate , Borsuk said the lack of cash in Ukraine 's agricultural sector is as bad as the drought .
Collective farms and Ukraine 's nascent private farming sector have no money for fertiliser , no money for herbicides and pesticides , no money to repair old or buy new machinery , no money for fuel , and none to buy good seed .
This year 's harvest is down from last year 's 36.5 million tonne harvest , which in turn compares with 50 million tonnes in 1990 , the year before independence .
The decline is all the worse for people who recall wasteful Soviet times , when the Kremlin imported grain but priced bread so cheaply that people bought it to feed their pigs .
" Agriculture is very expensive , and there are no solutions to our problems on the horizon , " said Odnosum .
He said his farm , its 260 workers now readying the fields for winter wheat sowing , expected the land to yield 5.2 tonnes per hectare ( 2.5 acres ) but ended up with 3.9 tonnes -- still better than the national average of 2.11 tonnes per hectare this year .
" We did not have money for fertiliser , we 're in debt for fuel , and we 're borrowing diesel , " Odnosum said .
A few kilometres ( miles ) down the two-lane road which passes Odnosum 's farm , where the occasional horse-drawn buggy passes by , is the 1,700-hectare ( 4,200-acre ) Shevchenko collective farm , built next to a village still neat and tidy despite post-Soviet decay .
Chief Accountant Natalya Sypron said the collective is strapped for cash , earlier this year bartering 220 tonnes of grain for diesel to fuel six rickety grain combines and tractors badly in need of repairs and basic maintenance .
The average family earns 160-200 million karbovanets a year ( $ 800 - $ 1,000 ) -- but many have not been paid in months , Soprun said . "
People are working out of their own dedication . "
Borsuk said the farm sector has two options : " We can sit down and cry , or we can do something . "
He said the government plans to increase the sowing of the winter wheat which will be harvested next year .
Planted in late summer and early autumn , the grain is Ukraine 's largest export item and traditionally grows better than summer wheat in Ukraine 's soil .
Further plans , he said , called for full provision of resources like fertiliser and herbicides for 25 percent of Ukraine 's arable land next year , for 50 percent in 1998 and 100 percent of the land in 1999 .
" If we follow this we 'll be able to sell 10 million tonnes of grain by the year 2000 , " Borkus said .
The government has been trying to phase out huge subsidies to the farm sector , and in a move back to pre-Soviet days has given up to 50 hectares ( 124 acres ) of land to some 36,000 private farmers willing to go it alone .
Collective farms will last for the next few years , because most private farms now only produce enough to feed themselves with maybe a little extra to sell , said one private farmer : " In the future , maybe , but it 's better not to hurry .
" Collectivisation brought us a lot of pain .
And it went too fast .
Privatising too quickly can also have a negative outcome . "
Gencor swells profit despite setbacks .
Melanie Cheary
JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-26
Gencor Ltd on Monday said it had swelled its year attributable profit and streamlined operations to strengthen it for the current financial year despite a variety of divisional setbacks .
Announcing the group 's results for the year ended June 30 , chairman Brian Gilbertson said : " Happily the strong improvement in financial performance is not an illusion arising from the recent weakness of the rand relative to the dollar . "
Gencor raised attributable earnings to 1,803 million rand from 1,003 million rand previously - in dollar terms an increase to $ 469 million from $ 279 million - and won despite the group 's Impala Platinum Holdings Ltd posting dismal results .
" Not everything has gone well .
We 've had substantial production difficulties at a number of our operations .
The most obvious one with the greatest effect on the corporation was at Impala where we had the furnace failure , " Gilbertson said .
Implats posted year attributable profit of 176 million rand from 281 million previously .
Not only did the company lock in 3.92 rand per dollar in February / March , but it suffered output losses due to a furnace shutdown last August .
The rand was last bid at 4.5350 against the dollar .
Nor was Implats the only operation to fail output targets .
Ingwe Coal Corporation Ltd was hit hard by heavy rains .
It forfeited nearly one million tonnes of production to flooding at its mines in Mpumulanga province .
But Gilbertson said the greatest gloom in the year came from the European Commission 's blocking of Implats ' proposed merger with Lonrho Plc 's platinum interests .
" The big disappointment for the year was the failure of the platinum merger .
From Gencor 's perspective we are taking the position that it is not on , " Gilbertson said .
Looking ahead to the current financial year , he said that Gencor would boost earnings further .
" Gencor is well placed to take up the challenges of the future .
The group is soundly structured and prudently financed and is blessed with an excellent portfolio of world-class businesses .
I think we can look forward to further growth " .
Citing the disposal of Gencor 's stake in industrial holdings group Malbak Ltd for one billion rand among other smaller disposals , Gilbertson said Gencor had pruned its portfolio to concentrate on core assets .
" We 've tried to clean up our overall portfolio by disposing of non-core assets .
The biggest of those was Malbak .
Overall a very substantial pruning ...
leaving Gencor clearly structured along commodity lines , " Gilbertson said .
He added that the group still had about 85 million rand after tax invested in various shares , which were market for disposal when required .
Referring to Gencor 's increased 41.5 percent stake in Ingwe , Gilbertson said the group would wait for coal shares to be cheaper before considering snapping up more .
" I think we would have liked to have more of Ingwe but it 's the question of adding value .
When we bought the shares we bought ...
at quite a bit lower than the price is now ...
maybe if we just wait another few years for the next downturn in coal . "
Finally , Gilbertson said a growing proportion of Gencor 's income was coming from offshore and unlisted investments .
-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003
Advanced Medical buying IVAC Medical .
SAN DIEGO 1996-08-26
Advanced Medical Inc. said Monday it will buy IVAC Medical Systems Inc. , a former Eli Lilly & Co .
unit , for about $ 400 million in cash , creating one of the world 's largest makers of intravenous infusion therapy products .
Under the agreement , IVAC and Advanced Medical 's wholly owned subsidiary , IMED Corp. , will merge to form a new company that will develop and manufacture infusion pumps that regulate the amount of intravenous fluid being administered to a patient , as well as proprietary disposable products .
The combined company will have estimated revenues of $ 353 million .
Advanced Medical , through IMED , is already one of the nation 's largest developers and manufacturers of intravenous infusion pumps and proprietary disposable products .
It has sales in 38 foreign countries .
San Diego-based IVAC is a major provider of infusion systems and related technologies to the health-care industry .
It has manufacturing plants in San Diego ; Creedmoor , N.C. ; Hampshire , England ; and Tijuana , Mexico , and distributes its prodcuts in more than 120 countries .
Eli Lilly sold IVAC on Dec. 31 , 1994 to DLJ Merchant Banking Partners LP , River Medical Inc. and other investors .
Advanced Medical said it expects to take an unspecified one-time charge to pay for the merger .
It did not say when the charge would be taken .
" The addition of IVAC is expected to contribute to financial results in the full second quarter of 1997 , " the companies said .
The merger will add to both companies ' historical leadership in infusion therapy and technology-based drug delivery devices , they said .
In 1968 , IVAC introduced the world 's first infusion therapy monitoring device .
A year later IVAC improved its system with the addition of an IV pump that regulated the flow of liquids through positive pressure .
IMED introduced the world 's first volumetric infusion pump in 1974 .
IMED had profits of $ 1.7 million , or 6 cents per fully diluted common share , on $ 53.9 million in revenues in the first half of 1996 .
Excluding the effect of a one-time restructuring charge of $ 17.4 million , IVAC had net income of $ 4.2 million on net sales of $ 112.8 million for the 1996 first half .
Advanced Medical reported profits of $ 8.4 million on sales of $ 29.2 million in the quarter ended June 30 .
William J. Mercer , IVAC president and chief executive officer , will become the president and CEO of Advanced Medical .
He led the transition of IVAC to a privately held company and was previously senior vice president at Mallinckrodt Group Inc .
Joseph Kuhn , Advanced Medical and IMED president , will become the new company 's executive vice president and chief financial officer .
The deal is expected to close by the first quarter of 1997 , subject to regulatory approval .
It has already been approved by both companies ' boards .
Dow rises on Philip Morris , other stocks lower .
NEW YORK 1996-08-26
The Dow Jones industrial average opened slightly higher on Monday , boosted by Philip Morris , which gained four to 92 .
Other shares were slightly lower , mirroring bonds .
The Dow was up eight to 5,731 , while the NASDAQ Index was off fractionally to 1,143 and the S&P Index down one to 666 .
New York Stock Exchange advances lagged declines by 476/698 while NASDAQ advances led declines 837/763 .
The 30-year U.S. Treasury bond was off 2/32 to yield 6.96 percent .
RUGBY LEAGUE - ST HELENS CLINCH SUPER LEAGUE TITLE .
ST HELENS , England 1996-08-26
St Helens completed their first league and Challenge Cup double in 30 years on Monday when they thrashed Warrington 66-14 to clinch the inaugural Super League title .
St Helens secured the two points they needed in the last game of the season at Knowsley Road to win their first championship since 1975 and their first double since 1966 .
In rain-soaked conditions , centre Alan Hunte grabbed a hat-trick of tries , while Tommy Martyn , Anthony Sullivan and Paul Newlove each scored two .
Captain and goalkicker Bobbie Goulding scored 18 points .
St Helens 's triumph marked the end of Wigan 's seven-year reign as British champions .
St Helens needed to win on Monday to take the title -- a defeat or draw would have allowed Wigan their eighth consecutive championship .
They were also the toast of London Broncos , who managed to scrape into the top four ahead of Warrington and qualify for the end-of-season play-offs .
Bradford finished third .
St Helens have now set their sights on taking the treble by winning the end-of-season premiership which begins with next Sunday 's semifinal against London .
RALLYING - 1,000 LAKES RALLY RESULT / WORLD CHAMPIONSHIP STANDINGS .
JYVASKLYA , Finland 1996-08-26
Result of the 1,000
Lakes Rally which ended on Monday :
1. Tommi Makinen ( Finland ) Mitsubishi Lancer 4 hours 4 minutes
13 seconds
2. Juha Kankkunen ( Finland ) Toyota Celica 46 seconds behind
3. Jarmo Kytolehto ( Finland ) Ford Escort 2:37
4. Marcus Gronholm ( Finland ) Toyota Celica 2:42
5. Kenneth Eriksson ( Sweden ) Subaru Impreza 3:22
6. Thomas Radstrom ( Sweden ) Toyota Celica 4.09
7. Sebastian Lindholm ( Finland ) Ford Escort 5:17
8. Lasse Lampi ( Finland ) Mitsubishi Lancer 12:01
9. Rui Madeira ( Portugal ) Toyota Celica 16:34
10. Angelo Medeghini ( Italy ) Subaru Impreza 18:28
RALLYING - MAKINEN STEPS UP TITLE BID WITH LAKES WIN .
JYVASKYLA , Finland 1996-08-26
Tommi Makinen took a significant step towards becoming world rally champion with a brilliant victory in the 1000 Lakes Rally on Monday .
Mitsubishi driver Makinen stopped experienced fellow Finn Juha Kankkunen in his tracks on the final day of the 1,452-km rally , doubling his lead on the first two decisive stages .
" This was the most difficult win - three days at 125 percent effort , " said Makinen , whose success completed his 1,000 Lakes hat-trick .
Kankkunen was runner-up in his Toyota as Finland 's Jarmo Kytolehto produced a remarkable drive to finish third in his Ford .
Swede Kenneth Eriksson kept Subaru in the hunt for the manufacturers ' title with fifth place in spite of a gearbox problem that nearly forced him off the road close to the end of the event .
Maakinen 's and Mitsubishi 's positions were strengthened by the late retirement of Spain 's Carlos Sainz when his Ford gearbox failed .
Makinen , with 95 points , now leads his nearest championship rival , Sainz , by 32 points .
RALLYING - MAKINEN WINS 1,000 LAKES RALLY .
JYVASKYLA , Finland 1996-08-26
Tommi Makinen of Finland , driving a Mitsubishi , on Monday won the 1,000 Lakes Rally , sixth round of the world championship .
SOCCER - SHARPE HITS WINNER TO EASE PRESSURE ON LEEDS .
LEEDS , England 1996-08-26
Winger Lee Sharpe hit a superb strike from the edge of the penalty area to give Leeds their first win of the season on Monday and leave hapless Wimbledon anchored at the bottom of the England premier league .
Sharpe repaid a huge slice of the 4.5 million pound ( $ 6.98 million ) fee Leeds handed Manchester United for his services with a top-draw second-half goal to hand Wimbledon their third successive defeat .
Ian Rush , the Welsh striker signed from Liverpool in the close season , set up the goal , feeding Sharpe as he galloped forward and the former England winger cut inside onto his unfavoured right foot to arc a shot into the right-hand corner of the net .
The only goal of the match also brought some relief for under-fire Leeds manager Howard Wilkinson following the team 's poor start to the season .
Home fans frequently booed their own side until Sharpe turned the jeers to cheers .
SOCCER - ENGLISH PREMIER LEAGUE SUMMARY .
LONDON 1996-08-26
Summary of Monday 's English
premier league soccer match :
Leeds 1 ( Sharpe 58th minute ) Wimbledon 0 .
Halftime 0-0 .
Attendance 25,860 .
SOCCER - ENGLISH PREMIER LEAGUE RESULT / STANDINGS .
LONDON 1996-08-26
Result of an English premier
league soccer match on Monday :
Leeds 1 Wimbledon 0
Standings ( tabulated under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , against , points ) :
Sheffield Wednesday 3 3 0 0 6 2 9
Chelsea 3 2 1 0 3 0 7
Arsenal 3 2 0 1 4 2 6
Aston Villa 3 2 0 1 4 2 6
Manchester United 3 1 2 0 7 4 5
Sunderland 3 1 2 0 4 1 5
Liverpool 3 1 2 0 5 3 5
Everton 3 1 2 0 4 2 5
Tottenham 3 1 2 0 3 1 5
Nottingham Forest 3 1 1 1 5 5 4
Leeds 3 1 1 1 4 5 4
West Ham 3 1 1 1 3 4 4
Leicester 3 1 1 1 2 3 4
Newcastle 3 1 0 2 3 4 3
Middlesbrough 3 0 2 1 4 5 2
Derby 3 0 2 1 4 6 2
Southampton 3 0 1 2 2 4 1
Blackburn 3 0 1 2 2 5 1
Coventry 3 0 1 2 1 6 1
Wimbledon 3 0 0 3 0 6 0
CRICKET - PAKISTAN 'S WASIM AKRAM JOINS 300 CLUB .
LONDON 1996-08-26
Wasim Akram 's three-wicket haul
for Pakistan in England 's second innings at The Oval on Monday
gave him his 300th test match wicket .
Wasim becomes the 11th player to join the 300-club of
bowlers and the second Pakistani , after Imran Khan , to achieve
the feat .
Other cricketers who have taken over 300 Test wickets :
Kapil Dev ( India ) 434 wickets , 131 Tests
Richard Hadlee ( New Zealand ) 431 , 86
Ian Botham ( England ) 383 , 102
Malcolm Marshall ( West Indies ) 376 , 81
Imran Khan ( Pakistan ) 362 , 88
Dennis Lillee ( Australia ) 355 , 70
Bob Willis ( England ) 325 , 90
Lance Gibbs ( West Indies ) 309 , 79
Fred Trueman ( England ) 307 , 67
Courtney Walsh ( West Indies ) 309 , 82
Wasim Akram ( Pakistan ) 300 , 70
CRICKET - ENGLISH COUNTY CHAMPIONSHIP STANDINGS .
LONDON 1996-08-26
English County Championship
cricket standings after Monday 's matches ( tabulated under
played , won , lost , drawn , batting bonus points , bowling bonus
points , total points ) :
Essex 13 7 2 4 45 43 212
Kent 14 7 1 6 42 40 212
Derbyshire 13 7 2 4 41 43 208
Leicestershire 13 6 1 6 43 45 202
Surrey 13 6 1 6 37 48 199
Yorkshire 14 6 5 3 41 46 192
Warwickshire 13 6 4 3 32 43 180
Middlesex 13 5 5 3 26 45 160
Sussex 13 5 6 2 27 43 156
Somerset 13 4 5 4 27 49 152
Worcestershire 13 3 3 7 33 48 150
Glamorgan 13 4 5 4 36 32 144
Hampshire 13 3 5 5 28 46 137
Gloucestershire 14 3 6 5 19 47 129
Northamptonshire 13 2 6 5 30 43 120
Lancashire 13 1 4 8 38 37 115
Nottinghamshire 13 1 6 6 34 40 108
Durham 14 0 9 5 22 50 87
CRICKET - ENGLISH COUNTY CHAMPIONSHIP RESULTS .
LONDON 1996-08-26
Results on the final day of
four-day English County Championship cricket matches on Monday :
At Colchester : Essex beat Gloucestershire by an innings and
64 runs .
Gloucestershire 280 and 188 ( J. Russell 57 , M. Lynch 50 ;
N. Williams 5-43 ) .
Essex 532-8 declared ( G. Gooch 111 , R. Irani 91 ,
P. Prichard 88 , D. Robinson 72 ; M. Alleyne 4-80 ) .
Essex 24 points ,
Gloucestershire 3 .
At Cardiff : Match drawn .
Kent 323-5 declared ( C. Hooper 77 ,
D. Fulton 64 , N. Llong 63 , M. Walker 59 ) and second innings
forfeited .
Glamorgan first innings forfeited and 273-5 ( H. Morris
118 , A. Cottey 70 ) .
Glamorgan 5 points , Kent 6 .
At Northampton : Northamptonshire beat Sussex by 6 wickets .
Sussex 389 and 112 .
Northamptonshire 361 and 142-4 .
Northamptonshire 24 points , Sussex 8 .
At Trent Bridge : Match abandoned as a draw - rain .
Nottinghamshire 446-9 declared and 53-0 .
Surrey 128-4 declared
( A. Brown 56 not out ) .
Nottinghamshire 8 points , Surrey 7 .
At Worcester : Match drawn .
Warwickshire 310 and 162-4
declared .
Worcestershire 205-9 declared ( K. Spiring 52 ; A. Giles
3-12 ) and 164-4 ( P. Weston 52 ) .
Worcestershire 8 points ,
Warwickshire 10 .
At Headingley : Match drawn .
Yorkshire 529-8 declared
( C. White 181 , R. Blakey 109 not out , M. Moxon 66 , M. Vaughan 57 ) .
Lancashire 323 ( N. Fairbrother 86 , M. Watkinson 64 ; D. Gough 4-53 )
and 231-7 ( N. Speak 77 , N. Fairbrother 55 ; D. Gough 4-48 ) .
Yorkshire 11 points , Lancashire 8 .
At Leicester : Match drawn .
Leicestershire 353 .
Hampshire 137
( G. Parsons 4-36 ) and 135-9 .
Leicestershire 11 points , Hampshire
7.
CRICKET - PAKISTAN BEAT ENGLAND BY NINE WICKETS IN THIRD TEST .
LONDON 1996-08-26
Pakistan beat England by nine wickets on the fifth day of the third and final test at The Oval on Monday to win the series 2-0 .
Scores : England 326 and 242 ; Pakistan 521-8 declared and 48-1 .
CRICKET - ENGLAND V PAKISTAN FINAL TEST SCOREBOARD .
LONDON 1996-08-26
Scoreboard on the last day of the
third and final test between England and Pakistan at the Oval on
Monday :
England first innings 326 ( J. Crawley 106 , G. Thorpe 54 ; Waqar
Younis 4-95 )
Pakistan first innings 521-8 declared ( Saeed Anwar 176 ,
Salim Malik 100 not out , Ijaz Ahmed 61 )
England second innings ( overnight 74-0 )
M. Atherton c Inzamam-ul-Haq b Mushtaq Ahmed 43
A. Stewart c Asif Mujtaba b Mushtaq Ahmed 54
N. Hussain lbw b Mushtaq Ahmed 51
G. Thorpe c Wasim Akram b Mushtaq Ahmed 9
J. Crawley c Aamir Sohail b Wasim Akram 19
N. Knight c and b Mushtaq Ahmed 8
C. Lewis lbw b Waqar Younis 4
D. Cork b Mushtaq Ahmed 26
R. Croft c Ijaz Ahmed b Wasim Akram 6
I. Salisbury not out 0
A. Mullally b Wasim Akram 0
Extras ( b-6 lb-2 w-1 nb-13 ) 22
Total 242
Fall of wickets : 1-96 2-136 3-166 4-179 5-187 6-205 7-220
8-238 9-242
Bowling : Wasim Akram 15.4-1-67-3 , Waqar Younis 18-3-55-1 ,
Mushtaq Ahmed 37-10-78-6 , Aamir Sohail 2-1-4-0 , Mohammad Akram
10-3-30-0
Pakistan second innings
Saeed Anwar c Knight b Mullally 1
Aamir Sohail not out 29
Ijaz Ahmed not out 13
Extras ( nb-5 ) 5
Total ( for one wicket ) 48
Fall of wicket : 1-7
Bowling : Cork 3-0-15-0 , Mullally 3-0-24-1 , Croft 0.4-0-9-0
Result : Pakistan won by 9 wickets
First test : Lord 's - Pakistan won by 164 runs
Second test : Headingley - Drawn
Pakistan win series 2-0
CRICKET - PAKISTAN NEED 48 RUNS TO WIN THIRD AND FINAL TEST .
LONDON 1996-08-26
England were dismissed for 242 in their second innings on the fifth day of the third and final test at The Oval on Monday leaving Pakistan requiring 48 runs to win .
Pakistan lead the series 1-0 .
RUGBY LEAGUE - EUROPEAN SUPER LEAGUE RESULT / FINALS STANDINGS .
LONDON 1996-08-26
Result of a European Super League
rugby league match on Monday :
St Helens 66 Warrington 14
Final standings ( tabulated under played , won , drawn , lost ,
points for , against , total points ) :
St Helens 22 20 0 2 950 455 40 - champions
Wigan 22 19 1 2 902 326 39
Bradford 22 17 0 5 767 409 34
London 22 12 1 9 611 462 25
Warrington 22 12 0 10 569 565 24
Halifax 22 10 1 11 667 576 21
Sheffield 22 10 0 12 599 730 20
Oldham 22 9 1 12 473 681 19
Castleford 22 9 0 13 548 599 18
Leeds 22 6 0 16 555 745 12
Paris 22 3 1 18 398 795 7
Workington 22 2 1 19 325 1021 5
SOCCER - ENGLISH AND SCOTTISH LEAGUE FIXTURES - AUG 30-SEPT 1 .
LONDON 1996-08-26
English and Scottish league soccer
fixtures for August 30 to September 1 :
Friday , August 30 :
English division one - West Bromwich v Sheffield United .
English division three - Swansea v Lincoln .
Saturday , August 31 :
English division one - Birmingham v Barnsley , Bradford v
Tranmere , Grimsby v Portsmouth , Huddersfield v Crystal Palace ,
Manchester City v Charlton , Norwich v Wolverhampton , Oldham v
Ipswich , Port Vale v Oxford , Reading v Stoke , Southend v
Swindon .
English division two - Blackpool v Wycombe , Bournemouth v
Peterborough , Bristol Rovers v Stockport , Bury v Bristol City ,
Crewe v Watford , Gillingham v Chesterfield , Luton v Rotherham ,
Millwall v Burnley , Notts County v York , Plymouth v Preston ,
Shrewsbury v Brentford , Walsall v Wrexham .
English division three - Brighton v Scunthorpe , Cambridge v
Cardiff , Colchester v Hereford , Doncaster v Darlington , Fulham v
Carlisle , Hull v Barnet , Leyton Orient v Hartlepool , Mansfield v
Rochdale , Scarborough v Northampton , Torquay v Exeter , Wigan v
Chester .
Scottish division one - East Fife v Clydebank , Greenock
Morton v Falkir , Partick v St Mirren , St Johnstone v
Airdrieonians , Stirling v Dundee .
Scottish division two - Ayr v Berwick , Clyde v Queen of the
South , Dumbarton v Brechin , Livingston v Hamilton , Stenhousemuir
v Stranraer .
Scottish division three - Albion v Cowdenbeath , Arbroath v
East Stirling , Inverness v Alloa , Montrose v Ross County ,
Queen 's Park v Forfar .
Sunday , September 1 :
English division one - Queens Park Rangers v Bolton .
SOCCER - COSTA RICA AND CHILE DRAW 1-1 IN FRIENDLY .
LIBERIA , Costa Rica 1996-08-26
Costa Rica and Chile
drew 1-1 ( halftime 1-0 ) in a friendly soccer international on
Sunday .
Scorers :
Costa Rica - Ronaldo Gonzalez ( 10th minute , penalty
Chile - Marcelo Salas ( 80th )
Attendance : 8,000
SOCCER - SEYCHELLES FAIL IN BID FOR HISTORIC VICTORY .
Mark Gleeson
JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-26
The tiny islands of the Seychelles failed to make soccer history at the weekend when they bowed out of the preliminary rounds of the African Nations Cup .
Trailing fellow Indian Ocean islanders Mauritius 1-0 from the first leg , they were held to a 1-1 draw at home on Saturday despite playing against 10 men for most of the match .
The 2-1 aggregate took Mauritius into the group phase of the qualifiers for the 1998 finals , and kept up the Seychelles ' record of never having won an official match in their 10 years of FIFA membership .
The Seychelles must have thought they were on course for a historic breakthrough when Mauritian midfielder Andre Caboche was sent off for a crude tackle in the 19th minute .
But the visitors responded to the setback immediately -- veteran striker Ashley Mocude scoring a minute later to give them a two-goal aggregate lead .
Although Danny Rose 's 50th-minute equaliser gave the Seychellois renewed hope they could not find the net again and were eliminated .
Mauritius now play in group seven of the qualifiers against Malawi , Mozambique and favourites Zambia .
Namibia , who drew 0-0 with Botswana in their first leg , won the second leg in Windhoek 6-0 to stretch their unbeaten run to eight matches and continue their remarkable progress on the African soccer stage .
They now play in group five with Cameroon , Gabon and Kenya .
German-based striker Bachirou Salou returned home to Togo to score the decisive only goal of their tie against Congo .
Salou , who plays for MSV Duisburg in the Bundesliga , scored in the 53rd minute of Sunday 's match in Lome for a 1-0 aggregate win which takes his side into group six , where they will meet Liberia , Tanzania and Zaire .
Ethiopia needed a penalty shoot-out in Addis Ababa to overcome Uganda after a 2-2 aggregate scoreline .
Both legs ended 1-1 before Ethiopia won the spot kick decider 4-2 .
Uganda 's elimination follows their humiliating 5-1 aggregate defeat by Angola in June 's World Cup qualifying preliminaries .
The other preliminary round second leg match , between Mauritania and Benin in Nouakchott , was postponed until Friday .
Benin won the first leg 4-1 .
SOCCER - AFRICAN NATIONS CUP COLLATED RESULTS .
JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-26
Collated results of African Nations Cup preliminary round , second leg matches played at the weekend :
Ethiopia 1 Uganda 1
2-2 on aggregate .
Ethiopia win 4-2 on penalties
Mauritania v Benin postponed to Friday
Benin lead 4-1 from the first leg
Namibia 6 Botswana 0
Namibia win 6-0 on aggregate
Seychelles 1 Mauritius 1
Mauritius win 2-1 on aggregate
Togo 1 Congo 0
Togo win 1-0 on aggregaete
Central African Republic walkover v Burundi
Winners progress to qualifying groups to start in October .
SOCCER - UKRAINIAN PREMIER DIVISION RESULTS / STANDINGS .
KIEV 1996-08-26
Results of Ukraine premier division
matches played at the weekend :
Dynamo Kiev 5 Kremin Kremenchuk 0
Vorskla Poltava 2 Nyva Ternopil 1
Torpedo Zaporizhya 2 Shakhtar Donetsk 1
Kryvbas Kryvy Rig 1 Karpaty Lviv 2
Prykarpattya Ivano-Frankivsk 0 Zirka-Nibas Kirovohrad 0
Chornomorets Odessa 2 Metalurg Zaporizhya 1
Dnipro Dnipropetrovsk 2 CSKA Kiev 1
Standings ( tabulated under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , against , points ) :
Dynamo 6 5 0 1 16 2 15
Vorskla 6 4 2 0 11 3 14
Dnipro 6 4 1 1 13 6 13
Chornomorets 6 4 1 1 11 7 13
Shakhtar 6 3 2 1 10 3 11
Metalurg 6 3 2 1 9 6 11
Karpaty 6 3 1 2 9 5 10
Zirka-Nibas 6 3 1 2 6 8 10
Torpedo 6 3 1 2 8 7 10
Tavria 5 2 0 3 3 7 6
Nyva Ternopil 6 2 0 4 4 11 6
CSKA 6 1 1 4 4 7 4
Kryvbas 6 1 1 4 5 9 4
Nyva Vinnytsya 5 0 2 3 1 7 2
Prykarpattya 6 0 2 4 4 13 2
Kremin 6 0 1 5 1 14 1
SWIMMING - POPOV IN `SERIOUS CONDITION ' AFTER STABBING .
MOSCOW 1996-08-26
Russian double Olympic swimming champion Alexander Popov was in a serious condition on Monday after being stabbed on a Moscow street .
A doctor said it was too early to say whether Popov , the only man to retain the Olympic 50 and 100 metres freestyle titles , would return to top-level sport .
" His condition is serious , " said Rimma Maslova , deputy chief doctor of Hospital No 31 in the Russian capital . "
But he is conscious and is talking and smiling . "
Maslova told Reuters she was not an expert in sports medicine , but said it was too early to judge Popov 's chances of returning to competitive swimming .
Popov , who won gold in the 50 and 100 metres freestyle at the recent Atlanta Olympics , was stabbed in the abdomen late on Saturday after an argument with a group of roadside watermelon sellers in south-west Moscow .
Maslova said the wound had affected a lung and a kidney .
Doctors operated on Popov , 24 , for three hours .
Popov told NTV television on Sunday he was in no danger and promised he would be back in the pool shortly . "
There 's no need to worry .
We 're going to be walking soon -- and swimming , " he insisted cheerfully from his bed in the intensive care unit .
Interfax news agency said police had detained one of the attackers .
It said the row started when Popov and a group of his friends were returning from a party .
Vitaly Smirnov , president of the Russian National Olympic Committee , said President Boris Yeltsin had given the swimmer Russia 's top award for his Olympic performance . "
I am not a doctor but I think he is doing all right , " said Smirnov .
Smirnov said the Olympic Committee might ask the government to take measures to protect the country 's best athletes , some of whom have already chosen to live abroad for fear of a surge in crime in post-Soviet Russia .
SOCCER - SLOVAK FIRST DIVISION RESULTS / STANDINGS .
BRATISLAVA 1996-08-26
Results of Slovak first
division soccer matches at the weekend :
Inter Bratislava 0 Slovan Bratislava 2
Chemlon Humenne 0 Tatran Presov 1
Artmedia Petrzalka 0 JAS Bardejov 0
DAC Dunajska Streda 1 Spartak Trnava 3
Dukla Banska Bystrica 3 FC Nitra 0
MSK Zilina 0 FC Kosice 2
Petrimex Prievidza 2 FC Rimavska Sobota 0
Lokomotiva Kosice 2 Kerametal Dubnica 0
Standings ( tabulate under games played , won , drawn , lost ,
goals for , goals against , points ) :
Tatran Presov 4 3 1 0 5 0 10
Dukla Banska Bystrica 4 3 0 1 7 2 9
Slovan Bratislava 4 3 0 1 7 2 9
Petrimex Prievidza 4 3 0 1 4 2 9
Spartak Trnava 4 2 2 0 10 5 8
FC Kosice 4 2 2 0 6 3 8
Artmedia Petrzalka 4 1 3 0 1 0 6
DAC Dunajska Streda 4 2 0 2 5 6 6
FC Rimavska Sobota 4 2 0 2 4 5 6
JAS Bardejov 4 1 2 1 2 2 5
Chemlon Humenne 4 1 1 2 1 2 4
Inter Bratislava 4 1 1 2 4 6 4
Lokomotiva Kosice 4 1 1 2 3 5 4
Kerametal Dubnica 4 0 1 3 3 9 1
FC Nitra 4 0 0 4 1 8 0
MSK Zilina 4 0 0 4 0 6 0
SOCCER - HUNGARY FIRST DIVISION RESULTS / STANDINGS .
BUDAPEST 1996-08-26
Hungarian first division
soccer results and standings from weekend and bank holiday :
Stadler 0 Haladas 0
MTK 3 Ferencvaros 0
Bekescsaba 0 BVSC 1
Csepel 1 Videoton(* ) 1
ZTE 1 Debrecen 5
Siofok 0 Ujpest 2
Vac 0 Vasas 1
Kispest 3 Pecs 1
Standings ( tabulated under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , goals against , points ) :
1. Ujpest TE 3 3 - - 10 2 9
2. MTK 3 3 - - 7 1 9
3. BVSC 3 2 1 - 6 2 7
4. Debrecen 3 2 - 1 10 4 6
5. Bekescsaba 3 2 - 1 6 2 6
6. FTC 3 2 - 1 8 7 6
7. Haladas 3 1 2 - 2 1 5
8. Videoton 3 1 1 1 7 5 4
9. Vasas 3 1 1 1 3 3 4
10. Kispest 3 1 1 1 6 7 4
11. Gyor 3 1 1 1 3 5 4
12. Csepel 3 - 3 - 3 3 3
13. Pecs 3 1 - 2 3 5 3
14. ZTE 3 1 - 2 3 10 3
15. Stadler FC 3 - 1 2 2 6 1
16. III.ker.TVE 3 - 1 2 2 7 1
17. Siofok 3 - - 3 2 7 0
18. Vac 3 - - 3 2 8 0
*Name of Parmalat / Fehervar FC has been changed to Videoton .
-- Budapest newsroom , +361 266 2410
SOCCER - CZECH FIRST DIVISION RESULTS / STANDINGS .
PRAGUE 1996-08-26
Results of the Czech Republic 's
first division soccer matches at the weekend :
Petra Drnovice 1 Slovan Liberec 3
SK Slavia Praha 3 SK Ceske Budejovice 0
FK Jablonec 3 Viktoria Zizkov 1
Banik Ostrava 3 FK Teplice 1
Boby Brno 1 Sigma Olomouc 0
FC Bohemians 0 FC Karvina 2
SK Hradec Kralove 0 Kaucuk Opava 0
Playing Monday : Viktoria Plzen v AC Sparta Praha
Standings ( tabulate under games played , won , drawn , lost ,
goals for , against , points ) :
Boby Brno 3 3 0 0 5 2 9
Banik Ostrava 3 2 0 1 7 3 6
FK Jablonec 3 2 0 1 5 2 6
SK Slavia Praha 3 1 2 0 6 3 5
Kaucuk Opava 3 1 2 0 2 1 5
Sigma Olomouc 3 1 1 1 6 3 4
Petra Drnovice 3 1 1 1 7 5 4
Slovan Liberec 3 1 1 1 5 4 4
FK Teplice 3 1 1 1 3 4 4
FC Karvina 3 1 1 1 3 5 4
SK Ceske Budejovice 3 1 1 1 3 5 4
Viktoria Plzen 2 0 2 0 2 2 2
AC Sparta Praha 2 0 1 1 3 4 1
FC Bohemians 3 0 1 2 1 4 1
Viktoria Zizkov 3 0 1 2 3 8 1
SK Hradec Kralove 3 0 1 2 1 7 1
SOCCER - MEXICAN CHAMPIONSHIP RESULTS / STANDINGS .
MEXICO CITY 1996-08-26
Results of weekend matches
in the Mexican soccer championship :
Atlante 1 Atlas 1
Cruz Azul 2 Leon 2
Guadalajara 5 America 0
Monterrey 2 Veracruz 1
Pachuca 3 Toluca 0
Puebla 2 UNAM 1
Santos 2 Morelia 1
UAG 1 Neza 2
Standings ( tabulated under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , against , points )
Group 1
Puebla 3 3 0 0 7 2 9
Cruz Azul 3 2 1 0 7 3 7
Atlante 3 2 1 0 6 2 7
Neza 3 1 0 2 2 7 3
Veracruz 3 0 1 2 2 6 1
Group 2
Necaxa 3 1 1 1 6 4 4
Pachuca 3 1 1 1 6 7 4
Leon 3 0 3 0 3 3 3
America 3 1 0 2 5 7 3
Morelia 3 0 1 2 3 8 1
Group 3
Atlas 3 2 1 0 7 2 7
Guadalajara 3 2 1 0 7 0 7
Toluca 3 1 0 2 6 5 3
UNAM 3 0 0 3 2 6 0
Group 4
Santos 3 3 0 0 4 1 9
Monterrey 4 1 1 2 2 5 4
Celaya 2 0 2 0 1 1 2
UAG 3 0 0 3 1 8 0
SOCCER - PLAYERS LEAVE MATCH EARLY TO CATCH PLANE .
Brian Homewood
RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-08-26
Two key players left a Brazilian championship match early on Sunday because they had to catch a plane to Russia to play with the national team .
Sao Paulo midfielder Andre and Santos defender Narciso were both substituted during their teams ' game , taken to Sao Paulo airport and flown to Rio de Janeiro in a private jet chartered by the Brazilian Football Confederation ( CBF ) .
At Rio , they joined up with the national team squad for the journey to Moscow , where Brazil will face Russia in a friendly international on Wednesday .
The problem arose because the Sao Paulo-Santos clash was selected as the day 's televised live match , forcing it to be put back three hours from the usual kickoff time .
Santos suffered more from their loss as Narciso 's replacement Jean gave away a penalty from which Sao Paulo scored the decisive goal in a 2-1 win .
Sao Paulo lead the first stage of the championship on goal difference from surprise package Juventude , who beat Internacional 2-1 .
Corinthians , who played in a tournament in Spain last week , also faced a plane marathon as they attempted to keep up with a hectic fixture list .
They were due to leave Spain Monday night , arrive in Sao Paulo on Tuesday morning , catch another plane to the southern city of Curitiba one hour later and then play away to Atletico Paranaense in the Brazilian championship the same evening .
Botafogo striker Tulio , who was overlooked by Zagalo for the tour which also features a game away to the Netherlands on Sunday , scored his third goal in three games as the defending champions beat Bahia 2-1 away .
Tulio , who has been top-scorer in the competition for the last two seasons , has been struggling against injury for most of this year .
SOCCER - ARGENTINE CHAMPIONSHIP RESULTS .
BUENOS AIRES 1996-08-26
Results of matches on the
opening weekend of the Argentine Apertura championship :
Estudiantes 2 Boca Juniors 3
Ferro Carril Oeste 0 Independiente 3
Gimnasia-Jujuy 1 Platense 0
Huracan 0 Lanus 0
Huracan-Corrientes 3 Union 6
Newell 's Old Boys 0 Velez Sarsfield 2
Racing Club 0 Rosario Central 2
River Plate 0 Gimnasia-La Plata 0
San Lorenzo 0 Banfield 1
Playing Monday : Deportivo Espanol v Colon
Note : the Apertura is the first of two championships played
in the Argentine season .
The teams meet each other once in each
tournament .
There is no overall champion .
SOCCER - HONDURAS BEAT CUBA 4-0 IN FRIENDLY .
TEGUCIGALPA 1996-08-26
Honduras beat Cuba 4-0
( halftime 3-0 ) in a friendly soccer international on Sunday .
Scorers : Juan Castro ( 3rd minute ) , Enrique Centeno ( 33rd and
84th ) , Carlos Pavon ( 37th )
SOCCER - BRAZILIAN CHAMPIONSHIP RESULTS / STANDINGS .
RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-08-26
Results of Brazilian
soccer championship matches played at the weekend .
Bahia 1 Botafogo 2
Bragantino 1 Vasco da Gama 2
Cricuma 4 Fluminense 1
Cruzeiro 2 Flamengo 1
Goias 0 Palmeiras 0
Gremio 2 Vitoria 2
Juventude 2 Internacional 1
Parana 3 Guarani 0
Portuguesa 3 Atletico Mineiro 1
Sao Paulo 2 Santos 1
Sport Recife 3 Coritiba 0
Standings ( tabulated under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , against , points ) :
Sao Paulo 4 3 1 0 10 5 10
Juventude 5 3 1 1 5 4 10
Portuguesa 4 3 0 1 8 3 9
Palmeiras 5 2 3 0 8 1 9
Goias 5 2 2 1 7 4 8
Gremio 3 2 1 0 11 4 7
Cruzeiro 3 2 1 0 4 2 7
Sport Recife 5 2 1 2 7 6 7
Parana 4 2 1 2 5 5 7
Flamengo 4 2 0 2 4 4 6
Atletico Mineiro 5 2 0 3 6 7 6
Vasco da Gama 4 2 0 2 6 7 6
Coritiba 5 2 0 3 3 9 6
Botafogo 3 1 2 0 4 3 5
Internacional 4 1 2 1 4 3 5
Criciuma 5 1 2 2 7 8 5
Vitoria 5 1 2 2 5 6 5
Santos 3 1 1 1 3 3 4
Corinthians 4 1 1 2 1 3 4
Bahia 5 1 1 3 5 8 4
Fluminense 4 1 1 2 3 6 4
Atletico Paranaense 3 1 0 2 4 6 3
Guarani 3 0 1 2 1 5 1
Bragantino 4 0 0 4 3 12 0
Note : Top eight teams qualify for the quarter-finals .
If
teams are level on points , positions are determined by the
number of games won .
BASKETBALL - PHILIPPINE PRO-LEAGUE RESULTS .
MANILA 1996-08-26
Results of semi-final round games played on late Sunday in the Philippine Basketball Association second conference , which includes American players :
Formula Shell beat Ginebra San Miguel 89-86 ( 45-46 half-time )
SOCCER - RESULTS OF SOUTH KOREAN PRO-SOCCER GAMES .
SEOUL 1996-08-26
Results of South Korean pro-soccer
games played on Sunday .
Puchon 3 Chonan 0 ( halftime 1-0 )
Pohang 3 Chonbuk 2 ( halftime 0-0 )
Standings after games played on Sunday ( tabulate under -
won , drawn , lost , goals for , goals against , points ) :
W D L G / F G / A P
Puchon 2 1 0 4 0 7
Chonan 2 0 1 9 9 6
Pohang 1 1 1 8 8 4
Ulsan 1 0 1 6 6 3
Anyang 0 3 0 5 5 3
Suwon 0 3 0 3 3 3
Pusan 0 2 0 3 3 2
Chonnam 0 2 1 4 5 2
Chonbuk 0 0 2 2 5 0
BASEBALL - RESULTS OF S. KOREAN PRO-BASEBALL GAMES .
SEOUL 1996-08-26
Results of South Korean
pro-baseball games played on Sunday .
OB 2 Lotte 1
Hanwha 3 Haitai 2
Hyundai 8 Samsung 1
Ssangbangwool 3 LG 1
Standings after games played on Sunday ( tabulate under won ,
drawn , lost , winning percentage , games behind first place )
W D L PCT GB
Haitai 63 2 41 .604 -
Ssangbangwool 58 2 47 .551 5 1/2
Hyundai 56 5 47 .542 6 1/2
Hanwha 56 1 48 .538 7
Samsung 47 5 55 .463 15
Lotte 44 6 53 .456 15 1/2
LG 44 5 58 .435 18
OB 41 6 60 .411 20 1/2
SOCCER - MOROCCAN FIRST DIVISION RESULTS .
RABAT 1996-08-26
Results of Moroccan first division
soccer matches played on Sunday :
Widad Fes 3 Oujda 1
Raja Casablanca 4 Tetouan 0
Jeunesse Massira 0 Widad Casablanca 2
Sporting Sale 0 Meknes 1
Settat 1 Marrakesh 0
Khouribga 3 Mohammedia 0
Sidi Kacem 0 Royal Armed Forces 0
El Jadida 1 Hassania Agadir 0
TENNIS - QUENCH YOUR THIRST - IF YOU CAN AFFORD IT AT U.S. OPEN .
Bill Berkrot
NEW YORK 1996-08-26
A message on television monitors all around the National Tennis Centre reads : " Due to hot weather please seek shade and drink plenty of fluids " -- sound advice until you check out the price of fluids .
Perhaps the advisory was cut off before concluding : " ...and bring plenty of money . "
A small bottle of a garishly-coloured sports drink at the sun-drenched U.S. Open is going for $ 3.75 , while a litre of basic , life-sustaining water will set you back $ 4.00 -- for water ?
" At the Olympics water was only a dollar , and that was the Olympics , " said one incredulous fan , noting that the Atlanta Games had been notorious for price gouging .
U.S. Open officials managed to insult most of the male tennis players last week with their controversial handling of the seeding and draw .
When the tournament began on Monday it was the fans ' turn to be offended .
" That baked lasagna better be good for $ 8.50 , " said New Yorker Rebecca Weinstein , a U.S. Open regular who was eating a sandwich she had brought from home .
A trio of hungry fans at the food court who had already forked over the lasagna money pronounced it good , but Carol Perry chimed in , " The water is ridiculous , they want four dollars for the water , you might as well get a glass of wine . "
Indeed , a nice glass of chardonnay or white zinfandel was going for $ 4.75 , while an imported beer was just a bit more than the water at $ 4.50 .
What 's the message here ? "
Maybe they want us to be alcoholics , " Perry joked before lifting her glass of wine .
Fans will be shelling out $ 12.50 for a hamburger and a large french fries .
And that little snack is guaranteed to make you thirsty .
Make that $ 16.50 .
Even a sandwich as pedestrian as a ham and swiss cheese is going for a whopping $ 8.00 .
Of course , it is served on a tuscan roll .
It must be the cost of flying those rolls over from Tuscany every day that drives up the price of the sandwich .
TENNIS - HUBER AND MALEEVA FALL , UP-AND-COMERS ADVANCE AT OPEN .
Larry Fine
NEW YORK 1996-08-26
Martina Hingis led a youthful charge and Australian Open finalist Anke Huber and Magdalena Maleeva were fallen seeds on Monday in a hot , sunny opening to the U.S. Open tennis championships .
The 15-year-old Hingis , seeded 16th , was honoured to play the first match of the season 's last Grand Slam on Stadium Court but happy to hurry off with a straight-sets victory over the 112th-ranked Angeles Montolio of Spain .
" It was very hot and I did n't want to stay long on the court , " said a cheery Hingis , who had no worries in racing to a 6-1 6-0 victory against the overmatched Spaniard .
Hoping for a longer engagement on the cement at Flushing Meadows were the sixth-seeded Huber of Germany and 12th seed Maleeva of Bulgaria .
Huber , who lost to Monica Seles in the Australian Open final , fell victim to an unfortunate draw in bowing to dangerous floater Amanda Coetzer of South Africa .
Coetzer , ranked 17th , avenged her defeat to Huber in the Australian Open semifinals by winning 6-1 2-6 6-2 .
" I looked at it as not a first round match , just a great challenge for me , " said Coetzer , 24 . "
I was really concentrating on keeping my own momentum and my own rhythm .
" She is tough to play in that way because she plays very up and down .
She played one great game and than a few errors .
The challenge was just for me to keep playing my own game . "
Huber , who reached the final a week ago at Manhattan Beach , could only mourn her luck of the draw .
" I was n't happy when I saw the draw .
She was the first non- seeded player , " said the 21-year-old German . "
It 's always tough to play somebody like that in the first round in a Grand Slam .
" I think I did n't play that bad today .
It was maybe my best first round match in a Grand Slam I ever played . "
Monday brought the best out in U.S. Open rookie Aleksandra Olsza of Poland , ranked 110th .
The 18-year-old Olsza , last year 's Wimbledon junior champion , celebrated her debut in the main draw of the Open by removing Maleeva 6-4 6-2 .
The curtain-raising victories by Hingis and Olsza provided a ringing endorsement for the newest wave of women 's players coming up from the junior ranks .
The Swiss teenager , a twice French Open junior champion and a Wimbledon juniors winner , had already proven her main stage mettle by reaching the quarters at this year 's Australian Open .
" I hope I can get into the last 16 , " said Hingis , seeded to face third seed Arantxa Sanchez Vicario in the fourth round .
Hingis has been working hard on conditioning and has lost eight pounds ( 3.5 kilos ) in advance of the championships .
" There will be tough matches but I hope I can get there , " she said . "
Then we 'll see if Arantxa will be there , too . "
The fast-moving Olsza , 18 , was cool in her opening match .
" I was n't scared when I heard that I was playing Maleeva , " said Olsza . "
I know that if I want to play professional tennis I have to do my best to try to beat her and I ca n't be scared . "
Olsza is undaunted by the level of competition in the pros .
" In terms of tennis , I think the junior players are really good now .
In a few years , it could change a lot among the top players . "
Two big-serving women 's players made quick work of Japanese opponents .
Brenda Schultz-McCarthy of the Netherlands , the 13th seed , was a 6-1 6-4 winner over Japan 's Nana Miyaga , while Czech veteran Helena Sukova prevailed over Yone Kamio 6-2 6-3 .
Austrian Barbara Paulus , seeded 14th , also reached the second round with a 6-2 6-1 victory over Yi Jing-Qian of China .
TENNIS - STICH GLAD HE STAYED AFTER OPEN VICTORY .
Richard Finn
NEW YORK 1996-08-26
Michael Stich nearly pulled out of the U.S. Open in protest over the men 's seeding fiasco but the former Wimbledon champion was glad he stayed after sweating out a four-set win on Monday over qualifier Tommy Haas .
" I still feel it 's embarrassing what happened and I was about to pull out yesterday and say , ' That 's it , ' " said Stich , one of a host of men who cried foul over seeding procedures that forced an unprecedented remaking of the men 's draw last week .
" But there are so many reasons to play , especially spectators and the kids who come out here and want to enjoy watching tennis , that I decided to stay . "
In a break from tradition , the Open did not seed in strict accordance with ATP rankings , instead taking into account other factors that raised objections of favourtism toward U.S. players .
One prominent player that did not stay for the Open was French Open champion Yvegeny Kafelnikov , who after being dropped three spots from his ATP ranking to a seventh seeding , withdrew and returned home to Russia .
Kafelnikov had pulled out of last week 's tournament with a rib injury .
At a news conference attended by approximately 50 players on Sunday , U.S. Davis Cup player Todd Martin expressed the players ' outrage at the seedings .
" The way the U.S. Open has seeded here , tampering with the ranking system , has tarnished the image and reputation of this U.S. Open in the players ' mind , and we think that is damaging to our sport , " Martin said .
Stich said he felt the players ought to have organised an active protest .
" I feel that we made it a little easy for the USTA .
They did n't really get hurt as much as I think they should have , " said Stich . "
I feel that we should have maybe just cancelled out the Monday , not show up today and start the tournament tomorrow . "
But once the 27-year-old Stich got on the court , he focused his energies on trying to win the year 's last Grand Slam .
He took a positive first step with his 6-3 1-6 6-1 7-5 win over compatriot Haas on a sun-baked Grandstand court .
Others advancing early on Monday included 11th-seeded American Malivai Washington , the Wimbledon runner-up , Sweden 's Magnus Gustafsson , and two-time former French Open champion Sergi Bruguera of Spain , who will be Stich 's next opponent .
The suspicion , however , lingers in Stich 's mind that U.S. Open officials did tamper with the seeding process in order to benefit homegrown players .
" I get the feeling that everything is done here for the American players and they forget about all the other players , " said Stich , who lost the 1994 Open final to Andre Agassi .
It was Agassi who was at the centre of the controversy that engulfed the tournament since the original draw was completed on Wednesday .
The flamboyant American star was bumped up two spots from his ATP ranking of eight to a seeding of six .
" He ( Agassi ) should be seeded the way he is playing tennis right now , " said Stich about the unfairness of moving up Agassi , who made early exits from the French Open and Wimbledon .
Stich , not seeded here for the first time since 1990 , might have benefitted from some fiddling with the seedings himself after Kafelnikov withdrew .
Ranked 18th in the world , Stich might have been slipped into that spot ahead of Spain 's Felix Mantilla , who is 16th but had never been played in the Open and had been left out of the seedings originally .
But Stich did n't want to play that game .
" I think he deserves to be seeded as everybody else who is in the top 16 deserves to be seeded , " Stich said .
TENNIS - MONDAY 'S RESULTS FROM U.S. OPEN .
NEW YORK 1996-08-26
Results of first round matches on Monday in the U.S. Open tennis championships at the National Tennis Centre ( prefix denotes seeding ) :
Women 's singles
16 - Martina Hingis ( Switzerland ) beat Angeles Montolio ( Spain ) 6-1 6-0
Anne-Gaelle Sidot ( France ) beat Janette Husarova ( Slovakia ) 6-4 6-4
13 - Brenda Schultz-McCarthy ( Netherlands ) beat Nana Miyagi ( Japan ) 6-1 6-4
Aleksandra Olsza ( Poland ) beat 12 - Magdalena Maleeva ( Bulgaria ) 6-4 6-2
Men 's singles
Michael Stich ( Germany ) beat Tommy Haas ( Germany ) 6-3 1-6 6-1 7-5
Sergi Bruguera ( Spain ) beat Kris Goossens ( Belgium ) 6-2 6-0 7-6 ( 7-1 )
Frederic Vitoux ( France ) beat Ramon Delgado ( Paraguay ) 6-4 6-4 7-6 ( 7-3 )
Women 's singles
Henrietta Nagyova ( Slovakia ) beat Gala Leon Garcia ( Spain ) 6-1 4-6 6-3
Asa Carlsson ( Sweden ) beat Gloria Pizzichini ( Italy ) 3-6 6-1 7-5
Barbara Schett ( Austria ) beat Sabine Appelmans ( Belgium ) 1-6 6-4 6-4
Cristina Torrens-Valero ( Spain ) beat Sabine Hack ( Germany ) 2-6 6-4 6-2
Women 's singles
Helena Sukova ( Czech Republic ) beat Yone Kamio ( Japan ) 6-2 6-3
Irina Spirlea ( Romania ) beat Petra Begerow ( Germany ) 6-3 6-2
Maria Jose Gaidano ( Argentina ) beat Melanie Schnell ( Austria ) 6-4 6-0
Men 's singles
Carlos Moya ( Spain ) beat Scott Humphries ( U.S. ) 6-1 6-7 ( 3-7 ) 6-7 ( 1-7 ) 6-0 6-4
Kenneth Carlsen ( Denmark ) beat Patrick Rafter ( Australia ) 7-6 ( 9-7 ) 6-3 7-6 ( 8-6 )
Magnus Gustafsson ( Sweden ) beat Carlos Costa ( Spain ) 7-5 4-6 7-6 ( 7-4 ) 6-3
Jeff Tarango ( U.S. ) beat Alex Radulescu ( Romania ) 6-7 ( 5-7 ) 6-4 6-1 retired , heat exhaustion
Men 's singles
11 - MaliVai Washington ( U.S. ) beat Karim Alami ( Morocco ) 6-4 2-6 7-6 ( 7-5 ) 6-1
Dirk Dier ( Germany ) beat Chuck Adams ( U.S. ) 6-4 2-6 6-4 6-4
Jason Stoltenberg ( Australia ) beat Stefano Pescosolido ( Italy ) 7-5 6-4 6-1
Arnaud Boetsch ( France ) beat Nicolas Pereira ( Venezuela ) 7-6 ( 7-4 ) 6-4 7-5
David Prinosil ( Germany ) beat Peter Tramacchi ( Australia ) 6-3 6-2 3-6 6-7 ( 5-7 ) 6-1
Women 's singles
Amanda Coetzer ( South Africa ) beat 6 - Anke Huber ( Germany ) 6-1 2-6 6-2
Anna Kournikova ( Russia ) beat Ludmila Richterova ( Czech Republic ) 7-6 ( 7-4 ) 6-3
Debbie Graham ( U.S. ) beat Stephanie Deville ( Belarus ) 6-4 6-2
Barbara Rittner ( Germany ) beat Katarina Studenikova ( Slovakia ) 7-5 7-5
Kristina Brandi ( U.S. ) beat Andrea Glass ( Germany ) 6-2 6-3
Ines Gorrochategui ( Argentina ) beat Magdalena Grzybowska ( Poland ) 4-6 6-4 6-1
Men 's singles
Alberto Berasategui ( Spain ) beat Cecil Mamiit ( U.S. ) 6-1 6-4 6-0
Guillaume Raoux ( France ) beat Filip Dewulf ( Belgium ) 7-6 ( 7-5 ) 3-6 1-6 6-4 7-5
Alex O'Brien ( U.S. ) beat Nicolas Lapentti ( Ecuador ) 6-4 1-6 6-4 6-3
2 - Michael Chang ( U.S. ) beat Jaime Oncins ( Brazil ) 3-6 6-1 6-0 7 - 6 ( 8-6 )
Women 's singles
14 - Barbara Paulus ( Austria ) beat Yi Jing-Qian ( China ) 6-2 6-1
Wang Shi-Ting ( Taiwan ) beat Corina Morariu ( U.S. ) 6-4 6-7 ( 5-7 ) 6-2
Linda Wild ( U.S. ) beat Sung-Hee Park ( South Korea ) 6-2 6-3
Sarah Pitkowski ( France ) beat Meghann Shaughnessy ( U.S. ) 6-3 6- 3
Dally Randriantefy ( Madagascar ) beat Elena Makarova ( Russia ) 6- 3 1-6 7-5
Laurence Courtois ( Belgium ) beat Flora Perfetti ( Italy ) 6-4 3-6 6-2
Men 's singles
Leander Paes ( India ) beat Marcos Ondruska ( South Africa ) 7-6 ( 7-3 ) 6-2 7-5
Jan Siemerink ( Netherlands ) beat Carl-Uwe Steeb ( Germany ) 4-6 6 - 1 7-6 ( 7-4 ) 6-4
Neville Godwin ( South Africa ) beat Tomas Carbonell ( Spain ) 6-4 6-2 3-6 6-1
Jim Grabb ( U.S. ) beat Sandon Stolle ( Australia ) 6-3 7-5 7-6 ( 7-4 )
Women 's singles
Alexandra Fusai ( France ) beat Jill Craybas ( U.S. ) 6-1 2-6 7-5
Naoko Kijimuta ( Japan ) beat Tatyana Jecmenica ( Yugoslavia ) 6-3 6-2
Nathalie Dechy ( France ) beat Christina Singer ( Germany ) 6-4 6-0
Jane Chi ( U.S. ) beat Maria Antonio Sanchez Lorenzo ( Spain ) 6-4 1-6 6-3
Els Callens ( Belgium ) beat Nicole Bradtke ( Australia ) 7-6 ( 7-1 ) 7-6 ( 9-7 )
Natalia Baudone ( Italy ) beat Jolene Watanabe ( U.S. ) 6-4 4-6 7-6 ( 8-6 )
Ai Sugiyama ( Japan ) beat Jana Kandarr ( Germany ) 6-2 6-1
BASEBALL - CUBS EDGE BRAVES WITH RUN IN TOP OF NINTH .
ATLANTA 1996-08-25
Brian McRae singled in Tyler Houston in the top of the ninth inning to snap a tie as the Chicago Cubs avoided a three-game sweep with 3-2 victory over the Atlanta Braves on Sunday .
The Braves scored four runs in the ninth for a 6-5 victory on Saturday .
Kevin Foster ( 5-2 ) won his second straight start , allowing two runs and six hits with two walks and three strikeouts over eight innings .
" The biggest thing was my fastball , I was able to rotate it pretty good , " Foster said . "
Also , I was able to keep my changeup down . "
At Colorado , Vinny Castilla homered twice and drove in four runs and Larry Walker went 3-for-4 with a homer and three RBI as the Colorado Rockies outslugged the Pittsburgh Pirates 13-9 in the rubber game of a three-game series .
Castilla 's first homer of the game , a solo shot in the seventh off reliever Marc Wilkins ( 3-1 ) extended Colorado 's lead to 9-7 .
He added a three-run homer in the eighth off John Ericks to make it 13-8 .
At Florida , Edgar Renteria 's two-out single in the bottom of the ninth inning scored Jesus Tavarez with the winning run as the Florida Marlins edged the Cincinnati Reds 6-5 .
" Right after Edgar made contact , I knew I had to score , " said Tavarez . "
I knew I would score even if he fielded it cleanly , he could n't throw me out . "
" Edgar is a tremendous player right now , " said Florida manager John Boles . "
But I ca n't wait to see how good he 'll be when he grows up . "
In San Francisco , Osvaldo Fenandez fired a seven-hitter and Trenidad Hubbard belted a two-run homer as the San Francisco Giants ended a three-game losing streak by defeating the Montreal Expos , 7-2 .
Fernandez ( 6-13 ) allowed two runs , walked one and struck out eight for his second career complete game , both against Montreal .
In Los Angeles , Greg Gagne had a run-scoring single and Chad Curtis drew a bases-loaded walk in the bottom of the eighth inning as the Los Angeles Dodgers rallied for a 6-5 victory and a three-game sweep of the New York Mets .
" It was one of these games where you get three straight pinch-hits and a walk of a pinch-hitter , that 's how you win pennants , " Dodgers manager Bill Russell said . "
Mike Piazza
In San Diego , Steve Finley and Jody Reed drove in three runs apiece as the San Diego Padres built a six-run lead after three innings and cruised to an 11-2 victory over the Philadelphia Phillies .
Ken Caminiti added two RBI for the Padres , who have won six of their last seven games and remained one game ahead of the Los Angeles Dodgers in the National League West .
In Houston , Jeff Bagwell homered and Donne Wall allowed one run over seven innings as the Houston Astros defeated the St. Louis Cardinals 4-1 .
Wall ( 8-4 ) allowed three hits , walked two and struck out seven as the Astros moved 1-1/2 games ahead of the Cardinals for the lead in the National League Central .
He left the game with a knot in his right shoulder .
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE STANDINGS AFTER SUNDAY 'S GAMES .
NEW YORK 1996-08-25
Major League Baseball
standings after games played on Sunday ( tabulate under won ,
lost , winning percentage and games behind ) :
AMERICAN LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
NEW YORK 74 55 .574 -
BALTIMORE 68 61 .527 6
BOSTON 66 65 .504 9
TORONTO 61 70 .466 14
DETROIT 47 83 .362 27 1/2
CENTRAL DIVISION
CLEVELAND 77 53 .592 -
CHICAGO 70 62 .530 8
MINNESOTA 65 65 .500 12
MILWAUKEE 62 69 .473 15 1/2
KANSAS CITY 59 73 .447 19
WESTERN DIVISION
TEXAS 75 56 .573 -
SEATTLE 66 63 .512 8
OAKLAND 63 70 .474 13
CALIFORNIA 61 69 .469 13 1/2
MONDAY , AUGUST 26TH SCHEDULE
CLEVELAND AT DETROIT
OAKLAND AT BALTIMORE
MINNESOTA AT TORONTO
MILWAUKEE AT CHICAGO
BOSTON AT CALIFORNIA
NEW YORK AT SEATTLE
NATIONAL LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
ATLANTA 81 48 .628 -
MONTREAL 70 59 .543 11
FLORIDA 61 70 .466 21
NEW YORK 59 72 .450 23
PHILADELPHIA 53 78 .405 29
CENTRAL DIVISION
HOUSTON 70 61 .534 -
ST LOUIS 68 62 .523 1 1/2
CHICAGO 64 64 .500 4 1/2
CINCINNATI 64 65 .496 5
PITTSBURGH 55 75 .423 14 1/2
WESTERN DIVISION
SAN DIEGO 72 60 .545 -
LOS ANGELES 70 60 .538 1
COLORADO 68 63 .519 3 1/2
SAN FRANCISCO 55 73 .430 15
MONDAY , AUGUST 26TH SCHEDULE
PHILADELPHIA AT SAN FRANCISCO
ST LOUIS AT HOUSTON
CINCINNATI AT COLORADO
BASEBALL - BONDS ' CONSECUTIVE GAME STREAK ENDS .
SAN FRANCISCO 1996-08-25
San Francisco Giants All-Star left fielder Barry Bonds did not appear in Sunday 's 7-2 victory over the Montreal Expos , ending his consecutive games streak .
After appearing as a pinch-hitter in the previous two games , Bonds , who has been battling a hamstring injury , did not see any action today , ending his streak at 357 consecutive games .
It was the second-longest streak by an active player in the the majors behind Baltimore 's Cal Ripken , who appeared in his major-league record 2,282nd straight game today , a 13-0 loss to the California Angels .
Bonds has been limited to a pinch-hitting role since an MRI Friday showed a mild strain of his left hamstring .
Bonds came out of Wednesday 's game against New York in the ninth inning after suffering a mild hamstring strain .
He was back in the starting lineup Thursday night and went 1-for-2 before exiting in the third inning .
The 32-year-old Bonds is hitting .307 with 35 homers and 107 RBI and has been one of the few bright spots for the last-place Giants .
Chicago Cubs outfielder Sammy Sosa had the third-longest streak at 304 games , but that ended earlier this week when he suffered a broken bone in his right hand .
Atlanta Braves first baseman Fred McGriff owns the second-longest streak at 295 games .
SOCCER - JONK RETURNS TO DUTCH SQUAD FOR BRAZIL FRIENDLY .
ROTTERDAM 1996-08-26
Dutch coach Guus Hiddink on Monday recalled midfielder Wim Jonk after a 14-month absence for a friendly against World Cup holders Brazil in Amsterdam on Sunday .
Feyenoord midfielder Jean-Paul van Gastel was also named to make his debut in the 18-man squad .
Hiddink did not name a replacement captain for Danny Blind , who announced his retirement from international soccer on Sunday .
Ronald de Boer and Dennis Bergkamp are the likely contenders to lead the team .
The 35-year-old Blind , who won 42 caps for the Netherlands , said he wanted to concentrate on playing for his Dutch club Ajax Amsterdam .
AC Milan midfielder Edgar Davids , who was sent home early from the European championship in England after a clash with the coach , was left out of the squad .
Squad :
Goalkeepers - Edwin van der Sar ( Ajax ) , Ed de Goey ( Feyenoord ) .
Defenders - Frank de Boer ( Ajax ) , John Veldman ( Ajax ) , Jaap Stam ( PSV ) , Arthur Numan ( PSV ) , Michael Reiziger ( AC Milan ) , Johan de Kock ( Schalke ' 04 ) .
Midfielders - Richard Witschge ( Ajax ) , Philip Cocu ( PSV ) , Wim Jonk ( PSV ) , Aron Winter ( Internazionale ) , Jean-Paul van Gastel ( Feyenoord ) , Clarence Seedorf ( Real Madrid ) .
Strikers - Ronald de Boer ( Ajax ) , Gaston Taument ( Feyenoord ) , Jordi Cruyff ( Manchester United ) , Dennis Bergkamp ( Arsenal ) .
SOCCER - BARCELONA BEAT ATLETICO 5-2 IN SUPERCUP .
BARCELONA 1996-08-26
Barcelona beat Atletico Madrid 5-2 ( halftime 2-1 ) in the Spanish Supercup on Sunday :
Scorers :
Barcelona - Ronaldo ( 5th and 89th minutes ) , Giovanni ( 31st ) , Pizzi ( 73rd ) , De la Pena ( 75th )
Atletico Madrid - Esnaider ( 37th ) , Pantic ( 57th , penalty )
Attendance 30,000
SOCCER - AUSTRIA FIRST DIVISION RESULTS / STANDINGS .
VIENNA 1996-08-26
Result of an Austrian first
division soccer match played on Sunday :
SV Ried 0 SV Salzburg 4
Standings ( tabulated under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , against , points ) :
FC Tirol Innsbruck 6 4 2 0 13 5 14
SV Salzburg 6 4 2 0 8 1 14
Austria Vienna 6 4 2 0 9 5 14
Sturm Graz 6 2 3 1 8 5 9
GAK 6 1 3 2 8 10 6
Rapid Wien 5 0 5 0 3 3 5
SV Ried 6 1 1 4 6 9 4
Linzer ASK 5 0 3 2 4 8 3
Admira / Wacker 6 0 3 3 5 10 3
FC Linz 6 0 2 4 1 9 2
CRICKET - AUSTRALIA BEAT ZIMBABWE BY 125 RUNS IN ONE-DAY MATCH .
COLOMBO 1996-08-26
Australia beat Zimbabwe by 125 runs in the first match of the Singer World Series one-day ( 50 overs ) cricket tournament on Monday .
Scores : Australia 263-7 in 50 overs , Zimbabwe 138 all out in 41 overs .
CRICKET - SCOREBOARD-AUSTRALIA V ZIMBABWE ONE-DAY SCOREBOARD .
COLOMBO 1996-08-26
Scoreboard in the Singer World
Series one-day ( 50 overs ) cricket match between Australia and
Zimbabwe on Monday :
Australia
M. Slater c P. Strang b Whittall 50
M. Waugh b P. Strang 18
R. Ponting c and b Whittall 53
S. Waugh c Campbell b Whittall 82
S. Law b Streak 20
M. Bevan c Campbell b Brandes 9
I. Healy b Brandes 5
B. Hogg not out 11
Extras ( b-1 lb-8 w-3 nb-3 ) 15
Total ( for seven wickets - 50 overs ) 263
Fall of wickets : 1-48 2-92 3-167 4-230 5-240 6-242 7-263
Did not bat : P. Reiffel , D. Flemming , G. McGrath
Bowling : Streak 10-1-50-1 ( 2w , 2nb ) , Brandes 10-1-47-2 ( 1w ) ,
P. Strang 9-0-41-1 , Flower 6-0-28-0 , Whittall 10-0-53-3 ( 1nb ) ,
Decker 3-0-17-0 , Shah 2-0-18-0
Zimbabwe
A. Shah c M. Waugh b Hogg 41
G. Flower c Ponting b Flemming 7
A. Flower lbw b Flemming 0
A. Campbell lbw b McGrath 9
C. Wishart c Healy b Reiffel 0
G. Whittall b Reiffel 11
C. Evans c Healy b S. Waugh 15
M. Dekker not out 8
P. Strang b M. Waugh 9
H. Streak b M. Waugh 0
E. Brandes c Hogg b M. Waugh 17
Extras ( lb-4 w-10 nb-7 ) 21
Total ( all out - 41 overs ) 138
Fall of wickets : 1-16 2-16 3-33 4-35 5-56 6-98 7-100 8-120
9-120
Bowling : McGrath 7-2-13-1 ( 2w ) , Flemming 7-0-24-2 ( 3w , 3nb ) ,
Reiffel 6-1-23-2 ( 2nb ) , S. Waugh 7-2-24-1 ( 1nb , 2w ) , Hogg
9-2-26-1 ( 1nb , 3w ) , M. Waugh 5-1-24-3
Result : Australia won by 125 runs .
CRICKET - AUSTRALIA 263-7 IN 50 OVERS V ZIMBABWE .
COLOMBO 1996-08-26
Australia scored 263-7 in their 50 overs against Zimbabwe in the first day-night limited overs match of the Singer World Series tournament on Monday .
CRICKET - AUSTRALIA WIN TOSS , OPT TO BAT AGAINST ZIMBABWE .
COLOMBO 1996-08-26
Australia won the toss and decided to bat against Zimbabwe in the first day-night limited overs match of the Singer World Series tournament on Monday .
Teams :
Australia - Mark Waugh , Michael Slater , Ricky Ponting , Steve Waugh , Stuart Law , Michael Bevan , Ian Healy ( captain ) , Brad Hogg , Paul Reiffel , Damein Fleming , Glenn McGrath .
Zimbabwe - Alistair Campbell ( captain ) , Andy Flower , Grant Flower , Guy Whittall , Craig Evans , Eddo Brandes , Heath Streak , Paul Strang , Craig Wishart , Ali Shah , Mark Dekker .
PRESS DIGEST - MOZAMBIQUE - AUGUST 26 .
MAPUTO 1996-08-26
This is the leading story in the Mozambican press on Monday .
Reuters has not verified this story and does not vouch for its accuracy .
NOTICIAS
- At least 20 people were killed when the two trucks in which they were travelling collided at Nhamavila about 160 km north of Maputo on Saturday , the Maputo daily Noticias said .
Lamonts Apparel files reorganization plan .
[ CORRECTED 18:00 GMT ]
KIRKLAND , Wash .
1996-08-26
Lamonts Apparel Inc , an operator of 42 family apparel stores in six northwestern states , said it has filed a reorganization plan in bankruptcy court in Seattle .
( Corrects to make clear a reorganization plan has been filed ) .
The reorganization plan calls for all secured claims to be paid in full .
Unsecured claims , including those of company bondholders , will be satisfied by issuing new common stock and warrants .
Unsecured claims are estimated at about $ 90 million .
Lamonts said it plans to issue 9 million shares of new common stock .
Of that amount , 4.05 million and 5.67 million shares will be allocated to the company 's trade creditors .
Between 4.75 and 3.13 million shares will be allocated to bondholders and other unsecured non-trade creditors and 200,000 will be allocated to existing shareholders in exchange for all existing stock of the company .
Bondholders and other unsecured non-trade creditors will receive warrants four about 2.2 million shares when the company 's market capitalization reaches $ 20 million .
Bondholders , other unsecured non-trade creditors , and existing shareholders also will receive warrants entitling them to roughly 800,000 shares when the company 's market capitalization reaches $ 25 million .
Management will receive options to purchase 10 percent of the company 's outstanding common stock with protection against dilution at an option exercise price of $ 1 million .
Passengers rescued from blazing ferry off France .
LONDON 1996-08-26
More than 100 people were safely evacuated on Monday from a ferry that caught fire soon after leaving Guernsey in Britain 's Channel Islands , police said .
Police said the 111 passengers and six crew on board the ferry Trident Seven , owned by France 's Emeraud line , were rescued by a variety of private and commercial boats after fire broke out in the engine room soon after it left port .
An 88-year-old woman was taken to hospital with leg injuries , according to a spokesman for Guernsey police .
The ferry , which was towed into port , had been bound for Jersey , another in a cluster of small British-ruled islands off north-west France .
OSCE delays decision on refugee voting .
Kurt Schork
SARAJEVO 1996-08-26
Bosnia 's election organisers will decide on Tuesday whether or not to postpone municipal elections scheduled as part of nationwide balloting , an OSCE spokeswoman said on Monday .
Officials from the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe ( OSCE ) are considering the postponement following allegations of serious irregularities in the registration of Serb refugees .
International observers say the alleged irregularities could affect the outcome of voting for municipal assemblies .
" Tomorrow ...
the Provisional Election Commission will consider the possible postponement of municipal elections only ...
the other elections will be held on September 14 , " OSCE spokeswoman Agota Kuperman told reporters in Sarajevo .
" I think that it would be very difficult to select which municipal elections would have to be cancelled .
I think probably if the decision ( to cancell ) were to be taken it would probably be all municipal elections ..
. "
Kuperman added that options other than postponement were also on the table , but she refused to specify what they were .
The Dayton peace agreement gave the OSCE a mandate to organise Bosnian elections .
The Provisional Election Commission is OSCE 's top rule-making body for the poll .
More than 600,000 refugees have registered to vote in 55 countries around the world , representing about 20 per cent of Bosnia 's total electorate .
They are due to begin voting on Wednesday , August 28 , just one day after the PEC is supposed to make its decision .
Balloting inside Bosnia is scheduled for September 14 , when citizens are slated to elect municipal and cantonal assemblies , separate Moslem-Croat and Serb parliaments , a national House of Representatives and a three-man Presidency .
A Sarajevo daily newspaper , Dnevi Avaz , which is close to Bosnia 's Moslem nationalist SDA party , on Monday said the OSCE would postpone the municipal-level elections until the Spring of 1997 because of the refugee registration problems .
SDA has a representative on the Provisional Election Commission .
" I do n't know what the source of the Dnevi Avaz report is , but it is consistent with what I have heard from western diplomats and from inside the OSCE , " said an OSCE staff member in Sarajevo who asked not to be named .
" The word is that Frowick has decided to postpone municipal elections but that he will wait for one more session of the PEC on Tuesday to take everyone 's temperature on the issue . "
Ambassador Robert Frowick , an American , heads the OSCE mission in Bosnia .
OSCE and independent monitors allege that Serb authorities have systematically discouraged refugees from registering to cast a ballot in the places they lived before the war .
Instead , the refugees were said to have been directed by their authorities to vote from strategic towns which had Moslem majorities before the 43-month Bosnian war , but which are now underpopulated as a result of " ethnic cleansing " .
Diplomats explain the purpose of this electoral engineering is to secure Serb control over pivotal towns inside the 49 per cent of Bosnia known as the Serb republic , consolidating through the ballot box what was initially taken in war .
The top U.N. refugee official in the Balkans highlighted the voter registration problem on Monday .
" Results of the registration for September elections herald a dismal future for multi-ethnicity in Bosia-Hercegovina , " warned Soren Jessen-Petersen , Special Envoy for the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees in Former Yugoslavia .
" In the run-up to elections , nationalistic political leaders are playing the ethnic / sectarian card , drumming up support within their constituencies by playing on bitter memories or fear . "
After truce , Lebed faces tougher Chechen problem .
Alastair Macdonald
MOSCOW 1996-08-26
Alexander Lebed may finally get to discuss his Chechen peace proposals with Boris Yeltsin on Tuesday after a lost weekend in the region when he was forced to abandon plans to sign a new political treaty with the separatist rebels .
It could be a sobering experience for the Kremlin security chief who , just two months after being appointed by the president and two heady weeks after taking charge of the Chechen crisis , had promised to wrap up the 20-month war by the weekend .
Despite a mood of compromise in the region after some of the worst fighting of the war , Lebed may be just finding out that concluding a long-term settlement , somewhere between rebel demands for independence and Moscow 's insistence that Chechnya remain part of Russia , will be no easy matter .
A chain-smoking former paratroop general with a sharp line in deadpan putdowns and a soldier 's knack for making life sound simple , Lebed managed to arrange an ambitious ceasefire in the region last week , days after the Russian army threatened to bomb its way back into the rebel-held Chechen capital Grozny .
He returned at the weekend , pledging to conclude a political settlement that would make this truce work where all others have failed .
But then he apparently thought better of it .
Saying he needed to tidy up legal loose ends on the deal -- and also cover his back against unnamed pro-war schemers in Moscow -- he flew back to the capital empty-handed on Sunday .
He met Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin on Monday and , according to the press service of Lebed 's Security Council , could meet Yeltsin on Tuesday .
It was not clear if the start of Yeltsin 's holiday , announced later , would affect plans to talk .
Moscow 's as yet undisclosed proposals on Chechnya 's political future have , meanwhile , been sent back to do the rounds of various government departments .
It is not known what caused the delay in the peace plan .
Speculation mounted last week that Lebed was operating out on a limb in Chechnya as Yeltsin , hardly seen since his reelection last month , kept out of sight and then gave an interview criticising his envoy just as he clinched a truce .
But Chernomyrdin took pains at the weekend to insist Lebed was playing for a united team and that the proposals he took to rebel chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov had been agreed by Yeltsin .
If that were the case , it was unclear why Lebed suddenly found it necessary to have the deal verified in Moscow .
Lebed himself said he was concerned that powerful interests in Moscow , who have profited from the war and want it to go on , would seize on any inadequacy in the deal to remove him .
Maskhadov warned that Lebed risked the same fate as a former Russian army commander in the region who sought a compromise and was blown up last year by -- so the Chechens say -- Russian forces .
Maskhadov may also have made new demands on Lebed , forcing him to check back with the Kremlin on what he could offer .
A rebel spokesman said the two military men had come close to agreement on a face-saving formula acceptable to both sides and involving a referendum on independence at some future date .
Chernomyrdin said voters should decide Chechnya 's future but stressed there was no question of the government letting the region quit the Russian Federation -- something Moscow fears could encourage separatist tendencies in other ethnic regions , particularly in the strategic North Caucasus .
Lebed may be be finding that closing that political gap between the two sides is more difficult than just ending a war .
Yeltsin on holiday from Monday - Interfax .
MOSCOW 1996-08-26
Russian President Boris Yeltsin began a new summer holiday on Monday but would remain in control of affairs of state , Interfax news agency said .
" The head of state 's holiday has only just begun , " the agency quoted Sergei Yastrzhembsky as saying , adding that the president was currently in a Kremlin residence near Moscow .
Interfax said Yastrezhembsky did not exclude that Yeltsin could spend some time in other places .
He would continue working on various documents and might meet " one state offical or another " .
" One must give B. Yeltsin a chance to rest and recover his health after the elections , " Interfax quoted Yastrezhembsky as saying .
" ( Yeltsin ) controls internal and international policies , daily receives a big packet of documents from Moscow , which demand his intervention ...
Many of those documents return to the president 's administration the same day , " he said .
Yeltsin went on a two-day trip outside Moscow last week to check out a holiday home .
Yugo Zastava workers ' protest enters 2nd week .
BELGRADE 1996-08-26
Thousands of workers of Serbia 's Zastava arms factory entered the second week of protests on Monday over unpaid wages and the lack of a programme to revive the plant 's production .
" We are stubborn , have strength and time to persist until our demands are met , " said the factory 's trade union secretary Dragutin Stanojlovic .
" We are united and we are waiting for the government to decide what to do with us . "
Trade unions demanded payment of June and July wages and last year 's holiday pay , and called on government to develop a revival programme for the plant .
The former Yugoslav national army consumed 90 percent of Zastava 's pre-war output , but like the rest of Yugoslavia 's economy , the new army of Serbia and Montenegro is crippled by lack of funds .
In Kragujevac where the plant is based , 9,000 to 10,000 people gathered in the central square to express their bitterness at what Stanojlovic called government indifference .
The ruling Socialist Party last week accused Serbia 's opposition of stirring up social unrest and using workers ' already difficult social position for their own interests .
" Late wages , no work and ( the lack of a ) production programme are the main reasons for their protests , " a senior member of the local Socialist Party branch told Reuters .
" But there is a significant influence of opposition parties that are collecting points ahead of coming elections . "
Federal Yugoslav elections are due on November 3 .
The party official said the union 's figure on the number of protesters was exaggerated . "
There were about 1,400 to 1,600 people at the protest today -- much less then last week .
" But there were more observers and passers by , " he said .
-- Gordana Kukic , Belgrade Newsroom +381 11 222 4254
Croatian lending rate falls to 8.0 vs 9.1 pct .
ZAGREB 1996-08-26
The Croatian lending rate fell to 8.0 percent on Monday from last Friday 's 9.1 percent after thin demand for kuna forced bank lenders to trim their rates further .
Interbank call money was down to 8.0 from 10.0 percent .
Insurers ' five-10 and 10-15 day loans were made at a steady 8.0 percent after last week 's drop from an earlier 15 percent .
Total Zagreb Money Market settlements shrank to 17.4 million kuna , of which dealers put new borrowing at a meagre 5.5 million .
Supply stood at a high 180 million kuna .
Overnight trade at the weekend left a surplus of 1.2 billion kuna on the supply side after 40 million were settled .
Croatia 's central bank again stayed out of the foreign exchange market .
It calculated the kuna midrates for Tuesday 's trade stronger at 5.2420 against the dollar and slightly weaker at 3.5486 against the German mark .
-- Kolumbina Bencevic , Zagreb Newsroom , 385-1-4557075
SVCD Bulgaria air traffic controllers to strike September 3 .
SOFIA 1996-08-26
Bulgarian air traffic controllers will go on strike on September 3 demanding higher pay , the chief of the Bulgarian association of air traffic controllers ( Bulatka ) said on Monday .
Stefan Raichev told a news conference the strike by more than half of the 1,380 traffic controllers and technicians would paralyse traffic which has increased by 10 percent since last year .
More than 1,500 planes per day fly over Bulgaria , in a strategic location between Europe and the Middle and the Far East , Raichev said .
The director general of the air traffic service Valentin Valkov said last Friday that a controllers ' strike would be illegal .
Valkov said he could not curb the summer charter flights of national carrier Balkan Airlines , which carries thousands of foreign tourists to the Bulgarian Black Sea resorts .
But Raichev said it would be " discrimination " against the other airlines if only Balkan planes were guided in .
" Under the law before launching the strike we have to sign an agreement with our employer for a minimal transport servicing of emergency flights , " Raichev said .
Raichev said a lock-out with military air controllers was impossible as they did not speak English .
The controllers are demanding the monthly wage be increased to $ 1,000 per month from the current $ 230 , as well as the resignation of the air traffic service 's management .
They also demand the financial separation of the 350 air controllers from the technical staff .
-- Liliana Semerdjieva , Sofia Newsroom , 359-2-84561
Yeltsin 's wife has kidney operation .
MOSCOW 1996-08-26
Naina Yeltsin , wife of the Russian president , has undergone " a planned operation " on her left kidney and is in a satisfactory condition , Itar-Tass news agency said on Monday .
Tass quoted the Kremlin press service as saying the operation took place on Saturday in the Central Clinical Hospital which treats top officials .
Mrs Yeltsin would be released from hospital in a few days .
Doctor Sergei Mironov told Tass Naina was " in permanent contact " with her husband and two daughters , Yelena and Tatyana .
The state of health of Boris Yeltsin , who had two heart attacks last year , has been the centre of media and market speculation after he won a second term in office in the July 3 election run-off and all but disappeared from the public eye .
A presidential spokesman said on Monday Yeltsin was in Moscow but could give no details about his agenda or whether meetings were planned .
Yeltsin is expected to go on holiday in the near future , but officials have not yet said where he will go or when .
Mostostal Z shareholders approve bonds .
WARSAW 1996-08-26
Shareholders of the Polish construction firm Mostostal Zabrze Holding SA approved a 25- million-zloty , five-year convertible issue with a par value of 100 zlotys each , the company 's spokesman said on Monday .
Piotr Grabowski told Reuters that a Mostostal extraordinary shareholders meeting on Saturday had decided that the price of the 250,000 bonds would be set as a 10-session average price of Mostostal shares plus a premium .
" The premium will be no lower than 15 percent and will be set by management before the issue ...
which we expect at the beginning of next year , " Grabowksi said .
Mostostal , based in southern Poland , wants to offer the bonds to large investors in a public offering , paying an annual coupon of no more than 80 percent of the yield of the benchmark 52-week T-bill .
The firm has signed an agreement with the Polish Development Bank ( PBR ) to manage the issue and plans them to be listed on the Warsaw bourse 's bond market .
Grabowski also said shareholders approved the issue of 1.6 million shares for which the bonds could be exchanged , a ratio of 6.4 shares per bond .
He also said shareholders approved the issue of 2.6 million new shares , two million of which are earmarked for large investors and 600,000 for retail domestic investors .
The price will be determined through book-building .
Mostostal plans to use the proceeds from the issues to add companies to its holding and modernise its plant .
-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700
Unknown group kidnaps Dutch couple in Costa Rica .
SAN JOSE , Costa Rica 1996-08-26
Kidnappers have seized a Dutch couple who manage a farm in northern Costa Rica and have demanded a $ 1.5 million ransom , authorities said on Monday .
Officials said Humberto Hueite Zyrecha and his wife Jetty Kors , both 50 , were kidnapped late on Saturday or early Sunday .
Col .
Misael Valerio , head of border police at the Security Ministry , told reporters surveillance of the northern border with Nicaragua has been stepped up to keep the kidnappers from fleeing Costa Rica .
Preliminary reports said the couple were kidnapped on the " Altamira " farm , owned by Dutchman Richard Wisinga , at Aguas Zarcas de San Carlos near the Costa Rica-Nicaragua border .
Unconfirmed news reports said a vehicle belonging to them was found abandoned at Santa Maria de Pocosol , about 12 miles ( 20 km ) north of the site of the abduction .
The reports said authorities found a statement , supposedly from the kidnappers , in the vehicle , addressed to Wisinga and demanding a $ 1.5 million ransom .
Wisinga was believed to be travelling in Europe , they said .
A Swiss tourist guide and a German tourist were kidnapped in the same area on New Year 's Day by a group of former Nicaraguan guerrillas .
Regula Susana Siegfried , 50 , and Nicola Fleuchaus , 25 , were released after 71 days after a $ 200,000 ransom was paid .
In a bizarre twist , Fleuchaus and the leader of the kidnappers , Julio Cesar Vega Rojas , developed a sentimental attachment during her captivity , according to photographs printed in Costa Rican newspapers and court documents including a love letter written by Vega .
Interacciones ups Mexico GDP forecast , lowers peso .
MEXICO CITY 1996-08-26
Interacciones brokerage on Monday raised its forecasts for 1996 gross domestic product growth to 4.3 percent from 3.8 percent , but it kept its 1997 projection unchanged at 4.5 percent , a statement said .
Economist Alonso Cervera said the revisions were chiefly fueled by stronger than expected growth of 7.2 percent in the second quarter and he forecast an annual GDP rise of 6.1 percent in the third quarter and 4.9 percent in Q4 .
The firm also revised down its year-end peso forecast to 7.85-8.15 per dollar from 8.20-8.50 .
It forecast an end 1997 peso in the range of 9.20-9.40 .
Interacciones kept its 1996 and 1997 inflation forecast unchanged at 26 percent and 20 percent , expecting the government 's 1997 inflation target to be around 15 percent .
It bumped up its average interest rate projection in 1997 to 25.8 percent from 23 percent .
Fiscal policy was expected to be loosened a bit in the second half of this year , boosting growth without running into a deficit .
" Next year , the fiscal policy will have less margin of freedom because the government will have to face commitments that it has taken on under different support schemes for the banks , debtors and firms , " the brokerage said .
-- Henry Tricks , Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9560
Bancomext official says Mexico peso level suitable .
MEXICO CITY 1996-08-26
A top official of export development bank Bancomext said the peso 's appreciation against the dollar this year has not hurt demand for Mexican exports .
" We have a suitable exchange rate .
We have n't felt a drop-off in demand ....
We have no basis for saying that the exchange rate is affecting exports , " Rafael Moreno Turrent , deputy director general for foreign trade promotion at the bank , said at a news conference .
Colombian peso closes lower , importers buy dlrs .
BOGOTA 1996-08-26
Colombia 's peso closed lower at 1,044 after coming under pressure from dollar-buying by importers seeking to meet their commitments abroad , interbank dealers said .
It was the second consecutive session that saw the peso , which ended at 1,041 Friday , close lower .
" The ( dollar 's ) rise was due to demand from importers who have a lot of wire transfers accumulated , " one dealer said .
Contributing to the peso 's weakness , another dealer said banks who might have sold greenbacks in Monday 's trading appeared to shy away from the market .
This , according to the trader , was typical of month-end position-squaring -- and the fact that a stronger U.S. currency helps limit some foreign exchange losses .
Dealers reported 355 trades for a total of $ 142 million and said the peso hit an intra-day high of 1,037 before heading lower into the close .
-- Juan Guillermo Londono , Bogota newsroom , 571 610 7944
Japan 's Hashimoto leaves Brazil for Peru .
BRASILIA 1996-08-26
Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto left Brasilia on Monday for Lima , the penultimate stop on a 10-day Latin American tour , a Brazilian Foreign Ministry spokeswoman said .
Hashimoto , who has already visited Mexico and Chile , spent three days in Brazil .
After Peru , he was due to go to Costa Rica .
Nicaraguan president has operation in U.S .
MANAGUA , Nicaragua 1996-08-26
Nicaraguan President Violeta Chamorro underwent successful surgery in the United States on Monday to correct a compression in her lower spinal column , the government said .
Doctors at Johns Hopkins Hospital in Baltimore found an inflamation in her spinal column that , once treated , will free her of chronic pain in her back and one leg that has limited her movement , a government statement said .
" ( Chamorro ) is in good health and , according to her doctors , will be able to return to Nicaragua next week , " it said .
Chamorro , 66 , had complained of lower back pain since a trip to Taiwan in May , when pain forced her to go to Taipei University Hospital for an examination .
She suffers from osteoporosis , a disease that weakens the bones , and has repeatedly flown to Washington for treatment .
She is scheduled to step down in January after a term of nearly seven years .
Eight drown in Venezuelan boating accident .
MARACAIBO , Venezuela 1996-08-26
Eight members of a family , five of them children aged between two and seven , drowned when their small boat sank on Lake Maracaibo in western Venezuela early on Monday , authorities said .
The accident happened when the Sanchez Zarraga family took their boat out for a nighttime spin , Civil Defence and Coast Guard officials said .
The cause of the sinking was not known but officials said the boat had a hole in the stern and no lifejackets .
Three members of the party were rescued unhurt .
Banco de Mexico to inject 3.412 bln pesos .
MEXICO CITY 1996-08-26
Banco de Mexico sought to inject 3.412 billion pesos in the secondary market on Monday through three credit auctions , dealers said .
The auctions were offered as follows :
AMOUNT TERM
1.206 bln 9 days
1.206 bln 3 days
1.000 bln 1 day
- Mexico City newsroom 525 728-9559
Dutch couple kidnapped in Costa Rica .
SAN JOSE , Costa Rica 1996-08-26
A Dutch couple who manage a farm in northern Costa Rica have been kidnapped by an unidentified group demanding $ 1.5 million in ransom , authorities said on Monday .
Officials said Humberto Hueite Zyrecha and his wife Jetty Kors , both 50 , were kidnapped late Saturday or early Sunday .
Col .
Misael Valerio , head of border police at the Security Ministry , told reporters that surveillance of the country 's northern border with Nicaragua has been stepped up to stop the kidnappers from fleeing Costa Rica .
No other details were immediately available .
RTRS - Melbourne train collides with truck , 15 injured .
MELBOURNE 1996-08-26
Fifteen people were injured when a suburban passenger train and a truck collided at a street-level rail crossing in the Australian city of Melbourne on Monday , said rail and ambulance officials .
The injured , which included a pregnant woman , were taken to hospital , but were not in a serious condition , an ambulance spokesman told Reuters .
A Public Transport Corporation spokesman said the train , collided with the truck loaded with concrete pylons in the north Melbourne suburb of Preston just before 8.30 a.m ..
The train was derailed when a corner of the driver 's compartment caught the rear of the truck , the spokesman said .
The truck was overturned , spilling its load onto the crossing , and careered into the nearby Bell St Station .
" Remarkably both the train driver and the truck driver were not injured , " the rail spokesman said .
" It had the potential to be quite a nasty accident . "
-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800
Police capture Auckland gunman .
AUCKLAND 1996-08-27
A gunman being hunted on Auckland 's North Shore was captured by police just after 9 a.m. on Tuesday , New Zealand Press Association reported .
Senior Sergeant Dave Pearson of Auckland police said John Grant Fagan was in police custody , but further details of his capture would not be released until a press conference later in the day .
Fagan had earlier telephoned an Auckland radio station in a distraught state , saying he feared for his life .
Police said he did not have a weapon when taken into custody and was now cooperating with them .
Radio New Zealand reported earlier that an armed man on Monday entered the Northcote College swimming pool changing sheds and confronted a 16-year-old schoolgirl .
A shot was fired , but onlookers managed to disarm the man .
-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746
Police seek fugitive after Auckland gun incident .
WELLINGTON 1996-08-27
Auckland police were seeking an escaped gunman on Tuesday after an incident in which he fired at a 16-year-old schoolgirl , Radio New Zealand said .
The man entered the Northcote College swimming pool changing sheds on Monday and told the girl and a friend : " You 're for it now . "
A shot was fired , but onlookers managed to seize the gun , the radio said .
Police , who were unsuccessful in finding the man overnight , described him as disturbed and dangerous .
-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746
SIMEX Brent closed on Monday owing to IPE holiday .
SINGAPORE 1996-08-26
The Brent crude futures market on the Singapore International Monetary Exchange ( SIMEX ) was closed on Monday in respect for a U.K. national holiday .
THE SIMEX Brent market keeps to the trading schedule of the International Petroleum Exchange ( IPE ) in London , which is closed for a British bank holiday .
Contracts traded in Singapore are mutually offset against contracts traded in London .
-- Singapore Newsroom ( +65 870 3081 )
Metro slides 3.3 pct after market opens .
SINGAPORE 1996-08-26
Shares in retailer Metro Holdings dropped 3.31 percent , or Singapore $ 0.20 , to S$ 5.85 minutes after the market opened on Monday .
By 0120 GMT , 357,000 Metro shares had been traded .
On Friday , Metro Holdings topped gainers , soaring by S$ 1.55 to close at S$ 6.05 on market rumours of a takeover bid by First Capital Corp .
The company said it was not aware of any reason for the surge .
-- Singapore newsroom ( 65 8703080 )
Indonesian rupiah stable in quiet late trading .
JAKARTA 1996-08-26
The Indonesian rupiah was stable against the dollar in quiet trading on Monday , dealers said .
They said volume was thin following a public holiday in Hong Kong and the United Kingdom .
" We did n't see anything from Singapore operators either .
It 's a pretty quiet day , " one foreign bank dealer said .
Spot rupiah was quoted at 2,342.0 / 42.5 at 0915 GMT , unchanged from the opening level .
It was softer in the morning due to relatively ample rupiah liquidity but recovered later .
Tomorrow and today rupiah closed at 2,342.00 / 42.45 and 2,341.5 / 42.0 , respectively .
Another dealer said operators were reluctant to unload rupiah despite ample conditions due to the month-end factor .
" There are two factors which determine the market at present .
The liquidity at month-end and the next court hearing scheduled for Thursday , " the dealer said .
Megawati Sukarnoputri , deposed leader of the Indonesian Democratic Party ( PDI ) has sued the government for ousting her as PDI leader .
The central Jakarta court adjourned the case last Thursday for possible out-of-court settlement .
The hearing is due to resume on Thursday .
Megawati 's lawyers said they were still discussing a possible out of court settlement but they was not optimistic an agreement could be reached .
The dealer said this issue remained a factor but its importance to the market seemed to diminish .
He said liquidity would be the main concern for the next few days .
Overnight swap was at 0.45 / 0.48 and tom / next at 0.50 / 0.55 .
One-month swap was at 18.0 / 18.5 , two at 34.0 / 35.0 , three at 52.75 / 53.50 and six at 106.5 / 107.0 points .
The central bank kept its intervention rate at 2,337 / 2,455 and the conversion rate at 2,337 / 2,383 on Monday .
Senate intelligence chairman in Saudi bomb probe .
DUBAI 1996-08-26
U.S. Senate Intelligence Committee chairman Arlen Specter , who has questioned whether Defence Secretary William Perry should resign over the latest bombing in Saudi Arabia , met Saudi officials on Monday during a brief visit to the kingdom .
A U.S. embassy spokesman in Riyadh said Specter , who arrived from neighbouring Oman on Sunday and left on Monday , had talks with Saudi and American officials in Dhahran , where 19 U.S. airmen were killed by a fuel truck bomb on June 25 , and Riyadh .
Specter met Crown Prince Abdullah and Minister of Defence and Aviation Prince Sultan in Jeddah , Saudi state television and the official Saudi Press Agency reported .
He had earlier visited Japan , South Korea and China .
Specter said after the bombing there should be a shake-up at the Pentagon and questioned whether Perry should resign .
He said he was not satisfied with some of Perry 's answers to the committee 's questions in closed testimony last month .
The question of whether Perry should resign remained open , the Pennsylvania Republican said .
FBI Director Louis Freeh , who has twice visited Saudi Arabia to seek improved cooperation with Saudi investigators , told the committee he was not entirely satisfied with Saudi cooperation on the Dhahran bomb and a previous bomb attack in Riyadh .
" If we 're to stay in Saudi Arabia , we need to have total cooperation , " Specter said .
The United States has 5,000 U.S. air force and other military personnel in Saudi Arabia .
Hijacked Sudanese plane leaves Cyprus for Britain .
LARNACA , Cyprus 1996-08-27
A Sudan Airways plane with 199 passengers and crew which was hijacked to Cyprus took off from Larnaca airport after refuelling and headed to Britain early on Tuesday , witnesses said .
Police said an unknown number of hijackers were on board the Airbus 310 which was hijacked on its way from Khartoum to Amman in Jordan .
One had threatened to blow it up unless it was refuelled and they were taken to London where they intended to surrender and seek political asylum .
Kurds clash again in Iraq , dozens reported dead .
ANKARA 1996-08-26
Heavy fighting broke out between two rival Kurdish factions in northern Iraq at midnight Sunday and at least 29 people were killed , one of the groups said on Monday .
The Kurdistan Democratic Party ( KDP ) said the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan ( PUK ) had broken the U.S.-brokered ceasefire agreed between the two parties last week .
The factions reached a ceasefire on Friday after a week of fierce fighting which had put an end to a truce agreed a year earlier .
" The PUK leadership who pledged to end fighting and cooperate with the latest U.S. initiative started a major military offensive against KDP positions , " the KDP said in a statement .
It said heavy fighting started at midnight in the region dividing the two warring factions , with the PUK aiming to break through to KDP 's headquarters in Salahuddin .
The KDP said 29 PUK fighters were killed in the attack .
It did not provide details of KDP casualties and a PUK spokesman was not immediately available for comment .
The statement said the PUK resumed its attack on Monday morning on KDP positions near Rawandouz and indiscriminately shelled the town of Dayana , killing a priest and injuring some civilians .
The fighting has threatened a U.S.-led peace plan to unite the mountainous Kurdish region in northern Iraq against President Saddam Hussein .
A U.S.-led air force has protected Iraqi Kurds against attack from Baghdad since shortly after the Gulf War in 1991 .
Egypt to press Britain over Islamist conference .
CAIRO 1996-08-26
Egypt will tell Britain it is concerned about a meeting of Islamists to be held in London soon , Foreign Minister Amr Moussa said on Monday .
" There is a question mark over this issue .
We , and many other countries , do n't understand this ( Britain 's ) position , " Moussa told reporters .
" Egypt will contact the British government to find out the truth of the matter and to discuss the possible consequences of such an unfortunate step , " he added .
Egyptian government newspapers have criticised Britain for allowing Islamists , whom they brand as " terrorists " , to hold their conference , saying the meeting will be a chance for dangerous Moslem militants to plot against their countries of origin .
It is not clear when the conference will be held .
About 1,000 people have been killed in Egypt since Islamic militants took up arms in 1992 in an attempt to overthrow the government and set up a strict Islamic state .
Cairo says several Egyptian militants on the run from death sentences or convictions for violent attacks at home have taken shelter in Britain .
Israeli army ransacks Bedouin Palestinian camp .
AL-MUNTAR , West Bank 1996-08-26
Israeli security forces ransacked a Bedouin encampment in the West Bank on Monday to expel them from an area which Palestinians say had been earmarked for Jewish settlement expansion , residents said .
They said soldiers stole a gold necklace and about $ 2,000 in Israeli currency from an elderly woman and her daughter-in-law while rummaging through their luggage before destroying family shacks and animal barns .
" They rammed our shacks with jeeps and destroyed the shack over my baby , " said 25-year-old Amina Muhammad . "
He was saved only by a miracle . "
A spokesman for Israel 's civil administration in the West Bank said the Bedouins were moved because they were encamped on an Israeli army firing zone .
The spokesman Peter Lerner said he knew nothing about soldiers having stolen anything from the Palestinians .
Israeli security forces have been pursuing Bedouin Palestinians living in the desolate wilderness between East Jerusalem and the Dead Sea , where several Jewish settlements have been established .
The Israeli army also uses the area for military training .
U.S. base metals and scrap prices - August 26 .
U.S. premiums added to LME official cash settlement price , except for copper , which is added to the COMEX spot month .
Premium includes price for delivery to consumer 's works .
--
Aluminum : Western grade 3.25-3.75 cents / pound
Russian grade A7E 3.25-3.75 cents / pound
Russian grade A0 nominal 2.00-2.25 cents / pound
Zinc : Special high grade SHG 5.50-6.00 cents / pound
Lead 3.50-4.00 cents / pound
Tin ( Grade A ) 6.5-8.5 cents / pound
( low lead , 50 ppm ) 9.0-10.5 cents / pound
Nickel ( melting grade ) 9.0-12.0 cents / pound
Copper ( high grade cathode ) 2.50-3.0 cents / pound
--
Aluminum alloy ( A380 grade ) , Midwest
and East coast , delivered to consumer 65-66 cents / pound
--
Aluminum scrap , Midwest and East coast average price ,
delivered to consumer
Old Sheet and Cast metal 42 to 44 cents / pound
Turnings , clean and dry 43 to 44 cents / pound
Mixed low-copper clips 48 to 49 cents / pound
--
Copper scrap , Midwest and East coast average price ,
delivered to consumer
No2 Refined 75 to 77 cents / pound
No1 Bare Bright 91 to 92 cents / pound
No1 Burnt 87 to 90 cents / pound
--
Lead batteries , delivered consumer 4.5 to 6.0 cents / pound
U.S. Producer list / transaction prices
--
Alcan aluminum , U.S. Midwest ( effective date : August 1 , 1996 )
P1020 ingot 75 cents / pound
extrusion billet 85 cents / pound
Noranda aluminum , U.S. Midwest ( effective date:August 1 , 1996 )
ingot 75 cents / pound
extrusion billet 85 cents / pound
RSR pure lead price ( effective date : March 20 , 1996 )
52 cents / pound
Doe Run pure lead price ( effective date : August 14 , 1996 )
50 cents / pound
ASARCO pure lead ( effective date : August 1 , 1996 )
premium over LME cash 7.5 cents / pound
-- ( New York commodities desk 212 859 1646 )
Florida boy kills himself before starting new school .
FORT LAUDERDALE , Fla. 1996-08-26
A 12-year-old Florida boy hanged himself in his backyard just hours before he was due to start at a new school on Monday , police said .
Samuel Graham , who told his family earlier that he was nervous about starting at a new school because he feared teasing about his weight problem , had been due to spend his first day at Parkway Middle School Monday , police said .
The boy was last seen alive Sunday night when he joined his two younger brothers and father in a bedtime prayer .
Two younger brothers found him hanging from a tree early Monday morning .
His father cut him down and tried to revive him but paramedics pronounced him dead when they arrived .
The Broward County Sheriff 's Office found a step stool and a flashlight under the tree where the boy was hanged .
They said there was no sign of foul play and that investigators believed the death was a suicide .
CBOT rice closes higher on technical bounce .
CHICAGO 1996-08-26
CBOT rice futures closed higher on a technical bounce tied to signs the market was oversold , traders said .
" It rallied on ideas the market was oversold , " a trader said .
Traders said the U.S. cash market remains well above the benchmark Thai price which limited gains .
Rice futures volume was estimated at 450 contracts , up from 202 Friday .
Rice options volume was estimated at 50 contracts , down from 56 Friday .
Rice futures closed 13 to 16 cents per cwt higher , with September up 16 at $ 10.28 a cwt .
Sam Nelson 312-408-8721
Talbott to meet Russian , Canadian counterparts .
WASHINGTON 1996-08-26
Deputy Secretary of State Strobe Talbott flew to Ottawa on Monday to meet his Russian counterpart and discuss a range of bilateral and European security issues , the State Department said .
Talbott , the second-ranking State Department official , was to meet Russian Deputy Foreign Minister Georgy Mamedov as part of a regular pattern of consultations , the department said .
" There is much to discuss on the fall calendar , " acting chief spokesman Glyn Davies said . "
There 's a fairly intensive diplomatic calendar coming up in the fall . "
He said Talbott , who was scheduled to return on Tuesday , would also to meet his Canadian counterpart , Gordon Smith , in Ottawa for talks that would include the situation in Haiti .
U.S. Midwest hog market seen steady Tuesday - trade .
CHICAGO 1996-08-26
Midwest direct cash hog prices Tuesday were seen steady following strong demand Monday that lifted prices as much as $ 1.50 per cwt in some areas , livestock dealers said .
The demand was sparked by Saturday 's active slaughter , which left some packers short on supplies to get Monday operations started , they said .
Top prices in Iowa / southern Minnesota Tuesday were expected to range from mostly $ 59.50 to $ 60.00 , steady following a $ 0.50 - $ 1.50 jump Monday .
Illinois tops were seen matching Monday 's at $ 59.00 with tops in Indiana at $ 57.50 .
However , USDA reported tops of $ 58.00 in Illinois and in Iowa / southern Minnesota , $ 60.00 on some hogs Monday .
Attempts to move prices higher again Tuesday could be offset by expected increased hog marketings this week , sources said .
Producers were expected to ship as many hogs as they can ahead of the Labor Day holiday weekend , they said .
Demand for hogs is expected to be light by the end of the week , as the industry prepares for Labor Day , Monday , September 1 when most U.S. packers will be closed .
-- Bob Janis 312-983-7347--
Gore presents new image of lead attack dog .
Michael Posner
CHICAGO 1996-08-26
No more mild-mannered and meek Al Gore , the vice president and likely heir apparent to President Bill Clinton , emerged on Monday as the new Democratic attack dog leading a front-line assault on Bob Dole and House Speaker Newt Gingrich .
While Clinton takes a train trip to the Democratic Convention that will renominate him on Wednesday for a second term , Gore is the bright star in the convention city now .
Crowds anxiously wait for his appearances , thrusting out hands for him to grip as they scream " 12 more years " -- a wishful hope to eight years of Gore after a Clinton re-election .
Over a 15-hour span from Sunday evening to Monday morning , so many people jammed Gore events that the fire marshal stopped members of Congress , reporters and others from entering a pro-Israel rally and a meeting of the New York delegation .
In his appearances , the often stiff and wooden Gore seemed transformed into a new energetic , gesturing " pol " as he ripped into Republican presidential nominee Dole and Gingrich , who has emerged as the favorite right-wing foil of Democrats .
Gore told a roaring labor rally of about 1,000 union workers that Dole and Gingrich were the virtual personifaction of evil , without even mentioning that former Housing Secretary Jack Kemp is Dole 's running mate .
" With equal measures of ignorance and audacity this two-headed monster of Dole and Gingrich has been launching an all out assault on decades of progress of behalf of working men and women , " Gore said to whoops of " 12 more years . "
" They want to drive you out of politics and they ca n't , " he added . "
They want to silence your voices in elections . "
At a downtown hotel Monday , the 48-year-old Gore gave Wisconsin delegates a taste again of the new Gore .
" I want you to ask this question .
What would Wisconsin face if the same extremist coalition , the Gingrich / Dole Congress , also controlled the executive branch ? "
Gore said .
Noting the next presidential term will probably see two or three Supreme Court justice nominations , he warned , " Their extremist agenda would come out of the Gingrich Congress , into and through the Dole White House , down through the Supreme Court . "
He painted a scene of horrors he saw if Republicans controlled the White House and the Congress they hold now . "
Our personal and religious liberties would be at risk .
Medicare would be at risk of withering on the vine .
Medicaid would be at risk of being taken away from poor children .
Education would be at risk .
The environment would be at risk from the polluters that control that coalition , " he said .
His new style mixed an assault on Republicans with what he sees as " productive opportunity , a vision for the future that lifts up working families , that builds Wisconsin stronger , that builds America stronger .
With your help we can re-elect Bill Clinton . "
Dole 's tax cut plans were called " deja-voodoo economics .... It 's a warmed-over plan that failed and drove our economy into a ditch .
We got burned once and we wo n't let that happen to our nation again . "
Gore ridiculed Dole 's defense of the tobacco industry , praised Clinton for " courage " in advancing regulations of it .
To the delegates of Wisconsin , a leading dairy state , Gore had the right audience in poking fun at Dole 's comparison to addiction to tobacco to those who ca n't tolerate milk .
" Some people say milk is bad for you , " Gore said as Wisconsin delegates held aloft a plastic inflated cow .
He praised Clinton for vetoing the Republican Congress ' attempt to repeal parts of the Clean Air Act , and criticized Republicans for " slashing money to combat drugs in schools . "
" The choice has never been starker , the stakes today have never been higher , " Gore said . "
We 're not going to let them get away with that . "
Actor Reeve highlights Democrats ' first night .
CHICAGO 1996-08-26
The highlights of the first day of the Democratic convention on Monday were expected to feature a mix of party leaders and people who have overcome adversity .
Among the latter were gun control advocate Sarah Brady and actor Christopher Reeve and the politicians included Rep .
Richard Gephardt and Sen .
Thomas Daschle .
Here are thumbnail profiles of the convention 's key Monday speakers .
Sarah Brady -- The nation 's toughest gun control law is named after Ronald Reagan 's press secretary James Brady but it was his wife who was the major force behind its passage .
As head of Handgun Control Inc. , Sarah Brady , 54 , campaigned nonstop for tough gun control in the years following the shooting of her husband and then President Reagan in 1981 .
Her reward was the passage in 1993 of the " Brady Bill " which requires a mandatory five-day waiting period for purchase of handguns and also mandates background checks for would-be gun purchasers .
Reagan recovered fully from his wounds but Brady , who was close to death after being shot by John Hinckley Jr .
, suffered serious brain damage .
Sarah was Brady 's second wife and they have a son , James Scott Brady Jr .
Before the assassination attempt , she had worked for Republican congressmen and for the Republican Party .
Christopher Reeve -- Reeve was best known for playing the comic book hero Superman in four movies but his greatest heroics came in real life .
Reeve , an accomplished rider who owned several horses , suffered multiple injuries including two shattered neck vertebrae when he was thrown from his horse at an equestrian event in Culpepper , Virginia , on May 27 , 1995 .
Almost entirely paralyzed , Reeve underwent extensive surgery to fuse the vertebrae to the base of the skull and prevent any further damage to his spine .
That allowed him to be moved to a semi-upright position .
Over time he regained the power of speech , so much so that he was asked to address the opening night of the Democratic National Convention .
Reeve , 43 , was classically trained as an actor but became the prototypical handsome leading man .
He performed in summer stock and soap operas before being plucked as an almost unknown to play the lead in " Superman " and three sequels .
Richard Gephardt -- Gephardt , House Democratic leader , is a politician with a " Mr Clean " reputation who sought the presidency eight years ago and is widely believed to still have ambitions for the job .
Gephardt , 55 , the son of a milkman from a working class district of St. Louis , is a consummate congressional insider , sufficiently skilled in compromise and the ways of the legislature to manage the often-unruly House Democrats .
A former lawyer , he was in the front line of President Bill Clinton 's battle with the Republican-led Congress over the budget but has opposed the president 's decision to sign the Republican-written welfare reform bill .
He advocated tough action against foreign countries to cut U.S. trade deficits but sometimes been out of step with the party 's liberal wing .
He was an opponent of abortion until 1986 and voted for President Ronald Reagan 's big tax cut bill .
Gephardt , a red-haired square-jawed man , is a less than fiery orator .
His 1988 bid for the Democratic nomination only took off after he recreated himself as a firebreathing reformer of the establishment , standing up for blue collar workers and farmers .
Tom Daschle -- Daschle , 48 , was largely unknown outside Washington and his state of South Dakota when he surprisingly beat more prominent rivals to become Senate Democratic leader after the party lost its majority to the Republicans in 1994 .
A mild-mannered and youthful man who rose rapidly after entering the Senate in 1987 , he presented himself as a Midwest moderate , as a Democratic winner in a Republican state able to unite Senate factions .
Concern that he might be steamrollered by the vastly more experienced Republican leader Bob Dole was dispelled when he showed a tough edge , outmaneuvering Dole in a wrangle over scrapping a gas tax and raising the federal minimum wage .
In his early Senate years he was seen as a " prairie populist " , working on legislation protecting farmers ' prices and also on compensating veterans sickened by Agent Orange defoliant spraying in the Vietnam War .
Daschle was a key player in President Bill Clinton 's failed attempt at sweeping healthcare changes but when he became minority leader he declared he would be no water-carrier for the White House .
He has made clear he opposed Clinton 's signing of the Republican-initiated welfare reform bill .
He has spent his adult life in politics , coming to Congress as an aide in 1972 after three years in the Air Force and then being elected to the House of Representatives himself in 1978 .
U.S. boy , 13 , accused of murdering adoptive mother .
DALLAS 1996-08-26
A 13-year-old Dallas boy has been charged with murdering his adoptive mother over the weekend , police said on Monday .
Margaret McCullough , 55 , was found dead in her home on Saturday with gunshot wounds to the head .
Police , who at first thought her son had been kidnapped , found him on Sunday with a friend in his mother 's car in Oklahoma and arrested him .
A shotgun and a .357 handgun were found in the car .
A police spokesman said the boy was being questioned . "
They are talking to him now about the motive and everything else . "
McCullough had adopted the boy , who was the grandson of her late husband , shortly after his birth but neighbours said they often had loud arguments .
Pakistani bourse to use new recomposed index .
KARACHI , Pakistan 1996-08-26
The Karachi Stock Exchange ( KSE ) said on Monday it would introduce a new recomposed KSE-100 index on September 10 .
A KSE statement said the recomposed index would be more representative , capturing market capitalisation of 82.3 percent , up from 79.9 percent previously .
-- Karachi newsroom 9221-5685192
NWE oil products mixed , holiday dulls trade .
LONDON 1996-08-26
NWE oil products were mixed on Monday but markets were becalmed because of a public holiday in the United Kingdom , traders said .
An explosion at Repsol 's Puertollano refinery , which killed four workers , had not affected output of oil products , an official said .
" The plant is functioning as usual , " Jose Manuel Prieto , director of personnel , told Spanish state television .
Gasoline prices were notionally unchanged from Friday despite sagging NYMEX numbers , with the arbitrage window to the U.S. considered closed for the moment .
Eurograde barges were offered at $ 207 fob ARA for Amsterdam-Rotterdam barrels , and at $ 206 for full ARA material .
" There is no market at the moment , " one Rotterdam trader said . "
Maybe sentiment is a little bit weaker but prices have not changed . "
Outright gas oil prices were notionally softer as the NYMEX heating oil contract headed lower , and following news that the Indian Oil Corp ( IOC ) had issued a tender to buy only 120,000 tonnes of high speed diesel for October .
Asian traders had earlier expected an IOC tender for around 400,000 tonnes .
ARA gas oil barges were quiet although one trader said he had seen offers at $ 1 a tonne over September IPE for prompt barrels , while Antwerp material was available for 0-50 cents over September .
The IOC tender had " a bearish impact , but not a great impact , " one German player said .
Fuel oil markets were also listless .
Offers were around a dollar a tonne higher at $ 102 fob ARA but bids were scarce .
-- Nicholas Shaxson , London newsroom +44 171 542 8167
Prairies saw no frost Monday , none rest of week .
WINNIPEG 1996-08-26
Canada 's Prairies saw no frost on Monday morning and none was expected anywhere on the grainbelt until late in the Labour Day long weekend , Environment Canada said .
" Apparently , we 're home free for the rest of the week .
We 're not calling for any frost until after the weekend when it starts to cool off in northwestern Alberta after the weekend probably Monday or Tuesday , " meteorologist Gerald Machnee told Reuters .
Sprague , Manitoba , on the Minnesota border was the cold spot of the Prairies Monday morning at 4.0 Celsius ( 39.2 F ) .
Temperatures at ground level can be 2.0 to 5.0 Celsius lower than at chest level depending on windspeed , sky conditions and ground surface moisture .
Freezing occurs at 0 Celsius ( 32.0 F ) .
North Battleford , Sask .
, reported a low of 5.0 Celsius ( 41.0 F ) and Grande Prairie , Alta .
, in the Peace River Valley reported 7.0 Celsius ( 44.6 F ) .
Machnee dismissed talk of frost Wednesday by proponents of the " full moon , frost soon " school of thought .
Lows on August 28 across the Prairies should range from 8.0 to 12.0 Celsius with highs around 30.0 Celsius .
-- Gilbert Le Gras 204 947 3548
Brush Wellman comments on beryllium lawsuits .
CLEVELAND 1996-08-26
Brush Wellman Inc said Monday that 10 of 24 lawsuits involving chronic beryllium disease have been dismissed since July 1 .
The leading U.S. beryllium producer said in a conference call it has traditionally been pro-active regarding the workplace disease , a lung ailment which can affects a small percent of people whose immune systems are susceptible .
Of the 14 remaining suits , 10 were filed by employees of industrial Brush Wellman customers and Brush Wellman liability in such suits is typically covered by insurance , Timothy Reid , vice president of corporate communications , said on the call .
The company was responding to an article in Sunday 's New York Times .
He said the article largely reiterated information about the suits and the disease which had previously been made public via Securities and Exchange Commission filings and annual reports .
" Brush Wellman has been a leader in dealing with health and safety issues ( related to chronic Beryllium disease ) for nearly 50 years , " he said . "
We have a record of going beyond regulatory requirements ... and we consistently share the most current information available ... with customers and employees . "
The customer employee suits were filed in 1990-95 , he said .
A class action filed by a former Brush Wellman employee in April 1996 was dismissed in July , he said .
The company is " vigorously defending " the remaining four suits filed by former and current Brush Wellman employees , he said .
After a delayed opening , the stock was off 1-1/2 to 18-7/8 .
-- Cleveland Newsdesk 216-579-0077
Salomon cuts refiner Q3 EPS view on margin concern .
NEW YORK 1996-08-26
Salomon Brothers analyst Paul Ting said he cut his share earnings estimates on refiners for the third quarter on the belief the companies will face sharp revisions in refining and marketing margins .
He cut his third-quarter share earnings estimate on :
-- Diamond Shamrock Inc to $ 0.38 from $ 0.73 versus the Street 's consensus $ 0.63
-- Sun Co to $ 0.15 from $ 0.85 versus the consensus $ 0.63
-- Tosco Corp to $ 0.95 from $ 1.03 versus the consensus $ 0.94
-- Total Petroleum ( North America ) Ltd to $ 0.15 from $ 0.46 versus the consensus $ 0.33
-- And , Valero Energy Corp to $ 0.27 from $ 0.55 compared with the consensus $ 0.40 .
PRESALE - Marion County Board of Education , W. Va .
AMT : 3,250,000 DATE : 09/04/96 NYC Time : 1200 CUSIP : 569399
ISSUER : Marion County Board of Education ST : WV
ISSUE : Public School , Series 1996 TAX STAT:Exempt-ULT
M / SP / F : NA / NA / NA BOOK ENTRY : Y
ENHANCEMENTS : None BANK QUAL : Y
DTD : 09/01/96 SURE BID : N
DUE : 5/1/98-02 SR MGR :
1ST CPN : 05/01/97
CALL : Non-Callable NIC
DELIVERY : 9/17/96 approx ORDERS :
PAYING AGENT : WesBanco Bank Fairmont , Fairmont
L.O. : Steptoe & Johnson , Clarksburg
F.A. : Ferris , Baker Watts , Inc. , Charleston
LAST SALE : $ 7,330,000 ( MBIA ) 3/1/90 @ 6.14900 % NIC ; 4yrs 4mos Avg ; BBI-7.27 %
Year Amount Coupon Yield Price Conc .
1998 575,000
1999 610,000
2000 650,000
2001 685,000
2002 730,000
COMPETITIVE PRE-SALE CONTRIBUTED BY J.J. KENNY K-SHEETS :
BALANCE - Ohio refunding bonds at $ 290,000 .
STATE OF OHIO
RE : $ 70,375,000
( OHIO BUILDING AUTHORITY )
STATE FACILITIES REFUNDING BONDS
1996 SERIES A
REPRICING OF THE BALANCE OF THE BONDS IN THE ACCOUNT .
9,215,000.00
OCASEK GOVERNMENT OFFICE BUILDING
( C )
MOODY 'S : A1 S&P : AA- FITCH : AA-
CONFIRMED CONFIRMED
Delivery Date : 08/29/1996
Maturity Balance Coupon List
10/01 / 1998C 125M 4.50 4.20
6,045,000.00
VERN RIFFE CENTER
( D )
MOODY 'S : A1 S&P : AA- FITCH : AA-
CONFIRMED CONFIRMED
Delivery Date : 08/29/1996
Maturity Balance Coupon List
10/01 / 1998D 165M 4.50 4.20
Grand Total : 290M
Goldman , Sachs & Co .
A.G. Edwards & Sons , Inc .
Banc One Capital Corporation
S.B.K- Brooks Investment Corp .
Seasongood & Mayer
-- U.S. Municipal Desk , 212-859-1650
PRESS DIGEST - Washington Post business - Aug 26 .
WASHINGTON 1996-08-26
The Washington Post carried only local business stories on August 26 , 1996 .
Chelsea makes political debut on Clinton train trip .
CHILLICOTHE , Ohio 1996-08-25
- Chelsea Clinton , until now carefully shielded from the exposure of public life , made her political debut on Sunday on her father 's whistlestop train trip .
Chelsea , 16 , was at President Bill Clinton 's side as he rode the rails through parts of West Virginia , Kentucky and Ohio , and was introduced at every stop .
She even worked ropelines , shaking hands with excited fans .
Hillary Rodham Clinton saw her husband and daughter off on the trip in Huntington , West Virginia and then went on to Chicago to begin a rigorous Democratic Convention schedule .
Asked if Chelsea would have a prominent role in the campaign , White House spokesman Mike McCurry said : " She 'll do what she did today when she can .
She has to go back to school . "
The president 's daughter is going into her senior year of high school at Sidwell Friends School , a private school in Washington .
McCurry said Chelsea has asked to go on the train trip and attend the convention where her father will be renominated , but said her exposure did not signal the start of a new political career .
Chelsea " is a very poised young lady , but she 's not that much interested in politics , " the spokesman said .
Dutch closing share market report .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-26
Dutch shares drifted to a lower close on Monday , dragged down by weakness in the domestic bond market and turnover depressed by the UK bank holiday and lack of any significant U.S. economic data .
The AEX index of leading shares closed 4.54 points easier at 556.19 , the day 's low .
The Dutch market had been on the defensive all day but a softer start to Wall Street did little to boost sentiment in late trade , dealers said .
" It was always going to be a tough day with participation so low .
But the only thing really worrying the market was the bonds , and that dragged us lower , " one dealer said .
Stocks were down across the board , with Dutch PTT topping the volume list and closing down 1.90 guilders at 58.70 .
The post and telecoms firm posted an 8.5 percent rise in first half earnings on Friday , just below analysts ' expectations .
IHC Caland reported first half results well under forecasts on Monday and the shares suffered as a result .
They were trading unchanged just before the release of figures but closed 2.40 guilders down at 80.70 after it reported net profits of 34.9 million guilders against 36.6 million last year and estimates ranging from 37.5 to 47.2 million .
IHC also forecast post tax earnings rising 21 percent for the full year .
Banking group ING traded ex-dividend today and finished 0.60 guilders weaker at 52.90 as a result .
But Nutricia shrugged off its ex-div tag to soar a further 4.10 guilders to 214.40 continuing its explosive rally sparked by the 51 percent jump in first half net profits last week , which set the market alight on Friday , sending the shares up 18.40 at 210.00 by the close .
Engineering concern Stork started the day well as the shares attracted some follow-through interest to the announcement late on Friday that its Fokker Aviation unit had won a major order .
But the rally was short-lived and Stork ended just 0.20 up at 51.00 guilders .
-- Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000
Tapie to quit French assembly seat as film opens .
PARIS 1996-08-26
Former businessman and soccer boss Bernard Tapie said that he would give up his seat in the National Assembly by Wednesday , the day a film by Claude Lelouche in which he stars opens in France .
" I will no longer be deputy by the time the film opens , " he said in a broadcast interview .
" Just about , " he told Europe 1 radio when asked whether he had sent his letter of resignation to Assembly speaker Philippe Seguin .
A Seguin spokeswoman confirmed that no letter or call had yet been received .
Tapie , 53 , was resigning just ahead of expected government action to eject him from the Assembly following a finding by the Supreme Court that he was bankrupt and thus ineligible for public office for a five-year period .
Tapie , the target of a blizzard of legal actions over his now-destroyed business empire and the Marseille soccer team he once ran , has a starring role in Lelouche 's " Homme , femmes : mode d'emploi " ( Men , women : instructions for use ) .
He plays a power-hungry lawyer in the movie described as " a tender and cruel comedy " by Lelouche , who is making his 35th film .
" I have paid too dearly for mixing two careers , " Tapie said . "
In France , you cannot be a film artist and a national politician at the same time .
That is why I will no longer be deputy by the time the film opens . "
Justice Minister Jacques Toubon began last month the formal process of ejecting Tapie from the French parliament as well as stripping him of his seat in the European parliament .
The French procedure was expected to be completed before October 2 , when the National Assembly is to reconvene after a summer break , but the European procedure was expected to take longer .
Tapie 's lawyer has said he intends to appeal to the European Court of Human Rights in an effort to prevent or delay the loss of his European seat .
But such an appeal , even if the court were to accept the case , which it is not obliged to do , would not suspend enforcement of the French judgement against him .
Tapie faces a probable spell in prison after he loses his parliamentary immunity , since two appeal courts have confirmed jail sentences of eight and six months against him for tax fraud and rigging a soccer match .
He is appealing in both cases to the Supreme Court .
Bank of France drains 3.9 bln Ffr at tender .
PARIS 1996-08-26
The Bank of France drained 3.9 billion francs at a securities repurchase tender held on Monday to allocate funds for injection into the money market on Tuesday .
It accepted bids for 44.3 billion francs in new liquidity , 3.9 billion less than the 48.2 billion leaving the market on Tuesday when a previous pact expires .
The new pact expires on September 3 .
The Bank of France said it allocated 13.4 billion francs to bidders offering Treasury bills as collateral , satisfying 3.4 percent of such demand .
It allotted a further 30.9 billion to bidders putting up private paper , satisfying 12.5 percent of this demand .
-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452
RABOBANK [ RABN.CN ] SEES H2 NET GROWTH UNDER 10 PCT .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-26
Dutch co-operative bank Rabobank Nederland BA 's net profit growth might slow to less than than 10 year percent in the second half of 1996 , executive board chairman Herman Wijffels said on Monday .
The unlisted bank earlier announced a 1996 interim net profit of 853 million guilders , up 21.5 percent on the 702 million guilders reported in the first half of 1995 .
He said second-half profit growth would depend on customer demand for loans , which was already easing , and the performance of financial markets , which were strong in the first half and boosted securities , trading and underwriting income .
" We expect reasonable growth in the second half .
Maybe it will be in single-digits , " Wijffels told Reuters .
He said growth in customer demand in the first half was 50 percent above normal but it was hard to maintain this pace .
Rabobank 's net profit was 1.43 billion guilders in 1995 .
The bank earlier warned that profit growth would slow in the second half , citing the increasing momentum in profit growth in the comparative period of 1995 and increased investment .
But Wijffels was unable to quantify second half investment to improve and extend domestic and offshore services .
-- Garry West , Amsterdam newsroom +31 20 504 5000
PRESS DIGEST - FRANCE - LE MONDE AUG 26 .
PARIS 1996-08-26
These are leading stories in Monday 's afternoon daily Le Monde , dated Aug 27 .
FRONT PAGE
-- Ipsos poll reports majority of French public opinion sympathises with plight of Africans seeking to renew or obtain work and residence permits , calling government " stubborn , " " confused " and " cold-hearted . "
BUSINESS PAGES
-- SNCF railway trade unions want renegotiation of government bailout package , as European Union prepares more proposals to increase competition .
-- World steel market shows signs of upturn .
-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 42 21 53 81
ATRIA SEES H2 RESULT UP ON H1 .
HELSINKI 1996-08-26
Finnish foodstuffs group Atria Oy said in a statement on Monday it expects its result to improve in the second half of 1996 compared to the first half .
" The result of the second year-half is expected to improve on the early part of the year , " Atria said .
Atria said earlier its January-June profit before extraordinary items , appropriations and taxes fell to 15 million markka from 39 in the first-half of 1995 .
BRIGHT-BELGIANS SPEED AFTER SCHUMACHER 'S WIN .
BRUSSELS
Michael Schumacher 's victory in the Belgian Formula One Grand Prix at Spa-Francorchamps sparked a speeding epidemic on Belgian roads after the race was over .
Belga news agency reported that police checked more than 3,000 drivers amd booked 222 for speeding on their way home after the race .
Some were clocked doing 180 kilometres an hour ( 112 miles per hour ) , Belga said .
Schumacher won the race in 1 hour 28 minutes 15.125 seconds at an average speed of 208.442 km / hour ( 130 m.p.h. ) .
Thai PM proposes Sept 18 for no-confidence debate .
BANGKOK 1996-08-26
Thai Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa on Monday proposed September 18 as the date for parliamentary debate on an opposition no-confidence motion accusing him of incompetence .
The president of parliament had earlier said September 11 could be set for the debate .
The opposition motion against Banharn accuses him of being incompetent , lacking ethical leadership and alleges his administration is corrupt .
His critics allege he may be attempting to delay the debate .
Banharn has denied the accusations and said he is ready to clear himself in parliament .
" In my opinion September 18 would be a convenient date for the government to answer questions .
This has nothing to do with the accusation that I am trying to escape the debate , " Banharn told reporters after meeting coalition partners .
Banharn 's 13-month-old , six-party coalition government controls 209 seats in the 391-seat lower house of parliament .
Political infighting within Banharn 's Chart Thai party has raised doubts whether he can hold his supporters together and defeat the opposition motion , political analysts said .
" We are still waiting to fix a date .
September 18 is regarded as tentative because we still have not received the order to fix it on the agenda , " said an official at parliament 's agenda section .
The last no-confidence debate against Banharn 's coalition in May was won by the government .
Fontaine - 6mth parent forecast .
TOKYO 1996-08-26
Six months to August 31 , 1996
( in billions of yen unless specified )
LATEST PREVIOUS ACTUAL
( Parent ) FORECAST FORECAST YEAR-AGO
Sales 3.30 3.17 2.75
Current 400 million 260 million 231 million
Net 170 million 170 million 142 million
NOTE - Fontaine Co Ltd sells women " s fashion wigs .
Manila international coconut oil prices .
MANILA 1996-08-26
International Philippine coconut oil prices as reported by the United Coconut Associations of the Philippines ( dollars per tonne cif Europe ) .
Buyers Sellers Last Prev
JulAug 775 787.50 unq unq
AugSep 752.50 758.75 unq unq
SepOct 733.75 743.50 unq unq
OctNov unq 740 unq unq
NovDec unq 732.50 unq unq
RESEARCH ALERT - Aronkasei cut .
TOKYO 1996-08-26
Nomura Research Institute Ltd downgraded Aronkasei Co Ltd to a " 2 " rating from its previous " 1 " , market sources said on Monday .
In its three-grade rating system , the research institute assigns a " 2 " rating to issues whose values it sees moving within 10 percentage points in either direction of the key 225-share Nikkei average over the next six months .
Nomura officials were not immediately available for comment .
PRESS DIGEST - Tunisia - Aug 26 .
TUNIS 1996-08-26
These are the leading stories in the Tunisian press on Monday .
Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy .
LA PRESSE
- English langage to be taught as of the eighth year of the primary school instead of the third year of the secondary school .
LE TEMPS
- International Fair opens in the northern city of Beja with the participation of 16 foreign countries .
U.N. official Ekeus heads for Baghdad .
MANAMA 1996-08-26
Senior United Nations arms official Rolf Ekeus left Bahrain for Baghdad on Monday for talks with Iraqi officials , a U.N. spokesman said .
The spokesman said Ekeus , chairman of the United Nations Special Commission ( UNSCOM ) , would spend two or three days in Iraq but declined to give further details .
U.N. oficials have said Ekeus would hold talks with Iraqi Deputy Prime Minister Tareq Aziz and other officials as part of an agreement Iraq reached with the United Nations in June to hold higher level political talks with Ekeus .
The Security Council on Friday asked Iraq to stop blocking arms inspectors search for concealed weapons or materials they believe were being shuttled around to avoid detection .
Disarming Iraq of weapons of mass destruction under 1991 Gulf War ceasefire terms is a prerequisite before the lifting of crippling sanctions imposed on Iraq in 1990 for invading Kuwait .
PRESS DIGEST - Lebanon - Aug 26 .
BEIRUT 1996-08-26
These are the leading stories in the Beirut press on Monday .
Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy .
AN-NAHAR
- The north Lebanon elections ...
Almost no chance at all for any complete ticket to win altogether and the results will weaken some leaders .
- The surprise ...
Opposition Boutros Harb scoring high in preliminary results and former prime minister Omar Karame moves backwards .
- Fears of an Israeli operation causes the redistribution of Syrian troops locations in Lebanon .
AS-SAFIR
- Parliament Speaker Berri : The occupied south should not be used as a winning card in elections .
- Prices of alimentary goods up 13.4 percent in 1996 .
AL-ANWAR
- Christian Maronite Patriarch Sfeir : We fear a movement from democracy to dictatorship .
AD-DIYAR
- A cabinet minister : " Lebanon First " aims at splitting the Syrian-Lebanese peace tracks with Israel .
NIDA'A AL-WATAN
- Prime Minister Hariri : Elections are the beginning of a long political life which we begin with an incomplete ticket of 17 candidates .
- The Lebanese Association for the Democracy of Elections cited 51 incidents of violation in the north Lebanon round .
PRESS DIGEST - Malta - Aug 26 .
VALLETTA 1996-08-26
These are the leading stories in the Maltese press on Monday .
Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy .
THE TIMES
- Visitors slam bus and taxi drivers for cheating .
Tourists interviewed in Malta complain about over-charging .
IN-NAZZJON
- Government considering measures for better road discipline .
Malta , with a population of 365,000 , has 195,000 registered vehicles , with 80,000 new cars having been introduced on the congested roads in 10 years .
- Five people arrested in Romania after drugs container found in Malta .
The container , with 7.5 tonnes of cannabis , was found in Malta Freeport in transit from Singapore to Romania .
L-ORIZZONT
- Opposition leader Alfred Sant on steep rise in taxes over 10 years .
He reiterates promise that a future Labour government will remove VAT .
Tamils demonstrate outside U.N. headquarters .
GENEVA 1996-08-26
Thousands of Tamils demonstrated outside the United Nations ' European headquarters in Geneva on Monday to appeal for U.N. recognition of their fight for independence from Sri Lanka .
The demonstrators , said by police to number 6,000 , also urged the release of Nadarajah Muralidaran , Swiss-based leader of the the Tamil Tiger guerrillas , who has been held in a Zurich jail since April on charges of extortion .
The demonstrators delivered an appeal to the U.N. human rights centre demanding an immediate end to " state terrorism " against Tamils and the Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam ( LTTE ) .
FOCUS - Eurobourses end mixed but London recovers .
Leonard Santorelli
LONDON 1996-08-27
European bourses closed mixed on Tuesday with London clawing back most of the day 's losses despite an unsteady start on wall Street , hit by inflation worries .
The dollar weakened during the day with many dealers sidelined because of uncertainty over Tokyo 's monetary direction ahead of the important Japanese Tankan economic survey out on Wednesday .
But it recovered at the close of trade .
Stocks in London started the week badly after a three-day weekend , slipping 0.3 percent , but bargain-hunters later moved in and the FTSE index recovered most of the lost ground to end only just in negative ground .
Tuesday 's patchy showing in London followed a string of records last week , culminating in Friday 's trading high of 3,911 , fuelled by a wave of European interest rate cuts .
The London bourse drew little help from the unsettled morning on Wall Street , which slipped in and out of positive ground after a stronger-than-expected August consumer confidence report refuelled inflation fears , pulling U.S. Treasuries back from their early peaks .
Shortly after the report appeared showing the confidence index rising to 109.4 in August from a revised 107.0 in July , Wall Street relinquished virtually all its morning gains .
" Treasuries remain very sensitive to any indication of a strong economy and we 're still in that summer doldrum period of light trading , " said Alan Ackerman , market strategist at Fahnestock & Co . "
Consequently , stocks and bonds are both subject to rapid swings . "
Frankfurt was the one bright spot in Europe .
Floor trading ended up 0.25 percent and the computerised IBIS index climbed nearly 0.4 percent , given a push by the performance of chemical shares . "
The market is trading 100 percent on fundamentals at the moment as interest rate fantasy disappears -- it 's all company news , " said one trader .
French shares ended slightly down amid growing unease about a difficult autumn for the government which also weighed on the franc , dealers said .
Bond prices were weaker and the franc was quoted at 3.4210 per mark for the first time since August 13 as worries about the government 's autumn budget and a weak U.S. currency lifted the mark and squeezed French investments .
The dollar , which dropped sharply on Monday because of jitters over the Japanese Tankan survey , weakened further in quiet trading but regained losses to end the day close to Monday 's levels .
" Besides the Tankan , there 's nothing really until the U.S. jobs numbers next week , " said a UK bank corporate dealer . "
There is still the summer malaise hanging over the market . "
Foreign exchange markets regard the Tankan report as an important indication of the country 's future monetary policy direction .
If it points to weakness in the economy , the report will help the dollar regain some lost ground as speculation of a near-term rise in Japanese interest rates will evaporate .
The Japanese discount rate is currently at a record low of 0.5 percent .
The dollar was also pressured by the mark 's strength against European currencies amid renewed concerns over Europe 's economic and monetary union ( EMU ) timetable .
CURRENCIES
The dollar was at 1.4788 marks and 107.74 yen at the close of European trading compared with 1.4789 marks and 107.55 yen on Monday .
STOCK MARKETS
The Financial Times-Stock Exchange index of 100 leading British shares ended 1.8 points lower at 3,905.7 .
In Paris , the CAC-40 share index finished down 2.43 at 2,017.99 .
The 30-share DAX index in Frankfurt closed up 6.48 at 2,558.84 .
PRECIOUS METALS
Gold closed at $ 388.55 an ounce , compared with Monday 's close of $ 388.75 on international markets .
Silver ended up one cent $ 5.24 .
More hostages freed from hijacked Sudanese plane .
STANSTED , England 1996-08-27
Armed hijackers believed to be Iraqis released between 60 and 70 people on Tuesday from a Sudan Airways plane carrying 199 passengers and crew that landed in London after being diverted on a flight from Khartoum to Amman , authorities said .
A spokesman for Stansted airport said that the unidentified hijackers were demanding to see a British-based member of the Iraqi Community Association , called Mr Sadiki , and that police were trying to trace him .
Police spokeswoman Kim White said police had already contacted Sadiki and were trying to arrange to bring him to Stansted , 30 miles ( 48 km ) north-east of London , to talk to the hijackers .
The airport spokesman said the six hijackers , who police said were armed with grenades and possibly other explosives , were believed to be Iraqi nationals .
The hijackers started to release people for the Airbus plane in batches of 10 , starting with women and children , in what police described as a " controlled release " .
Police said most of the passengers were Sudanese but that there were also an unknown number of Iraqis , Jordanians , Palestinians , Syrians and Saudis .
Later they said the number of passengers released from the plane had reached 80 .
FEATURE - " Eco terrorists " target UK builders .
Edna Fernandes
LONDON 1996-08-27
Ecological warfare has broken out across the British construction industry , striking some of the biggest corporates as activists give up peaceful protests and seek to hit builders where it hurts -- their profit margins .
Described by one British company as " eco-terrorism " , it is seen as the new business risk of the 1990s .
Famous names like Tarmac Plc , Costain Group Plc and ARC , a unit of conglomerate Hanson Plc , have all been targeted .
Activist groups are no longer seen by British firms as a harmless , badly organised ragbag of students and hippies .
" You only have to see them in action at protests , " said David Harding , spokesman at ARC , Hanson 's aggregates company . "
They walk around with mobile phones and camera equipment , they communicate and gather support for demos via the Internet -- we 're talking about a highly sophisticated organisation . "
One road protestor under the codename Steady Eddie told construction journal " Building " earlier this year , " If it comes down to full-scale economic warfare , we will aim to drive them out of business . "
As well as financial threats , companies also emphasise the " terror " tactics used .
Costain 's contract to build the controversial Newbury bypass , which runs through a conservation area , has led to violent protests delaying building , bomb threats , staff intimidation and picketing of chief executive Alan Lovell 's home .
A Costain spokesman told Reuters : " We 've had all sorts of protests at the head office and the chief executive 's house .
But it 's when it gets to the ( employee ) families -- that it goes across the line . "
Tactics used by some underground groups including the cryptic Berkshire Wood Elves , which distribute leaflets with instructions on home-made explosives , are now the subject of a police investigation .
Other larger activist groups include Earth First , The Land is Ours , Alarm UK and Road Alert .
The groups have targeted specific projects like the Newbury bypass and the M3 motorway through Twyford Down in the southern county of Hampshire .
But they are also campaigning on broader issue such as stopping the government road building programme and out-of-town superstores which they say create more traffic , pollution and damage local communities .
The government has slashed its road-building spending .
Although protests may have contributed to the decision it has been seen primarily as economic rather than ecological .
Graham Watts , chief executive of the Construction Industry Council , said : " I do n't think many firms involved in tendering for sensitive projects realise the impact environmental activity has on the cost of running a project .
" But they are more alert than they were 3-4 years ago .
There 's no doubt it 's a big issue now . "
He says the damage comes in two forms : " Tangible -- in the form of extra costs , additional security , threats to staff and the more intangible damage caused by negative publicity . "
Watts said the cost of protesting can be heavy once the company is locked into a contract .
" I do often hear on the industry circuit of tales where the company tenders at low margins and the demonstrations which follow means they are running the project at a loss . "
ARC says it 's not just contractors in the front line but also suppliers like itself .
Its own quarries came under attack after it emerged that it may be a supplier for the Newbury bypass .
" It was called the " First Battle of the Newbury bypass ' , " said ARC 's Harding .
" We had 300 Earth First protestors invade and occupy our site .
Hundreds of thousands of pounds ( dollars ) of damage was done in one day .
Plus there was the knock-on cost of lost production and extra security in future . "
Simon Brown , analyst at investement bank UBS , said this new phenomenon has led to a change in the way the industry evaluates project risk .
" When talking to Tarmac about the M3 link ( through Twyford Down ) they made it fairly clear that their risk assessment methods have been changed and now involve a very clear environmental risk analysis . "
Harding says others have done the same . "
As a result of eco-terrorism we are looking at controversial jobs more closely to see if the profit margins are wide enough to cover things like extra security . "
For an industry already suffering from razor-thin margins , overcapacity and stagnant demand , eco-terrorism is the latest bizarre twist in the construction sector 's tale of woe .
London Carnival ends in high spirits .
LONDON 1996-08-26
London 's annual Notting Hill Carnival , the largest in Europe and second in the world only to Rio , ended peacefully on Monday with an estimated 800,000 revellers singing and dancing the day away in high spirits .
Police said they made 30 arrests and there were two stabbings .
But there was no repeat of the ugly scenes that used to scar the street festival , and police praised the crowds over the two days of festivities as good-natured .
Around 400 police were wounded in riots in 1976 when the carnival , now in its 31st year , acquired its darker reputation from which it is now only slowly recovering .
Shopkeepers still board up their windows and many residents leave town for the weekend , but for four or five years there has been no disorder and relatively little crime .
OFFICIAL JOURNAL CONTENTS - OJ C 248 OF AUGUST 26 , 1996 .
*
( Note - contents are displayed in reverse order to that in the printed Journal )
ANNEX
STATEMENT OF THE COUNCIL 'S REASONS
ANNEX I
ANNEX A
STATEMENT OF THE COUNCIL 'S REASONS END OF DOCUMENT .
Indonesia newspaper reports central bank scandal .
JAKARTA 1996-08-27
Indonesia 's central bank suffered seven billion rupiah ( $ 2.9 million ) in losses resulting from fake transactions , the Jakarta Post reported on Tuesday .
A Bank Indonesia spokeswoman confirmed the newspaper report but declined to give further details .
The bank 's governor Sudradjat Djiwandono was quoted as saying on Monday about 5.4 billion rupiah of the seven billion rupiah had been recovered .
The newspaper said it was the central bank 's first public scandal in its 43-year history .
The paper said five people had been arrested and police were looking for two more suspects .
( $ 1 = 2,341 rupiah )
GOLF - PLAYERS DIVIDED ON CART REQUEST FOR OLAZABAL .
NORTHAMPTON , England 1996-08-27
Seve Ballesteros and Colin Montgomerie are divided on whether Jose Maria Olazabal should be allowed to return to the European PGA Tour using a motorised cart to transport him around the course .
The Spaniard has not played for nearly a year because of rheumatoid arthritis in both his feet , and organisers of a pairs event to be staged in Bordeaux , France from October 17 to 20 have been asked to provide him with a buggy .
" If the ( Tour 's tournament ) committee decides to change the rule I would not be against it , " said Ballesteros , Olazabal 's compatriot and Ryder Cup captain .
But commitee member Montgomerie said it could set an unhelpful precedent . "
I know Olly 's situation is very unfortunate , but I do n't think we can start giving dispensations , " he said . "
You 've got to have a rule for everybody and I do n't think it 's feasible . "
The use of carts is generally prohibited in the professional game , and if Olazabal is allowed to use one in Bordeaux , he might then request one for the qualifying tournaments for next year 's Ryder Cup .
SOCCER - POLAND TIES CYPRUS 2-2 IN FRIENDLY MATCH .
BELCHATOW , Poland 1996-08-27
Poland and Cyprus drew
2-2 ( halftime 0-0 ) in a friendly soccer international on
Tuesday .
Scorers :
Poland - Krzysztof Warzycha ( 46th minute ) , Marcin Mieciel
( 57th )
Cyprus - Klimis Alexandrou ( 75th ) , Kostas Malekos ( 80th )
Attendance 3,000
SOCCER - THOMSON RESIGNS AS MANAGER OF RAITH ROVERS .
KIRKCALDY , Scotland 1996-08-27
Jimmy Thomson became Scotland 's first managerial casualty of the season on Tuesday when he quit Raith Rovers , bottom of the premier division .
Thomson resigned after the club 's directors asked him to return to his previous position as youth team coach .
He had been in charge for six months .
Raith lost their first two games of the season away to Rangers and Celtic , then crashed 3-0 at home to Motherwell on Saturday .
A club statement said : " The directors of Raith Rovers FC invited Jimmy Thomson to relinquish the post of manager and to resume his former position as youth team coach .
" Regrettably Jimmy has felt unable to accept that offer , and has accordingly left the club . "
Thomson said : " I am leaving with my dignity and my pride intact , and that is very important to me .
" While not agreeing with the directors ' decision , I respect their reasons for making it . "
RUGBY UNION - GRIQUALAND WEST AND NEW ZEALAND DRAW IN TOUR MATCH .
KIMBERLEY , South Africa 1996-08-27
Griqualand West
and New Zealand drew 18-18 ( halftime 6-10 ) in their rugby union
tour maltch on Tuesday .
Scorers :
Griqualand West - Tries : Andre Cloete , Leon van der Wath .
Conversion : Boeta Wessels .
Penalties : Wessels 2 .
New Zealand - Tries : Scott McLeod , Glen Osborne .
Conversion :
Jon Preston .
Penalties : Preston 2 .
SOCCER - BALL RESIGNS AS MANCHESTER CITY MANAGER .
MANCHESTER , England 1996-08-27
Former England midfielder Alan Ball resigned as manager of first division side Manchester City on Monday night , the club said .
Ball , appointed in July 1995 , was unable to prevent City being relegated from the premier league last season and his record read 13 wins , 14 draws and 22 losses in 49 games .
They have lost two of their three matches so far this season .
Club secretary Bernard Halford said in a statement : " The chairman and Board would like to place on record their appreciation of his endeavours and efforts whilst in his period of office and wish him well in the future . "
SOCCER - ENGLISH LEAGUE STANDINGS .
LONDON 1996-08-27
English league soccer standings
after Tuesday 's matches ( tabulated under played , won , drawn ,
lost , goals for , against , points ) :
Division one
Tranmere 3 2 1 0 6 3 7
Bolton 3 2 1 0 5 2 7
Barnsley 2 2 0 0 5 2 6
Wolverhampton 2 2 0 0 4 1 6
Queens Park Rangers 2 2 0 0 4 2 6
Stoke 2 2 0 0 4 2 6
Norwich 3 2 0 1 4 3 6
Ipswich 3 1 1 1 6 4 4
Birmingham 2 1 1 0 5 4 4
Crystal Palace 3 1 1 1 3 2 4
Oxford 3 1 0 2 6 3 3
Bradford 2 1 0 1 3 2 3
Huddersfield 2 1 0 1 3 3 3
Portsmouth 3 1 0 2 3 5 3
Reading 2 1 0 1 3 5 3
Manchester City 3 1 0 2 2 3 3
West Bromwich 3 0 2 1 2 3 2
Port Vale 3 0 2 1 2 4 2
Sheffield United 2 0 1 1 4 5 1
Grimsby 3 0 1 2 4 7 1
Charlton 2 0 1 1 1 3 1
Swindon 2 0 1 1 1 3 1
Southend 3 0 1 2 1 7 1
Oldham 2 0 0 2 2 5 0
Divisionn two
Plymouth 3 2 1 0 8 5 7
Brentford 3 2 1 0 6 3 7
Shrewsbury 3 2 1 0 6 3 7
Bury 3 2 1 0 4 2 7
Burnley 3 2 0 1 5 5 6
Bournemouth 3 2 0 1 4 3 6
Blackpool 3 2 0 1 3 2 6
Chesterfield 3 2 0 1 3 2 6
Millwall 3 1 1 1 5 4 4
Crewe 3 1 1 1 4 4 4
Gillingham 3 1 1 1 4 5 4
Preston 3 1 1 1 3 3 4
Notts County 2 1 1 0 2 1 4
Bristol Rovers 2 1 1 0 1 0 4
Bristol City 3 1 0 2 7 4 3
York 3 1 0 2 5 6 3
Watford 3 1 0 2 2 5 3
Wrexham 2 0 2 0 5 5 2
Wycombe 3 0 2 1 2 3 2
Rotherham 3 0 1 2 3 5 1
Peterborough 2 0 1 1 2 3 1
Walsall 3 0 1 2 2 4 1
Stockport 3 0 1 2 0 2 1
Luton 3 0 0 3 3 10 0
Division three
Hartlepool 3 2 1 0 6 3 7
Wigan 3 2 1 0 5 2 7
Hull 3 2 1 0 4 2 7
Carlisle 3 2 1 0 2 0 7
Fulham 3 2 0 1 4 3 6
Scunthorpe 3 2 0 1 2 2 6
Scarborough 3 1 2 0 4 2 5
Exeter 3 1 2 0 4 3 5
Cambridge 3 1 2 0 3 2 5
Darlington 3 1 1 1 7 5 4
Northampton 3 1 1 1 5 3 4
Barnet 3 1 1 1 4 2 4
Chester 3 1 1 1 4 3 4
Torquay 3 1 1 1 3 3 4
Cardiff 3 1 1 1 1 2 4
Swansea 3 1 0 2 3 7 3
Brighton 3 1 0 2 2 5 3
Hereford 3 1 0 2 1 2 3
Lincoln 3 0 2 1 3 4 2
Colchester 3 0 2 1 1 3 2
Rochdale 3 0 1 2 2 4 1
Mansfield 3 0 1 2 2 6 1
Doncaster 3 0 1 2 1 3 1
Leyton Orient 3 0 1 2 1 3 1
SOCCER - ENGLISH LEAGUE RESULTS .
LONDON 1996-08-27
Results of English league soccer
matches on Tuesday :
Division one
Crystal Palace 0 West Bromwich 0
Ipswich 1 Grimsby 1
Oxford 0 Norwich 1
Portsmouth 1 Southend 0
Tranmere 2 Port Vale 0
Postponed : Charlton v Birmingham , Sheffield United v
Huddersfield
Division two
Brentford 2 Gillingham 0
Bristol City 5 Luton 0
Burnley 1 Shrewsbury 3
Chesterfield 1 Walsall 0
Preston 2 Crewe 1
Rotherham 1 Blackpool 2
Stockport 0 Bournemouth 1
Watford 0 Plymouth 2
Wycombe 0 Bury 1
York 3 Millwall 2
Postponed : Peterborough v Notts County , Wrexham v Bristol
Rovers
Division three
Barnet 3 Brighton 0
Cardiff 0 Wigan 2
Carlisle 1 Leyton Orient 0
Chester 2 Swansea 0
Darlington 1 Colchester 1
Exeter 1 Doncaster 1
Hartlepool 2 Mansfield 2
Hereford 0 Hull 1
Lincoln 1 Cambridge 1
Northampton 1 Torquay 1
Rochdale 1 Fulham 2
Scunthorpe 0 Scarborough 2
CRICKET - ENGLAND AND PAKISTAN TEST AVERAGES .
LONDON 1996-08-27
England and Pakistan Test averages
after their three-match series which ended on Monday :
England
Batting ( tabulated under matches , innings , not outs , runs ,
highest score , average ) :
Alec Stewart 3 5 0 396 170 79.20
John Crawley 2 3 0 178 106 59.33
Nick Knight 3 5 0 190 113 38.00
Nasser Hussain 2 3 0 111 51 37.00
Mike Atherton 3 5 0 162 64 32.40
Graham Thorpe 3 5 0 159 77 31.80
Jack Russell 2 3 1 51 41no 25.50
Ian Salisbury 2 4 1 50 40 16.66
Mark Ealham 1 2 0 30 25 15.00
Dominic Cork 3 5 0 58 26 11.60
Robert Croft 1 2 1 11 6 11.00
Simon Brown 1 2 1 11 10no 11.00
Alan Mullally 3 5 1 39 24 9.75
Chris Lewis 2 3 0 18 9 6.00
Andy Caddick 1 1 0 4 4 4.00
Graeme Hick 1 2 0 8 4 4.00
Bowling ( tabulated under overs , maidens , runs , wickets ,
average ) :
Atherton 7 1 20 1 20.00
Caddick 57.2 10 165 6 27.50
Cork 131 23 434 12 36.16
Mullally 150.3 36 377 10 37.70
Hick 13 2 42 1 42.00
Croft 47.4 10 125 2 62.50
Brown 33 4 138 2 69.00
Ealham 37 8 81 1 81.00
Salisbury 61.2 8 221 2 110.50
Lewis 71 10 264 1 264.00
Thorpe 13 4 19 0 -
Pakistan
Batting :
Moin Khan 2 3 1 158 105 79.00
Ijaz Ahmed 3 6 1 344 141 68.80
Salim Malik 3 5 2 195 100no 65.00
Inzamam-ul-Haq 3 5 0 320 148 64.00
Saeed Anwar 3 6 0 362 176 60.33
Rashid Latif 1 1 0 45 45 45.00
Aamir Sohail 2 3 1 77 46 38.50
Asif Mujtaba 2 3 0 90 51 30.00
Wasim Akram 3 5 1 98 40 24.50
Shadab Kabir 2 4 0 87 35 21.75
Mushtaq Ahmed 3 5 1 44 20 11.00
Waqar Younis 3 3 1 11 7 5.50
Ata-ur-Rehman 2 2 2 10 10no -
Mohammad Akram 1 0 0 0 0 -
Bowling :
Mushtaq Ahmed 195 52 447 17 26.29
Waqar Younis 125 25 431 16 26.93
Wasim Akram 128 29 350 11 31.81
Ata-ur-Rehman 48.4 6 173 5 34.60
Mohammad Akram 22 4 71 1 71.00
Aamir Sohail 11 3 24 0 -
Asif Mujtaba 7 5 6 0 -
Salim Malik 1 0 1 0 -
Shadab Kabir 1 0 9 0 -
CRICKET - GOOCH TO PLAY ANOTHER SEASON FOR ESSEX .
LONDON 1996-08-27
Graham Gooch , the 43-year-old former England captain , is to continue playing county cricket for at least another season , his club Essex announced on Tuesday .
Opener Gooch 's decision comes towards the end of a season in which he has underlined his consistency by becoming the leading scorer in Essex 's history , beating Keith Fletcher 's aggregate of 29,434 .
Gooch , who retired from test cricket after the 1994-95 tour of Australia but is now an England selector , is seventh in this season 's first-class averages with 1,429 runs at 64.95 , having hit five centuries and one double century .
Essex secretary-general manager Peter Edwards said : " He is a remarkable batsman and still the best in this country .
No-one will argue with that .
You just have to look at his record to appreciate that fact . "
SOCCER - ROMANIA CLUB BOSS BANNED FOR HEADBUTT .
BUCHAREST 1996-08-27
The Romanian Soccer Federation has banned first division club Jiul Petrosani 's president Miron Cozma for two years for headbutting a visiting team player , a federation statement said .
Romania 's soccer bosses also fined Cozma , a well-known miners ' union leader , 10 million lei ( $ 3000 ) for the half-time attack on Dinamo Bucharest 's Danut Lupu last Sunday .
Miners led by Cozma rioted in Bucharest in 1990 and 1991 , bringing down the reformist government of premier Petre Roman .
Cozma is awaiting trial for assault and criminal damage in a bar in his home town of Petrosan , 300 kms west of Bucharest .
The attack on Lupu came during a tunnel skirmish between opposing players as they left the field .
" Cozma 's blow was not too painful because I 'm a tall man , " Lupu told Reuters on Tuesday .
Lupu is one of the tallest players in Romania 's first division , towering over Cozma by some 17 cms ,
Jiul Petrosani , promoted to the first division this year , won the league game 1-0 .
Cozma is barred from taking part in any official soccer activity during the ban .
SQUASH - HONG KONG OPEN FIRST ROUND RESULTS .
HONG KONG 1996-08-27
First round results in the Hong
Kong Open squash tournament on Tuesday ( prefix denotes seeding ) :
1 - Jansher Khan ( Pakistnn ) beat Jackie Lee ( Hong Kong ) 15-8 15-8
15-6
3 - Brett Martin ( Australia ) beat David Evans ( Wales ) 14-17 15-1
13-15 17-14 15-12
Mark Cairns ( England ) beat 6 - Del Harris ( England ) 15-12 7-15
15-6 15-12
Anthony Hill ( Australia ) beat 8 - Mark Chaloner ( England ) 15-11
17-16 17-16
Simon Frenz ( Germany ) beat Martin Heath ( Scotland ) 12-15 15-6
15-4 12-15 15-14
Joseph Kneipp ( Australia ) beat Ahmed Faizy ( Egypt ) 15-8 12-15
15-14 15-9
Mir Zaman Gul ( Pakistan ) beat Stephen Meads ( England ) 10-15
15-12 15-10 15-3
Dan Jensen ( Australia ) beat Anders Thoren ( Sweden ) 8-15 15-12
10-15 15-5 15-11
TENNIS - EDBERG EXTENDS GRAND SLAM RUN , TOPPLES WIMBLEDON CHAMP .
Larry Fine
NEW YORK 1996-08-27
Stefan Edberg produced some of his vintage best on Tuesday to extend his grand run at the Grand Slams by toppling Wimbledon champion Richard Krajicek in straight sets at the U.S. Open .
Edberg , competing in the 54th consecutive and final Grand Slam event of his illustrious career , turned back the clock at Stadium Court with a flowing 6-3 6-3 6-3 serve-and-volley victory over the fifth-seeded Dutchman .
" It 's a win that I can be proud of , " said the 30-year-old Swede , winner of two U.S. Opens and six Grand Slam titles in all . "
It 's never easy to beat the Wimbledon champion . "
Edberg , who has said he will retire at season 's end , made it look easy under gray skies at the National Tennis Centre .
The unseeded Swede struck quickly , breaking Krajicek in the first game and never let loose his grip on the one hour 44 minute match as he served and volleyed with the grace that made him one of the dominant players of his time .
" There 's not doubt about it , Richard was definitely off his game and I took advantage , " said Edberg .
" I still have my days where I feel great out there . "
Also reaching the second round were top-seeded defending champion Pete Sampras , a 6-2 6-2 6-1 winner over last minute replacement Jimy Szymanski of Venezuela , called on after Adrian Voinea of Romania withdrew because of a sprained ankle .
Third seed Thomas Muster of Austria also charged into the second round with a 6-1 7-6 ( 7-2 ) 6-2 romp over Javier Frana of Argentina .
Marcelo Rios of Chile , the 10th seed , also advanced .
Rios claimed a 4-6 6-1 6-4 6-2 victory over Romania 's Andrei Pavel .
On the women 's side , second seed Monica Seles got off to a strong start by beating fellow-American Anne Miller 6-0 6-1 and was joined in the second round by Spain 's Arantxa Sanchez Vicario ( seeded third ) , Olympic champion Lindsay Davenport ( 8 ) and Karina Habsudova of Slovakia ( 17 ) .
The women 's draw lost another seed when Austrian Judith Wiesner overcame Iva Majoli of Croatia 2-6 6-3 6-1 .
The fifth- seeded Majoli joined Anke Huber ( 5 ) and Magdalena Maleeva ( 12 ) on the sidelines .
TENNIS - TUESDAY 'S RESULTS FROM U.S. OPEN .
NEW YORK 1996-08-27
Results of first round matches on Tuesday in the U.S. Open tennis championships at the National Tennis Centre ( prefix denotes seeding ) :
Women 's singles
2 - Monica Seles ( U.S. ) beat Anne Miller ( U.S. ) 6-0 6-1
Rita Grande ( Italy ) beat Alexia Dechaume-Balleret ( France ) 6-3 6-0
Judith Wiesner ( Austria ) beat 5 - Iva Majoli ( Croatia ) 2-6 6-3 6- 1
Men 's singles
3 - Thomas Muster ( Austria ) beat Javier Frana ( Argentina ) 6-1 7-6 ( 7-2 ) 6-2
1 - Pete Sampras ( U.S. ) beat Jimy Szymanski ( Venezuela ) 6-2 6-2 6 - 1
Jiri Novak ( Czech Republic ) beat Ben Ellwood ( Australia ) 6-2 6- 4 6-3
Women 's singles
Mariaan de Swardt ( South Africa ) beat Dominique Van Roost ( Belgium ) 1-6 6-2 7-6 ( 7-4 )
Florencia Labat ( Argentina ) beat Kathy Rinaldi Stunkel ( U.S. ) 6 - 2 6-2
Nathalie Tauziat ( France ) beat Angelica Gavaldon ( Mexico ) 7-6 ( 7-4 ) 6-2
Paola Suarez ( Argentina ) beat Marianne Werdel Witmeyer ( U.S. ) 6 - 4 6-3
Ann Grossman ( U.S. ) beat Silvia Farina ( Italy ) 6-4 6-3
Men 's singles
Alex Corretja ( Spain ) beat Byron Black ( Zimbabwe ) 7-6 ( 8-6 ) 3-6 6-2 6-2
Scott Draper ( Australia ) beat Galo Blanco ( Spain ) 6-3 7-5 6-3
Petr Korda ( Czech Republic ) beat David Caldwell ( U.S. ) 6-3 3-6 6-3 7-5
Bohdan Ulihrach ( Czech Republic ) beat 14 - Alberto Costa ( Spain ) 2-6 6-4 7-6 ( 7-2 ) 3-6 6-1
Bernd Karbacher ( Germany ) beat Jonathan Stark ( U.S. ) 7-5 6-3 5- 7 7-5
Women 's singles
8 - Lindsay Davenport ( U.S. ) beat Adriana Serra-Zanetti ( Italy ) 6 - 2 6-1
Elena Wagner ( Germany ) beat Gigi Fernandez ( U.S. ) 6-1 6-4
Kristie Boogert ( Netherlands ) beat Joannette Kruger ( South Africa ) 6-1 6-0
Men 's singles
Stefan Edberg ( Sweden ) beat 5 - Richard Krajicek ( Netherlands ) 6- 3 6-3 6-3
10 - Marcelo Rios ( Chile ) beat Andrei Pavel ( Romania ) 4-6 6-1 6-4 6-2
Women 's singles
3 - Arantxa Sanchez Vicario ( Spain ) beat Laxmi Poruri ( U.S. ) 6-2 6-1
Men 's singles
Andrei Olhovskiy ( Russia ) beat Pat Cash ( Australia ) 6-4 6-3 6-2
Filippo Veglio ( Switzerland ) beat Christian Ruud ( Norway ) 1-6 6
- 2 6-4 6-4
Tim Henman ( Britain ) beat Roberto Jabali ( Brazil ) 6-2 6-3 6-4
Pablo Campana ( Ecuador ) beat Todd Woodbridge ( Australia ) 6-2 4-
6 6-2 6-4
Herman Gumy ( Argentina ) beat Martin Damm ( Czech Republic ) 7-5 6
- 4 7-5
Jacob Hlasek ( Switzerland ) beat Nicklas Kulti ( Sweden ) 6-3 6-4
4-6 6-4
Women 's singles
17- Karina Habsudova ( Slovakia ) beat Radka Bobkova ( Czech
Republic ) 6-4 6-1
Karin Kschwendt ( Austria ) beat Sandra
Kleinova ( Czech Republic ) 6-3 6-4
Annabel Ellwood ( Australia ) beat Jennifer Capriati ( U.S. ) 6-4 6
- 4
Nicole Arendt ( U.S. ) beat Sandra Cacic ( U.S. ) 6-2 7-6 ( 8-6 )
Elena Likhovtseva ( Russia ) beat Kyoko Nagatsuka ( Japan ) 7-6 ( 7-
5 ) 6-1
Sandrine Testud ( France ) beat Pam Shriver ( U.S. ) 7-5 6-2
Women 's singles
Kimberly Po ( U.S. ) beat 10 - Kimiko Date ( Japan ) 6-2 7-5
Natasha Zvereva ( Belarus ) beat Virginia Ruano-Pascual ( Spain ) 6
- 2 6-7 ( 5-7 ) 6-2 Tina Kirzan ( Slovakia ) beat Rika Hiraki ( Japan )
7-6 ( 7-4 ) 7-5
Petra Langrova ( Czech Republic ) beat Karina Adams ( U.S. ) 6-4 6-2
Tami Whitlinger Jones ( U.S. ) beat Sandra Cecchini ( Italy ) 6-2 6-0
7 - Jana Novotna ( Czech Republic ) beat Francesca Lubiani ( Italy )
6-1 7-5
Men 's singles
13 - Thomas Enqvist ( Sweden ) beat Stephane Simian ( France ) 6-3 6-1 6-4
Mikael Tillstrom ( Sweden ) beat Tamer El Sawy ( Egypt ) 1-6 7-6 ( 9
- 7 ) 6-1 3-6 6-4
Roberto Carretero ( Spain ) beat Jordi Burillo ( Spain ) 6-3 4-6 6-
0 1-0 Retired ( ankle injury )
Thomas Johansson ( Sweden ) beat Renzo Furlan ( Italy ) 4-6 2-6 7-5
6-1 7-5
Mark Knowles ( Bahamas ) beat Marcelo Filippini ( Uruguay ) 6-3 7-5
6-1
Jared Palmer ( U.S. ) beat 15 - Marc Rosset ( Switzerland ) 6-7 ( 7-9 )
6-4 6-4 6-3
Women 's singles
Amy Frazier ( U.S. ) beat Larisa Neiland ( Latvia ) 6-1 6-3
Lisa Raymond ( U.S. ) beat Lori McNeil ( U.S. ) 7-6 ( 8-6 ) 6-3
Sandra Dopfer ( Austria ) beat Zina Garrison Jackson ( U.S. ) 2-6 6-3 7-5
4 - Conchita Martinez ( Spain ) beat Ruxandra Dragomir ( Romania ) 6-2 6-0
Naoko Sawamatsu ( Japan ) beat Rennae Stubbs ( Australia ) 6-4 6-3
Miriam Oremans ( Netherlands ) beat Radka Zrubakova ( Slovakia ) 6-2 4-6 6-1
Men 's singles
Doug Flach ( U.S. ) beat Gianluca Pozzi ( Italy ) 7-5 7-6 ( 7-5 ) 2-6 7-6 ( 8-6 )
16 - Cedric Pioline ( France ) beat Francisco Clavet ( Spain ) 6-4 7-6 ( 7-3 ) 6-4
Javier Sanchez ( Spain ) beat David Skoch ( Czech Republic ) 6-2 7-6 ( 7-0 ) 6-3
Women 's singles , first round 1 - Steffi Graf ( Germany ) beat Yayuk Basuki ( Indonesia ) 6-3 7-6 ( 7-4 )
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE STANDINGS AFTER MONDAY 'S GAMES .
NEW YORK 1996-08-27
Major League Baseball
standings after games played on Monday ( tabulate under won ,
lost , winning percentage and games behind ) :
AMERICAN LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
NEW YORK 74 56 .569 -
BALTIMORE 69 61 .531 5
BOSTON 67 65 .508 8
TORONTO 62 70 .470 13
DETROIT 47 84 .359 27 1/2
CENTRAL DIVISION
CLEVELAND 78 53 .595 -
CHICAGO 70 63 .526 9
MINNESOTA 65 66 .496 13
MILWAUKEE 63 69 .477 15 1/2
KANSAS CITY 59 73 .447 19 1/2
WESTERN DIVISION
TEXAS 75 56 .573 -
SEATTLE 67 63 .515 7 1/2
OAKLAND 63 71 .470 13 1/2
CALIFORNIA 61 70 .466 14
TUESDAY , AUGUST 27TH SCHEDULE
CLEVELAND AT DETROIT
OAKLAND AT BALTIMORE
MINNESOTA AT TORONTO
MILWAUKEE AT CHICAGO
TEXAS AT KANSAS CITY
BOSTON AT CALIFORNIA
NEW YORK AT SEATTLE
NATIONAL LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
ATLANTA 81 48 .628 -
MONTREAL 70 59 .543 11
FLORIDA 61 70 .466 21
NEW YORK 59 72 .450 23
PHILADELPHIA 53 79 .402 29 1/2
CENTRAL DIVISION
HOUSTON 70 62 .530 -
ST LOUIS 69 62 .527 1/2
CHICAGO 64 64 .500 4
CINCINNATI 64 66 .492 5
PITTSBURGH 55 75 .423 14
WESTERN DIVISION
SAN DIEGO 72 60 .545 -
LOS ANGELES 70 60 .538 1
COLORADO 69 63 .523 3
SAN FRANCISCO 56 73 .434 14 1/2
TUESDAY , AUGUST 27TH SCHEDULE
PHILADELPHIA AT SAN FRANCISCO
LOS ANGELES AT MONTREAL
ATLANTA AT PITTSBURGH
SAN DIEGO AT NEW YORK
CHICAGO AT HOUSTON
FLORIDA AT ST LOUIS
CINCINNATI AT COLORADO
BASEBALL - GIANTS EDGE PHILLIES 1-0 .
SAN FRANCISCO 1996-08-27
William VanLandingham pitched eight scoreless innings and Glenallen Hill drove in the game 's only run with a first-inning single as the San Francisco Giants claimed a 1-0 victory over the Philadelphia Phillies on Monday .
VanLandingham ( 8-13 ) , who entered the game with one complete game in the first 56 starts of his career , limited the Phillies to two hits and two walks with four strikeouts .
" We 've been working all year on my follow-through , and I really concentrated on that , " VanLandingham said . "
It gave me more life in all of my pitches , so the ball moved more . "
At Colorado , Andres Galarraga homered and drove in three runs as the Colorado Rockies had 10 extra-base hits and Billy Swift won his first game in almost a year in a 9-5 rain-shortened seven-inning victory over the Cincinnati Reds .
Swift ( 1-0 ) , who made his first start since June 3rd and underwent arthroscopic surgery on his right shoulder earlier in the season , allowed five runs and six hits in five innings .
In Houston , Andy Benes allowed two runs over seven innings and Royce Clayton had a run-scoring single in the seventh to lift the St. Louis Cardinals to a 3-2 victory over the Houston Astros .
Benes ( 14-9 ) allowed five hits , walked five and struck out 10 for his 11th win in 12 decisions .
The Cardinals moved within one-half game of first-place Houston in the National League Central Division .
BASEBALL - ORIOLES WIN , YANKEES LOSE .
BALTIMORE 1996-08-27
Cal Ripken 's bases-loaded walk scored Brady Anderson with the winning run in the bottom of the 10th as the Baltimore Orioles regained control of the top spot in the wild-card race with a wild 12-11 victory over the Oakland Athletics .
Trailing by a run entering the 11th , the Orioles rallied against Oakland reliever Mark Acre ( 0-2 ) with a walk and a triple by Brady Anderson to tie the game .
Then Oakland manager Art Howe decided to intentionally walk Rafael Palmeiro and Bobby Bonilla to load the bases but Acre was nowhere near the plate to Ripken .
The decisive pitch nearly hit Ripken and gave the Orioles a one-half game lead over the Chicago White Sox in the wild-card race .
In Seattle , Jay Buhner 's eighth-inning single snapped a tie as the Seattle Mariners edged the New York Yankees 2-1 in the opener of a three-game series .
New York starter Jimmy Key left the game in the first inning after Seattle shortstop Alex Rodriguez lined a shot off his left elbow .
The Yankees have lost 12 of their last 19 games and their lead in the AL East over Baltimore fell to five games .
At California , Tim Wakefield pitched a six-hitter for his third complete game of the season and Mo Vaughn and Troy O'Leary hit solo home runs in the second inning as the surging Boston Red Sox won their third straight 4-1 over the California Angels .
Boston has won seven of eight and is 20-6 since August 2nd .
The Red Sox are two games over .500 for the first time this season .
In Chicago , Cal Eldred pitched 5-1/3 scoreless innings and John Jaha scored one run and doubled in another as the Milwaukee Brewers held off the slumping Chicago White Sox , 3-2 .
Eldred ( 6-5 ) walked one and struck out three .
Angel Miranda retired one batter and Bob Wickman retired the next four but loaded the bases in the eighth .
In Detroit , Jim Thome 's solo homer in the ninth inning snapped a tie and Charles Nagy pitched a three-hitter for his first win in over a month , leading the Cleveland Indians to their 11th straight victory over the Detroit Tigers , 2-1 .
With the score tied 1-1 in the ninth , Thome hit a 2-2 pitch from starter Felipe Lira ( 6-11 ) over the left-field fence for his 29th homer .
In Toronto , Juan Guzman allowed three runs over seven innings to make homers by Joe Carter and Carlos Delgado stand up as the surging Toronto Blue Jays held off the Minnesota Twins , 5-3 .
Toronto returned home from a 10-game road trip and won for the eighth time in nine games as Guzman ( 11-8 ) allowed nine hits and struck out eight without a walk .
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE RESULTS MONDAY .
NEW YORK
Results of Major League Baseball games
played on Monday ( home team in CAPS ) :
American League
Cleveland 2 DETROIT 1
BALTIMORE 12 Oakland 11 ( 10 innings )
TORONTO 5 Minnesota 3
Milwaukee 3 CHICAGO 2
Boston 4 CALIFORNIA 1
SEATTLE 2 New York 1
National League
SAN FRANCISCO 1 Philadelphia 0
St Louis 3 HOUSTON 2
COLORADO 9 Cincinnati 5
TENNIS - CHANG , WASHINGTON ADVANCE , TWO WOMEN 'S SEEDS FALL .
Larry Fine
NEW YORK 1996-08-26
Michael Chang is playing in his 10th U.S. Open and enjoying his highest seeding ever , but the 24-year-old American had to overcome a case of the jitters Monday before winning his first-round match on opening day .
Chang , seeded second behind defending champion Pete Sampras , took two hours 40 minutes to defeat 186th-ranked Jaime Oncins of Brazil 3-6 6-1 6-0 7-6 , 8-6 in the tiebreaker .
" I was pretty tight the whole match , " conceded Chang , one of the hottest players on tour this summer with a 16-2 record on hardcourts that included two titles and a runner-up finish .
" Everyone has moments when they get tight .
Hopefully , this will have been my nerves for the whole tournament . "
Joining Chang into the second round was Wimbledon runner-up MaliVai Washington , the 11th seed , who also needed four sets to get past talented Moroccan Karim Alami 6-4 2-6 7-6 ( 7-5 ) 6-1 .
Washington 's win was not comfortable , either .
The 27-year-old American hurried off the Stadium Court for treatment of an upset stomach after his two and a half hour struggle against Alami .
" Towards the end of my match my stomach felt like week-old sushi , " said Washington . "
Maybe it was a combination of the heat and something I ate . "
Chang and Washington were the only men 's seeds in action on a day that saw two seeded women 's players fall .
Australian Open runner-up Anke Huber of Germany , the sixth seed , was undone by an unlucky draw that put her against 17th ranked South African Amanda Coetzer in her opening match .
Coetzer claimed revenge for the semifinal defeat she suffered to Huber in Melbourne by taking a 6-1 2-6 6-2 victory .
Last year 's Wimbledon junior champion , Aleksandra Olsza of Poland , removed another seed from the draw by eliminating number 12 Magdalena Maleeva of Bulgaria 6-4 6-2 .
Other men 's winners included a pair of former Grand Slam tournament champions whose victories set up a showdown in the second round .
Germany 's Michael Stich , the 1991 Wimbledon champion , and two-time French Open winner Sergi Bruguera of Spain will face each other next after beating German Tommy Haas 6-3 1-6 6-1 7-5 , and Belgian Kris Goossens 6-2 6-0 7-6 ( 7-1 ) , respectively .
Alex O'Brien , who scored his first professional title eight days ago in New Haven , advanced to the second round with a 6-4 1-6 6-4 6-3 win over Ecuador 's Nicolas Lapentti .
Wimbledon bad boy Jeff Tarango caught a break Monday when he advanced after the retirement of German Alex Radulescu due to heat exhaustion .
Tarango was leading 6-7 ( 5-7 ) 6-4 6-1 3-1 .
Chang blamed breezy conditions for some of the erratic play in his match with Oncins , who had beaten him in the round of 32 at the 1992 Barcelona Olympics .
Chang committed an untidy 53 unforced errors , though he made seven fewer than the Brazilian , who also walloped a woeful 24 double faults .
The most deflating double fault came when Oncins was serving to force a fifth set , leading 6-4 in the tiebreaker .
The set point came after confusion at the net on the point previous , which was awarded to Oncins after the two exchanged shots at close quarters at the net .
First Chang approached the umpire , then Oncins , then Chang again before play finally resumed .
" Those little seconds were like an hour to me , " said Oncins , who promptly fired two serves barely contained by the baseline as he frittered away his best chance .
Chang ran off the next three points to close out the match but for Oncins , the contest was a personal victory .
The 26-year-old Brazilian had risen into the top 30 in 1992 .
The next year a close friend was struck by a stray bullet while riding home in a car from a soccer game in Sao Paulo .
He died slumped against Oncins , who subsequently lost interest in tennis .
" Two months ago I started talking about quitting , " said Oncins , who decided to give it one last try and made it through the Open qualifying tournament last weekend .
" I believe in my game again , " he said .
At the end of the day , a spate of withdrawals from the tournament were announced .
Eighth seed Jim Courier withdrew because of a bruised right knee , and 1988 Open champion Mats Wilander bowed out due to a groin pull , organisers said .
Women 's ninth seed Mary Joe Fernandez pulled out because of tendinitis in her right wrist .
SOCCER - FRENCH FIRST DIVISION SUMMARY .
PARIS 1996-08-27
Summary of a French first division soccer match on Tuesday :
Auxerre 0 Marseille 0 .
Attendance : 20,000
SOCCER - MARSEILLE HOLD AUXERRE TO GOALLESS DRAW .
PARIS 1996-08-27
Former European champions Marseille held French champions Auxerre to a goalless draw in a lacklustre league match on Tuesday .
The bill looked promising but both sides , struggling to find their form early in the season , were disappointing .
Auxerre , who start their European Cup campaign next week against Ajax Amsterdam , dominated the match but were unable to score .
Unbeaten in four matches , they still trail leaders Lens by one point .
Lens , who have won all their three league matches so far , host Montpellier on Wednesday night .
Despite another dismal performance , especially in defence , Marseille restored some pride by keeping the reigning champions at bay after losing 2-1 at home to Metz last Saturday .
After two seasons in the second division and after taking on half a dozen new recruits this season , some of whom do not speak a word of French , Marseille are not playing with any fluidity .
But German international goalkeeper Andreas Koepke again proved a sound investment when under pressure from the Auxerre strikers , saving his team with a number of fine parries .
Marseille now lie seventh in the league on five points .
SOCCER - FRENCH FIRST DIVISION RESULT .
PARIS 1996-08-27
Result of a French first division
soccer match played on Tuesday :
Auxerre 0 Marseille 0
SOCCER - GERMAN FIRST DIVISION SUMMARIES .
BONN 1996-08-27
Summaries of Bundesliga matches
played on Tuesday :
Borussia Dortmund 3 ( Riedle 8th minute , Heinrich 29th ,
Tretschok 77th ) Freiburg 1 ( Decheiver 51st penalty ) .
Halftime
2-0 .
Attendance 48,800 .
Hamburg 0 VfB Stuttgart 4 ( Balakov 29th , Bobic 47th and 60th ,
Hagner 85th ) .
0-1 .
31,139 .
Werder Bremen 1 ( Schulz 31st ) Borussia Moenchengladbach 0 .
1-0 .
24,800 .
Schalke 1 ( Thon 2nd ) Bochum 1 ( Donkow 86th ) .
1-0 .
33,230 .
SOCCER - GERMAN FIRST DIVISION RESULTS .
BONN 1996-08-27
Results of Bundesliga matches
played on Tuesday :
Borussia Dortmund 3 Freiburg 1
Hamburg 0 VfB Stuttgart 4
Werder Bremen 1 Borussia Moenchengladbach 0
Schalke 1 Bochum 1
Bundesliga standings after Tuesday 's games ( tabulate under
played , won , drawn , lost , goals for , goals against , points ) :
VfB Stuttgart 3 3 0 0 10 1 9
Borussia Dortmund 4 3 0 1 12 6 9
Cologne 3 3 0 0 7 1 9
Bayern Munich 3 2 1 0 7 2 7
Bayer Leverkusen 3 2 0 1 7 4 6
VfL Bochum 4 1 3 0 4 3 6
Hamburg 4 2 0 2 7 7 6
Karlsruhe 2 1 1 0 5 3 4
St Pauli 3 1 1 1 7 7 4
Werder Bremen 4 1 1 2 5 6 4
1860 Munich 3 1 0 2 3 5 3
Schalke 4 0 3 1 5 9 3
Fortuna Duesseldorf 3 1 0 2 1 7 3
Freiburg 4 1 0 3 6 13 3
Hansa Rostock 3 0 2 1 3 4 2
Arminia Bielefeld 3 0 2 1 2 3 2
Borussia Moenchengladbach 4 0 2 2 1 4 2
MSV Duisburg 3 0 0 3 1 8 0
SOCCER - DUTCH FIRST DIVISION SUMMARY .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-27
Dutch first division summary on
Tuesday :
Fortuna Sittard 2 ( Jeffrey 7 , Roest 33 ) Heerenveen 4 ( Korneev
15 , Hansma 24 , Wouden 70 , 90 ) .
Halftime 2-2 .
SOCCER - DUTCH FIRST DIVISION RESULT .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-27
Result of a Dutch first
division soccer match played on Tuesday :
Fortuna Sittard 2 Heerenveen 4
ICE HOCKEY - FINLAND BEAT CZECH REPUBLIC IN WORLD CUP MATCH .
HELSINKI 1996-08-27
Finland beat the Czech Republic
7-3 ( period scores 4-1 1-1 2-1 ) in their ice hockey World Cup ,
European group match on Tuesday .
Scorers :
Finland - Ville Peltonen ( 10th minute ) , Juha Ylonen ( 10th ) ,
Teemu Selanne ( 11th ) , Jyrki Lumme ( 13th and 51st ) , Janne Ojanen
( 23rd ) , Christian Ruuttu ( 45th )
Czech Republic - Radek Bonk ( 7th ) , Robert Reichel ( 33rd ,
penalty ) , Jiri Dopita ( 57th )
Standings ( tabulate under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , against , points ) :
Sweden 1 1 0 0 6 1 2
Finland 1 1 0 0 7 3 2
Czech Republic 1 0 0 1 3 7 0
Germany 1 0 0 1 1 6 0
SOCCER - NEUCHATEL TO APPEAL AGAINST CYPRIEN 'S NINE-MONTH BAN .
GENEVA 1996-08-27
Swiss league leaders Neuchatel Xamax said on Tuesday they would appeal against a nine-month ban imposed on French international defender Jean-Pierre Cyprien for his part in a post-match brawl .
Cyprien , also fined 10,000 Swiss francs ( $ 8,400 ) , traded punches with St Gallen 's Brazilian player Claudio Moura after a match on Saturday .
When officials and coaching staff tried to intervene , Cyprien launched a flying kick at Moura , but only succeeded in kneeing St Gallen coach Roger Hegi in the stomach .
Moura , who appeared to have elbowed Cyprien in the final minutes of the 3-0 win by Neuchatel , was suspended for seven matches and fined 1,000 francs ( $ 840 ) by the Swiss league disciplinary committee .
Club president Gilbert Facchinetti said he was astonished the committee had arrived at its decision so quickly and vowed the club would appeal .
Neuchatel coach Gilbert Gress described the incident as " shocking " , but said Moura was also to blame .
" Moura physically and verbally provoked Cyprien during the match .
The referee could not have seen it or he would have punished him , " Gress said .
" During the scuffle , Moura threw the first punch .
Tomorrow , if someone punches me , I would not know how to react . "
Cyprien , who won his one French cap against Italy in February 1994 , cannot play in Switzerland or elsewhere until May next year .
CYCLING - BUGNO CLEARED OF DOPING .
MILAN 1996-08-27
Veteran Italian Gianni Bugno has been cleared of doping after testing positive for high levels of testosterone during the Tour of Switzerland in June , the Italian cycling federation said on Tuesday .
" He has been cleared .
The case is closed , " a spokesman said .
Bugno tested positive for the banned hormone after the fifth stage of the Tour , in which he finished third overall .
But the spokesman said subsequent tests in Cologne proved his body produced higher-than-average testosterone levels naturally .
Bugno , who won the Giro d'Italia in 1990 and two successive world titles , was banned for three months in 1994 after testing positive for the stimulant caffeine .
CYCLING - COLONNA WINS FIRST STAGE OF TOUR OF NETHERLANDS .
HAARLEM , Netherlands 1996-08-27
Leading results and overall standings after the 161 kilometre first stage of the Tour of the Netherlands between Gouda and Haarlem on Tuesday .
1. Federico Colonna ( Italy ) Mapei three hours 43 mins five secs
2. Robbie McEwen ( Australia ) Rabobank
3. Jans Koerts ( Netherlands ) Palmans
4. Sven Teutenberg ( Germany ) US Postal
5. Tom Steels ( Belgium ) Mapei
6. Endrio Leoni ( Italy ) Aki
7. Johan Capiot ( Belgium ) Collstrop
8. John den Braber ( Neths ) Collstrop
9. Jeroen Blijlevens ( Neths ) TVM
10. Michael van der Wolf ( Neths ) Foreldorado all same time .
Leading overall standings after first stage .
1. Colonna three hours 42 mins 55 seconds
2. McEwen 0:04 seconds behind
3. Koerts 0:06
4. Gianluca Corini ( Italy ) Aki 0:07
5. Wim Omloop ( Belgium ) Collstrop same time
6. Lance Armstrong ( USA ) Motorola 0:08
7. Tristan Hoffman ( Neths ) TVM same time
8. George Hincapie ( USA ) Motorola 0:09
9. John Talen ( Neths ) Foreldorado same time
10. Teutenberg 0:10
COFINEC SLIPS ON BUDAPEST BOURSE BUT FUTURE STRONG .
Emese Bartha
BUDAPEST 1996-08-27
Expectations that Cofinec S.A. , the Hungarian bourse 's first foreign listing , will report a disappointing first half have depressed the stock below its issue price , but analysts expect a rebound in the long term .
" The first half of the year is unlikely to be as strong as expected so the company will probably be unable to reach its annual plan in 1996 , " said Gabor Sitanyi , a London-based analyst for ING Barings .
The French-registered packaging materials company , which floated its shares in Hungary in July , for most of the past two weeks hovered below the 6,425 forints / Global Depositary Receipts price of its initial offering , which was oversubscribed .
The company , which asked for a two-week delay from the usual August 15 deadline for reporting first-half results , closed on Tuesday at 5,800 forints , down 300 .
" Cofinec 's first-half figures will be ...
between one-third of two-fifths of its annual plan , " said Tamas Erdei , a Budapest-based analyst for ABN-AMRO Hoare Govett .
Analysts blame , at least partly , Hungary 's macroeconomic environment for the weaker figures for Cofinec which , operating in Hungary , Poland and the Czech Republic , now generates about 55 to 60 percent of its annual sales from Hungary .
Hungary 's Gross Domestic Product fell one percentage point in the first quarter while real wages plunged 7.2 percentage points in the first half of 1996 .
Both will have their impact on Cofinec 's figures , the analysts said .
Despite the current difficulties , however , analysts were convinced that Cofinec 's outlook was strong .
" The eastern European market offers good chances , " said Erdei . "
Just like many other companies on the bourse , Cofinec has big growth opportunities . "
" At the same time , it 's an advantage for Cofinec that it has a foreign management which perhaps understands the market better , " Erdei added .
" Cofinec is a very good story in the long-term as the per capita packaging consumption is still so low in east Europe that a very strong increase can be expected ( long-term ) , " Sitanyi said , saying that several recent moves by Cofinec boosted its position .
Among them , he noted that Cofinec had acquired the outstanding stake in its Czech folding company Krpaco a.s. , increasing its ownership to 100 percent , so in the second half the whole of Krpaco 's figures will be consolidated .
The company also repaid some $ 21 million of debt , well above the originally planned $ 8 million to $ 9 million .
In addition , its Polish operation began with some six weeks of delay due to cold winter weather and the test run was also longer than planned .
-- Budapest newsroom ( 36 1 ) 266 2410
DIRECT EQUITY TRADES ON THE CZECH PSE - AUG 27 .
PRAGUE 1996-08-27
The following is a list of
direct equity trades made on the Prague Stock Exchange :
ISSUE Min .
Price Max .
Price Volume Turnover
( CZK ) ( CZK ) ( shares ) ( CZK 000 's )
AGROTONZ TLUMACOV 336.47 336.47 59440 19999.777
AVIA 290.00 290.00 700 203.000
BARUM HOLDING 171.00 171.00 14432 2467.872
CESKA SPORITELNA 335.00 375.00 533153 198354.941
CKD PRAHA HOLDING 369.66 384.00 5565 2065.260
EMKAM 25.00 25.00 34684 867.100
KABLO KLADNO 960.00 960.00 2230 2140.800
KOMERCNI BANKA 2320.00 2370.00 7000 16408.700
LECIVA PRAHA 2470.00 2470.00 1360 3359.200
METROSTAV 3024.95 3024.95 3000 9074.850
MORAV.CHEMIC. ZAV .
637.50 637.50 1626 1036.575
OKD 111.50 112.56 95975 10752.092
PF IKS KB PLUS 156.00 156.00 6000 936.000
RIF 900.00 900.00 5500 4950.000
SELIKO 4000.00 20000.00 3565 32607.500
SOKOLOVSKA UHELNA 785.00 785.00 6000 4710.000
SPIF CESKY 339.00 340.00 7546 2562.094
SPT TELECOM 3355.00 3404.71 10700 36337.137
SKODA PLZEN 1045.56 1060.00 10772 11361.330
TABAK 6700.00 6700.00 1000 6700.000
TRINECKE ZELEZARNY 210.00 210.00 3000 630.000
VODNI STAVBY PRAHA 1915.00 1915.00 2000 3830.000
-- Prague Newsroom , 42-2-2423-0003
AFTER THE BELL - After hours slows in light volume .
NEW YORK 1996-08-27
Traders said on Tuesday after-hours activity was light .
Both WorldCom Inc and MFS Communications Co Inc were trading but they moved in line with their close .
WorldCom , which said it will buy MFS , shed 1-3/4 to close at 21 while MFS lost 3-8/16 to close at 41-5/16 .
The New York Stock Exchange said its session one volume was 5,700 shares compared to 53,400 shares Monday .
Session two volume was 4,153,800 shares compared to no volume Monday .
The American Stock Exchange said there was no after-hours activity .
CBOE in routine review of MFS options .
CHICAGO 1996-08-27
The Chicago Board Options Exchange ( CBOE ) said on Tuesday it was doing a routine investigation into trading in options on MFS Communications Co Inc shares .
On Monday , the company said it had agreed to be acquired by WorldCom Inc in a deal valued at $ 14 billion .
MFS shares surged on the news while WorldCom fell on fears of dilution .
The New York Times said on Tuesday some of the options trading in MFS last Friday may suggest insider trading .
MFS options also trade on the American Stock Exchange and the Pacific Stock Exchange .
A spokesman for the American Stock Exchange would neither confirm or deny whether the exchange was looking into trading .
" If there is unusual activity , certainly we look at it , but that 's not to say we 're doing anything official , " he said .
Pacific Stock Exchange officials were not available .
One trader said trading in MFS options had increased steadily from about mid-August , and doubted whether any of last Friday 's activity was insider trading .
- Derivatives desk , 312 408-8750 / E-mail : derivatives@reuters.com
Faulding target of patent lawsuit .
ELIZABETH , N.J. 1996-08-27
Faulding Inc said on Tuesday Purdue Frederick Co filed a patent infringement lawsuit against Faulding and its Purepac Pharamceutical unit .
The suit was filed because of Purepac 's manufacture of Kadian , a sustained release morphine product , Faulding said .
Faulding said the claims in the lawsuit are without merit and will not impact upon the launch of Kadian in the United States .
Kadian was approved for sale in the United States last month , Faulding said .
Zeneca Group Plc , which will market Kadian , was named in the lawsuit with F.H. Faulding & Co , the majority shareholder of Faulding Inc , the company said .
McGrath left out of Ireland World Cup squad .
DUBLIN 1996-08-27
Ireland 's most experienced player , defender Paul McGrath , was left out of the national squad for the first time in 11 years on Tuesday when new manager Mick McCarthy named his side to face Liechtenstein in a World Cup qualifier .
The 36-year-old Aston Villa player won the last of his Irish record of 82 international caps against the Czech Republic in Prague in April .
" Paul accepted the situation .
He has n't played any first-team games for Villa this season and he 's not the type of player I would have brought on as a substitute , " McCarthy said . "
But he surprised me in training over the last two days because of his involvement .
He 's certainly is still very much part of my plans for the future .
" At 24 , 25 or 26 you could get away with it , not having played first-team games .
But at 36 it would be asking too much of Paul , " he said .
Also omitted from the 20-man squad which will travel to Vaduz for Saturday 's group eight match are central defenders Alan Kernaghan and Liam Daish .
Leeds United defender Gary Kelly is unable to travel because of a knee injury picked up in Monday 's 1-0 victory over Wimbledon at Elland Road .
Since taking over from Jack Charlton in February , McCarthy has played largely experimental sides and seen them lose five times , draw twice and win just once .
Squad : Alan Kelly , Shay Given , Denis Irwin , Phil Babb , Jeff Kenna , Curtis Fleming , Gary Breen , Ian Harte , Kenny Cunningham , Steve Staunton , Andy Townsend , Ray Houghton , Gareth Farrelly , Alan McLoughlin , Jason McAteer , Alan Moore , Keith O'Neill , Tony Cascarino , Niall Quinn , David Kelly .
-- Dublin Newsroom +6613377
S. African apartheid killer convicted of six murders .
PRETORIA 1996-08-27
South African apartheid killer Eugene de Kock was found guilty of murder and attempted murder on Tuesday , a day after he was convicted of five other murders .
De Kock , 48 , a former police colonel who commanded a hit-squad that wiped out opponents of apartheid , is the most senior servant of white rule yet to face justice .
Sudanese rebels say missionaries should be freed .
Peter Smerdon
NAIROBI 1996-08-27
The main rebel group in south Sudan said on Tuesday it was trying to arrange the release of six Roman Catholic missionaries , including three Australian nuns , held for nearly two weeks .
George Garang , Nairobi spokesman for the Sudan People 's Liberation Army ( SPLA ) , said it was urgently trying to contact SPLA commander Nuour Marial at Mapourdit in the south to free the six .
" The movement is making arrangements for them to be set free .
This is a decision of the leadership , " Garang said .
" Commander Nuour Marial is a soldier so he must accept the leadership 's decision .
But communications at this time of year are very difficult because of rains and a lack of power , " he added .
The Catholic Information Office in Nairobi said on Monday that four of the six had been charged by the SPLA with spying , spreading Islam and hindering recruitment into the rebel group .
" These charges are the interpretation of the church , " Garang said on Tuesday . "
We have no idea why they are being held .
We are still trying to establish contact with the local commander . "
Asked whether this meant the commander was out of control , Garang said the rebel movement was working on the problem .
He said he believed all six were being held in the mission compound at Mapourdit and were reported to be in good health .
The Catholic Information office in Nairobi said on Monday that Australian Sisters Moira Lynch , 73 , and Mary Batchelor , 68 , American Father Michael Barton , 48 , and Sudanese Father Raphael Riel , 48 , were held in a prison in south Sudan by the SPLA .
It said Australian Sister Maureen Carey , 52 , and Italian Brother Raniero Iacomella , 28 , were held inside the compound .
The church in Australia said on Monday Lynch , Batchelor , Barton and Riel were held in a prison until the weekend , when they were moved to join the other captives at the compound .
The Catholic Information Office said the SPLA in the Kenyan capital had attributed the detentions of the six to a local commander and had promised they would be freed by August 23 .
But the church learned in a recent meeting with the local commander that no instructions to release the prisoners were received and they would be held until investigations were completed .
It said last Friday they were visited by Monsignor Caesar Mazzolari , apostolic administrator of the diocese of Rumbek in southern Sudan , and an SPLA administrator and appeared in good condition .
" On August 17 the mission was surrounded ( by the SPLA ) and sealed off .
The evening of the same day the missionaries were put in prison or isolation .
Later the mission was looted , " it added .
An Australian foreign ministry official said the charges against them were " fairly bizarre " and a matter for concern .
He said Australian diplomats in Nairobi were working with the Roman Catholic church in southern Sudan and with U.S. and Italian diplomats in the region to help free the missionaries .
The SPLA has fought Khartoum 's government forces in the south since 1983 for greater autonomy or independence of the mainly Christian and animist region from the Moslem , Arabised north .
OSCE postpones Bosnian municipal elections .
SARAJEVO 1996-08-27
The U.S. diplomat in charge of elections in Bosnia announced on Tuesday that voting for municipal assemblies would be postponed because of irregularities by the Serbs in registering voters .
Ambassador Robert Frowick , representing the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe ( OSCE ) , told reporters that municipal polls due on September 14 with other Bosnian elections would be put off .
" I have made a chairman 's decision that it is not feasible to hold municipal elections on September 14 , " said Frowick .
He said no exact date had been set but it was possible the local elections would take place in the spring of 1997 .
According to OSCE officials , Serb authorities have pressed their refugees to register to vote in towns now under Serb control , but which used to have Moslem majorities .
Human rights workers say authorities in Serbia and Bosnian Serb territory have conducted a well-organised campaign to coerce refugees into registering only on Serb territory and failed to inform them of their rights under the Dayton peace agreement .
Diplomats say the effect of the electoral engineering would be to establish political control over districts they conquered and ethnically cleansed in war .
The response of the Bosnian Serbs to the OSCE 's announcement was not immediately clear .
But Bosnian Serb leaders have hinted they would boycott the poll if the municipal elections were postponed , or go ahead with their own .
The Bosnian Serb cabinet , in a letter to the OSCE , said on Monday that any delay of local elections would be " a direct and flagrant violation fo the Dayton agreement " .
The Serbs , who administer half of Bosnia in a Serb republic , said they had met all conditions for holding the September elections .
Diplomats fear that the crisis could cast doubt over the entire election process , which already appears set to confirm Bosnia 's ethnic partition rather than its reintegration as the Dayton peace agreement had planned .
New talks in Chechnya as Lebed waits for Yeltsin .
Dmitry Kuznets
NOVYE ATAGI , Russia 1996-08-27
Russian and rebel military commanders finally met in Chechnya on Tuesday for delayed talks aimed at finalising a ceasefire arranged last week by President Boris Yeltsin 's envoy Alexander Lebed .
The Russian army commander in the region , General Vyacheslav Tikhomirov , arrived at the rebel-held village of Novye Atagi , some 20 km ( 12 miles ) south of the Chechen capital Grozny for discussions with rebel chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov .
But Lebed himself , the Kremlin security chief , is still waiting back in Moscow to meet Yeltsin over his plans for a lasting political settlement in Chechnya .
Itar-Tass news agency quoted the Kremlin press service as saying Yeltsin , who left for a state holiday home near Moscow on Monday , would hold no working meetings on Tuesday .
Lebed interrupted talks with Chechnya 's separatists on a political deal on Sunday , saying he had to consult with Yeltsin .
After a meeting failed to materialise on Monday , Lebed 's spokesman said he might meet the president on Tuesday .
But Yeltsin 's spokesman rebuffed the suggestion , saying the president had left Moscow for a holiday near the capital .
The Russians postponed the talks after a Chechen band disarmed a column of interior ministry troops on Sunday .
The Chechens said a renegade group seized the weapons and said on Monday they had all been returned .
The Russian command insisted that not all the weapons were the same as those taken .
Tass said the weapons and the practical implementation of the ceasefire signed by Lebed and Maskhadov last Thursday would be on the agenda of today 's talks .
Neither spoke to reporters before the meeting , which started around 10.45 a.m. ( 0645 GMT ) .
Also in Novye Atagi on Tuesday morning , was Tim Guldimann , the Swiss diplomat who heads the Chechnya mission of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe ( OSCE ) .
Guldimann , who helped broker an earlier truce in May , was not taking part in the Tikhomirov-Maskhadov talks .
Lebed 's peace mission this month has stopped some of the worst fighting of the 20-month-old conflict .
However , tension on the ground indicates that it could falter if the momentum for a settlement is not maintained .
Three Russian servicemen were wounded in a total of six shooting incidents overnight , Itar-Tass news agency quoted the Russian military as saying on Tuesday morning .
RIA news agency quoted an army source accusing rebel fighters of failing to turn up for joint Russian-Chechen police patrols in some districts of the capital Grozny on Tuesday .
But the separatist command told Interfax news agency the patrols , part of the truce brokered by Lebed last week , would begin on Tuesday after delays for " technical reasons " .
Yeltsin 's spokesman said he might meet officials during his break , but indicated Lebed was low on the list by saying Yeltsin would need time to study the proposals before talking to him .
Russian news agencies also quoted the Kremlin spokesman as saying that Lebed 's representatives had not sought a meeting , hinting at an attempt by the president to put his popular and outspoken protege in his place with a lesson on protocol .
Yeltsin , 65 , has kept a low profile since he was reelected in July , prompting new speculation that the two heart attacks he suffered last year and a rumoured drinking problem could be taking their toll , weakening his grip on affairs of state .
Aides have dismissed such speculation , insisting that he simply needs a rest after his energetic election campaign .
Some analysts say the Kremlin leader , whose order sending troops and tanks into Chechnya in 1994 started Russia 's ill-fated military campaign , could merely be reluctant to put his name to a peace process which might fall apart .
But Lebed , who has no real power without his boss and has hinted at dark forces in Moscow working against him , appears to think a deal will not stick without strong backing from Yeltsin .
His proposals have not been spelled out but are expected to involve a compromise between the separatists ' demand for independence and Moscow 's insistence that Chechnya remain part of the Russian Federation .
Slovenia and Poland target EU , NATO membership .
LJUBLJANA 1996-08-27
Slovenia and Poland pledged to intensify cooperation on Tuesday and reinforced their determination to join the European Union and NATO at the earliest possible date .
Polish President Aleksander Kwasniewski and his Slovenian counterpart , Milan Kucan , met for talks at the start of a two-day visit to Slovenia by Kwasniewski .
It was their fourth meeting this year .
They said in a statement they agreed to have regular telephone contact to discuss progress in strengthening ties with the West .
" We expect our cooperation will help both countries towards entering the European Union and NATO , " Kwasniewski said .
" We have similar ambitions as far as our internal development and international life is concerned , " Kucan said .
Poland and Slovenia are hoping to be among the first group of former eastern bloc countries to join the European Union and NATO .
They have already signed an association agreement with the European Union and are both part of the Central European Free Trade Area , which also comprises Hungary , Slovakia and the Czech Republic .
Slovenia 's trade with Poland rose to $ 142.3 million in 1995 from $ 118.8 million in 1994 .
During his visit to Slovenia , Kwasniewski is also scheduled to meet Prime Minister Janez Drnovsek , representatives of Slovenian political parties and representatives of the Chamber of Economy .
Nationalists want Iliescu ousted for Hungary pact .
BUCHAREST 1996-08-27
Junior Nationalist members of Romania 's ruling coalition called on Tuesday for the impeachment of President Ion Iliescu for backing a friendship treaty with neighbouring Hungary .
Iliescu 's Party of Social Democracy , the senior coalition partner , immediately dismissed the National Unity Party ( PUNR ) demand as crude electioneering .
" It is a desperate move by the PUNR , which is losing its only reason for existing ahead of the electoral campaign , " said PDSR executive president Adrian Nastase .
" This treaty is both necessary and good , " Nastase said , adding that the PUNR 's stance was threatening its position in the government .
The treaty agreed unexpectedly two weeks ago will end years of disputes over the status of Romania 's large ethnic Hungarian minority .
It will also boost both countries ' chances of admission to NATO and the European Union .
" If they ( the PUNR ) are so vexed , they could leave the government ...
We might also help them to do it , if they go on like this , " he said .
The PUNR holds four key ministries -- justice , transport , agriculture and communications .
PUNR leader Gheorghe Funar said in a statement Iliescu , in power since the fall of communism in 1989 , should be impeached for treason for compromising on the issue of ethnic Hungarian minority rights in the treaty due to be signed next month .
Funar 's call came on the eve of the official launch of Iliescu 's campaign for a new term at November 3 polls .
His appeal to the opposition to back his attempt to oust Iliescu was unlikely to succeed , analysts said .
Iliescu has invited political leaders to a meeting on Thursday to discuss the final form of the pact which both Romanian and Hungarian nationalists oppose for different reasons .
Presidential officials were not available to comment on the call for Iliescu 's impeachment .
Estonian MPS see little hope of electing president .
Belinda Goldsmith
TALLINN 1996-08-27
Estonia 's parliament failed for a second time to elect a president on Tuesday , dealing a blow to incumbent Lennart Meri and pushing the country towards stalemate in its choice of a new head of state .
Neither Meri , who oversaw Estonia 's first steps into statehood after the collapse of the Soviet Union , nor his arch-rival , former communist Arnold Ruutel , have secured the 68 votes necessary from the 101-member parliament .
Meri garnered 49 votes and Meri 34 in Tuesday 's ballot for the five-year presidency of Estonia .
A third and final vote was due to be held when parliament reconvened on Tuesday but legislators were not expecting a clear result .
If there is no result the decision will be ceded to an electoral college .
" The votes are a strong message to Meri that he is not favoured by some politicians any more , " Reform Party head Heiki Kranich told Reuters .
Under a constitution agreed in 1992 , a year after independence , the president has no executive powers .
His only political role is to smoothe the functioning of government in periods of crisis .
But Meri , 67 , has been accused in parliament of taking too much power and not always consulting parliamentarians before making decisions .
His relations with a leftist-led government have sometimes been tense .
His support in the first round of voting on Monday was much lower than expected , scoring only 45 votes , which political analysts put down as a vote of no confidence in his performance .
This support only inched up to 49 in the second vote .
Support for Ruutel , 68 , remained constant at 34 votes .
If the third vote fails to give either Meri or Ruutel 68 votes , the parliamentary speaker will convene an electoral college of 101 MPs and 273 local goverment representatives to hold a new poll that could include new nominations .
This would be the first time that the former Soviet republic has had to call together an electoral college .
In its first presidential election in 1992 Meri won the necessary votes in in a parliamentary election against Ruutel .
Parliamentary organisers said the exact timetable remained unclear but it would probably take about a month to organise an electoral college which could also hold several rounds of voting before a clear winner emerges .
Estonia assembly fails to elect state president .
TALLINN 1996-08-27
The Estonian parliament failed for a third and final time to elect a new state president on Tuesday , refusing a second mandate for incumbent Lennart Meri .
Neither Meri nor his rival Arnold Ruutel could garner the 68 votes needed from the 101 members of parliament to become president .
In the third vote Meri won 52 and Ruutel won 32 votes .
The final decision will now be made by a larger assembly .
Meri won 49 in a second vote earlier on Tuesday and 45 in the first on Monday .
Ruutel won 34 votes in the first two secret ballots .
Enn Markvart , chairman of the National Election Commission said 96 members of parliament cast votes , with one ballot paper invalid and 11 abstentions .
The election will now go before an electoral college involving MPs and local government representatives that will be convened by the parliamentary Speaker in the next day or so .
It could take up to a month before a new vote but the timetable is not yet clear .
This is the first time the former Soviet republic has had to convene such a group .
Albania charges Briton with child sex abuse .
TIRANA 1996-08-27
Albanian authorities have arrested and charged a British man for sexually abusing two young boys , a Tirana prosecutor said on Tuesday .
" We have arrested him and charged him with these shameful acts of sex abuse of little children , " prosecutor Adnan Xhelili told Reuters .
Xhelili said Paul Thompson , 34 , from Wiltshire , was arrested on Sunday in a hotel in the Adriatic resort of Durres , 45 km ( 30 miles ) west of Tirana .
Thompson has denied the charges .
He could face up to five years in jail if convicted .
Xhelili said Thompson , who is divorced , said he befriended the boys , both aged under 10 , because they reminded him of his own children who live with his former wife in London .
The prosecutor 's office said no date had yet been set for a trial to begin as investigations had first to be completed .
The British embassy in Tirana said it had sent an embassy official to talk to Thompson who is being held in jail .
The age of consent for heterosexual and homosexual sex in Albania is 14 .
A large number of destitute children can be seen begging in the streets of impoverished Albania , especially in towns and resorts visited by foreigners .
Estonia assembly again fails to elect president .
TALLINN 1996-08-27
Estonia 's parliament again failed to elect a new state president on Tuesday when neither of two candidates secured a majority in second-round voting .
Incumbent president Lennart Meri won 49 votes compared to 34 won by his rival , deputy Parliamentary Speaker Arnold Ruutel .
But Meri 's support was not enough for the 68 needed for election and a third secret ballot will take place later in the day ( 1300 GMT ) , parliamentary officials said .
To win a clear mandate for the five-year presidential term , a candidate must secure 68 votes from the 101-member parliament .
Enn Markvart , Chairman of the National Election Commission , said 96 members of parliament voted in the second round , with 12 abstentions and one ballot paper invalid .
On Monday , in the first round of voting , Meri secured 45 votes and Ruutel 34 .
Meri 's popularity has suffered in recent years , with politicians criticising him for taking too much power and acting without consulting parliament .
If a third round of voting fails to give either candidate 68 votes , the parliamentary speaker has to convene an electoral college of all 101 MPs and 273 local government representatives for a new vote that could take up to a month .
Slovak women visited Dutroux , police say .
Peter Laca
BRATISLAVA 1996-08-27
Marc Dutroux , the chief accused in Belgium 's sensational child murder and sex abuse case , visited Slovakia a number of times and about 10 young Slovak women went to Belgium at his invitation , police said on Tuesday .
But they have difficulty remembering what happened there , perhaps because of drugs , and are unsure whether they were filmed for pornography , Rudolf Gajdos , head of the Slovak office of Interpol , told Reuters .
Although Gajdos spoke of " girls " his deputy , Eva Boudova , said the case involved about 10 young women in their early 20s .
" The police interrogated several Slovak girls who said that they had been invited by Mark Dutroux to visit Belgium , " Gajdos said .
" The girls said they went to Belgium voluntarily and the police suspect that they were used to act in pornographic films . "
" The police suspect ( the girls ) were under the influence of drugs as some girls admitted they took unspecified pills . "
" We have suspicions of a rape , but the police still have to find the victim , " Gajdos added .
Dutroux 's last visit to Slovakia was reported to have been as recent as July .
Slovak police are also cooperating with Belgium in the search for An Marchal and Eefje Lambrecks , who went missing last August .
Dutroux , 39 , who was charged last week with the abduction and illegal imprisonment of two other girls aged 14 and 12 , is one of several suspects in the Marchal and Lambrecks case .
Last Saturday he led police to the bodies of two other girls , aged eight , who died of starvation this year after their abduction in June , 1995 .
The Czech office of Interpol said on Friday it would neither confirm nor deny that Dutroux had been in the Czech Republic , Slovakia 's western neighbour and former federation partner .
Belgian police said an officer had visited Bratislava to talk with Slovak detectives about An and Eefje and other disappearances , and he planned to go also to Prague .
WEATHER - Conditions at CIS airports - August 27 .
MOSCOW 1996-08-27
No closures of airports due to bad weather are expected in the Commonwealth of Independent States on August 28 and August 29 , the Russian Weather Service said on Tuesday .
-- Moscow Newsroom +7095 941 8520
Russian serial killer strikes again .
MOSCOW 1996-08-27
Russian police in the Urals city of Perm are on the trail of a serial killer who has claimed his seventh victim in just a few months , Itar-Tass news agency said on Tuesday .
In the latest attack , the killer raped and stabbed a young woman in a lift , leaving her body on a landing .
Tass did not say exactly when it took place .
Police earlier released a suspect after women who had survived an attack failed to identify him .
Russian army , Chechens open new round of talks .
MOSCOW 1996-08-27
Russia 's military commander in Chechnya began new talks with separatist chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov on Tuesday , Itar-Tass news agency said .
Tass said the talks were taking place in the settlement of Novye Atagi , some 20 km ( 12 miles ) south of the Chechen capital Grozny .
The talks had been postponed while the Russians waited for the rebels to return arms and ammunition seized from Russian soldiers at the weekend .
The Chechens said on Monday they had returned all the weapons , which they said were seized by a renegade group .
The talks between Maskhadov and Russia 's Vyacheslav Tikhomirov are aimed at putting the finishing touches to a ceasefire sealed last week in talks with Russian security chief Alexander Lebed .
Lebed , who met Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin on Monday to discuss the progress he made on a political settlement for the breakaway region , has been seeking a meeting with President Boris Yeltsin , who started a holiday near Moscow on Monday .
Argentine bishop reminds cabinet of Commandments .
BUENOS AIRES , Argentina 1996-08-27
The Archbishop of Buenos Aires said on Tuesday the first thing he would do if elected president of Argentina would be to put up posters of the Ten Commandments in government offices .
" They asked me what would be the first thing I would do if I were president , and I said the first thing I would do would be to resign straight away , " Archbishop Antonio Quarracino said at a sermon attended by several cabinet ministers .
" But before going , I would have big signs put up in all government offices , those to do with justice , in all sectors , with the Ten Commandments , " he added .
Argentina 's top Roman Catholic cleric said the Biblical commandment " Thou shalt not steal " would get special emphasis " because it has to be about the most common thing these days . "
Quarracino and other Church leaders are regular critics of the government 's free-market economic policy .
Brazil 's Eletropaulo names new president .
SAO PAULO 1996-08-27
Sao Paulo state power firm Eletropaulo said it has named Eduardo Bernini as new president , replacing Emmanuel Sobral , who will head a secretariat at the Transportation Ministry .
Bernini is expected to take office Thursday , a Eletropaulo spokeswoman said .
-- Romina Nicaretta , Sao Paulo newsroom , 5511 232 4411 .
Dutch government wo n't pay ransom for kidnap victims .
SAN JOSE , Costa Rica 1996-08-27
The Netherlands government has ruled out paying ransom money for a Dutch couple kidnapped from their farm , while Costa Rican authorities said on Tuesday they had no leads in the case .
" We have not had contact with the kidnappers nor do we have any leads to take us to where they might be held , " Chief of Judicial Police Manuel Alvarado told Reuters .
Hurte Sierd Zylstra and his wife , Jetsi Hendrika Coers , both 50 , were abducted from the teak plantation they managed late Saturday or early Sunday by at least two men demanding $ 1.5 million ransom , authorities said .
Costa Rican officials on Monday had given different names for the couple .
Anton Schutte , an official with the embassy for Belgium , the Netherlands and Luxembourg , said the Dutch government had ruled out paying any money in ransom . "
We 're looking at a criminal act that has no political aspect as far as what we can tell , " Schutte added .
A note with the ransom demand was left in the couple 's car , which was used in the kidnapping , Schutte told a news conference on Monday .
He said the note , believed to have been hand-written in Spanish and signed by the victims , was addressed to Ebe Huizinga , another Dutch citizen who owns the tree plantation . "
Depending on you , we will either live or die , " it said .
Alvarado said the car was abandoned about 40 miles ( 60 km ) north of the couple 's house but said that did not indicate the kidnappers intended to take their victims into neighbouring Nicaragua .
The farm is in the border region where a German tourist and a Swiss tour guide were kidnapped last New Year 's Eve by a heavily armed band led by a former Nicaraguan guerrilla .
The two were held for 71 days until relatives paid a ransom .
Two of the suspected abductors have since been arrested .
Venezuela unions harden towards CVG privatization .
CARACAS 1996-08-27
A swell of protest is growing within Venezuela 's trade unions at the proposed year-end privatization of the state-owned holding company Corporacion Venezolana de Guayana ( CVG ) , CVG union leaders said Tuesday .
" We oppose the way the government is proceeding with the sale , " Ramon Machuca , Sidor trade union Secretary General and member of union-based opposition party Radical Cause , told reporters .
" We do n't believe the government will make its timetable , " he added .
Sidor is the CVG 's steel-producing arm , slated for a December sale worth an estimated $ 1.5 billion .
The CVG 's aluminum companies Venalum and Alucasa are also scheduled to be sold early 1997 .
Arguing that CVG 's privatization would result in some 13,000 layoffs , compared to the government 's estimated 1,500 , CVG 's union leaders told reporters they would strike and stage protests if their concerns were not addressed .
" We oppose any privatization that hurts workers ' welfare and does not take into account its social impact , " they said .
The opposition party Radical Cause controls all of the unionized workers at the CVG heavy industry complex and has systematically opposed all government legislation in congress .
-- Omar Lugo , Caracas newsroom , 582 834405
Nicaraguan drunks fear " lovebite " bandit .
MANAGUA , Nicaragua 1996-08-27
Heavy drinkers in a Nicaraguan city were searching for someone who has covered them in " lovebites " while they were passed out in a drunken stupor , a local newspaper reported on Tuesday .
The dreaded " chupabolos " -- " drunksucker " -- preys on men who have passed out in the streets of Matagalpa , 80 miles ( 130 kms ) north of Managua , placing hickey-like " lovebites " on various parts of their bodies , El Nuevo Diario reported .
Enraged drunks and street people in this town known for its machismo have organised a so-far unsuccessful search for the culprit who finds victims in the dark streets surrounding a local market .
The total number of victims was still unknown .
The first of the victims were two vagrants who slept in an abandoned car in front of a local bank , the newspaper said .
In spite of the collective fear gripping Matagalpa 's drinkers , local women expressed little sympathy .
" Its just desserts for all the ' bolos ' ( drunkards ) who sleep in the streets of our beautiful town , " said a woman who worked in the local market .
Brazil likely to turn Banespa federal bank - paper .
SAO PAULO 1996-08-27
Brazil is likely to turn Sao Paulo state bank Banespa into a federal bank in a prior step to privatization , according to unnamed government sources , O Globo daily said .
The newspaper said the Central Bank special administration of Banespa ends in December 30 and after that the bank has to be liquidated or turned into a federal bank since there are no conditions to return Banespa to Sao Paulo state government .
A Central Bank spokesman said he could not confirm or deny the report .
Banespa has been under central bank special temporary administration since December 1994 .
The central bank management could be lifted if Sao Paulo state decided to take part in the recent federal government 's plan to restructure state banks .
Under the plan , the federal government would provide 100 percent of the financing needed to restructure debt of state banks being privatized , liquidated or turned into development banks .
It also offers to refinance up to 50 percent of the debt held by state banks whose governments decide to keep control of their banks .
Although the plan was designed under terms proposed by Sao Paulo state governor Mario Covas , he has showed no interest in taking part in the plan because Sao Paulo 's debt with Banespa has increased sharply , O Globo said .
Sao Paulo state 's debt is now estimated at 19 billion reais .
O Globo also said another delicate case to be solved involves private bank Bamerindus .
The newspaper said Bamerindus has sent to the Central Bank a proposal for restructuring combined with a request for a 90-day credit line , paying four percent a year plus the Basic Interest Rate of the Central Bank ( TBC ) .
O Globo also said the loan would give Bamerindus time to sell assets .
Bamerindus , Brazil 's fourth-largest private bank , has been facing liquidity troubles .
Bamerindus declined to comment on negotiations being held with the Central Bank .
-- Fatima Cristina , Sao Paulo newsroom , 55-11-2324411
Czech Republic 's Havel to tour Brazil in September .
BRASILIA 1996-08-27
Czech Republic President Vaclav Havel is scheduled to make an official visit to Brazil Sept .
15-21 , Brazil 's Foreign Relations Ministry said on Tuesday .
Havel is due to meet with his Brazilian counterpart Fernando Henrique Cardoso in the capital Brasilia and will visit the cities of Manaus , Sao Paulo and Rio de Janeiro .
Also due to visit Brazil in September are South Korean President Kim Young Sam and German Chancellor Helmut Kohl .
Former Argentine benevolent dictator Alejandro Lanusse dies .
BUENOS AIRES 1996-08-26
Alejandro Lanusse , the former dictator who ruled Argentina for two years , died at age 78 on Monday .
Lanusse died after being brought to a hospital a week ago following a fall at home that resulted in a blood clot in the brain .
He was operated on earlier in the week but failed to recover from surgery .
The former dictator , who ruled from 1971 to 1973 , was best known for allowing Juan Domingo Peron , Argentina 's famed populist leader , to return to Argentina after 17 years of forced exile .
Lanusse took over the leadership of the country after five years of dictatorship .
But unlike his two predecessors , Juan Carlos Ongania and Marcelo Levingston , who ruled Argentina with an iron hand , Lanusse steered the country toward democracy .
That resulted in general elections in March 1973 when the Peronists led by Hector Campora and Vicente Solano Lima returned to power .
Lanusse was a candidate in the election but failed to defeat his old adversories and never returned to public office .
He was imprisoned for four years in 1951 for taking part in a coup attempt to overthrow Peron led by General Benjamin Menendez .
Lanusse 's rule saw the gradual rise of left-wing activism which culminated in another period of brutal Argentine dictatorship from 1976 to 1983 , during which the military launched its " dirty war " that resulted in 10,000 missing people .
In his autobiography published in 1990 , Lanusse described himself as a military man with " democratic ideas . "
He was born in Buenos Aires in 1918 and married Ileana Bell with whom he had nine children .
He entered the Military College in 1935 .
Ten missing in north China ship collision .
BEIJING 1996-08-27
Ten people were missing after a fishing boat collided with a passenger liner and sank off China 's northeastern province of Liaoning , state radio said on Tuesday .
The fishing boat sank and its entire crew was missing after a collision with the " Tiantan " liner off the port of Dalian early on Monday , the report said .
It said the liner was heading to Dalian from the northern port of Tianjin , it said .
Dalian port officials , contacted by telephone , confirmed the collision but gave no further details .
Matahari revises down 1996 net target .
JAKARTA 1996-08-27
Indonesian department store operator PT Matahari Putra Prima said on Tuesday that it had revised down its 1996 net profit target .
Matahari 's finance director , Hanifah Komala , said they revised down net profit for 1996 to 46 billion from its original target of 50 billion rupiah .
" We have to revised down our target due to weak sales performance in the third quarter , " said Komala .
He also said the company expect to record a 83 billion rupiah of net profit in 1997 .
-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364
S. Korea asked to stop China-bound missionaries .
BEIJING 1996-08-27
Beijing has called on Seoul to stop South Korean missionaries from travelling to China , a South Korean embassy spokesman said on Tuesday .
The appeal was made on Sunday during talks between South Korean deputy Foreign Minister Lee Ki-choo and his Chinese counterpart Tang Jiaxuan , the spokesman said .
It is not known why China raised the issue .
Atheist China officially bans missionary activities but often turns a blind eye to religious activities of people nominally employed as foreign language teachers , particularly in remote areas that are unable to attract other candidates .
Hong Kong nabs blind 10-year-old illegal immigrant .
HONG KONG 1996-08-27
A blind 10-year-old boy from China sneaked over the border into Hong Kong and was arrested as an illegal immigrant , Hong Kong police said on Tuesday .
He was caught by police trying to force his way into a home in the rural New Territories , a police spokesman said .
" The boy came from China 's eastern province of Jiangsu .
He was spotted by a passerby trying to climb into an apartment in the early hours of Monday morning , " the spokesman said .
No decision has yet been made on how to deal with the boy .
Hong Kong police regularly catch hundreds of illegal immigrants and people who have overstayed their visas from mainland China and send them back .
Hong Kong , a British colony , reverts to Chinese control next year but will remain sealed off from the mainland except to a tiny trickle of legal immigrants and people with special visit permits .
Bosnian premier in Turkey for one day visit .
ANKARA 1996-08-27
Bosnian Prime Minister Hasan Muratovic arrived in Ankara on Tuesday for an official visit where he is due to discuss Turkey 's aid to the former Yugoslav republic .
The premier , who is due to meet his Turkish counterpart Necmettin Erbakan on Tuesday , will also be discussing the postponed Bosnian elections , a foreign ministry official said .
A small number of Bosnians had also begun to vote in Turkey .
Muratovic is also due to meet with President Suleyman Demirel , Foreign Minister Tansu Ciller and Turkish businessman , the ministry official said .
He will leave on Thursday .
A U.S. diplomat in charge of elections in Bosnia announced earlier that municipal polls due on September 14 with other Bosnian elections would be put off because of irregularities by the Serbs in registering voters .
He said no new date had been set yet .
" Turkish people are watching closely the developments in Bosnia .
We have seen elections as a step in the normalisation process , " the foreign ministry official said .
New U.N. relief coordinator arrives in Iraq .
Leon Barkho
BAGHDAD 1996-08-27
A new U.N. relief coordinator has arrived in Baghdad to take up the task of organising humanitarian goods distribution and to face Iraq 's continuing opposition over the number of international monitors to be involved .
U.N. and diplomatic sources said on Tuesday that Secretary- General Boutros Boutros-Ghali had appointed Italian Gualtiero Fulcheri and sent him to Iraq last week to replace Moroccan Mohamed Zejjari .
One diplomat said Iraq and U.N. were still in disagreement on how many international observers would be required to ascertain the equitable distribution of humanitarian supplies that will be procured under Baghdad 's oil deal with U.N .
" The United Nations would like to employ hundreds of foreign monitors .
Baghdad says it can only accept a few dozens , " said the diplomat .
Baghdad holds that the Iraq-U.N. memorandum of understanding on partial oil sales signed last June does not specify how many foreign observers should be stationed in Iraq .
" Observation of food supplies and their distribution are still a major issue and seems the two sides have not yet filled the gap separating them , " said another diplomat .
Iraq 's partial oil sales pact with U.N. , allowing crude exports worth $ 2 billion every six months , gives U.N. the right to supervise the purchase and distribution of food supplies in the country .
The deal is a humanitarian exception to the U.N. sanctions imposed on Iraq for invading Kuwait in 1990 which include a ban on its oil exports .
Fulcheri declined comment on the differences between the U.N. and Iraq , saying only : " There are several different things which still need to be done . "
Fulcheri started his U.N. career in 1960 and has long experience in U.N. emergency relief in Congo , Angola , Sudan and Somalia .
Kansas feedlot cattle market quiet , no sales - USDA .
DODGE CITY 1996-08-27
Trade was quiet , with no sales slaughter steers or heifers confirmed .
Inquiry and demand very light .
Sales confirmed week to date on 4,200 head , mostly previously contracted or formulated cattle .
Confirmed - none .
-- Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8720--
Anti-abortion speaker praises Democrat tolerance .
Alan Elsner
CHICAGO 1996-08-27
An anti-abortion politician addressed the Democratic convention on Tuesday , but praised the overwhelmingly pro-abortion rights party for its tolerance of his minority views .
Rep .
Tony Hall of Ohio said he and other Democrats who opposed abortion had always felt left out in their own party .
" But this year is different .
For the first time , the Democratic Party has included in our platform a conscience clause , " he said .
The clause recognizes and welcomes Democrats with divergent views on abortion and states they have a full part to play at all levels of the party .
" The Democratic Party is indeed the party of true inclusiveness , " Hall said .
At its convention four years ago , organizers prevented then Pennsylvania Gov .
Robert Casey , a vehement opponent of abortion , from speaking .
Republicans have used their decision as an example of Democrat intolerance ever since .
Casey told a news conference in Chicago on Tuesday he had asked to speak again this year but was turned down .
Democratic leaders said there was not room on the program for every retired governor to speak .
" I believe the Democratic party ought to be pro-woman , pro-child and pro-life , " Casey said .
" I asked for the opportunity to deliver this message from the podium of the Democrat National Convention .
For the second time in four years , my request fell on deaf ears , " he said .
The Republican Party , whose platform calls for making all abortions illegal , faced a similar dilemma this year when Massachusetts Gov .
William Weld asked to deliver a speech defending abortion rights and was turned down .
Bob Dole , the Republican presidential nominee , tried and failed to insert a tolerance clause in his party 's platform recognizing the validity of those within the party who supported abortion rights .
Democrats also heard Tuesday two passionate speeches defending abortion rights .
Kate Michelman , president of the National Abortion Rights Action League , described how she had an abortion at a time when the procedure was illegal after her husband abandoned her with three young children .
" I 'm here to speak up for choice and to speak for truth .
The message from the Republican Party is one of disdain .
Their answer to choice is control and punishment .
Our answer is trust , compassion and respect , " she said .
Georgia Rep .
Cynthia McKinney said : " You make your moral decisions .
I 'll make mine and let 's leave ( Republican House Speaker ) Newt Gingrich out of it . "
U.S. Spring / White Wheat - Bids mostly steady .
CHICAGO 1996-08-27
Dark northern spring and white wheat bids were mostly steady on Tuesday but a few locations quoted weaker values as newly harvested spring wheat flooded the market , several cash grain dealers said .
" There 's too much nearby wheat coming into the market so we 're backing off the basis to slow it down , " a Montana dealer said .
Bids there dropped 10 cents per bushel .
Harvest was also progressing well in parts of North Dakota , but one dealer there said new crop movement remained limited to a steady trickle . "
We 're seeing some new crop coming in now but it 's slow going , " the dealer said .
Elsewhere , basis values were mostly steady in quiet conditions with little noteworty domestic or export business , dealers said .
Durum bids were steady after jumping 50 cents per bushel in some areas on Monday .
Price per bushel for 14-pct protein dark northern spring , durum and white wheats , in dollars per bushel :
Spring Chg Durum ( m ) Chg White Chg
MINNESOTA
Minneapolis 5.06 up .02 5.75 unc -- --
Duluth 5.06 up .02 --- --- -- --
NORTH DAKOTA
Hunter
( Red River ) 4.46 dn .02 5.00 unc -- --
Spring Chg HRW 12pct Chg White Chg
Billings MT 4.62 up .01 4.50 dn .01 --- ---
Havre MT 4.54 dn .10 --- --- --- ---
Rudyard MT 4.54 dn .10 --- --- --- ---
Wolf Point MT 4.41 dn .10 --- --- --- ---
Portland OR 5.60 up .02 5.1700 dn .01
Pendleton OR --- --- --- --- 4.7300 up .01
Coolee City WA 5.13 up .02 --- --- 4.7000 unc
Waterville WA 5.05 up .02 --- --- 4.6200 unc
Wenatchee WA 5.15 up .02 --- --- 4.7200 unc
note : nc=acomparison , na=not available
( Chicago bureau 312-408-8720 )
Birmingham Public Park , Ala .
, Aa3 / VMIG-1 - Moody 's .
NEW YORK 1996-08-27
Moody 's Investors Service -
Rating Announcement As of 08/23/96 .
Issuer : Birmingham Public Park & Rec .
Bd .
Revenue
ref .
( YMCA Proj .
) ser . '
State : AL
Rating : Aa3 / VMIG 1
Sale Amount : 3,390,000
Expected Sale Date : 08/28/96
-- U.S. Municipal Desk , 212-859-1650
U.S. lauds Russian-Chechen deal .
WASHINGTON 1996-08-27
The United States on Tuesday welcomed a deal aimed at resuming a troop withdrawal from the embattled Chechen capital , Grozny .
" That is a welcome development .
We urge both sides to continue their dialogue aimed at reaching a political settlement " of the 20-month conflict between Russian troops and Chechen rebels , State Department spokesman Glyn Davies said .
The commander of Russian troops in Chechnya , Vyacheslav Tikhomirov , and Chechen rebel chief-of-staff Aslan Mashadov signed the deal under which the troop withdrawal is to resume on Wednesday .
Akron , Ohio , $ 6 mln bonds rated single-A - Moody 's .
NEW YORK , Aug 27 - Moody 's Investors Service - Rating
Announcement As of 08/26/96 .
Issuer : Akron
State : OH
Rating : A
Sale Amount : 6,310,000
Expected Sale Date : 08/28/96
Stallone , fiancee have baby girl .
MIAMI 1996-08-27
Actor Sylvester Stallone and his fiancee , model Jennifer Flavin , had a baby girl on Tuesday , Stallone 's publicist said .
The 7-pound , 4-ounce ( 3.3 kg ) girl , named Sophia Rose , was born shortly after midnight at South Miami Hospital , publicist Paul Bloch said .
" Both mother and baby are doing fine and are in wonderful health , " he said , adding that it was the couple 's first child .
He said Stallone , best known for the " Rocky " and " Rambo " movies , left the set of " Copland , " which is filming in New York and New Jersey , to be with Flavin for the birth .
Poll shows Clinton lead over Dole jumps to 15 pts .
CHICAGO 1996-08-27
An ABC News poll released on Tuesday showed President Bill Clinton 's lead over Republican challenger Bob Dole stretching to 15 points in advance of the Nov. 5 election .
The poll , taken on Sunday and Monday as the president engaged in a whistle-stop train trip to the Democratic Convention in Chicago , put Clinton at 51 percent , Dole at 36 percent and Ross Perot of the Reform Party at 8 percent .
A similar poll conducted on Saturday and Sunday had showed a nine point lead for Clinton , ahead by 47-38 percent .
Dole , down by around 20 points in early August in ABC polls , had closed to within four percentage points immediately after the Republican convention in San Diego earlier in August .
Other polls also showed a strong Dole bounce after San Diego but Clinton then rebuilding his lead .
Tuesday 's poll involved 1,002 registered voters and had a margin of error of 3.5 percentage points .
ABC said a parallel poll of 824 likely voters showed the president ahead by 11 points , with Clinton at 50 percent , Dole at 39 percent and Perot at 6 percent .
The poll of registered voters showed a shift in favor of the Democrats in the elections for House of Representatives , with 51 percent saying that if the vote were today they would go for a Democrat and 41 percent opting for a Republican .
That compared with the previous poll 's 48-43 lead for the Democrats .
The poll gave Clinton a 53 percent to 39 percent lead over Dole if Perot were not in the race .
The poll indicated a fall in the number of people who believed Dole would be able to fulfil his promise to cut the federal budget deficit and cut income taxes by 15 percent at the same time .
It showed 23 percent believed it possible compared to 70 who believed it was n't .
That compared to 26-57 in the previous poll .
U.S. bulk millfeeds - Immediate supply tight .
CHICAGO 1996-08-27
Millfeed supplies for prompt shipment remained tight and prices continued to move higher , millfeed dealers said .
High-priced corn and increased demand for livestock feed continued to support millfeed prices in nearly all sectors .
Flour mills sold much of their production through September leaving little available for prompt shipment .
Portland sources said feed mixer demand was keeping pace with millfeed production and driving prices higher .
Portland sources said with corn priced there at $ 200 per ton and barley at $ 140 , the millfeeds at $ 125 represent a good value .
In the southeast U.S. , dealers said feed mixers continued to be steady buyers with demand increasing for October to March positions .
The closely-watched Kansas City rail market was steady at $ 115 per ton bid and $ 118 offered .
-- Chicago newsdesk 312-408-8720--
Puerto Rico girl has surgery for hairy face .
PHILADELPHIA 1996-08-27
A two-year old Puerto Rican girl began surgical treatment on Tuesday for a rare condition that has left half of her face covered with a hairy , dark-brown patch of skin .
The girl , Abyss DeJesus , suffers from a " hairy nevus " on the right side of her face , a condition that has only been reported a few times in medical journals , the St. Christopher Children 's Hospital said .
In addition to social ostracism , the condition also carries a high risk of cancer .
It will be corrected by gradually expanding healthy skin with a surgical balloon , then transplanting that skin to the afflicted side of her face .
" She is doing well , " hospital spokeswoman Carol Norris said . "
The surgery is under way . "
Norris said Tuesday 's surgery involved placing five balloons in DeJesus 's forehead , shoulders and the back of her neck and partially filling them with a saline solution .
More saline solution will be inserted in 16 weekly treatments .
The girl , who was accompanied to Philadelphia by her parents , will need more surgery later to correct the condition on her chest , back and legs , the hospital said .
Eau Claire , Wisc .
revs won by Robert W. Baird .
NEW YORK 1996-08-27
Robert W. Baird & Co .
, Inc. , said it won $ 1 million of Eau Claire , Wisc .
, waterworks system mortgage revenue bonds , Series 1996 , with a true interest cost of 5.2893 percent .
Massachusetts home sales dip in July - report .
BOSTON 1996-08-27
Home sales across Massachusetts were down 2.3 percent in July , compared to a month earlier , but up 21 percent for the year , according to the Massachusetts Association of Realtors .
The association said a total of 4,464 single-family homes were sold in July , compared to 4,570 in June .
The average selling price , $ 206,464 , was up 10.6 percent over July 1995 .
Condominium sales edged up 6.0 percent for July and 24.8 percent for the year , the group said , while prices for condos nudged up less than 1.0 percent to an average of $ 123,394 .
In July , the average rate on a 30-year fixed rate mortgage was 8.25 percent , below June 's 8.32 percent but still higher than February 's 7.03 percent , the report noted .
-- Boston bureau , 617-367-4106
Amtrak train derails , three injured - officials .
MONTPELIER , Vt .
1996-08-27
At least three people were injured when an Amtrak passenger train slammed into an empty logging truck and derailed Tuesday , officials said .
The Vermonter , which runs between St. Albans , Vermont , near the Canadian border and Washington , D.C. , collided with the truck at 7:51 a.m. EDT near the rural town of Roxbury some 15 miles southeast of the state capital Montpelier , Amtrak spokeswoman Maureen Garrity said .
Vermont Central Hospital spokesman Dan Pudvah said two of the injured were treated there -- the truck driver , who was suffering from multiple trauma injuries , and a passenger .
Pudvah said he understood other people with minor injuries were being treated at the scene .
Garrity said a train conductor was also injured .
The train 's engine and its six cars derailed but were still standing , state police said .
The exact number of passangers on the train was not known . "
We had 70 reservations for the train , but that does n't mean there were 70 passengers aboard , " Garrity said .
Uninjured passengers were to be taken by bus to Springfield , Massachusetts , where they will be put aboard another train to continue their journey to New York City and Washington , Garrity said .
She said the train was travelling at 54 mph when it crashed into the truck , which was crossing the tracks onto a dirt road in the rural area bordering the Northfield Mountains .
Paralympics an example for gloomy France-Juppe .
PARIS 1996-08-27
Prime Minister Alain Juppe on Tuesday hailed handicapped athletes who took part in Atlanta 's Paralympic Games as an example for gloom-stricken France .
" What we hear every morning is gloom , resignation and scepticism ...
You are the opposite , " Juppe told a successful French team at Paris airport as he welcomed them back from the games which followed the July-August Olympics .
" If you had been struck ...
by the disease of scepticism , gloom and resignation , you would not be here .
You are a true example for the nation , " he said .
The French team won 95 medals in Atlanta , 35 of them gold .
Opinion polls consistently show French voters pessimistic and fed up as the economy stagnates and unemployement lingers at near-record levels .
French shares end fractionally weaker .
PARIS 1996-08-27
French shares ended fractionally weaker as unease about union unrest slated for the autumn and a weaker franc got the better of a slight rise on Wall Street .
The blue-chip CAC-40 index ended 2.43 points or 0.12 percent lower at 2,017.99 points after a brief foray into positive territory when the New York stock market opened higher .
The broader SBF-120 index closed 1.19 points or 0.08 percent lower at 1,421.90 points .
Market turnover was 3.8 billion francs , about average for the quiet August period , including 2.6 billion on the most actively traded CAC-40 shares .
The Socialist CFDT union warned of " tension and conflict " when France returns to work after the summer break and called for a drive to create up to 500,000 jobs in nine months .
A teachers ' union , the Federation Syndicale Unitaire ( FSU ) , called for members to protest against job cuts expected in the government 's austerity budget due to be unveiled in September .
Anxieties over the budget niggled the currency markets where the franc lost around half a centime from Monday 's late European levels to 3.4211 per mark .
Index heavyweights Elf and Rhone Poulenc both ended slightly weaker while active Eurotunnel was unchanged on nearly a million shares traded .
" People are morose and it 's not the post-holiday period or the budget or company results that are going to lift anyone 's spirits , " a broker said .
* UIC , part of insurer GAN , slid 12.19 percent to 55.1 francs after reporting a net attributable first-half loss of 758 million francs after the close on Monday .
Markets were disappointed by a recapitalisation of 800 million francs which commentators said was larger than expected .
* Supermarkets group Carrefour gained 2.19 percent to 2,616 francs after brokers Cheuvreux de Virieu confirmed the stock on their buy list , a fund manager said .
* Reinsurance group Scor gained 2.1 percent to 202 francs on news that British insurer Prudential had sold its Mercantile & General reinsurance business to Swiss Re .
* Conglomerate Bollore lost 2.4 percent to 521 francs after a morning trading suspension during which it said it had approved plans to buy out its 73.83 percent owned transport unit Scac Delmas Vileujeux ( SDV ) and invited shareholders to tender their shares .
* Alcatel Alsthom fell 1.7 percent to 395.0 .
* Opthalmic products manufacturer Essilor gained 2.6 percent to 1,328 francs after Oakley Inc of the United States said it had been granted an option to buy the non-prescription lens production unit of Gentext Optics Inc , an Essilor International subsidiary .
-- Paris newsroom +331 4221 5452
PRESS DIGEST - Sri Lankan Newspapers - August 27 .
Following are some of the main stories in Tuesday 's Sri Lankan newspapers :
---
VEERAKESARI
Bomb blast in TELO office in Trincomalee kills one , wounds six .
One officer and a soldier killed in accidental clash between two groups of soldiers near Chavakachcheri in Jaffna .
Army sentries thought a group of soldiers approaching them were Tamil rebels and opened fire .
---
THINAKARAN
TULF leader M. Sivasiththamparam says it is meaningless to talk to UNP about peace package and that the government should submit peace plan to parliament very soon .
---
DAILY NEWS
Bread and flour prices have been raised with immediate effect but government will provide relief to underpriviledged sections of society .
---
THE ISLAND
Excise Commissioner W.N.F. Chandraratne denies allegations that new guidelines in issue of liquor licences are aimed at forcing large number of liquor licence holders out of business for political reasons .
---
LANKADEEPA
Tamil Tiger rebels have sent 12 female suicide bombers to stage simultaneous attacks on President Chandrika Kumaratunga 's motorcade in Colombo .
---
DIVAINA
Cultural Ministry planning to spend large sum of money to buy silver crown believed to have been worn by ancient king and now in Australia .
---
DINAMINA
Government closes Ruhunu University indefinitely after big clash between two groups of students in which eight were wounded and hospitalised .
-- Colombo newsroom tel 941-434319
Mother Teresa turns 86 but still in danger .
Rupam Banerjee
CALCUTTA 1996-08-27
Mother Teresa spent her 86th birthday in a Calcutta hospital bed on Tuesday as tributes to the legendary missionary poured in from around the world .
Doctors said that later in the day they would try to wean the Nobel Peace Prize laureate from the respirator that has aided her breathing for the past six days .
" Her condition seems to be better , but the danger remains as long as she is on respirator , " an official at Woodlands Nursing Home said . "
She is conscious but her breathing is irregular . "
The revered Roman Catholic nun was admitted to the Calcutta hospital a week ago with high fever and severe vomiting .
She later suffered heart failure and was diagnosed with malaria .
Her fever has since abated and the heart failure has been brought under control , but her heart continues to beat irregularly , doctors said .
" Unless she breathes on her own , I would advise you to keep your fingers crossed , " said a doctor who was familiar with her case but not part of the six-member team treating Mother Teresa .
The nun 's birthday prompted greetings , bouquets and prayers from around the world .
Pope John Paul II and Israeli Foreign Minister David Levy sent her get-well messages , the Press Trust of India said .
" Ask for a miracle .
Happy Birthday to our Dearest Mother , " read a placard at the Shishu Bhavan children 's home in central Calcutta run by Mother Teresa 's Missionaries of Charity .
On Monday , both houses of India 's parliament wished the nation 's adopted sister a happy birthday and speedy recovery from her illness .
Prayers continued in Calcutta , one of the world 's poorest cities , where Mother Teresa 's Missionaries of Charity runs several homes for the poor and destitute .
Street children , some of them born to prostitutes , held prayers on the street . "
All of us know about her .
She is like a goddess , " said Raju , 8 , who has a mother but no father .
The Statesman newspaper quoted 40-year-old Mangala Das , paralysed from her waist down and a resident of the Prem Dan ( Gift of Love ) home for the destitute , as saying she and her friends had been praying incessantly for Mother Teresa 's recovery .
Tarak Das , 70 , was picked up from a Calcutta footpath a week ago by passers-by who took pity on him and brought him to Nirmal Hriday ( Immaculate Home ) .
" I do not know who she is .
I have never seen her , but I can only bless her for what she has done for people like me , " Das told The Statesman .
Mother Teresa 's condition improved on Sunday as her fever abated , and on Monday she was able to scribble notes to doctors and nuns .
Thousands in Calcutta , where she founded her Missionaries of Charity religious order in 1949 , prayed for her recovery .
Ministers of the communist government of West Bengal state and people of different religions joined Catholics to pray for Mother Teresa 's recovery at Mother House .
" We joined the prayer to express our solidarity with her work for the cause of the poor and downtrodden , " said Nanda Gopal Bhattacharya , a communist minister in West Bengal .
Islamists can meet in London , minister .
ISLAMABAD 1996-08-27
British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind said on Tuesday that his government would only take action against a planned conference of Islamist groups in London if British law was broken .
" People who wish to hold conferences of course do n't need to seek permission from the government in Britain , " Rifkind , in Pakistan for a visit , told Reuters . "
As long as they obey our laws then that is not something the government would normally interfere with . "
The Islamist conference , due to be held in London on September 8 , has caused concern in countries such as Algeria and Egypt , which are fighting armed Islamic militants .
British Jewish groups have also protested because they say members of Algeria 's Islamic Salvation Front ( FIS ) and the Palestinian Islamic group Hamas are on the guest list .
Rifkind said it was for the home secretary ( interior minister ) to act by denying visas to participants if he felt there was reason to believe that they might break the law .
" Our policy has to be fundamentally based on respect for the rule of law and insistence that it be observed , " he said .
Rifkind was in Pakistan at the start of an Asian tour that will also take him to India , Sri Lanka , Japan and Mongolia .
Afghan leader tells U.S. Congressman of peace plan .
Sayed Salahuddin
KABUL 1996-08-27
Afghan government military chief Ahmad Shah Masood briefed visiting U.S. Congressman Dana Rohrabacher on Tuesday on a peace plan for his wartorn country .
A spokesman for Masood said he had told the California Republican at a meeting in northern Kabul that President Burhanuddin Rabbani 's government favoured talks with all Afghan factions to set up an interim government .
The factions should agree to appoint a transitional leader , draft a new constitution , collect heavy weapons , create a national army and hold free elections in which the transitional leader would be barred from standing , he added .
Rohrabacher flew into Bagram military airbase north of Kabul in a Red Cross plane on Tuesday after meeting northern opposition militia leader General Abdul Rashid Dostum .
Masood 's spokesman Amrollah ( one name ) said Rohrabacher had recently visited Italy , Saudi Arabia and Pakistan as part of a mission to promote peace in Afghanistan .
" We are certainly serious more than before to find a solution to the Afghan problem and support every U.N. plan , " Amrollah quoted Rohrabacher as saying .
However , a spokesman for Prime Minister Gulbuddin Hekmatyar , a long-time rival of Masood , expressed concern at signs of renewed U.S. interest in Afghanistan .
" America wants to block the establishment of a strong Islamic government in Afghanistan and the U.S. intends to neutralise the Afghan peace process initiated by the Afghans themselves , " said the spokesman , Hamid Ibrahimi .
" A great game has been started in Afghanistan as America feels that Tehran and Moscow have got stronger in the Afghan picture -- something Washington wants to change , " he said .
Rohrabacher was expected to visit neutral faction leaders in the eastern city of Jalalabad and meet leaders of the rebel Islamic Taleban militia in the southern city of Kandahar .
Afghan guerrilla factions have been locked in a bloody power struggle since the fall of the communist government in April 1992 .
Hekmatyar , once Rabbani 's main rival , made a peace pact with him and rejoined the government as prime minister in June .
Pakistan state bank sells 1.38 bln rupees of bonds .
KARACHI , Pakistan 1996-08-27
The State ( central ) Bank of Pakistan auctioned three- , five- and 10-year federal investment bonds worth 1.38 billion rupees on Tuesday .
The bank said it had accepted bids of 250 million rupees at par for three-year bonds , 3.5 million rupees at par for five-year bonds and 1.126 billion at par for 10-year bonds .
The auction is set for settlement on Thursday .
In the previous auction on July 11 , it accepted bids worth 300 million rupees at par for three-year bonds , 44.5 million rupees at par for five-year bonds and 782.6 million rupees at par for 10-year bonds .
-- Karachi newsroom 9221-5685192
Nepal offers to talk to Maoist insurgents .
Gopal Sharma
KATHMANDU 1996-08-27
Nepal 's centre-right coalition government has offered to meet the country 's hardline Maoist communists for talks in a bid to end an insurgency in Nepal 's western districts , officials said on Tuesday .
The Maoists oppose multi-party democracy and want to establish a communist state .
But the Nepali government said the insurgents must give up violence before it negotiates with them .
" They ( the insurgents ) should first give up their violent activities , " Home ( Interior ) Minister Khum Bahadur Khadga said .
About 54 people have died in Maoist insurgent activity and in police action against them since February , officials said .
Nepali opposition parties have accused the police of having killed more people than the insurgents .
Some human rights groups have criticised the government 's handling of the situation .
In a speech in parliament on Tuesday , Khadga challenged the Maoist communists to " win the people 's confidence " and win election to parliament .
On Monday , he had offered to talk to leaders of the United People 's Front Nepal ( Bhattarai ) , the Maoist faction which leads the insurgency .
" The government is ready to guarantee security of the Maoist representatives who want to take part in peaceful dialogue , " Khadga said .
A multi-party democracy was set up in Nepal six years ago , after a popular movement by the centrist Nepali Congress party jointly with the Communist United Marxist-Leninist ( UML ) party .
The Nepali Congress leads the three-party coalition government while the UML is the main opposition party .
Indian soy prices end steady ahead of holiday .
INDORE , India 1996-08-27
Indian soybean prices on Tuesday remained steady at 12,900-13,100 rupees per tonne in plant delivery condition , dealers said
They said arrivals were poor due to the festival season .
Markets in central India would be closed for a local religious holiday on Wednesday .
Soyoil prices fell on increased selling against poor demand .
Soyoil solvent was down by 400 rupees per tonne and soyoil refined was down by 400 rupees .
Soyoil refined fell by 200 rupees on weak undertone .
Soymeal yellow was $ 276-277 and soymeal black was $ 246-248 per tonne in export .
Rapeseed extraction was $ 115 per tonne in export .
Export demand was good but availability was limited .
Rapeseed extraction was 3,850 rupees FOR Bedibunder and was 3,800-3,825 rupees FOR Bhavnagar .
---------------------
( Prices in rupees per tonne )
Market Arrivals Auction Traders Plant
( in tonnes )
Dewas 45 Yellow 12,700-12,950 12,900-13,150 12,900-13,100
Black 11,900-12,100
Mandsaur 10 Yellow 12,600-12,750 12,700-12,850
Neemuch n.a Yellow - -
Mhow 2 Yellow 12,700-12,800 12,750-12,850
Ratlam 10 Yellow 12,600-12,750 12,700-12,800
Ashta 10 Yellow 12,700-12,900 12,800-13,000
Indore 25 Yellow 12,750-12,950 12,900-13,100
Dhar 5 Yellow 12,700-12,800 12,750-12,900
Ujjain 8 Yellow 12,750-12,900 12,850-13,050
Jaora n.a Yellow - -
Barnagar n.a Yellow - -
Khandwa n.a Yellow - -
Ashoknagar n.a Yellow - -
Nalkhera n.a Yellow - -
----------------------------------
Soyoil ( in rupees per tonne )
Soyoil solvent plant delivery 30,300-30,400
Soyoil solvent market delivery 30,700-30,800
Soyoil refined plant delivery 32,700-32,800
Soyoil refined market delivery 32,900-33,000
--------------------------------
Soymeal ( in rupees per tonne , free on rail-FOR )
Yellow Black
FOR Bombay 9,800 8,800
FOR Bedi Bunder 9,800 8,800
( $ 1=35.73 rupees )
Bangladesh Speaker says he received death threats .
DHAKA 1996-08-27
The Speaker of Bangladesh 's parliament , Humayun Rasheed Choudhury , said he had received death threats from anonymous callers after opposition parties threatened to boycott proceedings chaired by him .
He told the Bengali newspaper Banglabazar Patrika on Tuesday that such threats were possibly coming from " those who want to push the country into chaos and unrest . "
The callers said his life could be cut short , the newspaper said .
The speaker was not immediately available for comment .
Choudhury , a former foreign minister and veteran diplomat , was appointed speaker of the 330-member parliament on July 13 , a month after general elections returned the Awami League of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina to power after 21 years .
Choudhury also was president of the 41st session of the U.N. General Assembly in 1986-87 .
Former prime minister Begum Khaleda Zia , now the opposition leader in parliament and head of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party ( BNP ) , said her followers might boycott assemby sessions chaired by the " partisan " speaker .
" The ruling Awami league is making parliament ineffective and the speaker is contributing to that by not allowing the opposition MPs enough time to speak , " she told a rally in northern district of Bogra on Monday .
Hasina , speaking to a group of engineers in Dhaka on Monday , accused the BNP of resorting to " terrorism " as part of its plan to create instability and chaos in the country .
" This is not desireable ...
and we will deal with such designs sternly , " the prime minister said .
Bangladesh June M2 up 3.8 pct m / m , up 8.2 pct y / y .
DHAKA 1996-08-27
Bangladesh 's M2 money supply rose 3.8 percent in June to 456.8 billion taka after a 0.27 percent rise to 439.9 billion in May , central bank officials said .
The year-on-year rise was 8.2 percent to June , 1996 .
BANGLADESH 'S MONEY SUPPLY
JUNE MAY JUNE 1995
M2 money supply ( bln taka ) 456.8 439.9 422.1
M1 money supply ( bln taka ) 144.5 139.3 131.7
HELIBOR INTEREST RATES LARGELY UNCHANGED .
HELSINKI 1996-08-27
Helibor market interest rates
were largely unchanged at the Bank of Finland 's daily fixing on
Tuesday .
The key three-month rate was steady at 3.40 percent .
August 27 fix August 26 fix
1-mth Helibor 3.27 pct 3.29 pct
2-mth Helibor 3.34 pct 3.34 pct
3-mth Helibor 3.40 pct 3.40 pct
6-mth Helibor 3.56 pct 3.55 pct
9-mth Helibor 3.73 pct 3.70 pct
12-mth Helibor 3.89 pct 3.87 pct
-- Helsinki newsroom +358 - 0 - 680 50 248
Barrick gets 93 pct of Arequipa .
TORONTO 1996-08-27
Barrick Gold Corp said on Tuesday its takeover offer for Arequipa Resources Ltd was successful , with 93 percent of the 36.3 million shares not already owned tendered under the bid , which expired overnight .
" We are pleased that Arequipa shareholders ahave chosen so overwhelmingly to accept this offer .
We now have the opportunity to realize the potential of Arequipa 's excellent assets , " Barrick chairman and chief executive Peter Munk said in a statement .
The C$ 30-a-share deal means Barrick will own Arequipa 's attractive Pierina gold deposit in Peru .
Barrick said details involving the allocation between Barrick shares and cash will be available shortly .
Barrick 's offer of C$ 30 a share or part cash , part share offer was Barrick 's second attempt to swallow the small Vancouver-based gold prospector .
Toronto-based Barrick , the world 's third largest gold producer , sweetened its July 11 bid to C$ 30 a share from C$ 27 on August 16 after a fresh batch of drill results from the Pierina deposit .
Experts have speculated the deposit has potential reserves of up to 12 million ounces .
More drilling results are expected soon .
The Barrick bid took observers by surprise , since Arequipa 's exploration was still in its early stages .
Arequipa shareholders had the option to choose C$ 30 cash or 0.79 Barrick shares plus 50 cents for each Arequipa share .
Shares were to be pro-rated if more than 14.4 million were requested .
-- Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8100
Penn Treaty terminates acquisition pact .
ALLENTOWN , Pa .
1996-08-27
Penn Treaty American Corp said Tuesday it terminated a previously announced non-binding letter of intent to purchase Merrion Insurance Company Inc , a New York licensed company .
In announcing its decision , Penn Treaty said it " will continue to actively pursue entering into the New York long-term care market through licensing or by acquisition . "
It explained the " addition of a New York license will enable Penn Treaty American Corp to conduct business in all 50 states , following the company 's acquisition of Health Insurance of Vermont , a Vermont domiciled insurer , scheduled to close on August 30 , 1996 . "
-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610 .
VNU details first-half operating profits .
HAARLEM , Netherlands 1996-08-27
Publisher VNU gave the following breakdown of its first-half results :
H1 1996 H1 1995
Sales Op profit Sales Op profit
Consumer magazines 618 90 568 80
Newspapers 363 49 295 46
Commercial TV 127 6 loss 174 33 profit
Business info Europe 231 24 178 18
Business info USA 382 61 362 41
Education 42 6 36 3
Miscellaneous charges --- 16 --- 30
NOTES - Sales and operating profit are given in millions of guilders .
Commercial TV includes pro rata share of sales and operating profits in Dutch group HMG and Belgium 's VTM .
-- Amsterdam newsroom +31 20 504 5000 , Fax +31 20 504 5040
AOL Europe forms online advertising agency .
HANOVER , Germany 1996-08-27
The joint venture between America Online ( AOL ) and Bertelsmann AG has formed a new company to sell advertising space on AOL in Europe , a Bertelsmann official said on Tuesday .
The new company is called AdOn GmbH and is located in Hamburg , Bernd Schiphorst , president and chief operating officer of Bertelsmann 's New Media business division said on the sidelines of an AOL news conference at the CeBIT Home consumer electronics fair in Hanover .
Jan Buettner , managing director of AOL Germany , said AdOn was in the formation phase and would " get off the ground next year , bringing in advertising from around Europe . "
He would give no forecasts on advertising revenue .
AOL is the leading global commercial online service with some six million subscribers worldwide .
It has around 200,000 subscribers in Europe , with two thirds of that number in Germany alone .
In Europe , the service is available in Germany , France and Britain .
It will be available in Austria and Switzerland later this year and in Scandanavia and the Benelux countries next year .
-- William Boston , CeBIT newsroom , 0172 6736510
All passengers freed from Sudanese hijack plane .
STANSTED , England 1996-08-27
All passengers held hostage aboard a hijacked Sudanese Airways plane diverted to London 's Stansted airport carrying 199 passengers and crew have been freed , an airport spokeswoman said on Tuesday .
Eyewitnesses said six crew members had also been allowed to leave the aircraft .
Airport spokeswoman Rona Young confirmed that all the passengers had left the aircraft .
Police said a number of crew members had left the aircraft and said details would be given at a news conference expected to be held in the next few minutes by the local police chief .
The passengers were released in batches during the course of the morning after the Airbus A310 landed at Stansted , having been diverted from Cyprus .
The aircraft was hijacked on a flight from Khartoum to Amman by six or seven men , who police say may be Iraqis .
-- London Newsroom + 00--44-171-542-7947
Swiss Bank Corp sets warrants on DTB-Bund-Future .
LONDON 1996-08-27
Swiss Bank Corp says it has issued 60 million American-style call and put warrants , in six equal tranches , on the DTB-Bund-Future March 1997 .
EXERCISE PERIOD 02.SEP.96-06.MAR.97 PAYDATE 30.AUG.96
LISTING FFT DDF MIN EXER LOT 100
SPOT REFERENCE 95.35 PCT
WARRANTS STRIKE ISS PRICE PREMIUM GEARING
CALL A 96.00 PCT 1.16 DEM 1.90 PCT 82.20 X
CALL B 97.00 PCT 0.75 DEM 2.50 PCT 127.10 X
CALL C 98.00 PCT 0.47 DEM 3.30 PCT 202.90 X
PUT D 94.00 PCT 0.94 DEM 2.40 PCT 101.40 X
PUT E 95.0 PCT 1.33 DEM 1.80 PCT 71.70 X
PUT F 96.0 PCT 1.84 DEM 1.20 PCT 51.80 X
-- Reuter London Newsroom +44 171 542 7658
DBRS confirms Power Corp , Power Financial ratings .
TORONTO 1996-08-27
Dominion Bond Rating Service said on Tuesday it confirmed the ratings on Power Corp of Canada 's senior debt and preferred shares at A ( high ) and Pfd-2 , respectively , with stable trends .
DBRS said it also confirmed Power Financial Corp 's senior debentures , cumulative preferred shares and non-cumulative first preferred shares , series B , at AA ( low ) , Pfd-1 and Pfd-1 ( low ) , all with stable trends .
Turkey 's Kurd rebels kill two , take three hostage .
ANKARA 1996-08-27
Kurdish guerrillas killed two people and took three hostage after stopping two intercity buses at a roadblock in eastern Turkey , security officials said on Tuesday .
They told reporters a group of Kurdistan Workers Party ( PKK ) guerrillas stopped the buses at a roadblock on the road linking the eastern provinces of Erzincan and Sivas on Monday night and forced the passengers to get out .
The rebels killed one of the drivers and a passenger after checking the identities of the passengers , they said .
The officials said the rebels set ablaze two buses and released all but three passengers .
More than 20,000 people have been killed in the 12-year-old conflict between Turkish troops and PKK guerrillas fighting for autonomy or independence from Turkey .
Egypt confiscates paper for " mad rulers " article .
CAIRO 1996-08-27
Egypt has banned and confiscated 10,000 copies of the Cyprus-based Arabic monthly newspaper al-Tadamun because of an editorial suggesting mental health tests for Arab leaders , the editor-in-chief said on Tuesday .
Mohamed Abu Liwaya , said Information Ministry censors had told him to send all the copies of the August edition back to Cyprus at his own expense .
He told Reuters the reason was his own front-page editorial , entitled " A Chronic Mental Illness " in which he attacks compliant Arab leaders for serving U.S. and Israeli interests .
" The Arabs demand that our Arab leaders undergo a compulsory examination by a team of psychiatrists to see how sound their mental capacities are , " the editorial said .
" Because our leaders have started to behave with extreme hostility towards the interests of their peoples to court the goodwill of the Americans and the Zionists , " he added .
The censorship office denied they had confiscated the newspapers but declined to say when they could go on sale .
IPO FILING - Transkaryotic Therapies Inc .
WASHINGTON 1996-08-27
Company Name Transkaryotic Therapies Inc
Nasdaq Stock symbol TKTX
Estimated price range $ 13 - $ 15 / shr
Total shares to be offered 2.5 million
Shrs offered by company 2.5 million
Shrs outstanding after ipo 16,668,560
Lead Underwriter Morgan Stanley and Co Inc
Underwriters over-allotment 375,000 shrs Shares to be purchased by Hoechst Marion Roussel Inc 357,143 Business : developed two proprietary technology platforms , gene activation and gene therapy .
Use of Proceeds : Research , preclinical and clinical product development , and general corporate purposes .
Financial Data in 000s : 1995 1994
- Revenue $ 15,400 $ 10,000
- Net Income ( loss ) $ 2,074 ( $ 3,422 )
AMTRAK train hits truck , derails in Vermont .
MONTPELIER , Vt .
1996-08-27
An Amtrak train struck a logging truck early on Tuesday and derailed , Vermont state police said .
A state police spokeswoman said there were reports of minor injuries as a result of the derailment near Roxbury , a small town on the edge of the Northfield Mountains some 15 miles southwest of Montpelier , the state capital .
Further details were not immediately available .
Wife of gun victim Brady praises Clinton .
CHICAGO 1996-08-26
Sarah Brady , whose Republican husband was severely disabled in an assassination attempt on President Ronald Reagan , took centre stage at the Democratic National convention on Monday night to praise President Bill Clinton 's gun control efforts .
With her husband James sitting in a wheelchair to the side of the podium , Mrs. Brady called the handgun control bill that a Democratic Congress passed and Clinton signed in 1994 a major step in controlling firearm violence in the United States .
But she said more had to be done .
The Bradys walked on to the stage , he on her arm and with the aid of a cane , to a rousing reception from the convention .
Their teenaged son sat in a VIP box with first lady Hillary Rodham Clinton and watched as his father returned to his wheelchair .
" Jim , we must have made a wrong turn .
This is n't San Diego ( site of the Republican convention ) , " Mrs. Brady joked to her husband , who was serving as Reagan 's press secretary when he was shot .
" Sarah , I told you this is the Democratic convention , " he responded to his wife , who before the shooting had worked for two Republican congressmen and the Republican national party .
" Since the Brady Law went into effect on February 28 , 1994 ( it ) has stopped more than 100,000 convicted felons and other prohibited purchasers from buying a handgun .
Today , and every day , the Brady Law is stopping an estimated 85 felons from buying a handgun , " Mrs. Brady said .
She added , " But we need to do more .
We should , as President Clinton proposed today , stop people convicted of domestic violence from buying a handgun .
Jim and I join with you tonight in saluting the great job that President Clinton has done in fighting crime and gun violence . "
" He 's a hunter and a sportsman , but he understands the difference between a Remington rifle and an AK47 .
And he knows that you do n't go hunting with an Uzi .
Mr. President you deserve our thanks . "
Jim Brady then gave a big thumbs to the audience .
Brady
was shot in the head in 1981 by gunman John Hinckley , who tried to kill Reagan in a deranged bid to impress Jodie Foster , an actress he never met but with whom he was obsessed .
The Brady bill , calling for a waiting period before someone could buy a gun so a background check could be made , was first introduced in Congress in 1987 but it took seven years to pass because of opposition from the National Rifle Association gun lobby .
Latest opinion polls on German political parties .
BONN 1996-08-27
Here are the latest opinion polls tracking national support for Germany 's main political parties :
AUGUST 1996 CDU / CSU SPD FDP Greens PDS
Emnid Aug 25 41.0 34.0 7.0 10.0 6.0
Elect Res Aug 23 41.0 35.0 5.0 11.0 4.0
Allensbach Aug 21 37.2 32.8 8.0 13.0 5.6
Emnid Aug 18 41.0 34.0 6.0 10.0 5.0
JULY 1996 CDU / CSU SPD FDP Greens PDS
Emnid July 7 39.0 32.0 7.0 11.0 5.0
Elect Res July 40.0 33.0 6.0 12.0 4.0
JUNE 1996 CDU / CSU SPD FDP Greens PDS
Emnid June 30 39.0 33.0 6.0 12.0 5.0
Elect Res June 21 42.0 33.0 6.0 12.0 4.0
Allensbach June 12 37.4 32.8 7.3 12.3 5.4
Forsa June 6 39.0 36.0 6.0 12.0 5.0
MAY 1996 CDU / CSU SPD FDP Greens PDS
Emnid May 26 40.0 31.0 6.0 13.0 6.0
Elect Res May 25 43.0 32.0 6.0 12.0 4.0
Forsa May 23 38.0 37.0 7.0 11.0 5.0
Allensbach May 15 38.5 32.5 8.1 12.0 4.4
APRIL 1996 CDU / CSU SPD FDP Greens PDS
Emnid April 28 40.0 32.0 5.0 11.0 5.0
Elect Res April 20 43.0 32.0 6.0 12.0 4.0
Allensbach April 17 38.1 32.3 6.5 12.9 6.3
OFFICIAL RESULTS OF THE OCTOBER 16 , 1994 GENERAL ELECTION :
CDU / CSU SPD FDP Greens PDS
41.5 36.4 6.9 7.3 4.4
NOTE : Elect Res = Electoral Research Group ( Forschungsgruppe Wahlen )
-- Bonn newsroom , +49 228 2609760
Most hostages freed from hijacked Sudanese plane .
STANSTED , England 1996-08-27
Armed hijackers believed to be Iraqis released 140 people on Tuesday from a Sudan Airways plane carrying 199 passengers and crew that landed in London after being diverted on a flight from Khartoum to Amman , police said .
Police spokesman Roger Grimwade said the six or seven hijackers remained on board the aircraft , which arrived from Cyprus at 4.30 a.m. ( 0330 GMT ) .
He said they had made various requests to police negotiators but stepped back from earlier suggestions that the hijackers had asked to speak to a British-based Iraqi police named as Mr Sadiki .
The hijackers , who have said they want to seek asylum in Britain , are believed to be armed with grenades and possibly other explosives , according to police .
They earlier threatened to blow up the aircraft .
The Airbus A310 was diverted first to Cyprus , then to Britain .
British Data in merger talks with Mentmore .
LONDON 1996-08-27
Mentmore Abbey said on Tuesday that merger discussions were taking place with the board of British Data Management , an information resource management and archive storage company .
But it noted in a brief statement : " However , it is too early to say at this stage whether or not terms can be agreed . "
Mentmore Abbey , the UK stationery and housewares business formerly known as Platignum , said it was making the statement in response to recent newspaper articles linking the two groups .
Shares in Mentmore Abbey edged two pence higher to 81.5 pence , valuing the group at just under 30 million stg .
British Data Management 's shares slipped 0.5 pence to 179.5p , valuing that company at around 45 million stg .
-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 4017
Hijacked Sudan plane lands at a London airport .
STANSTED , England 1996-08-27
A hijacked Sudan Airways plane carrying 199 passengers and crew landed at Stansted airport just outside London early on Tuesday morning after flying from Cyprus , eyewitnesses said .
The Airbus 310 Flight 150 , which was hijacked on Monday evening on its way from Khartoum to the Jordanian capital Amman , landed at 4.30 a.m. ( 0330 GMT ) after a flight of more than four hours .
At least one of the unidentified hijackers was apparently armed with grenades and TNT and threatened to blow the plane up in Cyprus unless it was refuelled so they could fly to Britain to claim political asylum .
" They will surrender the passengers there and surrender themselves , " police spokesman Glafcos Xenos told reporters at Cyprus 's Larnaca airport .
Security was tight at Stansted airport , which is about 30 miles ( 50 km ) northeast of the capital .
Stansted has been designated as the preferred option for handling hijackings in southern England because it is more remote than Heathrow and Gatwick , London 's two major airports , and handles less air traffic .
Hijacked Sudan plane expected at London 's Stansted .
LONDON 1996-08-27
A hijacked Sudan Airways plane with 199 passengers and crew on board was expected to land at London 's Stansted airport later on Tuesday morning , a police spokeswoman said .
" That is the plan at the moment .
That is where the plane is being directed to , " Ruth Collin of Essex police , the force responsible for Stansted , said .
Stansted , London 's third-busiest airport after Heathrow and Gatwick , is located about 30 miles ( 48 km ) northeast of the capital .
British officials said they would much prefer to deal with a hijacking at Stansted because of its relatively remote location and because air traffic would be less badly disrupted there than at Heathrow or Gatwick .
They said police and the emergency services were implementing a well-rehearsed contingency plan to handle the hijacking .
The armed hijackers of the Airbus 310 Flight 150 , which is expected to arrive about 4 a.m. ( 0300 GMT ) , have said they intend to surrender and seek political asylum in Britain .
The plane was hijacked on its way from Khartoum to the Jordanian capital Amman on Monday evening and landed at Larnaca airport in Cyprus to refuel .
The identity and number of the hijackers was not known .
One of them negotiated through the pilot in English .
The pilot said several hijackers appeared to be placed around the plane .
Painted parrot scam lands Australian in jail .
PERTH , Australia 1996-08-27
A conman who painted common Australian parrots with dye to make them look like rare birds worth thousands of dollars was jailed for fraud on Tuesday .
Denham Peiris painted six green parrots , worth about A$ 100 ( US$ 79 ) a pair , with a cinnamon hair dye and traded them as Indian Ringneck Parrots , valued at A$ 14,000 a pair .
Peiris , 32 , of Perth , was sentenced in the Western Australian District Court to two years in jail for fraud after trading three pairs of impostor birds for 21 parrots worth a total of A$ 28,000 .
" Everyone was fooled , " said pet shop owner Shane Drew , who unknowingly traded the disguised birds .
" I 'd already had three local breeders have a look at them and sent photos and videos of the birds to the eastern states for authentication -- they said they 're nice birds , " Drew told reporters outside court .
" After I was told they were dyed , I checked them over again .
It was a perfect paint job except for one feather under a wing of one bird that was only half dyed , " Drew said .
Drew said Peiris , a bird enthusiast , would have succeeded with the fraud if he had not tried to trade a fourth pair of bogus birds after an associate had told police of the scam .
If not for the informant , the painted parrots ' true colours would not have been known for six months , he said .
" They moult in the summer , so five or six months down the track , I would have looked like the guilty party , " Drew said .
NZ motorist 's arrest brings free flight to Tonga .
WELLINGTON 1996-08-27
A New Zealand motorist got an unexpected free flight to Tonga on Tuesday after being caught drinking and driving .
The man drew attention to himself in the North Island town of Tauranga while trying to reverse his car out of a pothole on Saturday night .
He spun the wheels so much that the tyres caught alight and smoke began pouring from under the bonnet , the New Zealand Press Association reported .
Police arrested the man and charged him with drink-driving , but then iscovered he was wanted by the Immigration Service as an overstayer .
The man was due to catch a flight to Nuku'alofa in Tonga later on Tuesday .
Indonesia 's SBPUs auction results .
JAKARTA 1996-08-27
The following is the result of central bank securities ( SBPUs ) auction on Tuesday at 0800 GMT :
SBPUs seven-day 14-day
Cut-off-rate ( percent ) 15.75 16.00
Total ( in billion rupiah ) 38.43 218.50
-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364
Seoul embassies warned of terrorist attacks .
SEOUL 1996-08-27
South Korea has told its overseas missions to step up security since its embassy in the former Yugoslavia received a threat over Seoul 's crackdown on radical students , the foreign ministry said on Tuesday .
A letter to the Belgrade embassy on Monday under the name of the Macedonian Communist Party demanded South Korea release detained student leaders , a ministry spokesman said .
" The letter said the party would assault the embassy , other South Korean-related facilities and Korean nationals unless our authorities released arrested students , " he said .
Nearly 400 members of an outlawed student group were arrested after violent protests demanding reunification with communist North Korea were crushed by riot police at a Seoul university this month .
Authorities branded the violence , in which a police officer was killed , as an act of terror .
" The ministry has ordered the embassy to take urgent security measures against possible terrorist attacks , " the official said , asking not to be named .
It had called for similar precautions at other overseas missions , including those in Canada and Bangladesh where leftist groups have staged protests over the crackdown .
Nuclear pact will be a step to disarmament-China .
BEIJING 1996-08-27
China on Tuesday reaffirmed its support for a global nuclear test ban treaty blocked by India last week , saying the pact would be an important step in achieving total nuclear disarmament .
" Although the final draft of the treaty probably did n't totally satisfy any country , it was in general balanced , " the official People 's Daily newspaper said in a commentary .
India blocked the Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty ( CTBT ) at the Conference on Disarmament in Geneva , saying the pact did not contain a clause committing the five declared nuclear powers to a timetable for nuclear disarmament .
New Delhi 's stance , which was seen as effectively thwarting 2-1/2 years of negotiations at the Conference on Disarmament , drew widespread but generally muted foreign criticism .
India has also pledged to oppose any forwarding of the draft treaty to the United Nations General Assembly .
China said many countries had compromised to complete the treaty and that the issue of a disarmament schedule could be discussed in future negotiations .
" The completion of the test ban treaty would be an important and practical step in the gradual process of achieving total nuclear disarmament , " it said .
China has pledged support for the pact since reaching a deal with the United States that made international inspections of nuclear sites more difficult than in earlier drafts of the accord .
The newspaper said China advocated the complete ban and destruction of nuclear weapons but that there was little hope other nuclear powers would soon adopt the same stance .
" Some nuclear powers stubbornly uphold policies of nuclear deterrence based on first use of nuclear weapons , " it said .
China held on July 29 what it said would be its last nuclear test before a self-imposed moratorium that took effect the following day .
China was the last declared nuclear power to announce a halt to testing .
Japan declares food poisoning threat receding .
TOKYO 1996-08-27
The government said on Tuesday that the threat from a mysterious killer germ , while still requiring vigilance , appears to be receding in the western Japan city of Sakai , where the epidemic hit the hardest .
The food poisoning epidemic caused by the O-157 colon bacillus in Sakai appears to be " settling down " , Health Minister Naoto Kan was quoted by a government spokesman as telling the cabinet .
The O-157 colon bacillus has been found responsible for a widespread food poisoning epidemic that has killed 11 people and made over 9,500 ill this year .
Sakai , near the regional commercial centre of Osaka , has been hit hardest by the deadly bacteria , with nearly 6,500 , mostly schoolchildren , affected by the disease .
Two children in Sakai have died from complications associated with the bacteria .
Kan told a cabinet meeting on Tuesday that no new victims have been reported since August 8 , indicating that the peak has passed , at least for Sakai .
Sakai officials agreed with the assessment , but said it was too early to feel relieved .
" There are still patients hospitalised and problems which must be dealt with , " a city spokesman said , citing the issue of whether to allow children infected with the bacteria but not showing symptoms to attend school from September .
Health authorities believe school lunches were the source of the food poisoning in Sakai , but researchers have been unable to pinpoint the exact source of the infection .
The outbreak has prompted authorities to tighten sanitary standards at slaughterhouses and meatpacking plants and sparked calls for an overhaul of the nation 's school lunch programme .
The ministers agreed at Tuesday 's cabinet meeting to step up inspection measures for school lunches in September and October , when schools around the country resume .
Japan 's Agriculture Ministry also announced that it will compile hygiene guidelines based on U.S. government methods of checking the safety of farm produce to prevent another outbreak of the epidemic .
As of Monday , 31 children were still hospitalised in Sakai city , of whom six were in serious condition .
Japan aluminium shipments surge 8.9 pct in July .
TOKYO 1996-08-27
Japanese shipments of aluminium mill products in July surged 8.9 percent over the same month last year to 224,609 tonnes , while production rose 6.4 percent to 222,457 tonnes , according to preliminary data released on Tuesday by the Japan Aluminium Federation .
The surge reflected strong demand from the beverage can and housing construction sectors , federation officials said .
Figures released two weeks ago from Japan 's seven largest mills already showed that Japan 's can sheet output reached its highest monthly level ever in July , reflecting above-average temperatures that sparked a jump in beer consumption .
A federation official added that the half-year through September 1996 also appeared likely to set a new record for can production , despite cooler temperatures in August .
July inventories stood at 75,632 tonnes , down 2.6 percent from the prior month .
July foil output was off 0.2 percent year-on-year at 11,525 tonnes , while foil shipments fell 0.8 percent to 11,244 tonnes .
June mill output data were revised slightly downward to 210,622 tonnes from the preliminary 210,683 , while shipments were revised marginally upward to 213,989 tonnes from 213,845 .
Final figures for June pegged can stock shipments at 40,144 tonnes , up 2.4 percent year-on-year .
Shipments to the auto sector fell 5.5 percent to 15,286 tonnes , while the construction sector rose 2.4 percent to 79,390 tonnes .
Exports dipped 3.7 percent to 18,867 tonnes .
-- Tokyo Commodities Desk ( 81-3 3432 6179 )
China thanks Gabon for support on human rights .
BEIJING 1996-08-27
China has publicly thanked Gabon for its strong support at the United Nations Human Rights Commission , where Beijing has come under attack from Western nations for its human rights record .
China 's President Jiang Zemin offered his gratitude in a meeting on Monday with visiting Gabon President Omar Bongo , the official Xinhua news agency said .
Jiang also acknowledged the Central African nation 's support for China 's stance on Taiwan , which Beijing views as a renegade province , while Bongo was quoted as thanking China for economic and technological aid , the agency said late on Monday .
In April , China quashed a draft resolution by the U.N. Human Rights Commission expressing concern over continuing reports of Beijing 's violations of fundamental freedoms .
After the defeat of the resolution , drafted by the European Union and the United States , China 's Foreign Ministry thanked 26 countries for backing its motion for " no action " on the document .
It was the sixth year in a row that China avoided censure at the U.N. 's main human rights forum .
China has been accused of a wide range of human rights abuses , often in violation of its own legal code , in an effort to silence dissent .
A Xinhua commentary earlier this year said a plot by the West to force its human rights standards and values on other countries was doomed to failure .
Taiwan 's Cooperative Bank cuts prime lending rate .
TAIPEI 1996-08-27
Cooperative Bank of Taiwan , one of the island 's leading state-run banks , said it was cutting its prime lending rate by 0.05 percentage point , effective on Tuesday .
The bank said in a statement it was cutting its prime lending rate to 7.35 percent from 7.40 percent .
It also would cut its three-month-to-three-year time deposit rates by between 0.05 and 0.10 percentage points .
The moves made Cooperative the first major bank to cut rates in response to a call on Friday from central bank governor Sheu Yuan-dong .
In the central bank 's latest bid to jumpstart Taiwan 's sluggish economy , Sheu ordered a reduction of up to a half-percentage point in banks ' reserve requirements and called on commercial banks to pass on the savings in the form of interest rate reductions .
-- Taipei Newsroom ( 5080815 )
Palestinians to strike over Jerusalem demolition .
JERUSALEM 1996-08-27
Palestinian leaders in Jerusalem called on Tuesday for a two-hour strike to protest what they called Israel 's war on Arab East Jerusalem after police demolished a building there .
Israeli police demolished a 10 metre ( yard ) by 20 metre structure in Jerusalem 's Old City they said had been built with funding from the Palestinian self-rule Authority for use as a social club .
Police used a huge crane to lift a bulldozer over the Old City 's walls to reach the building amidst narrow alleys , witnesses said .
Bystanders at the scene said work had begun on the building in 1991 and it had yet to be completed when the Israeli police bulldozed it .
The Palestinian Authority was set up under the 1993 PLO-Israel interim peace deal .
" There has been a call for a general strike between one ( 1000 GMT ) and three o'clock , " Palestinian lawmaker Ahmed Hashem Zighayer told Reuters .
" This is a war that has been declared on us and we want our people to come and see the site where they declared the war . "
Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu 's government , which took office in June , has said it will not allow the Authority , set up under a 1993 interim peace deal to control parts of the Gaza Strip and West Bank , to operate in Jerusalem .
Israel 's previous government held the same position but in general turned a blind eye to Palestinian Authority activity in the city .
Tuesday 's demolition came a day after PLO officials said they had bowed to Netanyahu 's demand they close offices in Jerusalem .
They said two of the three offices Israel wanted closed had been shut .
Netanyahu has made closure of the three offices a condition for resuming peace negotiations with the Palestine Liberation Organisation ( PLO ) .
Israel captured Arab East Jerusalem in the 1967 Middle East war and annexed it .
It says it will never cede any part of the city .
Palestinians want East Jerusalem as capital of a future state .
The city is up for negotiation at final peace talks which have yet to resume under Netanyahu .
SEC adopts rules to improve investor access to best stock prices .
WASHINGTON 1996-08-28
The Securities and Exchange Commission Wednesday approved rules designed to give stock market investors a better chance at getting the best price available for their orders .
The so-called order handling rules , which were proposed last September , were approved in a 4-0 vote .
The new rules will require specialists at stock exchanges and market makers on Nasdaq to allow customers to view price quotes from other electronic trading systems that may not be readily available to them .
The rules will also require that customer limit orders be displayed with prices better than those available in quotes publicly available at the time .
Specialists and market makers are companies or individuals recognised as qualified to maintain an orderly market in a stock .
In a limit order , investors specify the price at which they are willing to buy or sell , as opposed to a market order executed at prevailing prices .
" These rules are intended to empower all investors , by allowing their orders to compete on a level playing field , and by providing the disclosure they need to make informed decisions , " said SEC Chairman Arthur Levitt .
The SEC 's goal , he added , was to create " one system where one price could be available to everybody . "
The director of the SEC 's division of market regulation , Richard Lindsey , said Wall Street firms will probably need to spend about $ 7 million to carry out the improvements called for by the new rules .
In proposing the rules last year , the SEC noted that while technology has improved , commonplace practices still existed that worked against investors ' best interests .
It noted that customers whose orders were not displayed lost the chance of getting the best possible price available in the market .
It also cited the potential problem of a two-tiered market in which market makers quote one price to public investors while quoting better prices in private systems , thus robbing investors without access to " hidden " quotes the benefit of the best available prices .
Earlier this month , the SEC settled charges of alleged malpractices on Nasdaq when the parent of the Nasdaq market , the National Association of Securities Dealers , agreed to spend $ 100 million over five years to upgrade its oversight of brokers ' trading practices .
The SEC dropped a third proposal that would have allowed investors with market orders to trade at a better price if there were shifts in prices before their orders were executed .
The agency said it would monitor effects of the two new rules before considering the " price improvement " proposal again .
The agency also proposed rule changes that would require continuous " bid " and " ask " quotations from exchange specialists and market makers who trade more than 1 percent of a stock during any quarter on Nasdaq .
The SEC 's limit order display rule will mean a major change for Nasdaq , where such orders have never been displayed .
The president of the Nasdaq , Alfred Berkeley , was to hold a news conference Wednesday afternoon to elaborate on the new rules ' effects on the market , the second largest in the world .
ITALIAN CABINET APPROVES TELEVISION DECREE .
ROME 1996-08-28
The Italian cabinet on Wednesday granted a reprieve for media mogul Silvio Berlusconi 's Mediaset television empire with a decree extending the current legal framework for television stations until January 31 , 1997 .
The decree plugs a legal void in which magistrates could have forced the former prime minister to take one of the three stations he controls off the air because of a court ruling that no single proprietor should be allowed to keep three channels .
Passengers injured in train collision in Linz .
LINZ , Austria 1996-08-28
A passenger train collided with a locomotive at a main railway station in Linz on Wednesday and police said around 10 people were injured .
Austrian television reported earlier that more than 20 had been hurt in the accident at the station in Linz , 300 km ( 180 miles ) west of Vienna .
" One locomotive was stationary and the passenger train collided into the back of it , " a police spokesman in Linz told Reuters by telephone .
The express passenger train travelling from Steyr , southeast of Linz , with around 80 people on board , hit the back of a service locomotive used to shunt wagons into sidings .
The police spokesman said he was not sure whether any more passengers were still trapped in the wreckage .
Doctors and medical staff from a hospital across the road from the station were at the scene of the accident within minutes and were able to treat the injured quickly , he added .
Greater damage was averted as the driver of the passenger train had time to apply his emergency brakes before the collision occurred , a state railways spokesman told Austrian news agency APA .
Saskatchewan Wheat Pool eyes hog market .
WINNIPEG 1996-08-28
Canada 's largest grain handling firm said Wednesday it expects to forge a partnership with hog farmers by 1997 with a view to expanding the company 's scope into pork production .
" Saskatchewan is well positioned to take advantage of growing world markets for pork , " Saskatchewan Wheat Pool chief executive Don Loewen said in a company statement .
SWP said it was analyzing potential partnerships with hog farmers and expected the first deal to be in place in 1997 .
The end of Canada 's rail freight subsidy last year caused a shift in feed grain production to the eastern Prairie .
Analysts said livestock production would likely shift to the eastern Prairie rather than feed grains being shipped to the western Prairie .
SWP said it may develop pork production systems that provide farmers with large integrated units , and it may consider contracting programs between producers and packers which would operate within the existing hog market framework .
Saskatchewan Pork International Marketing Group has an export monopoly but some Saskatchewan farmers earlier this month called for an open market in hogs .
-- Gilbert Le Gras 204 947 3548
ATHLETICS - ROVERETO INTERNATIONAL MEETING RESULTS .
ROVERETO , Italy 1996-08-28
Leading results from an
international athletics meeting on Wednesday :
Women 's long jump :
1. Ludmila Ninova ( Austria ) 6.72 metres
2. Heike Drechsler ( Germany ) 6.65
3. Fiona May ( Italy ) 6.64
Men 's 110 metres hurdles :
1. Emilio Valle ( Cuba ) 13.42 seconds
2. Steve Brown ( U.S. ) 13.45
3. Andrea Giaconi ( Italy ) 13.80
Women 's 100 metres :
1. Chandra Sturrup ( Bahamas ) 11.34 seconds
2. Natalya Voronova ( Russia ) 11.53
3. Gabi Rokmeier ( Germany ) 11.61
Men 's javelin :
1. Sergey Makarov ( Russia ) 85.26 metres
2. Tom Pukstys ( U.S. ) 84.20
3. Peter Blank ( Germany ) 81.64
Men 's 100 metres :
1. Osmond Ezinwa ( Nigeria ) 10.13 seconds
2. Davidson Ezinwa ( Nigeria ) 10.18
3. Stefano Tilli ( Italy ) 10.43
Men 's 400 metres :
1. Davis Kamoga ( Uganda ) 45.15 seconds
2. Marco Vaccari ( Italy ) 46.16
3. Kennedy Ochieng ( Kenya ) 46.21
Women 's pole vault :
1. Mariacarla Bresciani ( Italy ) 3.85 metres
2. Andrea Muller ( Germany ) 3.75
3. Nastja Rysich ( germany ) 3.75
Women 's 800 metres :
1. Ana Fidelia Quirot ( Cuba ) 1 minute 58.98 seconds
2. Letitia Vriesde ( Surinam ) 2:00.39
3. Inez Turner ( Jamaica ) 2:00.91
Men 's high jump :
1. Wolfgang Kreissig ( Germany ) 2.20 metres
2. Kostantin Matusevitch ( Israel ) 2.20
3. Michele Buiatti ( Italy ) 2.15
Men 's 800 metres :
1. Robert Kibet ( Kenya ) 1:45.24
2. Vincent Malakwen ( Kenya ) 1:45.62
3. Philip Kibitok ( Kenya ) 1:46.09
Women 's javelin :
1. Oksana Ovchinnikova ( Russia ) 58.94 metres
2. Natalya Shikolenko ( Belarus ) 57.44
3. Silke Renk ( Germany ) 56.70
Women 's 400 metres hurdles :
1. Virna De Angeli ( Italy ) 55.66
2. Natalya Torshina ( Kazakhstan ) 55.99
3. Anna Knoroz ( Russia ) 57.02
Men 's 400 metres hurdles :
1. Lauren Ottoz ( Italy ) 49.16
2. Brian Bronson ( U.S. ) 49.67
3. John Ridgeon ( Britain ) 49.83
Men 's 3,000 metres :
1. Luke Kipkosgei ( Kenya ) 7:46.91
2. Alessandro Lambruschini ( Italy ) 7:47.78
3. Richard Kosgei ( Kenya ) 7:48.38
GOLF - BRITISH MASTERS FIRST ROUND SCORES .
NORTHAMPTON , England 1996-08-28
Leading completed
first-round scores in the rain-affected British Masters golf
championship at Collingtree Park on Wednesday ( Britain unless
stated ) :
66 Gavin Levenson ( South Africa )
68 Colin Montgomerie
69 Jose Coceres ( Argentina ) , Raymond Russell , Robert Allenby
( Australia ) , David Gilford , Stuart Cage , Mike Clayton
( Australia ) , Mark Roe , Emanuele Canonica ( Italy )
70 Francisco Cea ( Spain ) , David Howell , Peter Hedblom
( Sweden )
71 Steven Bottomley , Ove Sellberg ( Sweden ) , Joakim Haeggman
( Sweden ) , Stephen Ames ( Trinidad and Tobago ) , Klas Eriksson
( Sweden ) , Roger Chapman , Mark Davis , Pierre Fulke ( Sweden ) ,
Martin Gates , Anders Haglund ( Sweden )
72 Niclas Fasth ( Sweden ) , Michael Jonzon ( Sweden ) , Chistian
Cevaer ( France ) , Thomas Bjorn ( Denmark ) , Tony Johnstone
( Zimbabwe ) , Padraig Harrington ( Ireland ) , Pedro Linhart
( Spain ) , David Carter
73 Ross McFarlane , Domingo Hospital ( Spain ) , Seve Ballesteros
( Spain ) , Paul Broadhurst , Greg Turner ( New Zealand ) , Mike
Harwood ( Australia ) , Brenden Pappas ( South Africa ) , Peter
Teravainen ( U.S. ) , Jean Van de Velde ( France ) , Oyvind Rojahn
( Norway ) , Stephen McAllister , Neal Briggs
Note : 77 players to complete their first rounds on Thursday
CYCLING - KELLY WINS WORLD TIME TRIAL TITLE .
MANCHESTER , England 1996-08-28
Shane Kelly of Australia retained the world one-kilometre time trial title at the world track championships on Wednesday , with a track record time of one minute 2.777 seconds .
Kelly averaged 57.345 kph to beat Soren Lausgberg of Germany by eighteen hundredths of a second .
The bronze medal went to another German , Jan Van Eijden , in 1:04.541 .
CYCLING - VAN HEESWIJK WINS SECOND STAGE OF TOUR OF NETHERLANDS .
ALMERE , Netherlands 1996-08-28
Leading placings in
the 195-km second stage of the Tour of the Netherlands between
Haarlem and Almere on Wednesday :
1. Max van Heeswijk ( Netherlands ) Motorola 4 hours 39 minutes
six seconds .
2. Johan Capiot ( Belgium ) Collstrop
3. Sven Teutenberg ( Germany ) U.S. Postal
4. Erik Zabel ( Germany ) Telekom
5. Federico Colonna ( Italy ) Mapei
6. Jans Koerts ( Netherlands ) Palmans
7. Michel Zanoli ( Netherlands ) MX Onda
8 .Giuseppe Citterio ( Italy ) Aki
9 .Robbie McEwen ( Australia ) Rabobank
10. Kaspars Ozers ( Latvia ) Motorola all same time
Leading overall placings after two stages :
1. Colonna 8:22:00
2. Van Heeswijk 1 second behind
3. McEwen same time
4. Teutenberg 4 seconds
5. Capiot 5
6. Koerts 7
7. Ozers 8
8. Gianluca Corini ( Italy ) Aki same time
9. Lance Armstrong ( U.S. ) Motorola 9
10. George Hincapie ( U.S. ) Motorola same time
CYCLING - VAN HEESWIJK WINS TOUR OF NETHERLANDS SECOND STAGE .
ALMERE , Netherlands 1996-08-28
Leading results and overall standings after the 195 kilometre second stage of the Tour of the Netherlands between Haarlem and Almere on Wednesday .
1. Max van Heeswijk ( Netherlands ) Motorola 4 hours 39 minutes six seconds .
2. Johan Capiot ( Belgium ) Collstrop
3. Sven Teutenberg ( Germany ) U.S. Postal
4. Erik Zabel ( Germany ) Telekom
5. Federico Colonna ( Italy ) Mapei
6. Jans Koerts ( Netherlands ) Palmans
7. Michel Zanoli ( Netherlands ) MX Onda
8. Giuseppe Citterio ( Italy ) Aki
9. Robbie McEwen ( Australia ) Rabobank
10. Kaspars Ozers ( Latvia ) Motorola all same time .
Leading overall standings after second stage .
1. Colonna 8:22:00
2. Van Heeswijk 1 second behind
3. McEwen same time
4. Teutenberg 4 seconds
5. Capiot 5
6. Koerts 7
7. Ozers 8
8. Gianluca Corini ( Italy ) Aki same time
9. Lance Armstrong ( U.S. ) Motorola 9
10. George Hincapie ( U.S. ) Motorola same time .
CYCLING - WORLD CHAMPIONSHIPS RESULTS .
MANCHESTER , England 1996-08-28
Results from the
world track cycling championships on Wednesday :
Men 's individual pursuit :
Selected result from first round
Chris Boardman ( Britain ) 4:13.353 seconds ( world record ) caught
Jens Lehman ( Germany )
Quarter-finals
Boardman 4:14.784 caught Edouard Gritson ( Russia )
Francis Moreau ( France ) 4:16.274 beat Heiko Szonn ( Germany )
4:21.715
Andrea Collinelli ( Italy ) 4:17.551 beat Michael Sandstod
( Denmark ) 4:24.660
Alexei Markov ( Russia ) 4:19.762 beat Mariano Friedick ( U.S. )
4:20.241
one kilometre time-trial final
1. Shane Kelly ( Australia ) 1 minute 02.777 seconds
2. Soren Lausberg ( Germany ) 1:02.795
3. Jan Van Eiden ( Germany ) 1:04.541
4. Herve Thuet ( France ) 1:04.732
5. Grzegorz Krejner ( Poland ) 1:04.834
6. Ainars Kiksis ( Latvia ) 1:04.896
7. Dimitrios Georgalis ( Greece ) 1:05.022
8. Jose Moreno ( Spain ) 1:05.219
9. Keiji Kojima ( Japan ) 1:05.300
10. Graham Sharman ( Australia ) 1:05.406
11. Jose Escuredo ( Spain ) 1:05.731
12. Craig MacLean ( Britain ) 1:05.735
13. Christian Meidlinger ( Austria ) 1:05.850
14. Darren McKenzie-Potter ( New Zealand ) 1:06.289
15. Masanaga Shiohara ( Japan ) 1:06.615
16. Jean-Pierre Van Zyl ( South Africa ) 1:07.258
Keirin final
1. Marty Nothstein ( U.S. ) , last 200 metres in 10.982 seconds .
2. Gary Neiwand ( Australia )
3. Frederic Magne ( France )
4. Pavel Buran ( Czech Republic )
5. Michael Hubner ( Germany )
6. Laurent Gane ( France )
Madison final ( 50 kms )
1. Silvio Martinelli - Marco Villa ( Italy ) 34 points , in a
time of 55 minutes 47.4 seconds
2. Scott McGrory - Stephen Pate ( Australia ) 25
3. Andreas Kappes - Carsten Wolf ( Germany ) 23
4. Kurt Betschart - Bruno Risi ( Switzerland ) 22
5. Gabriel Curuchet - Juan Curuchet ( Argentine ) 15
6. Peter Pieters - Tomas Post ( Netherlands ) 14
7. J immi Madsen - Jens Veggerby ( Denmark ) 14
8. Isaac Galvez-Lopez - Juan Llaneras ( Spain ) 11
9. Wolfgang Kotzmann - Franz Stocher ( Austria ) 5
10. Christophe Capelle - Jean-Michel Monin ( France ) 2
CYCLING - BOARDMAN FULFILS WORLD RECORD PREDICTION .
Martin Ayres
MANCHESTER , England 1996-08-28
Britain 's Chris Boardman fulfilled his prediction that he would break the world 4,000 metres world record in the world track cycling championships on Wednesday .
Boardman clocked four minutes 13.353 seconds to slice more than six seconds from the previous world mark of 4:19.699 set by Olympic champion Andrea Collinelli of Italy in Atlanta in July .
Collinelli qualified in second place , also beating his old record in 4:17.696 .
" I was very nervous before the start but then I was amazed by the speed of my ride , " Boardman said . "
I do n't know if I can go any faster .
Who knows what will happen in the later stages ? "
Boardman , 28 , did not contest the Olympic pursuit because of its proximity to the Tour de France in which he led the French GAN team .
However , he took a bronze medal in the Olympic road time-trial and then returned home to prepare for the world track series in the Manchester indoor velodrome .
He adopted the " superman " riding position with arms at full stretch perfected by fellow Briton Graeme Obree , the 1995 world champion , and taken up in Atlanta by Collinelli .
Obree was forced to pull out of his title defence because of a viral infection .
Qualifiers for Wednesday evening 's quarter-finals :
1. Chris Boardman ( Britain ) 4:13.353
2. Andrea Collinelli ( Italy ) 4:17.696
3. Mariano Friedick ( U.S. ) 4:19.808
4. Heiko Szonn ( Germany ) 4:21.009
5. Francis Moreau ( France ) 4:21.454
6. Alexei Markov ( Russia ) 4:22.738
7. Michael Sandstod ( Denmark ) 4:24.427
8. Edouard Gritsoun ( Russia ) 4:26.467
CYCLING - BOARDMAN BREAKS WORLD 4,000 METRES RECORD .
MANCHESTER , England 1996-08-28
Britain 's Chris Boardman broke the world 4,000 metres cycling record by more than six seconds at the world championships on Wednesday .
Boardman clocked four minutes 13.353 seconds in the qualifying round of the individual pursuit event to beat the previous mark of 4:19.699 set by Andrea Collinelli of Italy at the Atlanta Olympics on July 24 .
SOCCER - ENGLISH FIRST DIVISION RESULTS / STANDINGS .
LONDON 1996-08-28
Results of English first division
soccer matches on Wednesday :
Barnsley 3 Reading 0
Stoke 1 Bradford 0
Swindon 1 Oldham 0
Wolverhampton 1 Queens Park Rangers 1
Standings ( tabulated under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , against , points ) :
Barnsley 3 3 0 0 8 2 9
Stoke 3 3 0 0 5 2 9
Tranmere 3 2 1 0 6 3 7
Bolton 3 2 1 0 5 2 7
Wolverhampton 3 2 1 0 5 2 7
Queens Park Rangers 3 2 1 0 5 3 7
Norwich 3 2 0 1 4 3 6
Ipswich 3 1 1 1 6 4 4
Birmingham 2 1 1 0 5 4 4
Crystal Palace 3 1 1 1 3 2 4
Swindon 3 1 1 1 2 3 4
Oxford 3 1 0 2 6 3 3
Bradford 3 1 0 2 3 3 3
Huddersfield 2 1 0 1 3 3 3
Portsmouth 3 1 0 2 3 5 3
Reading 3 1 0 2 3 8 3
Man City 3 1 0 2 2 3 3
West Bromwich 3 0 2 1 2 3 2
Port Vale 3 0 2 1 2 4 2
Sheffield United 2 0 1 1 4 5 1
Grimsby 3 0 1 2 4 7 1
Charlton 2 0 1 1 1 3 1
Southend 3 0 1 2 1 7 1
Oldham 3 0 0 3 2 6 0
CRICKET - ENGLISH COUNTY CHAMPIONSHIP SCORES .
LONDON 1996-08-28
Close of play scores on the first
day of four-day English County Championship cricket matches on
Wednesday :
At Portsmouth : Middlesex 199 in 60 overs ( K. Brown 57 ;
L. Botham 5-67 ) .
Hampshire 105-4 .
At Chester-le-Street : Glamorgan 73-3 v Durham .
SOCCER - FOWLER AND MCMANAMAN OUT OF ENGLAND SQUAD .
LONDON 1996-08-28
England soccer manager Glen Hoddle confirmed on Wednesday that the Liverpool pair of Steve McManaman and Robbie Fowler would miss England 's World Cup qualifying match against Moldova on Sunday .
The two men , both suffering from back injuries , joined the England squad at training but it was soon clear they had no chance of making the flight to Kishinev on Friday .
" They had some scans and X-rays yesterday and they 're out , " said Hoddle .
" The more important thing for me was to get them down here and have a chat .
To go another five weeks without that chance would have been foolish , " he added .
Hoddle , who has already lost the services of midfielder Darren Anderton and defender Steve Howey , delayed naming any replacements .
There was also concern over injuries to Paul Gascoigne , Les Ferdinand and David Batty .
HORSE RACING - JOCKEY WEAVER RECEIVES 21-DAY BAN .
LONDON 1996-08-28
Leading rider Jason Weaver received a 21-day ban from the disciplinary committee of the Jockey Club on Wednesday .
Weaver had been reported after being found guilty of irresponsible riding at the provincial track of Pontefract 10 days ago .
It was his fourth riding offence this season .
Although five days of the ban were suspended until January 1 , Weaver will miss next month 's big St Leger meeting , including the ride on top stayer Double Trigger in the Doncaster Cup .
Weaver shot to prominence in 1994 when he won the English 2,000 Guineas on Mister Baileys in his first ride in a classic .
ROWING - REDGRAVE MAY SEEK FIFTH OLYMPIC GOLD .
LONDON 1996-08-28
Britain 's Steven Redgrave said on Wednesday he might change his mind and go for a fifth consecutive Olympic gold medal at the 2000 Games in Sydney .
Redgrave is one of only five athletes who have won gold medals at four successive Olympics .
He shared victory with Matthew Pinsent in the coxless pairs at the Atlanta Games and said at the time that would be his last shot .
But he has had second thoughts since then . "
I 'm only 34 .
Some say that 's too old for an athlete , " he said .
" But I 'll be 38 by Sydney and that 's not too old .
It 's whether I have got the enthusiasm for the training over the next four years .
Rowing is an endurance sport . "
CRICKET - BOTHAM DISMISSES GATTING IN FIRST CLASS DEBUT .
LONDON 1996-08-28
Liam Botham demonstrated his father Ian 's golden touch on Wednesday shortly after making his county debut for Hampshire .
Botham dismissed Mike Gatting with his seventh ball when the former England captain pushed a half-volley to square-leg on the first day of the four-day match against Middlesex at Portsmouth .
Earlier Botham arrived in Portsmouth from Southampton only to be told his services would not be required .
He then drove 40 kms back to play for the second XI to learn that John Stephenson had dropped out of the Middlesex match in the meantime with a shoulder injury .
Botham dashed back to Portsmouth and took the field as the thrid over began .
Ian Botham began his test career in 1977 by dismissing Australian captain Greg Chappell with a long hop and went on to become his country 's most successful all-rounder ever with 5,200 runs , 383 wickets plus 120 catches in 102 tests .
RUGBY UNION - CARLING LEFT OUT OF ENGLAND TRAINING SQUAD .
LONDON 1996-08-28
Former England captain Will Carling along with Jeremy Guscott , Rory Underwood and Dean Richards have been left out of England 's first training squad of the season .
The quartet , who possess 244 international caps between them , were also omitted from a summer training camp but will still be in contention when the northern international season starts later this year .
" Their qualities are well known to the selectors and they will , of course , be considered when the season gets underway , " the Rugby Football Union said in a statement on Wednesday .
BASEBALL - DODGERS WIN FIFTH STRAIGHT .
MONTREAL 1996-08-28
Hideo Nomo allowed a run in seven innings for his fifth win in seven road starts and Greg Gagne capped a three-run fourth with a two-run homer as the Los Angeles Dodgers claimed a 5-1 victory the Montreal Expos on Tuesday .
With their fifth straight win , the Dodgers moved a half-game ahead of the Expos at the top of the wild card hunt behind Nomo ( 13-10 ) , who allowed six hits and walked four with six strikeouts .
In San Francisco , Mike Williams allowed two runs in 7-1/3 innings and Benito Santiago and Ruben Amaro had RBI hits in the first inning as the Philadelphia Phillies edged the San Francisco Giants 3-2 .
Williams ( 5-12 ) , who snapped a personal three-game losing streak , allowed five hits , walked two and struck out five .
It was also Williams ' first win in three career decisions against San Francisco .
In Pittsburgh , Al Martin 's run-scoring single snapped a fifth-inning tie and Denny Neagle outdueled John Smoltz as the Pittsburgh Pirates edged the Atlanta Braves 3-2 .
The Braves led 2-1 entering the fifth , but the Pirates pushed across two runs against Smoltz ( 20-7 ) .
Neagle ( 14-6 ) beat the Braves for the third time this season , allowing two runs and six hits in eight innings .
In St Louis , Gary Sheffield and Devon White each drove in two runs and Mark Hutton scattered four hits over six innings to lead the Florida Marlins past the St. Louis Cardinals 6-3 .
White added a solo homer , his 11th , off reliever Mark Petkovsek with one out in the fifth , giving the Marlins a 6-0 lead .
In New York , Steve Finley 's three-run homer capped a four-run eighth inning and gave the San Diego Padres a 4-3 victory over New York , spoiling Bobby Valentine 's debut as Mets ' manager .
The rally made a winner out of reliever Willie Blair
Tony Gwynn and Wally Joyner had two hits apiece , helping the Padres to their third straight win .
First-place San Diego has won seven of its last eight games and improved to 34-20 against NL East opponents .
In Houston , Tony Eusebio 's eighth-inning sacrifice fly capped a comeback from a five-run deficit that gave the Houston Astros a 6-5 victory over the Chicago Cubs .
The Astros trailed 5-0 after three innings , but scored three runs in the fourth and one in the sixth before taking the lead in the eighth .
In St Louis , Gary Sheffield and Devon White each drove in two runs and Mark Hutton scattered four hits over six innings to lead the Florida Marlins past the St. Louis Cardinals , 6-3 ,
Sheffield , who was benched Monday , delivered a double down the left-field line in the first , scoring Luis Castilla and Alex Arias to put the Marlins ahead to stay .
At Colorado , Hal Morris and Eric Davis each homered and John Smiley scattered six hits over 6 2/3 innings as the Cincinnati Reds defeated the Colorado Rockies 4-3 , snapping a four-game losing streak .
The Reds took a one-run lead in the second inning when Morris led off with his 10th homer off starter Armando Reynoso ( 8-9 ) .
They increased their bulge to 4-0 in the third when Barry Larkin drew a one-out walk , Kevin Mitchell singled and Davis launched his 22nd homer over the right-field wall .
RUGBY UNION - NEW ZEALAND RECALL MEHRTENS FOR FINAL TEST .
JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-28
The New Zealand rugby selectors recalled fly-half Andrew Mehrtens on Wednesday when they announced their team for the third and final test in Johannesburg on Saturday .
He returns in place of Simon Culhane who broke a wrist in the All Blacks ' series-clinching victory in Pretoria on Saturday .
Mehrtens played in the last TriNations test in Cape Town but missed the first two tests in the current series after tearing a cartilage in his knee while training , an injury which needed a small operation .
Lock Ian Jones and wing Jeff Wilson have also been named in the team despite doubts over their fitness .
Jones has a knee injury while Wilson is suffering from a viral infection .
Blair Larsen or the uncapped Glenn Taylor are on standby to replace Jones and , with Jonah Lomu out of action with a shoulder injury picked up in Tuesday 's drawn match against Griqualand West , Eric Rush is favourite to play should Wilson fail to recover .
Team :
15 - Christian Cullen , 14 - Jeff Wilson , 13 - Walter Little , 12 - Frank Bunce , 11 - Glen Osborne ; 10 - Andrew Mehrtens , 9 - Justin Marshall ; 8 - Zinzan Brooke , 7 - Josh Kronfeld , 6 - Michael Jones , 5 - Ian Jones , 4 - Robin Brooke , 3 - Olo Brown , 2 - Sean Fitzpatrick ( captain ) , 1 - Craig Dowd .
HOCKEY - BONNET TAKES OVER AS SOUTH AFRICAN COACH .
JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-28
Former South African captain Giles Bonnet was named by the South African Hockey Association on Wednesday as the new coach of the men 's national side .
Bonnet , who has been coaching the Kwazulu-Natal provincial team , takes over from Englishman Gavin Featherstone who took South Africa to 10th place in the Olympic Games in Atlanta .
Featherstone , a former Britain captain , has accepted a coaching position with a women 's team in Ireland .
CRICKET - GIBBS GETS INTERNATIONAL CALL UP .
JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-28
Western Province batsman Herschelle Gibbs was the only uncapped player in South Africa 's 14-man squad named on Wednesday for a quadrangular one-day series in Kenya next month .
Kenya , South Africa , Pakistan and Sri Lanka will take part in the series .
National coach Bob Woolmer said Gibbs , 22 , had been rewarded for a tremendous tour of England with the South African A team earlier this year .
" I 've known Herschelle since he was 11 years old and he showed in England how he has matured .
His 170 against the MCC was an innings of supreme class against the best bowling attack we faced all tour , " Woolmer told a news conference .
.
" We were not able to consider Jacques Kallis , Paul Adams and Shaun Pollock due to injury and the replacements have all come from the A tour and it 's great that they are all in form . "
Spin-bowling all-rounders Nicky Boje and Derek Crookes replace Pollock and Adams , while Gibbs comes in for his Western Province colleague Kallis .
Squad : Hansie Cronje ( captain ) , Craig Matthews ( vice-captain ) , Dave Richardson , Brian McMillan , Gary Kirsten , Andrew Hudson , Pat Symcox , Jonty Rhodes , Allan Donald , Fanie de Villiers , Daryll Cullinan , Derek Crookes , Herschelle Gibs , Nicky Boje .
BASKETBALL - OLYMPIAKOS BEAT RED STAR 71-57 .
BELGRADE 1996-08-28
Olympiakos of Greece beat Yugoslavia 's Red Star 71-57 ( halftime 40-34 ) in the first match of an international club basketball tournament on Wednesday .
Partizan ( Yugoslavia ) , Alba ( Germany ) , Dinamo ( Russia ) and Benetton ( Italy ) are also taking part in the event which continues until Saturday .
SOCCER - RUSSIA AND BRAZIL DRAW 2-2 IN FRIENDLY .
MOSCOW 1996-08-28
Russia and Brazil drew 2-2
( halftime 1-0 ) in a friendly soccer international on Wednesday .
Scorers :
Russia - Yuri Nikiforov ( 18th minute ) , Vladislav Rodimov
( 80th )
Brazil - Donizetti ( 47th ) , Ronaldo ( 85th )
Attendence : 20,000
SQUASH - HONG OPEN FIRST ROUND RESULTS .
HONG KONG 1996-08-28
First round results in the Hong
Kong Open on Wednesday ( prefix denotes seeding ) :
2 - Rodney Eyles ( Australia ) beat Zarak Jahan Khan ( Pakistan )
15-6 8-15 15-10 7-15 15-12
4 - Peter Nicol ( Scotland ) beat Julian Wellings ( England ) 15-8
15-7 15-6
Derek Ryan ( Ireland ) beat 5 - Simon Parke ( England ) 15-11 15-11
2-15 15-11
7 - Chris Walker ( England ) beat Julien Bonetat ( France ) 15-12
15-6 15-2
Jonathon Power ( Canada ) beat Ahmed Barada ( Egypt ) 11-15 8-15
15-13 15-11 15-2
Amr Shabana ( Egypt ) beat John White ( Australia ) 10-15 15-9
15-10 16-17 15-1
Paul Johnson ( England ) beat Tony Hands ( England ) 12-15 15-11
7-15 15-6 15-11
Zubair Jahan Khan ( Pakistan ) beat Faheem Khan ( Hong Kong ) 12-15
15-10 15-10 15-10
R
BASKETBALL - FORMULA SHELL WIN GAME ONE IN PHILIPPINES .
MANILA 1996-08-28
Result of game one of the Philippine Basketball Association second conference finals on Tuesday :
Formula Shell beat Alaska Milk 85-82 ( 36-46 )
( Formula Shell leads best-of-seven series 1-0 )
SOCCER - ISRAELI FIRST DIVISION RESULTS .
JERUSALEM 1996-08-28
Results of first division
soccer matches played over the weekend and Tuesday :
Hapoel Kfar Sava 0 Hapoel Zafririm Holon 1
Hapoel Tel Aviv 1 Maccabi Haifa 3
Hapoel Jerusalem 0 Hapoel Petah Tikva 3
Hapoel Ironi Rishon Lezion 3 Hapoel Taibe 1
Hapoel Beit She'an 0 Hapoel Beit She'an 1
Maccabi Petah Tikva 0 Betar Jerusalem 3
Hapoel Haifa 3 Maccabi Tel Aviv 1
Hapoel Beersheva 2 Maccabi Herzliya 0
TENNIS - SELES HAS WALKOVER TO U.S. OPEN THIRD ROUND .
NEW YORK 1996-08-28
Second seed and co-world number one Monica Seles advanced to the third round of the U.S. Open Tennis Championships without hitting a ball on Wednesday .
Seles , the 1991 and 1992 champion who dropped just one game in her opening match , was scheduled to play Laurence Courtois of Belgium Wednesay night .
But tournament officials announced about four-and-a-half hours before the match that Courtois had pulled out due to a left knee bone inflammation , moving Seles into the next round on a walkover .
TENNIS - SERIOUS MEDVEDEV IS HAVING FUN AGAIN .
Richard Finn
NEW YORK 1996-08-28
Outspoken Andrei Medvedev exchanged his reputation as the clown prince of tennis on Wednesday for a new no-nonsense attitude that has made life on the courts fun again .
" I think I 'm much more focused on what I have to do , and that 's playing tennis , " Medvedev said after routing Frenchman Jean-Philippe Fleurian 6-2 6-0 6-1 in the opening round of the U.S. Open .
It was Medvedev 's sixth victory in a row after winning his first tournament of the year last week at the Hamlet Cup .
" I realised this year , that without putting 99.9 percent of your mind into tennis , I do n't think you can successful , " said the 22-year-old Medvedev .
" The whole day I 'm thinking abnout tennis .
I felt that all the other things I was doing the years before , they were distracting me , they were not helping me at all . "
For Medvedev that meant confining his post-match comments to tennis and not going off on tirades about about peripheral issues such as the poor quality of food in the players lounge , an entertaining rant that took his mind off the task at hand .
" I know what I 'm here for , " said Medvedev , who lost in the second round of the Open the last two years after reaching the quarters in 1993 , the same year he tried his hand as a restaurant critic .
" I 'm not here to fight the press or talk about the food or entertain the people off the court .
I 'm here to play tennis and to win .
I have much less fun off the court .
I have much more fun on the court , " he said .
Just three years ago Medvedev was one of the world 's best , with a ranking of six after reaching the French Open semifinal and winning three tournaments .
But Medvedev 's ranking slowly began to drop last year as he struggled with a wrist injury .
The Ukrainian finally hit a low of 44th two months ago .
" It 's somewhere where I would n't like to stay very long , " Medvedev said of his current ranking of 36 . "
It 's a part of the penalty that I have to accept . "
As part of his new businesslike approach , Medvedev hired Australian coach Bob Brett at the start of this year and the partnership is beginning to pay off .
" At the beginning of the year we started from zero , " said Medvedev . "
Winning in Long Island ( last week ) was like winning for the first time . "
While Medvedev 's 77-minute romp past Fleurian was rather ordinary , the fact that the two were playing each other was rather remarkable .
In the original draw , Medvedev and Fleurian were slotted to play each other .
When controversy forced the draw to be done over -- against odds of 151-to-1 -- Medvedev and Fleurian drew each other a second time .
" When I saw the new draw I did n't have to change my preparation , " Medvedev said . "
I think it 's destined that it turned out for me . "
TENNIS - WEDNESDAY 'S RESULTS FROM THE U.S. OPEN .
NEW YORK 1996-08-28
Results of Wednesday 's matches in the U.S. Open Tennis Championships at the National Tennis Centre ( prefix number denotes seeding ) :
Women 's singles , second round
15 - Gabriela Sabatini ( Argentina ) beat Ann Grossman ( U.S. ) 6-2 6 - 3
Irina Spirlea ( Romania ) beat Maria Jose Gaidano ( Argentina ) 6-1 6-2
8 - Lindsay Davenport ( U.S. ) beat Henrietta Nagyova ( Slovakia ) 6- 0 6-4
Anne-Gaelle Sidot ( France ) beat Wang Shi-Ting ( Taiwan ) 6-4 3-6 6-3
Sandrine Testud ( France ) beat Cristina Torrens-Valero ( Spain ) 6 - 2 6-1
Men 's singles , first round
Andrei Medvedev ( Ukraine ) beat Jean-Philippe Fleurian ( France ) 6-2 6-0 6-1
David Nainkin ( South Africa ) beat 9 - Wayne Ferreira ( South Africa ) 6-4 6-4 2-6 7-5
David Rikl ( Czech Republic ) beat Hicham Arazi ( Morocco ) 6-4 7-5 6-2
Andrea Gaudenzi ( Italy ) beat Shuzo Matsuoka ( Japan ) 7-6 ( 7-4 ) 6 - 2 6-3
Men 's singles , first round
17 - Felix Mantilla ( Spain ) beat Fernando Meligeni ( Brazil ) 6-1 6 - 7 ( 2-7 ) 7-6 ( 7-5 ) 6-3
Jonas Bjorkman ( Sweden ) beat Karol Kucera ( Slovakia ) 6-2 5-7 7- 6 ( 7-3 ) 7-5
Jan Kroslak ( Slovakia ) beat Chris Woodruff ( U.S. ) 2-6 6-4 3-6 6 - 2 7-6 ( 7-1 )
Women 's singles , second round
Amanda Coetzer ( South Africa ) beat Mariaan de Swardt ( South Africa ) 6-2 7-5
Linda Wild ( U.S. ) beat Kristie Boogert ( Netherlands ) 5-7 6-3 6-3
Kimberly Po ( U.S. ) beat Kristina Brandi ( U.S. ) 6-1 6-4
Helena Sukova ( Czech Republic ) beat Paola Suarez ( Argentina ) 6- 4 7-6 ( 7-2 )
Women 's singles , second round
2 - Monica Seles ( U.S. ) beat Laurence Courtois ( Belgium ) by walkover ( knee injury )
Dally Randriantefy ( Madagascar ) beat Jane Chi ( U.S. ) 6-3 6-1
Ines Gorrochategui ( Argentina ) beat Aleksandra Olsza ( Poland ) 6 - 1 6-1
Men 's singles , first round
12 - Todd Martin ( U.S. ) beat Younes El Aynaoui ( Morocco ) 6-3 6-2 4-6 6-4
Sjeng Schalken ( Netherlands ) beat Gilbert Schaller ( Austria ) 6- 3 6-4 6-7 ( 6-8 ) 6-3
Men 's singles , first round
Michael Tebbutt ( Australia ) beat Richey Reneberg ( U.S. ) 3-6
6-1 3-6 7-5 6-3
Paul Haarhuis ( Netherlands ) beat Michael Joyce ( U.S ) 6-7
( 5-7 ) 7-6 ( 8-6 ) 1-6 6-2 6-2
Women 's singles , second round
Barbara Rittner ( Germany ) beat 13 - Brenda Schultz-McCarthy (
Netherlands ) 6-2 6-1
Men 's singles , first round
Guy Forget ( France ) beat Grant Stafford ( South Africa ) 3-6 2-6 6-4 7-6 ( 7-2 ) 6-3
( End first round )
Women 's singles , second round
Lisa Raymond ( U.S. ) beat Sarah Pitkowski ( France ) 6-2 6-0
Asa Carlsson ( Sweden ) beat Barbara Schett ( Austria ) 6-2 3-1 retired ( Thigh injury )
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE STANDINGS AFTER TUESDAY 'S GAMES .
NEW YORK 1996-08-28
Major League Baseball
standings after games played on Tuesday ( tabulate under won ,
lost , winning percentage and games behind ) :
AMERICAN LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
NEW YORK 74 57 .565 -
BALTIMORE 70 61 .534 4
BOSTON 68 65 .511 7
TORONTO 62 71 .466 13
DETROIT 47 85 .356 27 1/2
CENTRAL DIVISION
CLEVELAND 79 53 .598 -
CHICAGO 70 64 .522 10
MINNESOTA 66 66 .500 13
MILWAUKEE 64 69 .481 15 1/2
KANSAS CITY 60 73 .451 19 1/2
WESTERN DIVISION
TEXAS 75 57 .568 -
SEATTLE 68 63 .519 6 1/2
OAKLAND 63 72 .467 13 1/2
CALIFORNIA 61 71 .462 14
WEDNESDAY , AUGUST 28TH SCHEDULE
CLEVELAND AT DETROIT
MILWAUKEE AT CHICAGO
OAKLAND AT BALTIMORE
MINNESOTA AT TORONTO
TEXAS AT KANSAS CITY
BOSTON AT CALIFORNIA
NEW YORK AT SEATTLE
NATIONAL LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
ATLANTA 81 49 .623 -
MONTREAL 70 60 .538 11
FLORIDA 62 70 .470 20
NEW YORK 59 73 .447 23
PHILADELPHIA 54 79 .406 28 1/2
CENTRAL DIVISION
HOUSTON 71 62 .534 -
ST LOUIS 69 63 .523 1 1/2
CINCINNATI 65 66 .496 5
CHICAGO 64 65 .496 5
PITTSBURGH 56 75 .427 14
WESTERN DIVISION
SAN DIEGO 73 60 .549 -
LOS ANGELES 71 60 .542 1
COLORADO 69 64 .519 4
SAN FRANCISCO 56 74 .431 15 1/2
WEDNESDAY , AUGUST 28TH SCHEDULE
CINCINNATI AT COLORADO
LOS ANGELES AT MONTREAL
ATLANTA AT PITTSBURGH
SAN DIEGO AT NEW YORK
CHICAGO AT HOUSTON
FLORIDA AT ST LOUIS
PHILADELPHIA AT SAN FRANCISCO
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE RESULTS TUESDAY .
NEW YORK 1996-08-28
Results of Major League
Baseball games played on Tuesday ( home team in CAPS ) :
National League
Philadelphia 3 SAN FRANCISCO 2
Los Angeles 5 MONTREAL 1
PITTSBURGH 3 Atlanta 2
San Diego 4 NEW YORK 3
HOUSTON 6 Chicago 5
Florida 6 ST LOUIS 3
Cincinnati 4 COLORADO 3
American League
Cleveland 12 DETROIT 2
BALTIMORE 3 Oakland 1
Minnesota 6 TORONTO 4
Milwaukee 4 CHICAGO 2
KANSAS CITY 4 Texas 3 ( 10 innings )
Boston 2 CALIFORNIA 1
SEATTLE 7 New York 4
TENNIS - GRAF WORKS HARD FOR FIRST-ROUND WIN .
Bill Berkrot
NEW YORK 1996-08-27
It was n't supposed to be this hard for defending champion Steffi Graf to win her opening match at the U.S. Open on Tuesday night .
But the script that called for the usual first-round demolition by the top-ranked top seed was rewritten by 29th-ranked Indonesian Yayuk Basuki playing with nothing to lose abandon .
Graf , of course , prevailed 6-3 7-6 , but not before some tense moments that even had the German superstar thinking the match was going three sets .
" I won the second set , which I did n't think I would do , being down 5-2 and the chances she had at 6-5 , " Graf recalled .
Several of the other women 's seeds eased into the second round with more typical Graf-like efficiency Tuesday .
As afternoon turned to evening , fourth-seeded Spaniard Conchita Martinez took apart Romanian Ruxandra Dragomir in 58 minutes with the loss of just two games , one more than second seed Monica Seles , who opened the second-day programme by crushing American Anne Miller 6-0 6-1 .
Third seed Arantxa Sanchez Vicario , the 1994 champion , and eighth-seeded Olympic gold medalist Lindsay Davenport dropped three game each en route to the second round .
But the day was not without its seeded casualties on the women 's side .
Fifth-seed Iva Majoli of Croatia was picked off by Austrian Judith Wiesner and Wimbledon semifinalist Kimiko Date of Japan , the 10th seed , fell 6-2 7-5 to 53rd-ranked American Kimberly Po .
Date 's defeat left no other seeded players in Seles 's quarter of the draw , which lost Anke Huber ( 6 ) and Maggie Maleeva ( 12 ) on Monday .
But Graf , winner of 20 Grand Slam titles , was not about to join that list .
" At some points I felt a little nervous , " she admitted . "
When it came down to the important points , I felt more confident . "
Basuki , a first-round loser here for the fifth consecutive year , was clearly going for winners , hitting the lines and running Graf around the court as she broke the top seed twice in the second set to grab that shocking 5-2 lead .
Graf ran off the next three games to restore some semblance of order .
But Basuki , her long black ponytail flying as she raced for shots , held her serve and twice had set point on Graf 's serve at 6-5 before the German unleashed a forehand pass to force the tie-break .
" I lost the moment , " lamented Basuki , who has reached the fourth round at Wimbledon four times and was a semifinalist in Montreal earlier this month .
Still , the feisty Indonesian got off to a 3-0 lead in the tie-breaker before a pair of costly double faults gave Graf her chance to avoid a third set .
" Usually in the first one or two matches , you want to find your rhythm and want to get into it , " said Graf , who won seven of the last eight points in the breaker .
" To be in that situation today , a couple of times having to play well , get down and play point-by-point , definitely is a good start . "
BASEBALL - SOSA HAS SURGERY , OUT UP TO SIX WEEKS .
CHICAGO 1996-08-27
Chicago Cubs right fielder Sammy Sosa underwent surgery on Monday to remove a fractured bone from his right hand and will miss four to six weeks , the club announced Tuesday .
Sosa , a leading candidate for National League Most Valuable Player honours , was injured August 20th when he was hit by a Mark Hutton pitch in the first inning of an 8-1 victory over the Florida Marlins .
The 27-year-old Sosa leads the league with 40 homers and is tied for 10th with 100 RBI .
The loss of Sosa , who appeared in all 124 games this season , is a huge blow to the Cubs ' playoff hopes .
SOCCER - MARCELO HAT-TRICK KEEPS PSV AT TOP OF DUTCH LEAGUE .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-28
Brazilian striker Marcelo scored a hat-trick as PSV Eindhoven maintained their 100 percent record and stayed on top of the Dutch first division with a 3-1 win at Volendam on Wednesday .
PSV 's main rivals for the title , defending champions Ajax Amsterdam , celebrated the novelty of having the roof of their new 51,000 seat stadium closed against the rain , with a 1-0 win over AZ Alkmaar .
Ajax were missing six first-team players but Frank de Boer shot home the winner from a 20-metre free kick in the 30th minute of a dull game .
Marcelo , signed in close season to replace compatriot Ronaldo who left to play for Barcelona , opened the PSV scoring in the 19th minute when he fired home after good work from Rene Eijkelkamp .
The Brazilian found the mark again two minutes after halftime and again in the 56th minute before midfielder Pascal Jongsma scored a consolation goal for Volendam five minutes from time .
Feyenoord Rotterdam suffered an early shock when they went 1-0 down after four minutes against de Graafschap Doetinchem .
The equaliser came in the 73rd minute when Swedish international Henke Larsson scored from close range and 10 minutes later Jean-Paul van Gastel gave Feyenoord a 2-1 victory from the penalty spot .
After three matches PSV lead the first division with nine points , three points clear of fifth-placed Ajax .
SOCCER - ROBSON WINS FIRST TROPHY WITH BARCELONA .
MADRID 1996-08-28
Former England manager Bobby Robson enjoyed his first success in charge of Barcelona as his team weathered 90 minutes of non-stop Atletico Madrid pressure to win the Spanish Super Cup 6-5 on aggregate on Wednesday .
Barcelona had won the first leg 5-2 but the second leg was a different story .
Atletico came within a whisker of taking the Cup on the away-goal rule but squandered several chances after going 3-1 ahead 15 minutes from the end .
Juan Lopez gave Atletico the lead midway through the first half after Barcelona fullback Albert Ferrer and substitute goalkeeper Julen Lopetegui failed to clear a Milinko Pantic cross .
Barcelona 's Hristo Stoichkov made his only significant contribution of the evening 10 minutes after halftime when Sergi Barjuan broke down the right to set up the fiery Bulgarian with a simple equaliser .
But Atletico struck back almost immediately through new signing Juan Eduardo Esnaider and then Serbian set-piece specialist Pantic made it 3-1 with a superb free-kick in the 75th minute .
Robson praised Atletico after the game , which was played in the Community of Madrid athletic stadium because of pitch problems at the Vicente Calderon ground .
The venue of Atletico 's first league game , scheduled for Sunday , is still in doubt with the Real Madrid 's Santiago Bernabeu a distinct possibility .
SOCCER - SUMMARY OF SPANISH SUPER CUP .
MADRID 1996-08-28
Summary of the Spanish Super Cup , second leg , played on Wednesday :
Atletico Madrid 3 ( Juan Lopez 28th minute , Juan Esnaider 58th , Milinko Pantic 75th ) Barcelona 1 ( Hristo Stoichkov 55th ) .
Halftime 1-0 .
Attendance 11,000 .
( Barcelona win 6-5 on aggregate ) .
SOCCER - BARCELONA WIN SPANISH SUPER CUP .
MADRID 1996-08-28
Result of the Spanish Super Cup , second leg , played on Wednesday :
Atletico Madrid 3 Barcelona 1
( Barcelona win 6-5 on aggregate )
SOCCER - AJAX SIGN ARGENTINE STRIKER GABRICH .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-28
Argentine striker Iwan Cesar Gabrich signed a five year contract with Dutch champions Ajax Amsterdam on Wednesday .
The 24-year-old Gabrich , who signed for an undisclosed fee from the Argentine side Newell Old Boys , is set to join Dutch international Patrick Kluivert in the Ajax forward line .
He is Ajax 's sixth new signing this year , joining midfielder Richard Witschge , defenders John Veldman and Mariano Juan and strikers Tijjani Babangida and Dani .
SOCCER - PARMA , ROMA AND UDINESE OUT OF ITALIAN CUP .
ROME 1996-08-28
UEFA Cup hopefuls Parma and Roma , under new coaches this season , crashed out of the Italian Cup to second division opponents on Wednesday while league champions Milan could only draw 1-1 at humble Empoli .
Wealthy Parma , now coached by the former Italian international Carlo Ancelotti , were without new striker Enrico Chiesa and went down 3-1 at serie B club Pescara in their second round clash .
Pescara 's Ottavio Palladini shattered Parma with goals in the second and fourth minutes .
Midfielder Marco Giampaolo made it 3-0 in the 38th minute and Parma 's Alessandro Melli pulled back a late goal six minutes from time .
The second round was the entry point for the bulk of the serie A sides with the winners going through .
The later stages of the cup are played over two legs .
Parma 's defeat was a repeat of last season 's fiasco when they lost their opening cup match 3-0 to Palermo .
Roma , now coached by Argentine Carlos Bianchi and watched by Italian national coach Arrigo Sacchi , lost 3-1 to Cesena -- another repeat of last season when the Rome club also went out at the first hurdle .
Udinese , with Germany 's Euro ' 96 hero Oliver Bierhoff in their lineup , completed the hat-trick of beaten serie A sides when they went under 2-1 to newly relegated Cremonese .
Milan 's new Uruguayan coach Oscar Tabarez avoided the nightmare of defeat but faces a replay at home next Sunday .
Cup holders Fiorentina easily beat Cosenza 3-1 while European Cup holders Juventus also cruised through with a 2-0 win at small southern club Fidelis Andria .
Two other serie A sides lost at the weekend -- Piacenza and last year 's losing finalists Atalanta .
Two cup matches could not be played on Wednesday due to argument over first round results .
Lecce 's 3-0 weekend defeat of Genoa was expected to be overturned by a sporting judge on Thursday after the home club fielded an ineligible player .
That would set Genoa up for a second round match against local rivals Sampdoria .
Nocerina 's 4-3 defeat of Piacenza was also subject to a complaint , later removed , that forced their second round match against serie A newcomers Perugia to be delayed .
SOCCER - BAYERN HIT FOUR TO TAKE BUNDESLIGA TOP SPOT .
BONN 1996-08-28
Goals from Thomas Helmer and Juergen Klinsmann helped Bayern Munich to a 4-2 home win over Bayer Leverkusen on Wednesday and powered them to the top of the Bundesliga .
The comfortable victory gave Bayern 10 points from their first four games , a point ahead of second-placed Stuttgart , who have a game in hand .
Brazilian midfielder Paulo Sergio put Leverkusen ahead in the 25th minute but Alexander Zickler equalised just a minute later .
A header from Helmer and an acrobatic strike from Klinsmann gave Bayern a two-goal cushion at halftime .
But the pick of the 13-times champions ' goals came from Ruggiero Rizzitelli , who beat three defenders to put Bayern 4-1 up .
Markus Feldhoff hit a consolation goal for Leverkusen .
Hansa Rostock brought Cologne 's 100 percent record to an end with a 2-0 win over the Rhineside club while a Sean Dundee hat-trick inside seven minutes stood out in Karlsruhe 's 4-0 demolition of St Pauli .
SOCCER - ITALIAN CUP SECOND ROUND RESULTS .
ROME 1996-08-28
Results of Italian Cup second round
matches played on Wednesday :
Empoli 1 Milan 1
Spal 2 Reggiana 4
Lucchese 1 Vicenza 2
Cremonese 2 Udinese 1
Cesena 3 Roma 1
Bologna 2 Torino 1
Cosenza 1 Fiorentina 3
Avellino 0 Lazio 1
Bari 1 Verona 1
Pescara 3 Parma 1
Monza 0 Napoli 1
Chievo 2 Cagliari 3
Ravenna 0 Inter 1
Fidelis Andria 0 Juventus 2
SOCCER - GERMAN FIRST DIVISION SUMMARIES .
BONN 1996-08-28
Summaries of Wednesday 's German
first division soccer matches :
Karlsruhe 4 ( Keller 18th minute , Dundee 56th 59th and 64th )
St Pauli 0 .
Halftime 1-0 .
Attendance 27,600 .
Bayern Munich 4 ( Zickler 26th , Helmer 37th , Klinsmann 44th ,
Rizzitelli 48th ) Bayer Leverkusen 2 ( Sergio 25th , Feldhoff
54th ) .
3-1 .
48,000 .
Cologne 0 Hansa Rostock 2 ( Akpoborie 5th and 59th ) .
0-1 .
27,000 .
Fortuna Duesseldorf 0 1860 Munich 0 .
11,500 .
Arminia Bielefeld 1 ( Von Heesen 56th ) Duisburg 1 ( Hirsch 65th ) .
0-0 .
15,000 .
SOCCER - LEADING FRENCH LEAGUE SCORERS .
PARIS 1996-08-28
Leading scorers in the French
first division after Wednesday 's matches :
3 - Anton Drobnjak ( Bastia ) , Vladimir Smicer ( Lens ) , Miladin
Becanovic ( Lille ) , Alain Caveglia ( Lyon ) , Xavier Gravelaine
( Marseille ) , Robert Pires ( Metz ) , Thierry Henry ( Monaco )
2 - Christopher Wreh ( Guingamp ) , Marc-Vivien Foe ( Lens ) , Enzo
Scifo ( Monaco ) , James Debbah ( Nice ) , Patrice Loko ( PSG ) ,
Stephane Guivarch ( Rennes )
SOCCER - SMICER 'S LAST-GASP GOAL KEEPS LENS IN THE LEAD .
PARIS 1996-08-28
Euro 96 star Vladimir Smicer of the Czech Republic scored at the last second for Lens , allowing them to retain the lead in the French soccer league on Wednesday .
Smicer pushed the ball home in injury time to lead his team to a 3-2 victory over Montpellier , who were leading 2-1 until Cameroon 's Marc-Vivien Foe equalised on a header in the 85th minute .
The win was the fourth in as many matches this season for Lens , who lead the table on 12 points .
In-form Paris St Germain , who dismissed Nantes 1-0 , are second with 10 points .
Along with Smicer , Robert Pires was the star of the night in France , scoring the first hat-trick of the league season in Metz 's 3-1 home victory over neighbouring Strasbourg .
Pires , one of the most promising strikers in the country , was called up for the first time this week by French manager Aime Jacquet for a friendly against Mexico on Saturday at the Parc des Princes .
Pires scored first with a powerful shot in the 35th minute before striking again from close range just before the break .
A solitary raid allowed him to score his third in the 74th .
Smicer 's goal was as hard-won as his team 's victory .
Spurred by Foe 's leveller five minutes before , Lens pressed hard and Foe hit the crossbar in the dying seconds on another header .
The ball bounced back to Smicer 's feet and he scored .
Montpellier seized an unexpected lead thanks to Kader Ferhaoui in the fourth minute after a blunder from Lens goalkeeper Jean-Claude Nadon .
The side from northern France , forced to fight an uphill battle from then on , pulled level thanks to Tony Vairelles in the eighth minute but young striker Fabien Lefevre made it two for Montpellier five minutes later .
League favourites PSG scored a convincing 1-0 win over Nantes and confirmed they would again be the team to beat this season .
Ironically , PSG 's victory owed a lot to two former Nantes players , striker Patrice Loko , who scored on a brilliant shot in the 33rd minute , and defender Benoit Cauet , who started the one-two which allowed Loko to score .
The Parisians , who have yet to concede a goal , were without Brazil 's Leonardo and Panama 's Julio Cesar Dely Valdes , both called up by their national sides .
For Nantes , who shocked PSG to win the league crown two years ago , the fall is very painful .
The Canaries , who lost most of their key players within two years , have yet to win a match this season .
Reigning champions Auxerre had to settle for a goalless draw against Marseille on Tuesday .
SOCCER - DUTCH FIRST DIVISION SUMMARIES .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-28
Summary of Dutch first division
soccer played on Wednesday :
Willem II Tilburg 1 ( Van Hintum 69th penalty ) RKC Waalijk 2
( Schreuder 39th , Van Arum 76th , 83rd ) .
Halftime 0-1 .
Attendance
6,150 .
Vitesse Arnhem 1 ( Vierklau 85th ) Sparta Rotterdam 1 ( Gerard
de Nooijer 80th ) .
Halftime 0-0 .
Attendance 5,696 .
Utrecht 0 Twente Enschede 0 .
Attendance 9,000 .
Groningen 1 ( Gorre 66th ) Roda JC Kerkrade 1 ( Vurens 3rd )
Halftime 0-1 .
Attendance 10,000 .
Feyenoord 2 ( Larsson 73rd , Van Gastel 83rd penalty ) Graafschap
Doetinchem 1 ( Schultz 4th ) .
Halftime 0-1 .
Attendance 22,434 .
Volendam 1 ( Jongsma 85th ) PSV Eindhoven 3 ( Marcelo 19th , 47th ,
56rd ) .
Halftime 0-1 .
Attendance 6,000 .
Ajax Amsterdam 1 ( Frank de Boer 30th ) AZ Alkmaar 0 .
Halftime
1-0 .
Attendance 48,123 .
Played on Tuesday .
Fortuna Sittard 2 ( Jeffrey 7th , Roest 33rd ) Heerenveen 4
( Korneev 15th , Hansma 24th , Wouden 70th , 90th ) .
Halftime 2-2 .
Attendance 4,000 .
SOCCER - GERMAN FIRST DIVISION RESULTS / STANDINGS .
BONN 1996-08-28
Results of German first division
soccer matches on Wednesday :
Karlsruhe 4 St Pauli 0
Bayern Munich 4 Bayer Leverkusen 2
Cologne 0 Hansa Rostock 2
Fortuna Duesseldorf 0 1860 Munich 0
Arminia Bielefeld 1 Duisburg 1
Standings ( tabulated under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , against , points ) :
Bayern Munich 4 3 1 0 11 4 10
VfB Stuttgart 3 3 0 0 10 1 9
Borussia Dortmund 4 3 0 1 12 6 9
Cologne 4 3 0 1 7 3 9
Karlsruhe 3 2 1 0 9 3 7
Bayer Leverkusen 4 2 0 2 9 8 6
VfL Bochum 4 1 3 0 4 3 6
SV Hamburg 4 2 0 2 7 7 6
Hansa Rostock 4 1 2 1 5 4 5
Werder Bremen 4 1 1 2 5 6 4
Munich 1860 4 1 1 2 3 5 4
St Pauli 4 1 1 2 7 11 4
Fortuna Duesseldorf 4 1 1 2 1 7 4
Arminia Bielefeld 4 0 3 1 3 4 3
Schalke 04 4 0 3 1 5 9 3
Freiburg 4 1 0 3 6 13 3
Borussia Moenchengladbach 4 0 2 2 1 4 2
Duisburg 4 0 1 3 2 9 1
SOCCER - FRENCH LEAGUE SUMMARIES .
PARIS 1996-08-28
Summaries of French first division
matches on Wednesday :
Bastia 0 Lille 0 .
0-0 .
5,000 .
Cannes 0 Monaco 2 ( Henry 26th , 71st ) .
0-1 .
7,000 .
Le Havre 1 ( Samson 24th ) Caen 1 ( Etienne Mendy 4th ) .
1-1 .
12,000 .
Lens 3 ( Vairelles 8th , Foe 85th , Smicer 90th ) Montpellier 2
( Ferhaoui 4th , Lefevre 13th ) .
1-2 .
30,000 .
Lyon 2 ( Caveglia 23rd , Giuly 30th ) Nancy 0 .
2-0 .
15,000 .
Metz 3 ( Pires 35th , 48th , 74th ) Strasbourg 1 ( Rodriguez 56th ) .
1-0 .
14,000 .
Nice 1 ( Chaouch 64th ) Guingamp 2 ( Rouxel 10th , Baret 89th ) .
0-1 .
4,000 .
Paris St Germain 1 ( Loko 33rd ) Nantes 0 .
1-0 .
30,000 .
Rennes 1 ( Guivarch 27th ) Bordeaux 1 ( Colleter 86th ) .
1-0 .
16,000 .
SOCCER - FRENCH LEAGUE STANDINGS .
PARIS 1996-08-28
Standings in the French first
division after Wednesday 's matches ( tabulate under played , won ,
drawn , lost , goals for , against , points ) :
Lens 4 4 0 0 9 3 12
Paris Saint-Germain 4 3 1 0 4 0 10
Bastia 4 2 2 0 4 1 8
Auxerre 4 2 2 0 3 0 8
Monaco 4 2 1 1 7 4 7
Lyon 4 2 1 1 6 4 7
Metz 4 2 1 1 6 4 7
Lille 4 2 1 1 4 3 7
Guingamp 4 2 1 1 4 3 7
Cannes 4 2 1 1 4 4 7
Bordeaux 4 1 3 0 3 2 6
Marseille 4 1 2 1 5 4 5
Rennes 4 1 1 2 5 7 4
Strasbourg 4 1 0 3 2 7 3
Montpellier 4 0 2 2 3 5 2
Le Havre 4 0 2 2 2 4 2
Caen 4 0 2 2 2 6 2
Nice 4 0 1 3 3 7 1
Nantes 4 0 1 3 2 6 1
Nancy 4 0 1 3 2 7 1
SOCCER - FRENCH LEAGUE RESULTS .
PARIS 1996-08-28
French first division soccer
matches on Wednesday :
Paris SG 1 Nantes 0
Lens 3 Montpellier 2
Bastia 0 Lille 0
Cannes 0 Monaco 2
Rennes 1 Bordeaux 1
Lyon 2 Nancy 0
Nice 1 Guingamp 2
Metz 3 Strasbourg 1
Le Havre 1 Caen 1
Played Tuesday :
Auxerre 0 Marseille 0
ATHLETICS - CHRISTIE AND JOHNSON ASKED TO JOIN OWENS ' TRIBUTE .
Adrian Warner
BONN 1996-08-28
Organisers hope to persuade Britain 's former Olympic 100 metres champion Linford Christie to join a " Dream Team " sprint relay in a special tribute to Jesse Owens at Friday 's Berlin grand prix .
Christie , who is retiring from international competition at the end of the season , was not due to compete in the German capital but Berlin promoter Rudi Thiel said : " We are still hopeful of getting him to come . "
Thiel has managed to get most of the Olympic 100 metres champions since 1948 to attend the meeting , which is being held in the stadium where Owens won four gold medals 60 years ago at the Berlin Olympics .
Canada 's Donovan Bailey , the Olympic 100 metres champion and world record holder , and Namibian Frankie Fredericks , the silver medallist at the recent Atlanta Games , have already agreed to run in the 4X100 metres team .
Thiel said on Wednesday that he had also asked Olympic 200 and 400 champion Michael Johnson to run as well as Christie .
" Most of the Olympic champions of the past are coming including Britain 's ( 1980 champion ) Allan Wells .
Christie belongs to them .
It would be great to have him here .
" There is a good offer ....
My minimum would be that he just ran the relay , " he said .
The 36-year-old Briton is still considering the offer and is expected to announce his decision later on Wednesday .
Owens 's widow Ruth is not well enough to attend but a message from her will be read out during the meeting and one of the sprinter 's relatives is expected to attend .
The relay race , which will include squads from Africa , the United States and Europe as well as the Owens ' quartet , will be held at the end of the meeting .
Organisers had hoped to include 1984 and 1988 champion Carl Lewis in the squad but he injured himself in Brussels last Friday .
CRICKET - NEW CAPTAIN TENDULKAR UPSTAGED BY 120 FROM JAYASURIYA .
COLOMBO 1996-08-28
Sachin Tendulkar marked his debut as Indian captain with a patient 110 on Wednesday , but was upstaged by dashing Sri Lankan opener Sanath Jayasuriya whose 120 steered the world champions to a nine-wicket Singer Cup win .
Sri Lanka , playing in front of their home crowd for the first time since winning the World Cup last March , comfortably passed India 's modest 226-5 from 50 overs in 44.2 overs .
The devastating opening pair of Jayasuriya and Romesh Kaluwitharana shared a fine first wicket stand of 129 to the delight of the 25,000 fans .
Jayasuriya , whose first 50 included three sixes and three fours , went on to an unbeaten 120 and the man-of-the-match award .
Kaluwitharana , slow in comparison , was bowled by Tendulkar for 53 , but Aravinda de Silva with 49 not out helped see Sri Lanka home .
Earlier , Tendulkar completed his ninth century in one-day cricket , taking 138 balls to do it before being run out .
The rest of the Indian batting was generally tied down by brilliant fielding and some fairly tight bowling , although ex-captain Mohamed Azharuddin chipped in with 58 , adding 129 with Tendulkar off 28 overs , before being stumped .
The next match in the four-nation tournament is on Friday when Sri Lanka play Australia in a repeat of the World Cup final in Lahore where Sri Lanka won by seven wickets .
CRICKET - SRI LANKA BEAT INDIA BY 9 WICKETS IN ONE-DAY MATCH .
COLOMBO 1996-08-28
Sri Lanka beat India by nine wickets in the second match of the Singer World Series one-day ( 50 overs ) cricket tournament on Monday .
Scores : India 226-5 in 50 overs , Sri Lanka 230-1 in 44.2 overs .
CRICKET - INDIA V SRI LANKA SCOREBOARD .
COLOMBO 1996-08-28
Scoreboard of the second Singer
World Series cricket match between India and Sri Lanka on
Wednesday :
India
A. Jadeja run out 0
S. Tendulkar run out 110
S. Ganguly c de Silva b Dharmasena 16
M. Azharuddin st Kaluwitharana b Jayasuriya 58
V. Kambli run out 18
R. Dravid not out 7
J. Srinath not out 1
Extras ( b-1 lb-3 w-9 nb-3 ) 16
Total ( 5 wickets , 50 overs ) 226
Fall of wickets : 1-4 2-57 3-186 4-217 5-217 .
Did not bat : A. Kumble , N. Mongia , V. Prasad , A. Kapoor .
Bowling : Vass 9-2-35-0 , Pushpakumara 6-0-23-0 , Dharmasena
10-0-59-1 Muralitharan 10-0-42-0 , Jayasuriya 10-1-39-1 , de Silva
5-0-24-0 .
Sri Lanka
S. Jayasuriya not out 120
R. Kaluwitharana b Tendulkar 53
A.de Silva not out 49
Extras ( lb-3 nb-3 w-2 ) 8
Total ( for one wicket - 44.2 overs ) 230
Fall of wicket : 1-129
Did not bat : Arjuna Ranatunga , Asanka Gurusinha , Hashan
Tillekeratne , Roshan Mahanama , Kumara Dharmasena , Chaminda Vaas ,
Muthiah Muralitharan , Ravindra Pushpakumara
Bowling : Kumble 10-1-40-0 , Prasad 6-0-47-0 , Srinath
8-0-33-0 , Tendulkar 6-0-29-1 , Kapoor 10-2-51-0 , Jadeja
2.2-0-13-0 , Ganguly 2-0-14-0
Result : Sri Lanka won by 9 wickets
Man-of-the-Match : Sanath Jayasuriya
CRICKET - INDIA WIN TOSS AND BAT AGAINST SRI LANKA .
COLOMBO 1996-08-28
India won the toss and elected to bat against Sri Lanka in the second day-night limited overs cricket match of the Singer World Series tournament on Wednesday .
Teams :
India - Sachin Tendulkar ( captain ) , Anil Kumble , Ajay Jadeja , Sourav Ganguly , Mohamed Azharuddin , Vinod Kambli , Rahul Dravid , Nayan Mongia , Javagal Srinath , Venkatesh Prasad , Ashish Kapoor .
Sri Lanka - Arjuna Ranatunga ( captain ) , Sanath Jayasuriya , Romesh Kaluwitharana , Asanka Gurusinha , Aravinda de Silva , Hashan Tillekeratne , Roshan Mahanama , Kumara Dharmasena , Chaminda Vaas , Muthiah Muralitharan , Ravindra Pushpakumara .
PRESS DIGEST - ANGOLA - AUG 28 .
LUANDA 1996-08-28
These are the leading stories in the Angolan press on Wednesday .
Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy .
JORNAL DE ANGOLA
- Princeton Lyman , the U.S. Under-Secretary of State for International Organisations , will on Wednesday continue his work in Angola visiting Bailundo , where he should be received by Jonas Savimbi , leader of Unita .
On Tuesday Lyman participated in a meeting of a joint-commission where he considered that the Angolan politicians should advance faster and find a way to cooperate .
In his opinion the quartering of Unita forces must be concluded in all the Angolan territory and the troops must be selected and integrated in the armed forces , the government forces must be concentrated in the principal units and the free circulation of people and goods must be reality in all the country .
S.AFRICAN TRUTH BODY TO SUMMON APARTHEID POLICE .
CAPE TOWN 1996-08-28
South Africa 's Truth and Reconciliation Commission said on Wednesday it would subpoena persons accused of human rights violations to appear before it .
" We can subpoena anyone we want to , even the president of the country , " spokesman John Allen told Reuters . "
Subpoenas are due to be served on a number of people this week . "
Media reports have speculated that the commission , which is trying to heal the wounds of apartheid by confronting the past , could subpoena apartheid-era President P.W. Botha and former police generals Basie Smit and Johan Van Der Merwe .
In submissions last week to the commission National Party leader and former president F.W. De Klerk said he had received no co-operation from Botha in compiling his party 's report .
Since it began work in April the commission has been hearing harrowing tales from the victims of apartheid-era abuses , by both the white minority regime and its opponents .
It also wants to hear from those who committed the abuses , to whom it can offer amnesty in return for frankness .
Hopes that reformed perpetrators would come forward voluntarily have faded but the commission has the legal power to force them to appear .
Allen declined to give say who would be subpoenaed .
" At the moment we have a preliminary list of less than 10 people , but this is just the beginning , " he said .
The commission was set up last year to probe 30 years of human-rights violations during the apartheid era .
It is chaired by Nobel Peace winner , retired Archbishop Desmond Tutu .
Allen said the commission could announce the names of subpoenaed persons on Monday next week .
TURKISH AIRPLANE LANDS IN SOFIA ON BOMB THREAT .
SOFIA 1996-08-28
A Turkish airliner on flight from Istanbul to Vienna on Wednesday landed in emergency at Sofia airport after receiving a bomb threat , said an airport official .
" The plane landed at Sofia airport at 1503 ( 1203 GMT ) after receiving a signal that there is an explosive on board , " the official , who declined to be named told Reuters .
The plane , surrounded by 11 fire-engines , is being checked for explosives at the moment .
Nothing has been found so far , added the official .
In March a Turkish Cypriot airliner hijacked while on a flight from northern Cyprus to Istanbul landed in Sofia airport to refuel before landing in Munich , where the hijacker was arrested .
Arch Alberta well tests 1,100 bbl / day .
FORT WORTH , Texas 1996-08-28
Arch Petroleum Inc said Wednesday an exploratory well in Alberta 's Morinville area tested in excess of 1,100 barrels daily and will begin production immediately .
The company said the 90 percent owned Trax et al Morinville 10-23 logged 28 feet of productive Leduc Reef at 5,350 feet .
Reserve estimates from this well are at 250,000 gross barrels of oil .
The Trax well is one of the prospects developed by Arch through its early 1996 purchase of Trax Petroleums Ltd , the company said .
It said another , the Cometra et al Morinville 11-13 , has logged 128 feet of productive Leduc Reef at 5,400 feet and is flowing water free at the rate of 590 barrels of oil per day on a 15 / 64ths-inch choke .
Arch owns a 16 percent working interest in this well with most of the rest held by the privately owned operator .
Arch said full production has begun and initial estimates of gross reserves attributable to this well range up to one million barrels of oil .
A third well drilled in this area , the Trax et al Morinville 2-25 , encountered the Leduc Reef but tested wet .
At the company 's Nordegg prospect , the Apache et al Saunders 14-28 , has reached total depth in the Leduc Reef at approximately 3,800 feet and has been abandoned , Arch said .
It said this acreage earning well brought an interest in an additional 5,120 acres , building the company 's gross land position in this area to 8,320 acres .
At the Butte prospect , the Garrington 4-8 has reached total depth of 11,500 and has logged 278 feet of Leduc Reef .
Testing has begun and results will be announced within the next several days , Arch said .
Including the costs of the two abandoned wells , the company said , these first prospects have added to reserves at a finding cost of about U.S. $ 2 per barrel of oil equivalent .
-- Jim Brumm 212-859-1710 .
U.S. judge orders Biogen , Berlex officials deposed .
Leslie Gevirtz
BOSTON 1996-08-28
In order to help him decide whether he should hear the case , a U.S. District Court judge Wednesday ordered the legal counsels of Biogen Inc and Berlex Laboratories , a subsidiary of Schering AG , deposed .
The tempest beyond the test tube involves allegations that the U.S. Food and Drug Administration violated the Orphan Drug law by allowing Biogen the right to sell its multiple sclerosis drug Avonex .
Berlex also charges that Avonex is so similar to its MS drug , Betaseron , that it is a patent infringement .
Both drugs are types of interferon .
One analyst said sales of Avonex had already cut into Betaseron market share .
BioVest Research , Inc 's analyst Eddie Hedaya said , " Berlex sales are losing share like mad ...
my understanding of the marketplace is that they 're below expectations . "
He added Chiron Corp reported its sales of inventory to Berlex was down .
Chiron makes Betaseron ; Berlex markets it , he said .
Biogen , in its Securities and Exchange Commission quarterly report for the period ending June 30 , said it had earned $ 6.1 million from Avonex sales during the drugs first six weeks on the market .
When it approved Avonex in May , the FDA said both Biogen 's product and Betaseron were developed under the incentives of the Ophran Drug Act which provides seven years of marketing exclusivity for products that treat rare diseases .
Avonex " has been allowed to enter the market because it differs from interferon beta-1b ( Betaseron ) ..
. "
the FDA said .
Now , U.S. District Judge Mark Wolf has ordered the chief counsel for Biogen , Michael Astrue , and Robert Chabora , his counterpart at Berlex be deposed about a May 21 meeting the two men attended to help him determine whether the lawsuit filed by Biogen against Berlex should be heard in Massachusetts .
Berlex filed a lawsuit against Biogen in U.S. District Court in Newark , N.J. in July , but Biogen had already filed a suit against Berlex in Massachusetts in May .
Wolf ordered the depositions to determine if he or U.S. District Judge John Bissell of Newark should preside over the case .
U.S. Treasury balances at Fed rose on Aug 27 .
WASHINGTON 1996-08-28
U.S. Treasury balances at Federal Reserve based on Treasury Department 's latest budget statement .
( BILLIONS OF DLRS )
Aug 27 Aug 26
Fed acct 5.208 4.425
Tax / loan note acct 14.828 15.687
Cash balance 20.036 20.112
---
Total public debt ,
subject to limit 5,124.053 5,122.084
COMEX copper ends higher after late recovery .
NEW YORK 1996-08-28
COMEX copper ended higher after a late , modest recovery dragged the market from the lows , but traders shrugged-off an imminent strike at Codelco 's Salvador mine in Chile .
The market was also waiting for Friday 's LME stock report which will include figures delayed from Tuesday because of the U.K. public holiday on Monday when the LME was closed .
" We are in the late stages of the weaker period of the market , and as we get to the post Labor Day market we will start to see more consumer interest and the demand side of the market will start to firm prices up , " said William O'Neill of Merrill Lynch .
December COMEX settled 0.35 cent higher at 90.20 cents , traded 90.50 to 89.40 cents .
September went out 0.05 cent lower at 91.05 .
The August contract expired at 0.85 cent down at 90.85 cents .
Volume was estimated at 8,000 lots .
Workers at Salvador voted to strike from Saturday , and it was not clear when further talks between the unions and management would take place .
" Salvador is a small facility , and the prospects are that if there will be a strike , it will not be a long strike , " O'Neill said .
-- Huw Jones , New York Commodities 212-859-1646
U.S. copper service center shipments stable - CBSA .
NEW YORK 1996-08-28
Average daily shipments from U.S. copper service centers in July fell three percent from the previous month , but were higher than in July 1995 , the Copper and Brass Servicenter Association reported .
" July was still above the historic average for that month , " the CBSA said .
In the first seven months of 1996 , shipments of copper sheet , coil and strip were 2.2 percent ahead of the same period last year .
Alloy shipments , however , were 7.5 percent down .
" Several service centers indicated that while their volume of orders remains constant , the size-per-order continues to be smaller than what was realised during the first five months of the year , " the CBSA said .
Service centers continued to lower their inventories in July when total copper stocks were off two percent and alloy products down 1.9 percent .
-- New York Commodities 212-859-1646
Harleysville Group ups qrtly dividenD .
HARLEYSVILLE , Pa .
1996-08-28
Quarterly
Latest Prior
Amount $ 0.21 $ 0.19
Pay Sept 30
Record Sept 16
Chile 's ENAP buys Oriente , Escravos crude for Oct .
NEW YORK 1996-08-28
Chile 's state oil company Empresa Nacional del Petroleo ( ENAP ) bought a second spot cargo of Oriente and nearly one million barrels of Escravos in a recent tender , traders said Wednesday .
A 400,000 barrel cargo of Ecuadorian Oriente and 960,000 barrels of Nigerian Escravos was awarded in a tender for Oct 15-18 late last week , but price information remains vague .
" The Oriente will be supplied by the same seller at a small premium to formula , " a trade source said , referring to the first October cargo sold two weeks ago at Petroecuador 's sale formula plus five cents fob .
Escravos was sold on a Dated Brent related basis , with premiums for the light grade seen in the low 50-cent range .
The next purchase tender from ENAP is expected for late October or early November crude , traders said .
-- Jacqueline Wong , New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1620
Reuters historical calendar - September 4 .
LONDON 1996-08-28
Following are some of the major events to have occurred on September 4 in history .
1241 - Alexander III , King of Scotland , born .
King from 1249-1286 , he consolidated royal power , leaving Scotland united and independent .
1260 - The Ghibellines retook the city of Florence from the Florentine Guelfs at the battle of Monte Aperto .
1768 - Francois-Rene ( Vicomte de ) Chateaubriand born .
He was a politician , one of the first French romantic writers and ambassador to the British court .
He wrote " Rene " , a seminal work in the French romantic movement and a famous autobiography " Memoires d'Outre Tombe " .
1781 - Los Angeles was founded by Spanish settlers and named " El Pueblo de Nuestra Senora La Reina de Los Angeles " ( The Town of Our Lady the Queen of the Angels ) .
1824 - Anton Bruckner born .
Austrian composer and organist , he wrote nine symphonies on a huge scale and three grand masses in the romantic tradition .
1870 - In France , the Second Empire was ended and Napoleon III was deposed after his surrender two days earlier in the Franco-Prussian war .
1886 - At Skeleton Canyon in Arizona , Geronimo , Apache chief and leader of the last great Red Indian rebellion finally surrendered to General Nelson Miles .
1892 - Prolific French modernist composer Darius Milhaud born .
He wrote a jazz ballet " La Creation du Monde " and scores for many films including an early version of " Madame Bovary " .
1906 - German-born U.S. biologist Max Delbruck born .
Winner of the 1969 Nobel Prize for physiology or medicine for work on the genetic structure of viruses that infect bacteria .
1907 - Edvard Grieg , Norwegian composer best known for his " Peer Gynt Suite " and his Piano Concerto , died in Bergen .
1908 - U.S. film director Edward Dmytryk born .
Best known for his films " Crossfire " - one of Hollywood 's first attempts to deal with racial discrimination and " Farewell My lovely " .
1909 - The world 's first Boy Scout Rally was held at Crystal Palace near London .
1944 - Brussels and Antwerp in Belgium were liberated by British and Canadian troops in World War Two .
1948 - Wilhelmina , Queen of the Netherlands from 1890 and throughout World Wars One and Two abdicated in favour of her daughter Juliana .
1963 - Robert Schuman , French statesman , Prime Minister 1947-48 and Foreign Minister 1948-52 , died .
He was responsible for the establishment of the European Coal and Steel Community .
1964 - The Forth Road Bridge in Scotland , measuring 6156 ft , and with a centre span of 3300 ft , was opened by Her Majesty the Queen .
1965 - Albert Schweitzer , theologian , philosopher and organist died in Gabon where he had set up a hospital in 1913 .
Acclaimed for his interpretations of J.S. Bach 's works , he also won the Nobel Peace Prize for his efforts on behalf of the " Brotherhood of Nations " in 1952 .
1972 - At the Olympic Games , U.S. swimmer Mark Spitz won his seventh gold medal , a record for a single Olympiad .
1974 - East Germany and the United States established formal diplomatic relations for the first time .
1977 - E.F. ( Fritz ) Schumacher , economic guru and author of the best seller " Small is Beautiful " , died on his way to a conference in Switzerland .
1989 - Georges Simenon , writer of 84 books based on the detective character Inspector Maigret , died .
1992 - Bulgaria 's former Communist leader Todor Zhivkov , deposed in 1989 , was sentenced to seven years in prison after being found guilty of embezzling state funds .
1995 - Declaring " united Jerusalem is ours " , Israel launched a 15-month celebration of the 3,000th anniversary of King David 's proclamation of the city as the capital of the Jewish people .
1995 - The Fourth World Conference on Women , the biggest U.N. gathering in history , began in China 's Great Hall of the People with a U.N. declaration that sexual equality was the last great project of the 20th century .
UK lowers noise limits for three London airports .
LONDON 1996-08-28
The British government on Wednesday lowered the noise limits for London 's Heathrow , Gatwick and Stansted airports and announced it would make a bigger effort in detecting and fining violators .
The limits , effective from January 1 , 1997 , are reduced as much as possible while still complying with international obligations , a spokesman for the Department of Transport said .
The maximum noise level during the day is trimmed by three decibels to 94 , while the night time level is reduced by two decibels to 87 .
" It is a smaller reduction in terms of loudness than was sought by local people .
Nevertheless I am satisfied that the overall benefits will be worthwile , " Lord Goschen , minister for aviation , said in a statement .
The ministry said it believed the new limits could be met with existing aircraft . "
They can be flown in quieter ways , " a spokesman said .
The reduction in noise levels is the same as proposed in a consultation paper which was published in October 1995 .
The present noise levels have applied at Heathrow , one of the world 's busiest airports , since 1959 and at Gatwick since 1968 .
The number of monitors will be increased and some will be repositioned to detect noisy planes .
-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717
Tennis - Philippoussis beats Woodforde in U.S. Open .
NEW YORK 1996-08-27
Mark Philippoussis beat fellow Australian Mark Woodforde 6-7 ( 6-8 ) 6-3 6-3 6-3 in a men 's singles first round match at the U.S. Open on Tuesday .
The two Davis Cup team-mates were pitted against each other after last week 's controversial redraw of the men 's singles competition .
Philippoussis is on course for a third round meeting with world number one Pete Sampras of the United States , whom he beat at the Australian Open last January .
-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800
Rugby union-England given final chance to stay in Five Nations .
LONDON 1996-08-28
England have been given a final chance to remain in the Five Nations ' championship despite striking an exclusive television deal with Rupert Murdoch 's Sky television .
In a statement on Wednesday , the Four Nations TV Committee said dates had been set for a competition involving Scotland , Wales , Ireland and France next year .
" Between now and then , discussions will take place in one final attempt to persuade the Rugby Football Union to save the Five Nations ' championship in its current form , " the statement said .
No further details were immediately available .
England infuriated their championship colleagues when they decided to sign a 87.5 million pounds sterling ( $ 135.8 million ) deal giving Sky television exclusive rights to rugby union matches in England .
The present contract with the British Broadcasting Corporation was shared between the four home nations while France have their own television deal .
Last month Five Nations ' committee chairman Tom Kiernan said England would be thrown out of the competition " unless circumstances change in the near future " .
Cricket - NZ face tough schedule at home and abroad .
WELLINGTON 1996-08-28
World Cup cricket champions Sri Lanka will play two tests and three one-day internationals in a tour of New Zealand next March , officials said on Wednesday .
New Zealand Cricket said the Sri Lankans would play tests in Hamilton and Wellington and one-dayers in Auckland , Christchurch and Dunedin , following hard on the heels of a tour by England .
New Zealand will also line up against Sri Lanka and Pakistan this November in a one-day champions trophy competition in Sharjah .
The team will go one to tour Pakistan , playing two tests and three one-day internationals .
Soccer - Burundi disqualification from African Cup confirmed .
CAIRO 1996-08-28
The African Football Confederation ( CAF ) on Wednesday formally confirmed Burundi 's disqualification from the African Nations Cup following the team 's inability to travel for a qualifier against Central African Republic .
The Burundi team were unable to leave their troubled country for a preliminary round first leg match in Bangui earlier this month because of an air ban imposed in a recent set of internationally-sponsored sanctions .
The Central African Republic qualified on a walkover to play in group four with Guinea , Sierra Leone and Tunisia .
" After examining the dossier of the Burundi-Central Africa match , we decided ...
to disqualify the national team of Burundi from the 21st African Cup of Nations ...
as a result of the absence of this team from the match , " CAF said in a statement .
Cricket - India 226-5 in 50 overs v Sri Lanka .
COLOMBO 1996-08-28
India scored 226 for five wickets in their 50 overs against Sri Lanka in the second day-night limited overs match of the Singer World Series tournament on Wednesday .
Canada fast-tracks Chinese asylum-seekers - report .
VANCOUVER , British Columbia 1996-08-28
Canada is fast-tracking immigration applications from Chinese dissidents in Hong Kong before the British colony reverts to China 's control next year , the Vancouver Sun reported on Wednesday .
The applications are being " fast-tracked in the sense that we are processing them and the ones who have been referred to us have been interviewed , " the newspaper quoted Garrett Lambert , Canada 's high commissioner in Hong Kong , as saying .
" A small number already have preliminary indications as to what the disposition of their cases are and so I suppose in that sense , I guess we have given them some preferential treatment , " Lambert said .
He declined to say how many people were being considered for asylum .
Canada 's ministry of foreign affairs in Ottawa had no immediate comment on the report .
About 80 Chinese dissidents are believed to be living in exile in Hong Kong .
Their fate after the territory reverts to Chinese rule is unclear .
Britain hands Hong Kong back to China at midnight on June 30 , 1997 , after 150 years of colonial rule .
Canada 's Minister of Foreign Affairs Lloyd Axworthy said after meeting Hong Kong Gov .
Chris Patten last month that Canada may grant asylum to dissidents who have fled to Hong Kong from China .
Chinese officials have said such dissidents may not become Hong Kong permanent residents since they entered the territory illegally but have also said their status would be decided by the post-1997 local Hong Kong administration .
Ivorian journalist held , asked to reveal source .
ABIDJAN 1996-08-28
An Ivorian journalist spent a third day in custody on Wednesday and investigators were demanding that he reveal the source of an official document published in his newspaper , colleagues said .
Raphael Lapke , publication director of Ivorian newspaper Le Populaire , was taken in for questioning on Monday over an article about the public prosecutor and has been detained since then .
Colleagues said he had been charged with theft of administrative documents . "
He is being asked for the source of his information and who gave him this confidential document , " one colleague told Reuters .
Three journalists from the Ivorian opposition daily La Voie are serving two-year prison terms for insulting President Henri Konan Bedie .
A court sentenced two in December and the third in January .
La Voie published an article suggesting the presence of Bedie had brought local team ASEC bad luck during their defeat by Orlando Pirates of South Africa in the final of the African Champions Cup in December .
The United States embassy in Abidjan and international press organisations denounced the sentences as excessive .
Last year , Bedie pardoned four journalists jailed for the same or similar offences .
They included one of the three La Voie journalists .
Bedie pardoned two other journalists jailed for incitement to disturb public order .
Village attack kills 38 in eastern Sierra Leone .
FREETOWN 1996-08-28
Sierra Leonean rebels killed 31 villagers and seven soldiers in an attack on the eastern village of Foindu , Eastern Region Brigade Commander Major Fallah Sewa said on Wednesday .
Sewa said the rebels overran Foindu despite the presence of government troops in the village on the highway between Mano Junction and the diamond town of Tongo Field .
An army spokesman in Freetown said Monday night 's attack was the third on a military post in the past week .
Rebels of the Revolutionary United Front agreed a ceasefire in April .
Continuing attacks are generally ascribed to renegade soldiers or uncontrolled bands of rebels and refugees displaced by the fighting starting to return to their homes .
Peace talks in Ivory Coast began in February .
Diplomats say they are deadlocked over the RUF 's insistence that foreign troops helping the government army should leave , and that they should have some say in the allocation of budget spending .
Aid agency says Sudan missionaries released .
NAIROBI 1996-08-28
An aid agency said six Roman Catholic missionaries , including three Australian nuns , were freed by rebels in southern Sudan on Wednesday after being held for nearly two weeks .
But Catholic church officials said they had no confirmation of the report and would have to wait until Thursday to be sure .
Zambia 's Chiluba shuffles cabinet to fill vacancy .
LUSAKA 1996-08-28
Zambian President Frederick Chiluba shuffled his cabinet on Wednesday to fill a vacancy left after the sacking of Legal Affairs Minister Remmy Mushota .
Mushota was fired a month ago after a government tribunal found he tried to withdraw cash from state coffers without authority .
The president 's office said in a statement that Lands Minister Luminzu Shimaponda had been appointed Legal Affairs Minister , while Deputy Foreign Minister Peter Machungwa would take over from Shimaponda .
Guinea launches war on fictitious civil servants .
CONAKRY 1996-08-28
Guinea launched a drive on Wednesday to rid the civil service payroll of fictitious workers as part of new prime minister Sidia Toure 's campaign to cut government spending .
Deputy Minister for Finance Ousmane Kaba said teams of inspectors would check government offices in the capital and the provinces to root out civil servants who drew salaries but had left their jobs , were dead , or had never existed .
Some 50 million Guinean francs ( $ 50,000 ) has been pumped into the exercise to deter the inspectors from taking bribes .
Kaba told reporters the annual wage bill of 171 billion Guinean francs represented 50 percent of current state expenditure , " whereas the acceptable proportion in countries similar to ours is one third " .
Toure , who took office last month , has said he plans to cut public service spending by 30 percent by the end of the year as part of measures to revive the economy .
Guinea is rich in minerals and has a vast potential for hydroelectric power generation but it faces stiff competition from its West African neighbours for foreign investment .
President Lansana Conte appointed Toure , a former senior civil servant in Ivory Coast , last month to clean up the administration and reform the economy following February 's bloody army revolt .
( $ =1,000 Guinean francs )
New Liberia Council chief to be installed Tuesday .
MONROVIA 1996-08-28
Ruth Perry , the woman with the task of uniting Liberia 's squabbling factions around the latest peace plan , will be formally installed as head of the ruling State Council next Tuesday , a Council statement said .
Perry , a Liberian Senate member during the 1980s , returned to Monrovia on August 22 after West African leaders nominated her for the job under a peace deal signed in Nigeria 's capital Abuja five days earlier .
The formal inauguration had been due to take place this week but was put back .
There was no official explanation but politicians said faction leaders and State Council vice-chairmen Charles Taylor and Alhadji Kromah were unable to attend because they were travelling .
Liberia 's civil war , launched by Taylor in 1989 , has killed well over 150,000 people .
Faction fighting and an orgy of looting in the capital Monrovia in April and May killed hundreds of people .
Over a dozen peace deals have collapsed .
The latest sets a timetable for disarmament by the end of January and elections by May 30 .
West African leaders have threatened individual sanctions against faction leaders to ensure compliance .
Freed American slaves founded Liberia in 1847 .
Nigeria rights group says four academics arrested .
LAGOS 1996-08-28
A Nigerian human rights group said on Wednesday that four members of a recently banned university union had been arrested .
" The Constitutional Rights Project ( CRP ) believes that William Istafanus , Elisha Shamay , O.K. Likkason and Jerome Egurugbe were arrested because of their role in the ongoing ASUU ( Academic Staff Union of Universities ) strike , " the group said in a statement .
The CRP said the four were arrested on Monday night at the northeastern Tafawa Balewa University .
The main academic union , ASUU , along with two smaller university unions , was banned by Nigeria 's military government last week , because of a four-month strike by teachers for better working conditions .
Nigeria is under fire from many Western countries for human rights abuses and lack of democracy .
Dozens of people opposed to the government are in detention .
Commonwealth foreign ministers are to meet in London on Wednesday to discuss what action to take , after a visit to Nigeria was called off when the government imposed strict rules on whom the mission would be allowed to see .
Nigeria was suspended from the club of Britain and its former colonies in November after the hanging of nine minority rights activists for murder in spite of international pleas for clemency .
Dutroux suspected in murder of Slovak woman .
Peter Laca
BRATISLAVA 1996-08-28
Marc Dutroux , the chief accused in a Belgian child murder and sex abuse scandal , is suspected of murdering a young Slovak woman , the Slovak office of Interpol said on Wednesday .
Rudolf Gajdos , head of Slovak Interpol , told a news conference Dutroux was also believed to have planned the kidnapping of at least one Slovak woman .
" One of the police versions in the case of the murder of young gypsy woman in Topolcany , western Slovakia , this July , is a suspicion that Mark Dutroux could have been involved in the murder , " Gajdos said without elaborating on the age of the victim and on the other versions .
Slovak police , Interpol , and Belgian police have been following leads on Dutroux 's activities in Slovakia and the neighbouring Czech Republic where he is known to have made frequent visits .
Gajdos said the police sketch of the suspected murderer was " 60 percent identical with Dutroux 's portrait " , and that Dutroux was known to have been in Topolcany around the time of the woman 's murder .
" Topolcany and the area around this town were reported to have been the most visited places by Dutroux and his accomplices in Slovakia , " Gajdos said .
Dutroux , a convicted child rapist and unemployed father-of-three , led police 11 days ago to the bodies of eight-year-olds Julie Lejeune and Melissa Russo in the garden of another of the six houses he owns around the southern Belgian city of Charleroi .
" The Belgian police also informed us that Dutroux , together with one other man , had ( also ) planned the kidnapping of at least one Slovak woman , " Gajdos said .
" The plan apparently failed due to difficulties in crossing the border , " he added , but did not elaborate .
The Slovak police are also investigating visits by about 10 Slovak women , aged 17 to 22 , to Belgium , at the invitation of Dutroux .
The women said they went to Belgium voluntarily and police suspect they were used to act in pornographic films , Gajdos said earlier this week .
But he added they had difficulty remembering what happened during their visits to Belgium , perhaps because of drugs , and were unsure whether they were filmed for pornography .
Dutroux , 39 , who was charged last week with the abduction and illegal imprisonment of two girls aged 14 and 12 , is also suspected in the disappearance of Belgians An Marchal , 19 , and Eefje Lambrecks , 17 , who went missing a year ago .
Knifeman kills Polish beauty queen , wounds husband .
WARSAW 1996-08-28
A man knifed to death international model Agnieszka Kotlarska outside her home in Wroclaw , western Poland , Polish television said on Wednesday .
The man , who said he had once been engaged to her , first knifed Kotlarska 's husband in the leg , then stabbed her three times in the chest when she tried to intervene during the incident on Tuesday .
She died in hospital .
Kotlarska , who was 24 and had a three-year-old child , was Miss Poland in 1991 and went on to a U.S.-based modelling career that included working with Italian designer Gianni Versace and Vogue magazine , the Gazeta Wyborcza newspaper said .
She had been due to fly on a TWA airliner which exploded near New York last month , but had cancelled her booking , the newspaper said .
Her attacker , identified only as Jerzy L. , 36 , was arrested by police and will appear in court on Thursday morning , television reported .
It said he had admitted the attack but had denied intending to kill Kotlarska .
Russian shares slip in thin volume .
MOSCOW 1996-08-28
Leading Russian shares edged down on Wednesday in thin volume in the absence of Western orders , traders said .
The Russian Trading System index of 21 issues fell 1.64 percent to 180.38 on volume of $ 4.38 million .
" The market was extremely quiet today , some profit-taking locally , no Western orders , " said Nick Mokhoff , director of sales and trade at Alliance-Menatep . "
We are just a bit lower with a lot of inactivity during the whole day . "
Alexander Babayan , managing director at CentrInvest Securities , said the volume of orders was four to five times lower than a week ago .
As often , the most volume was in UES .
" Unified is one of the blue chips , which has more prospects than anybody else does , because they have ADRs supposedly coming up , " Mokhoff said .
UES officials said last week the board had not yet approved the final version of its application to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission to issue ADRs .
UES fell to $ 0.0817 from $ 0.0822 at Tuesday 's close with 8.90 million shares changing hands .
Gazprom was the loser of the day with prices closing at $ 0.300 , down from $ 0.355 on Tuesday and $ 0.445 on Monday .
Mokhoff said uncertainty about when Gazprom would issue ADRs and about whether shares from the Russian market could be converted into ADRs had hurt prices .
" Western investors ... will be investing in ADRs and I do not think people in Russia will be able to come up with the money for the underlying shares to drive the Russian shares to those levels , " Mokhoff said .
Gazprom has also tightened the rules restricting shareholers ' rights to trade its shares .
Mosenergo closed at at $ 0.958 after $ 0.966 , Rostelekom fell to $ 2.56 from $ 2.58 and LUKoil was $ 9.82 after $ 9.85 .
-- Julie Tolkacheva , Moscow Newsroom , +7095 941 8520
Albania asks Greece to explain deportations .
TIRANA 1996-08-28
Albania asked Greece on Wednesday to explain why it was deporting more Albanian immigrants , Foreign Minister Tritan Shehu said .
The Albanian daily Koha Jone reported earlier that Greece had deported about 5,000 Albanians in the last five days .
" The Foreign Ministry is trying to find out from the Greek embassy why Albanian refugees have been deported from Greece , " Shehu told Reuters .
Athens and Tirana signed an accord in May to legalise the status of Albanian immigrant workers , estimated at 350,000 , and remove a long-standing stumbling block in relations between the two Balkan neighbours .
Bulgarians recover 75 pct of confiscated land .
SOFIA 1996-08-28
Bulgaria has restored ownership rights to pre-communist private owners of 75 percent of the arable land or around four million hectares , an Agriculture Ministry official said on Wednesday .
" So far 75 percent has been returned with the land restitution almost completed in some regions like Southeastern Bulgaria but lagging behind in other areas , predominantly in the mountains , " the official told a news conference .
The ministry has said that it planned to return 96.6 percent of the arable land or 5.2 million hectares to its original owners by the end of this year .
A land reform act passed four years ago abolished Soviet-style collective farms , allowing the return of 5.4 million hectares to original owners or their heirs .
-- Sofia Newsroom , ( ++359-2 ) 981 8569
German chancellor to meet Yeltsin Sept 7 - Interfax .
MOSCOW 1996-08-28
German Chancellor Helmut Kohl , who spoke to President Boris Yeltsin by telephone on Wednesday , plans a trip to Moscow on September 7 and will visit Yeltsin at his vacation home near Moscow , Interfax news agency said .
Interfax , quoting Yeltsin press secretary Sergei Yastrzhembsky , said Yeltsin and Kohl had discussed bilateral relations and international issues on the telephone .
Yeltsin had told Kohl about efforts to find a political solution to the conflict in Russia 's breakaway Chechnya region , Interfax added .
Yeltsin , who left on vacation on Monday , is staying at an exclusive private hunting lodge some 100 km ( 60 miles ) from Moscow .
Germany has been one of the loudest critics of Russia 's military intervention in Chechnya , a 20-month-old conflict in which tens of thousands of people have been killed .
Exiled Bosnians protest confusing voting rules .
Duncan Shiels
NAGYATAD , Hungary 1996-08-28
Bosnian refugees in Hungary , the first to vote last weekend in their country 's first post-war election , found the rules confusing and some had no idea who they voted for , refugees and officials said on Wednesday .
" For the most part they really did n't understand what was going on , " the director of the Nagyatad camp Lajos Horvath told Reuters on Wednesday .
" It was confusing , they had no experience of voting , many of the refugees are only semi-literate and none of them knew anything about the candidates , " he said .
" They just voted along ethnic lines where they could . "
The Bosnian election is set for September 14 and voting began on Wednesday for most of the 600,000 Bosnians living abroad .
The Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe , which is running the election , allowed the ballot to be held on Sunday in four Hungarian refugee camps .
Some Moslem refugees among the 385 registered voters Hungary 's largest camp Nagyatad have written to the OSCE complaining that they were unable to vote in contests for the president or assembly of the Bosnian-Croat Federation , where most Moslems live .
This was because their pre-war homes are now in the Serb-controlled territory , so they were voting for the national assembly of the Republika Srbska , most of the candidates for which are Serbs .
For the foreign powers which back last year 's Dayton peace agreement , the main point of the election rules is that by voting as though they were still in their pre-war homes , Bosnians should override the effects of ethnic cleansing and reassert the concept of a single multi-ethnic state .
But Adem Hodzic , one of the refugees who signed the letter of complaint , told Reuters :
" We only realised after voting that we were being denied the rights of other Bosnian Moslems to choose our president .
This vote seals the division of my country . "
Under the election rules citizens vote for a three-man presidency and House of Representatives for all Bosnia-Hercegovina and for assemblies and cantonal seats in either the Moslem-Croat Federation or the Republika Srbska .
On Sunday voters in Hungary also cast ballots for municipal councils but these will be invalidated following the cancellation of local elections by the OSCE on Tuesday .
Husein Micijevic , who also signed the letter , alleged that elderly voters were directed who to vote for by Hungarian translators who stood in the polling booth to help them .
" Probably 100 refugees were shown where to put their cross , " he said .
Seventy eight-year-old Mandolina Zelic , a Bosnian Croat who has spent the last five years in Nagyatad , told Reuters she had cast her ballot because she 'd been told to by the camp authorities but had no idea who she voted for .
" At first the organisers would n't let anyone help me but when they saw I did n't understand a young translator ringed the names I had to mark , " she said . "
I do n't know who I voted for . "
Maria Szabo of the Hungarian office organising the elections on behalf of the OSCE told Reuters on Wednesday her office was studying the letter but said they had followed OSCE instructions very carefully .
" The envelopes , each with the five different voting slips , were sealed until voting and had written instructions on how to vote , " she said . "
But of course those who could not read had to be shown . "
Estonia presidential race next round on Sept 20 .
TALLINN 1996-08-28
Estonia will hold the next round of an inconclusive state presidential race on September 20 , parliamentary officers of the Baltic state ruled on Wednesday .
This comes after three votes in the 101-strong parliament on Monday and Tuesday failed to give either incumbent Lennart Meri or rival candidate Arnold Ruutel the necessary 68 votes for a clear mandate .
The outcome was a rebuff for Meri , failing three times to win backing in his bid for a second term as head of state of the former Soviet republic .
Parliament 's press officer told Reuters that Speaker Toomas Savi will convene an electoral college involving 101 MPs and and 273 local government representatives on September 20 .
Both Meri , 67 , and Ruutel , 68 will automatically be listed as candidates but the election will also be open to new nominations with the backing of any 21 members of the college .
The winner has to secure a majority from the college within two rounds of voting otherwise the election will go back before the parliament .
Lebed likely to fail on Chechnya - Polish minister .
WARSAW 1996-08-28
Russian security chief Aleksander Lebed faces an almost impossible task in Chechnya and is likely to be sidelined , Polish Foreign Minister Dariusz Rosati was reported as saying on Wednesday .
According to best-selling daily Gazeta Wyborcza , Rosati told the Polish parliament 's foreign affairs committee on Tuesday that the fact Lebed had been charged with resolving the conflict in Chechnya showed he would be marginalised .
" It is almost impossible to gain success in this , " it quoted Rosati as saying during a committee debate .
" Lebed has no diplomatic experience .
Yeltsin sent him there to compromise him .
This tactical manoeuvre also shows that in the ruling circle there is no unity of action , " he said .
Lebed , who has arranged a military truce with separatist rebels in the southern Russia region , was in Moscow this week seeking support for a deal on Chechnya 's political status .
But Russian President Boris Yeltsin has seemed unwilling to meet his envoy and went on holiday on Monday .
Gazeta Wyborcza quoted Rosati as saying Yeltsin was very ill and effectively on leave , but for now retained control in Russia although matters were passing into the hands of his close collaborators .
Rosati said Russia 's July polls , in which Yeltsin won re-election , showed democracy had passed an important test and the Russian people had chosed the path of further reforms .
But he said a power struggle in Russia 's ruling circles could not be ruled out , which could harm further reforms .
He expressed concern over problems in the Russian economy , saying this could lead to social unrest , the daily reported .
On Moscow 's foreign policy , Rosati said it had changed its stance on NATO 's eastward expansion and was preparing itself for Poland 's inevitable entry into the Western alliance .
He also reportedly criticised Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov , saying his style of work resembled that of the Soviet-era 1970s and 1980s .
Romania state budget soars in June .
BUCHAREST 1996-08-28
Romania 's state budget deficit jumped sharply in June to 1,242.9 billion lei for the January-June period from 596.5 billion lei in January-May , official data showed on Wednesday .
Six-month expenditures stood at 9.50 trillion lei , up from 7.56 trillion lei at end-May , with education and health spending accounting for 31.6 percent of state expenses and economic subsidies and support taking some 26 percent .
January-June revenues went up to 8.26 trillion lei from 6.96 trillion lei in the first five months this year .
Romania 's government is expected to revise the 1996 budget on Wednesday to bring it into line with higher inflation , new wage and pension indexations and costs of energy imports that have pushed up the state deficit .
Under the revised version state spending is expected to rise by some 566 billion lei .
No new deficit forecast has been issued so far .
In July the government gave a 6.0-percent wage and pension indexation to cover energy , fuel and bread price increases , which quickened inflation to 7.5 percent last month .
In the original state budget , approved in March , revenues were envisaged at around 16.98 trillion lei and expenditures 20.17 trillion lei for 1996 .
The state budget deficit was originally forecast to be 3.19 trillion lei for the whole year .
On Wednesday , the leu 's official rate was 3,161 to the dollar .
-- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264
Costa Rica says Dutch pair kidnapped by Nicaraguans .
SAN JOSE , Costa Rica 1996-08-28
The Costa Rican government said on Wednesday that a Dutch couple abducted over the weekend from a tree farm in northern Costa Rica was kidnapped by former Nicaraguan guerrillas .
" Even though it 's an act of common delinquency , the case could take a difficult turn because former Nicaraguan guerrillas are involved , " Security Minister Bernardo Arce told reporters .
Earlier this year , a German tourist and a Swiss tour guide were kidnapped from the same general area in northern Costa Rica near the Nicaraguan border .
They were held for 71 days before relatives paid a ransom to free them .
Two Nicaraguan former guerrillas have been arrested in the case .
Because of the apparent threat to foreigners in Costa Rica near the Nicaraguan border , Arce said the government has advised many to take additional security measures on their own .
Hurte Sierd Zylstra and his wife , Jetsi Hendrika Coers , both 50 years old , were seized late on Saturday or early on Sunday from a teak tree plantation they manage by at least two heavily armed men who took the two off in their own car , leaving behind a ransom note demanding $ 1.5 million .
The plantation is owned by Dutch citizen Ebe Huizinga , who has since arrived in Costa Rica to deal with the matter .
Gov't dodging extradition , Colombian official says .
BOGOTA , Colombia 1996-08-28
A top judicial official and critic of President Ernesto Samper accused the government of indifference on Wednesday over efforts to lift Colombia 's five-year-old ban on extradition .
" It would seem that the subject of extradition is unworthy of an opinion from the government , " Deputy Prosecutor-General Adolfo Salamanca said .
Constitutional reforms were proposed on Tuesday by two senators , one of them a member of Samper 's own Liberal Party , aimed at lifting the ban on extradition introduced in 1991 .
U.S. Ambassador Myles Frechette applauded the move , saying it could prompt the Clinton administration to remove Colombia from a list of outcast nations that have failed to cooperate in U.S. counternarcotics efforts .
Samper -- who weathered a year-old crisis stemming from charges he financed his 1994 election campaign with drug money -- appeared less than enthusiastic , however .
" Extradition is not on the government 's legislative agenda , " he told reporters on Tuesday .
He added that he did not oppose the idea of opening a public debate over the issue .
But he fell far short of endorsing the idea of putting Colombian drug lords onto U.S.-bound flights to serve stiff penalities in American prisons .
Salamanca , who spoke at a meeting on kidnapping in Colombia , has said in the past that there was ample evidence to prove that Samper 's campaign received millions of dollars in contributions from the country 's top drug lords .
Quake shakes Costa Rica during Hashimoto visit .
SAN JOSE , Costa Rica 1996-08-28
A moderate earthquake measuring 5.0 on the Richter scale shook Costa Rica on Wednesday during a visit by Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto , but there were no reports of casualties or damage , officials said .
The quake struck at 11.16 a.m. ( 1716 GMT ) and was centred 10 miles ( 16 km ) south of the port of Quepos , which is 90 miles ( 140 km ) south of the capital San Jose , the Costa Rican Volcanic and Seismologicial Observatory said .
The quake was felt for about seven seconds in most of the country but preliminary reports said no one was hurt , it added .
The quake took place a few minutes before the end of a welcoming ceremony at Juan Santamaria airport for Hashimoto , who was starting a three-hour visit as part of a Latin American tour .
Hashimoto , who arrived at 11 a.m. ( 1700 GMT ) , showed no sign of having felt the quake , witnesses said .
Barrier removed to Brazil CVRD sell-off .
BRASILIA 1996-08-28
The Brazilian Senate Wednesday agreed to shelve a bill linking the privatization of mining conglomerate Vale do Rio Doce to congressional approval , officials said .
Officials said the Senate vote removed all existing legislative hurdles in the way of CVRD 's sell-off .
The motion was put forward by Sen .
Jose Eduardo Dutra , who had drawn up the bill .
The Senate vote also annulled a substitute version of Dutra 's bill which had sought to dedicate revenue from Vale 's privatization to regional infrastructure projects .
-- William Schomberg , Brasilia newsroom 55-61-2230358
RTRS - Arthur Yates year net A$ 6.1 mln .
SYDNEY 1996-08-29
Year to June 30
( million A$ unless stated )
Operating profit 9.75 vs 5.79
Net profit 6.08 vs 3.98
Final dividend ( cents ) 4.0 vs 4.0
Total dividend ( cents ) 6.0 vs 6.0
NOTE : Arthur Yates and Co ltd is a garden products group .
Sales 148.29 vs 133.82
Other income 1.90 vs 2.07
Shr ( cents ) 8.63 vs 7.23
Dividend is 100 percent franked
Pay date Nov 25
Reg date Nov 11
Tax 3.67 vs 1.82
Interest 2.78 vs 2.69
Depreciation 3.25 vs 2.79
-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800
Briton held in Thailand over 4.4 kg heroin find .
BANGKOK 1996-08-28
Thai airport police arrested a British bartender for allegedly attempting to board a flight for Amsterdam with nearly 4.4 kg ( 9.68 lb ) of heroin in his luggage , police said on Wednesday .
Police said James Lee Williams , 28 , was stopped at a Bangkok airport departure lounge on Monday after officials found the drug in a bag that Williams planned to carry onto the plane .
Williams ' hometown was not immediately available .
The maximum sentence for heroin trafficking is the death penalty , although it is normally commuted to life imprisonment .
PLO Council calls for halt to contacts with Israel .
RAMALLAH , West Bank 1996-08-28
The Palestinian Legislative Council on Wednesday called for a halt to contacts with Israel , just hours after President Yasser Arafat said the Jewish state had effectively declared war on the Palestinians by pursuing its hardline policies .
A resolution released by the council called for " halting contacts with the Israeli side and leaving the mechanism to carry out this to Palestinian President Yasser Arafat " .
The council was meeting in Ramallah to discuss Israel 's new policy of Jewish settlement expansion and its uncompromising line on Jerusalem since Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu took office in June .
Council resolutions are not necessarily binding .
Arafat had earlier blasted Israel saying its policies amounted to a declaration of war against the Palestinian people .
He also called for the first general strike in two years in the West Bank and Gaza on Thursday .
" What happened concerning continuous violations and crimes from this new Israeli leadership means they are declaring a state of war against the Palestinian people , " Arafat told the council .
Council speaker Ahmed Korei said the decision was part of a comprehensive plan to confront Israeli settlement policy , land confiscation and what he termed other violations of the Israeli-PLO peace deals .
Iraqi Kurd group says agrees new ceasefire .
ANKARA 1996-08-28
An Iraqi Kurdish group on Wednesday said it had agreed a new U.S.-brokered ceasefire with a rival faction after a previous accord was shattered by sporadic fighting between the groups in recent days .
" The Patriotic Union of Kurdistan ( PUK ) leadership declares its endorsement for a ceasefire arrangement with the KDP ( Kurdistan Democratic Party ) to take effect as of 8:00 a.m. on August 28 , " the PUK said in a statement .
The PUK said the ceasefire was agreed after talks between U.S. Assistant Secretary for Near East Affairs Robert Pelletreau and PUK leader Jalal Talabani .
The KDP , led by Massoud Barzani , had said a previous ceasefire negotiated by Pelletreau last Friday was broken by the PUK .
Talabani has agreed to take part in talks in London on reaching a comprehensive settlement for the PUK-KDP conflict , the PUK statement said .
It said the KDP was responsible for breaking the previous ceasefire by refusing to endorse it publicly .
Kurd group says Iraqi troops massing near north .
ANKARA 1996-08-28
An Iraqi Kurdish group on Wednesday said Iraq was massing troops near Kurdish regions in the north , where a U.S.-led allied air force protects the local population against attacks from Baghdad .
" The Iraqi regime has started threatening the Kurdish population by massing troops in preparation to attack Kurdish towns and population centres , " the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan ( PUK ) said in a statement .
The PUK said it had received confirmed reports that Iraqi troops , supported by tanks , artillery and armoured vehicles , have already penetrated some Kurdish areas .
It said the military presence reflects cooperation between President Saddam Hussein and the PUK 's rival , the Kurdistan Democratic Party ( KDP ) .
The PUK statement follows KDP assertions that the PUK is receiving military support from Iran .
Hostilities between the two warring Iraqi Kurdish factions have continued in the last few days despite a U.S.-brokered ceasefire last Friday .
The PUK called on the United Nations and allied forces to halt the Iraqi aggression .
U.S. , French and British aircraft have safeguarded the Iraqi Kurdish population against aggression from Baghdad since shortly after the Gulf War in 1991 .
The allied force , known as Operation Provide Comfort , is based in southern Turkey .
Iraq says hijackers were not diplomats .
BAGHDAD 1996-08-28
Iraq on Wednesday said the hijackers of a Sudanese airliner were not Iraqi diplomats and added that " noble Iraqis " would never contemplate such an action .
The official Iraqi News Agency ( INA ) quoted Iraq 's ambassador in Khartoum as saying that Iraq 's embassy in the Sudanese capital had nothing to do with the Monday night hijacking .
Iraq 's ambassador in Khartoum denounced the hijacking and described it as a terrorist act which had nothing to do " with the morals and values of noble Iraqis , " INA said .
Ambassador Abdulsamad Hameed Ali told INA there was only one diplomat among the 199 passengers and crew on the Sudan Airways Airbus .
" He was not involved ...
on the contrary he was harassed by the elements which carried out the hijacking , " he said .
INA did not say the hijackers were Iraqis .
The hijack started when the flight left Khartoum for Amman on Monday night .
The hijackers told the crew they had grenades and other explosives and threatened to blow up the plane if they were not taken to London .
The airliner refuelled at Larnaca , Cyprus and landed at London 's Stansted airport in the early hours of Tuesday .
Seven Iraqi suspected hijackers surrendered and British police said they had apparently asked for political asylum .
Several had brought their families along , including children .
Dole blasts Clinton for ignoring teen drug use .
Judith Crosson
VENTURA , Calif. 1996-08-28
Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole Wednesday accused the Clinton administration of ignoring drug use among teenagers and said if elected he would use the National Guard to stop drugs from entering the United States .
" He 'll probably mention his war on drugs , which he 's going to start like everything else -- next year .
It 's too late , Mr. President , " Dole told an outdoor crowd of several hundred at a private religious school .
He also commented briefly on published reports that the administration was planning to announce a plan to lower capital gains taxes for home sales . "
Welcome to the club .
We 've had it out there for weeks and weeks and weeks , " Dole said .
Dole said former first lady Nancy Reagan was laughed at with her " just say no " anti-drug message . "
But it worked , " Dole said .
Meanwhile , in Los Angeles , Dole 's running mate , Jack Kemp , campaigned aggressively for the black vote in an area that was the flashpoint of the 1992 Los Angeles riots .
Kemp told a crowd of about 300 African Americans in south central Los Angeles , " Keep your eyes open , keep your ears open , keep your heart open .
I want to tell you with all my heart that we want to win your vote . "
In Dole 's address to a group that was largely white , the presidential nominee likened the stream of illegal drugs into the United States to missiles aimed at American children and promised to appoint federal judges who would be tough on illegal drug use .
" They 're aiming millions and millions of missiles right at these young people , whether it 's a needle , whether it 's a cigarette , whatever the delivery system is -- it 's poison and it 's got to stop in America . "
he said .
Dole said 70 percent of the cocaine that entered the United States and 40 percent of the marijuana came from Mexico . "
We 've got an international problem and I 'm prepared to use our military might .
We want to stop drugs at the border , " he said .
Dole 's remarks prompted questions about whether he was seeking a ban on cigarettes . "
I did n't say anything about cigarettes .
I was talking about drugs .
I said you should n't smoke either .
That 's all I said , " he replied as he was shaking hands with well-wishers .
When asked specifically if he was suggesting a ban on cigarettes , Dole replied : " Oh no .
Come on , you know better than that . "
Dole campaign aides said the candidate was telling young people not to smoke .
Dole also said he opposed California Proposition 215 which , if approved by voters , would allow the cultivation of marijuana plants for medicinal uses .
Dole said the initiative would allow marijuana to be used for anything from a headache to an ingrown toenail .
In an effort to paint the drug issue in non-political terms , Dole said three times during his 20-minute address that illegal drug use was neither a Democratic nor a Republican issue but one that involves all people .
The anti-drug message is a theme Dole feels has strong voter appeal .
On Sunday near Chicago he accused President Bill Clinton of " raising the white flag " in the war on drugs .
A recent survey showed that illegal drug use among 12-17 year-olds had doubled in the past four years .
Dole was flanked by several California Republican politicians including Gov .
Pete Wilson , who said local and state governments cannot fight illegal drugs alone .
" We need all the help we can get .
We need to get the kind of help we used to get when Ronald Reagan and George Bush were in the White House , " Wilson said .
BALANCE-Water Dist 1 Johnson Cty , Kan .
, at $ 11 mln .
WATER DISTRICT 1 OF JOHNSON CO .
, KS
RE : $ 45,020,000
WATER REVENUE BONDS
$ 22,040,000 SER .
1996A
$ 22,980,000 RFDG , SER .
1996B
MOODY 'S : Aa S&P : AA+
Delivery Date : 09/05/1996 ( FIRM )
06/01 12/01
MATURITY SER A SER B SER A SER B
-------------------------------------------------------------
1998 665M 840M 570M
2000 - - 605M
2001 - 70M -
2002 - 895M 600M
2003 705M - 795M
2004 655M 90M 965M
2009 65M - -
2010 60M - 100M
2011 30M - 90M
2012 20M - 35M
TOTAL : 11,450
A.G. Edwards & Sons , Inc .
-- U.S. Municipal Desk , 212-859-1650
CME lumber futures close lower on profit taking .
CHICAGO 1996-08-28
Profit taking continued to weigh on CME lumber futures but prices ended only slightly lower as strong cash markets underpinned futures , traders said .
The same pattern of the past few days persisted with futures declining early on the profit taking before firming late .
There was cash-related buying late from people who want to take delivery of the September contract , they said .
Cash sources noted that although the cash market is generally quiet , prices remain firm on demand for prompt delivery wood , they added .
Random Lengths quoted cash spruce at $ 419 per tbf , up $ 5 from last Friday and $ 7 over the last midweek quote .
Reduced concern over Hurricane Edouard prompted some of the early profit taking .
Expectations the storm would turn more to the north partly eased concerns , they said .
Lumber closed $ 2.20 to $ 0.20 per tbf lower with September off $ 0.70 at $ 413.20 and November off most at $ 369.00 per tbf .
-- Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725
WHEAT--Rains boost U.S. HRW planting prospects .
Greg Frost
KANSAS CITY , Mo .
1996-08-28
Above-normal summer rainfall in the U.S. High Plains has produced near-ideal conditions for planting the 1997 hard red winter wheat crop , analysts said Wednesday .
From central Texas north to Kansas , rains throughout July and August have relieved most of the drought conditions that plagued the region earlier this year .
" Our moisture situation is excellent , especially for fall planting of winter wheat , " said Kim Anderson , extension wheat marketing economist at Oklahoma State University .
The irony of the above-average summer rainfall was not lost on High Plains wheat producers , who only three months ago were caught in a drought so severe that old-timers likened conditions to the " Dust Bowl " days of the 1930s .
" It 's definitely a turnabout from this past year , but you know last year we had pretty good moisture about this time of year , and then about October 1 it quit , " said Mark Hodges , executive director of the Oklahoma Wheat Commission . "
Hopefully that 's not going to happen this year . "
According to figures released by the Oklahoma Climatological Survey , an average of 20.19 inches fell across the state between March 1 and August 26 , 1996 .
That 's about 1/2 inch above the average for the same time period , according to Howard Johnson , associate state climatologist at the University of Oklahoma .
He noted that the majority of that 20.19 inches had fallen since July .
As an example of just how dry it was , data showed that between October 1 , 1995 and March 1 , 1996 , the state received an average of only 4.6 inches of rainfall .
In northern Texas , the current rainfall situation was similar to most of Oklahoma , said Rodney Mosier , executive assistant for the Texas Wheat Producers .
" Up here in the Texas Panhandle , we 've had some extremely beneficial rains that came through within the last several days and are really setting us up for ideal conditions for planting wheat , " Mosier said .
But he warned that the situation was not as ideal in central and southern Texas , where mositure levels were still short despite the rains brought by Hurricane Dolly last week .
In Kansas , typically the number one U.S. hard red winter wheat producer , topsoil moisture levels were rated mostly adequate during the week ended Sunday , according to the state 's agricultural statistics service .
In its weekly report released Monday , the service said Kansas topsoil moisture was rated eight percent surplus , 77 percent adequate and 15 percent short to very short .
Oklahoma 's Agricultural Statistics Service showed similar conditions , rating topsoil moisture levels as seven percent surplus , 81 percent adequate and 12 percent short to very short .
Data on topsoil moisture ratings were not released by the Texas Agricultural Statistics Service .
-- Greg Frost , 816 561-8671
First Union National Bank of Fla. settles suit .
JACKSONVILLE , Fla. 1996-08-28
First Union National Bank of Florida said on Wednesday it agreed to settle a class action law suit involving its collateral protection insurance ( CPI ) program .
To provide for the settlements , First Union has established a common fund of $ 4.7 million for cash refunds and $ 19.4 million in credit refunds for outstanding CPI balances .
The bank is a division of First Union Corp .
The bank said most of the charges resulted from loan portfolios from banks and thrifts that were acquired in the 1980s .
First Union said it has discontinued CPI as an element of its motor vehicle or boat installment loan contracts .
As part of the settlement agreement , customers who had CPI placed on loans from January 1 , 1986 to September 31 , 1996 , will receive cash or credit refunds , the bank said .
Cash refunds will go to those who paid their loans to First Union while credit refunds will go to those who have existing loan balances , the bank said .
Amoco says in talks over Yemen oil acreage .
NEW YORK 1996-08-28
Amoco Corp officials said the company is in talks over crude oil production sharing in Yemen , but declined to comment on a published report Amoco had reached preliminary agreement on a block in the Shabwa area .
" We 've been asked ( by Yemen ) not to comment ( on the talks ) , " said Amoco spokesman Dan Dietsch . "
We can neither confirm nor deny that report , " he said .
According to Middle East Economic Survey ( MEES ) , Yemen and Amoco signed a " memorandum of understanding " for a production-sharing agreement in Shabwa Block No .
S-1 in the former South Yemen , which united with North Yemen in 1990 .
According to another Amoco official , the company is not exploring now for oil anywhere in Yemen .
The officials said Amoco was deferring to the Yemeni Ministry of Petroleum and Minerals for any specific comments on the Amoco-Yemen talks .
The former Soviet Union was displaced as contractor of the potentially rich Shabwa oilfields once it collapsed in December 1991 , according to the International Petroleum Encyclopedia .
-- Oliver Ludwig , New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1633
Burundi defends military regime to hostile UN .
Evelyn Leopold
UNITED NATIONS 1996-08-28
Burundi 's ambassador on Wednesday lashed out at economic sanctions imposed by African states and said any thought of an arms embargo would be a windfall for guerrillas fighting his army-run government .
In a lengthy debate on Burundi before the U.N. Security Council , Ambassador Nsanze Terence said the new military government took over to stabilise the country and wanted negotiations under former Tanzanian President Julius Nyrere .
Nearly every African member who spoke , as well as most Security Council members , however , were unsympathetic towards the government of President Pierre Buyoya , an army major put in power in a July coup by the Tutsi-run military , which is locked in a guerrilla war with the majority Hutus .
" These ( African ) brothers should have been the first to bind the wounds of Burundi , " Terence said of the economic embargo . "
Quite the contrary , Burundi has seen economic war declared against it by fellow African people ... a gratuitous immolation of the people of Burundi . "
He said his government had just asked U.N. human rights monitors to increase their numbers in Burundi in an effort " to put an end to this vicious circle of violence . "
More than 150,000 people have been killed in violence between the minority Tutsis and the majority Hutus since 1993 .
Botswana 's envoy , Mothusi Nkgowe , said coups should be relegated " to the dump heap of history " as there could be no justification for the overthrow of a legitimate government .
Chile has proposed a resolution , still under discussion , that would impose an immediate arms embargo on Burundi and call for negotiations .
The draft suggests further sanctions against those who impede a political solution .
Among the council 's five permanent members , Russia and the United States appeared to support most elements of the Chilean proposal , while Britain , France and China were cautious .
Terence , a Tutsi , said any arms embargo would leave the army unable to defend itself against Hutu guerrillas and leave the population exposed to " armed terroritsts . "
But Chilean Ambassador Juan Somavia said : " Every weapon that reached Burundi is a weapon aimed mainly at killing an unarmed civilian .
We must not send a signal different from the African leaders themselves .
Inaction is becoming the worst possible course of action . "
Burundi 's parliament has been suspended and political parties are banned but Terence told reporters Buyoya would reconvene a new type of national assembly in October .
The United States said the coup leaders had taken no steps to restore democracy and indiscriminate killings continued .
Ambassador Karl Inderfurth said the new government should have " unconditional " negotiations with all parties inside and outside of the country .
He said Washington strongly supported the economic sanctions imposed already and if these did not work the council would consider " an arms embargo or targeted sanctions against faction leaders . "
But he said the international community had to be prepared for the worst and avoid a replay of the horrors in neighbouring Rwanda , where widespread genocide broke out against the Tutsis two years ago .
He again said the United Nations should draw up contingency plans for a rapid humanitarian intervention .
Swiss arrest Rwandan on genocide suspicion .
BERNE 1996-08-28
Swiss authorities said on Wednesday they had arrested a former Rwandan mayor , now living in Switzerland , on suspicion of violating human rights during the genocide in his country in 1994 .
The Defence Ministry said in a statement that investigations were still in the preliminary stage but it was cooperating closely with police in the cantons of Geneva and Freiburg .
It did not identify the man .
OPTIONS -- EOE options volumes - close .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-28
1605 GMT
CALLS PUTS PCT OF TOTAL
TOTAL VOLUME -- 83,008 60,131 22,877 --
FEATURES - AEX INDEX 7,391 5,658 15.72
- AHOLD 7,190 1,123 10.01
- BOLSWESSANEN 4,420 705 6.17
- ABN AMRO 3,003 1,940 5.95
- ING 3,853 673 5.45
- VNU 3,060 843 4.70
-- Amsterdam newsdesk +31 20 504 5000 ( Fax 020-504-5040 )
French tax office sucks in money .
PARIS 1996-08-28
Workers fixing the ceiling of a tax office in Paris found a dozen seven-year-old cheques for a total of six million francs ( $ 1.2 million ) in a ventilation pipe , the weekly Le Canard Enchaine said on Wednesday .
A Finance Ministry official explained that the cheques for corporate tax payments had been sucked into the ventilation system , the weekly reported .
The companies had been contacted at the time and had not been fined for failing to pay , the official said .
Swiss bond market closing report .
ZURICH 1996-08-28
Swiss bonds ended mostly higher in generally quiet activity , with the September confederate bond futures contract holding just above 113.00 .
" Today was very quiet after a lot of activity on Tuesday , " said one Swiss bond futures trader .
He said the market began strong , gave up some gains at midday and then was able to recover back at the close , but all on light volume .
In the primary market , Eksportfinans and Suedwest LB launched issues for 100 million and 300 million Swiss francs , respectively .
Eksportfinans ' seven-year issue was quoted at a yield of 3.98 percent , and Suedwest LB 's five-year issue was quoted at 3.60 percent .
Swiss money market rates remained lower at around 1.75 percent offered .
As to fundamentals , economists at Credit Suisse said they expect the country 's gross domestic product to be flat to negative in 1996 , and to grow only 0.6 percent in 1997 .
The Swiss government also said Wednesday it had made progress in cutting Switzerland 's projected spending for 1997 .
Switzerland reports July consumer prices later this week .
Closing prices as follows :
Sept conf bond up 12 at 113.02 .
Sept comi medium-term bond up three at 109.45 .
Sept Euro Swiss francs up three at 97.82 .
-- Cash :
4-1/2 Apr 2006 bond 101.80 / 90 yield 4.252 pct
-- Zurich Editorial , +41 1 631 7340
Anti-Bhutto rally draws about 8,000 in Karachi .
KARACHI , Pakistan 1996-08-28
About 8,000 protesters marched through Karachi on Wednesday demanding the removal of Pakistani Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto , witnesses said .
" From here we will march to Islamabad and by God we will not let Benazir and ( Bhutto 's husband Asif Ali ) Zardari escape justice , " Nawaz Sharif , leader of the main opposition Pakistan Muslim League told a rally organised by a 16-party alliance .
Sharif accused Bhutto of corruption and nepotism , charges she has denied in the past .
Witnesses said protesters carrying colourful party flags walked for several miles , chanting anti-government slogans .
The event was part of an opposition campaign launched on August 14 , Pakistan 's independence day .
Sharif said similar rallies would be held in the Balochistan provincial capital Quetta and the Punjab provincial capital Lahore before an opposition march on the capital Islamabad .
" I promise the people of Karachi that those responsible for the extra-judicial killing of innocent youths would not be spared , " Sharif said .
Karachi 's ethnic Mohajir National Movement ( MQM ) accuses the government of killing many of its militants in cold blood .
The government has denied the charge and blames the MQM for much of the violence that killed 2,000 people in the city last year .
Political observers said the turn-out was disappointing for a city of about 12 million people , possibly indicating that the MQM , although a member of the opposition alliance , had not mobilised its supporters for the event .
The turbulent southern port has been calmer this year , but police say more than 300 people have died in political unrest .
The MQM speaks for Urdu-speaking Moslems who migrated from India at Partition in 1947 and their descendants .
Sharif , a former prime minister , is the main political rival of Bhutto , who defeated him in the October 1993 election .
He said only the removal of the government and an early election could save Pakistan from disaster . "
We will dislodge the Bhutto government .
It is a holy war for us , " he said .
Bhutto has vowed to complete her five-year term .
India ACC Apr-Jul ' 96 sales , output up .
BOMBAY 1996-08-28
India 's leading cement firm Associated Cement Companies ( ACC ) said on Wednesday its cement sales rose to 3.1 million tonnes in April-July 1996 from 2.93 million a year ago .
ACC Chairman Nani Palkhivala told shareholders at the firm 's annual meeting cement output rose to 3.14 million tonnes in the first quarter of 1996/97 ( April-March ) , from 3.01 million a year ago .
Palkhivala said ACC had secured government approval to take over a sick cement firm with a grinding capacity of 275,000 tonnes per year . "
We will take it over early next month , " he said .
Talking about the cement industry in general , Palkhivala said Indian production rose by about 10 percent in 1995/96 .
" The industry saw capacity expansion of about 13 percent over 1994/95 from 77.79 million tonnes to 87.45 million tonnes , " Palkhivala told shareholders .
He said Indian cement exports dropped about eight percent from the previous year because of stiff international competition and inadequate infrastructural facilities .
ACC 's own export performance was marginally better than in 1994/95 on account of a 36 percent rise in exports to Nepal and the opening of a new market - Sri Lanka , he said .
Despite power shortages , ACC achieved a satisfactory growth in production during the year with the help of its power plants .
ACC sold 9.4 million tonnes in 1995/96 , retaining its top position in the Indian cement industry , Palkhivala said .
-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000
Belgium bank sanctions $ 6.5 mln loan to India WSRL .
BOMBAY 1996-08-28
Belgium 's Kredietbank has approved a $ 6.5 million loan to India 's Welspun Stahl Rohren Ltd ( WSRL ) to part-finance its submerged arc welded pipes plant , the Indian company said in a statement on Wednesday .
The loan is at LIBOR plus one percent , it said .
The loan , maturing in six years , is guaranteed by Indusind Bank for $ 3.5 million and by UTI Bank for $ 3 million , it said .
The WSRL plant , located in the western Indian state of Gujarat , will have a capacity to manufacture 175,000 tonnes per annum of longitudinal pipes and 25,000 tonnes per annum of spiral welded pipes , the statement said .
The longitudinal pipes plant is expected to be complete by the second quarter of September 1997 and the saw arc welded pipes plant by September 1996 , it said .
WSRL is part of the Welspun group which has a presence in the cotton yarn , terry towels and polyester yarn industry , the statement said .
-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000
India fishermen say forced to carry Tamil refugees .
P.V. Krishnamoorthy
RAMESWARAM , India 1996-08-28
Indian fishermen said on Wednesday they had been forced at gunpoint to ferry refugees fleeing the ethnic war in Sri Lanka to India , as a protest strike by more than 30,000 fishermen entered its ninth day .
" There is little we can do when at mid-sea .
The LTTE ( Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam ) accosts us and , at the point of a gun , forces us to take refugees , " said senior fishermen leader P. Arulanandam .
Some 850 refugees have landed in recent weeks at the port of Rameswaram in the southern Indian state of Tamil Nadu , home to 50 million Tamil-speaking people , port officials say .
Rameswaram is 15 km ( 10 miles ) off the coast of Sri Lanka .
State chief minister M. Karunanidhi has publicly welcomed the refugees , who are fleeing the 13-year war between Tamil separatists and government troops that Colombo says has cost 50,000 lives .
But the influx has triggered fears of a repeat of the 1980s when some 200,000 refugees landed in Tamil Nadu .
Intelligence officals said more than 5,000 Tamils were waiting on the western coast of Sri Lanka to cross into India .
The Indian government has warned its fishermen that their boats would be impounded if they were caught ferrying refugees .
The fishermen went on strike last week to protest the government 's cancellation of three trawlers ' fishing licenses after the boats were caught carrying Tamil refugees .
All Fishermen 's Association secretary N.J. Bose said the strike would continue indefinitely and the fishermen would block road and rail traffic if their demands were not met .
" Until the government releases our boats from naval custody and Sri Lankan naval custody , and gives us assurance ( it will not revoke licences of boats ferrying refugees ) , we will not call off our strike , " Bose said .
LTTE spokesmen could not immediately be reached for comment , but Sri Lankan fishermen denied that Indians were being coerced into carrying refugees across the Palk Strait .
" Indian fishermen come right up to Pesalai to fish , and when refugees request them to ferry them across , they readily oblige .
Only some take money , " Sri Lankan boatman Chinnathambi said .
Arulanandam denied the fishermen charged the refugees for passage to India and said it was unfair to penalise them for the refugees ' arrival .
" We have not gone to sea since August 19 , but refugees are arriving daily nevertheless .
How could we alone be held responsible for the influx ? "
he said .
An Indian Fisheries Department official said the government planned to urge fishermen not to cross the international boundary between India and Sri Lanka , but admitted this would be hard to enforce because of Sri Lanka 's pomfret-rich waters .
Indian cotton trade shut for local festival .
BOMBAY 1996-08-28
India 's cotton trade was shut on Wednesday for a local religious festival , dealers said .
Trading will resume on Thursday .
On Tuesday , cotton prices fell on profit-taking prompted by increased offerings from state agencies .
" Export deals remained thin and hardly a few thousand bales were traded at the rate of 57.50 / 60 cents per pound , " one broker said .
-- Bombay Commodities +91-22-265 9000
VW sees group net profit doubling in Q3 .
DRESDEN , Germany 1996-08-28
German carmaker Volkswagen AG said on Wednesday that it expected group net profit to double in the third quarter .
" We have been seeking to double our profits ( during the period ) and we are confident of doing so , " VW chief financial officer Bruno Adelt told a briefing as part of the formal introduction of the new VW Passat sedan .
Adelt did not give a concrete forecast .
VW had a 1995 third quarter group net profit of 72 million marks .
The group reported a 1996 first-half group net profit of 282 million marks .
-- John Gilardi , Frankfurt Newsroom , +49 69 756525
MILTIADIS EVERT HEADS TO ALEXANDROUPOLIS THIS WEEKEND .
ATHENS 1996-08-28
Conservative New Democracy ( ND ) party leader Miltiadis Evert will be hitting the campaign trail and head to Alexandroupolis this weekend to speak to the city 's businessmen on Sunday morning , ND said .
Evert will depart for Alexandroupolis on Saturday afternoon .
Prime Minister Costas Simitis criticized Evert today for unleashing a seven-point economic package that offers tax relief to merchants and other professionals , higher pensions to farmers and support for small business .
The finance ministry estimated the cost of ND 's economic measures to over 600 billion drachmas but ND officials put the figure much lower to about 300 billion drachmas .
Simitis blamed ND for the low absorption rate of EU funds and said the socialists will increase farmers ' pensions , combat tax evasion and accelerate GDP growth rates to 4.0 percent in a few years .
Faster economic growth is a major component of ND 's economic programme and Evert has repeatedly blamed the socialists for the slow economic growth .
-- Dimitris Kontogiannis , Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4
Dow pushes London stocks to new record .
Peter Griffiths
LONDON 1996-08-28
A firm start on Wall Street helped push leading London shares to a new record high on Wednesday and German stocks closed floor trading up but the Paris bourse slipped sharply , hit by a weakening franc and fears of industrial unrest .
On the foreign exchange markets , a survey indicating weaker than expected Japanese business sentiment boosted the dollar in early trading but it failed to build on its gains against the yen and slipped lower against the mark in quiet afternoon trade .
London shares , boosted by Wall Street , added to early gains with the blue chip FTSE 100 index hitting a new peak of 3921.8 before dropping back slightly .
One focus was British Airways , which rebounded after fears faded that the cancellation of " open skies " talks between the U.S. Transportation Department and the British government may jeopardise its tie-up with American Airlines .
The conclusion of an open skies agreement had been made a prerequisite of the proposed link-up by the U.S .
Better-than-expected British trade figures had little impact on equities .
The non-EU July trade deficit totalled 506 million sterling ( $ 788 million ) while June 's world deficit was 1.12 billion pounds .
Forecasts were for deficits of 900 million sterling and 1.4 billion sterling .
German shares shed some gains on profit-taking but nonetheless ended the floor session higher buoyed by demand for chemical stocks and a stable dollar .
The 30-share DAX index closed at 2,563.16 points , up 4.32 .
However , French stocks extended opening losses to more than one percent in morning trading , falling through the 2000 point resistance level on the main CAC-40 index .
Dealers blamed a weakening franc and worries about the 1997 budget and possible autumn strikes
Louis Viannet , leader of France 's Communist-led CGT union , criticised government plans for spending cuts in the 1997 budget on Wednesday and warned of labour unrest as France gets back to work after the holidays .
Later in the day , helped by the firmer Wall Street opening , Paris climbed back to the 2000 level but still remained well into negative territory .
In foreign exchange the dollar was trading at around 108.40 yen in the European afternoon , up from its European close on Tuesday of 107.55 but off the day 's highs .
It had been boosted overnight by the Bank of Japan 's quarterly corporate survey , or " tankan " , of major manufacturers -- an important gauge of business sentiment .
The unexpectedly weak figures convinced markets that Japanese interest rates would stay at rock-bottom levels -- weakening the yen .
The Japanese discount rate is currently at a record low of 0.5 percent .
The BOJ sought to put the best face on the data which defied economists ' predictions of improving sentiment and was the first decline in business sentiment in a year .
A BOJ spokesman said " the doors to the recovery have not been shut ...
the recovery is still continuing . "
These remarks gave the yen some backbone and the dollar failed to progress further .
" The dollar 's gains were less than spectacular , suggesting that while it 's likely to benefit from revised Japanese rate expectations , a breakout from the established trading range does n't appear likely , " said currency economist Klaus Baader .
Dealers said shares were also affected by a slippage in bond prices due to lower than expected June industrial production , showing the economy was still faltering .
CURRENCIES AT 1500 GMT
The dollar was at 108.40 yen and 1.4765 marks compared with Tuesday 's European close of 107.78 yen and 1.4779 marks
STOCK MARKETS AT 1500 GMT
The Financial Times-Stock Exchange index of 100 leading British shares had risen 15 points to 3,920.7 .
In Paris , the CAC-40 share index dropped 15.09 to 2,002.9 .
The 30-share DAX index in Frankfurt closed up 4.32 at 2,563.16 .
PRECIOUS METALS
Gold fixed at $ 388.50 versus Tuesday 's London close of $ 388.55 .
Silver was at 521.15 cents .
( $ 1=.6421 Sterling )
AEI 's Spanish operation wins ISO 9002 .
LONDON 1996-08-28
Air Express International said in a statement that Spain has become the twenty-second country in its network to achieve ISO 9002 quality accreditation .
It added Bureau Veritas has accredited AEI Iberfreight 's offices at Alicante , Barcelona , Bilbao , Madrid , Seville and Valencia as meeting the necessary standards .
-- Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax+44 171 542 5017
Arafat says Israel declares war on Palestinians .
Wafa Amr
RAMALLAH , West Bank 1996-08-28
Palestinian President Yasser Arafat said on Wednesday that Israel had declared war on the Palestinians and called for the first general strike in the West Bank and Gaza in two years .
" What happened concerning continuous violations and crimes from this new Israeli leadership means they are declaring a state of war against the Palestinian people , " Arafat told the Palestinian legislature .
Accusing Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu of stupidity , Arafat launched his strongest attack on the right-wing government since its election in May .
The tirade was sparked by Israel 's announcement on Tuesday of plans to expand the Jewish settlement of Kiryat Sefer and its demolishing of a community centre in Arab East Jerusalem .
" Israel has started the war on Jerusalem .
They are idiots to have started the Jerusalem battle , " Arafat said in Arabic . "
There will be no Palestinian state without Jerusalem .
Netanyahu should know he is stupid to have started this battle . "
Arafat called for a general strike " for Jerusalem " on Thursday in all of the West Bank and Gaza Strip .
There has not been a joint shutdown there since May 1994 when Israeli troops began withdrawing under an interim self-rule agreement signed in 1993 .
The strike will have little effect on the Israeli economy while hurting Palestinian merchants in East Jerusalem and Bethlehem who cater to the tourist trade .
Some 25,000 Palestinian labourers are likely to stay away from their jobs , mainly in construction , in Israel .
But Palestinians , once the backbone of the building industry , have been largely replaced by labourers from Romania and China .
" On Friday , all Moslems , including Palestinians in Israel ...
will go to ( Jerusalem 's ) Al-Aqsa mosque and pray .
Jews and Christians who do not pray should accompany them and stand behind them , " Arafat said .
Officials in Netanyahu 's office were not immediately available for comment on Arafat 's remarks .
Israeli travel restrictions , imposed after bombings by Moslem militants in February and March , ban most of the two million Arabs in the West Bank and Gaza from entering Jerusalem .
Netanyahu , who opposes trading occupied land for peace , made Jerusalem a central issue in his election campaign , accusing Labour Prime Minister Shimon Peres of planning to hand control of the Arab eastern part of the city to the Palestinians .
Israel captured East Jerusalem in the 1967 Middle East war and claims both halves of the city as its capital .
The PLO wants East Jerusalem as the capital of a future Palestinian state .
In his speech to the crowded legislature , Arafat signalled he was not abandoning diplomacy although " alarm bells are ringing " .
He unexpectedly broke off his address to take a telephone call from U.S. Middle East envoy Dennis Ross , who held talks in Paris on Tuesday with Israeli and Egyptian officials .
When Arafat returned to the podium , he said senior PLO negotiator Mahmoud Abbas , better known as Abu Mazen , and Netanyahu aide Dore Gold could meet on Thursday .
He quoted Ross as telling him : " The important thing is the Israelis are prepared to move . "
Arafat said he replied : " is this like their previous promises ? "
" No , they have good intentions , " Arafat quoted Ross as saying .
Palestinians have been pressing Israel to carry out a long-delayed partial troop pullout from the flashpoint West Bank city of Hebron agreed by the previous Labour government .
The Israeli government is studying redeployment plans submitted by Defence Minister Yitzhak Mordechai which are likely to demand a wider than agreed army presence in Hebron .
Turkey 's Ciller to hold talks in Jordan .
ANKARA 1996-08-28
Turkish Foreign Minister Tansu Ciller will visit Jordan on September 3 on her first trip abroad since she took office in June , Foreign Ministry spokesman Omer Akbel said on Wednesday .
" The two-day visit will take place at the invitation of Jordanian Prime Minister Abdul-Karim al-Kabariti , " he told reporters .
He said Turkey considered Jordan a suitable country with which to cooperate on Middle East matters .
Bilateral relations and the Middle East peace process would be on the table during the visit , Akbel said .
Turkish Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan visited mainly Moslem countries , including Iran , during a 10-day tour earlier in August .
Italian prime minister to visit Turkey .
ANKARA 1996-08-28
Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi will pay a one-day working visit to Turkey on September 3 , the Turkish Foreign Ministry said on Wednesday .
" Both countries ' governments were formed recently .
This visit will create a direct contact opportunity for the two parties to express their views , " spokesman Omer Akbel told a news briefing .
The Italian prime minister , in office since May 18 , will be the first Western leader to meet Islamist Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan since he came to power on June 28 .
Prodi will also meet President Suleyman Demirel and Foreign Minister Tansu Ciller , Akbel said .
Turkey says 25 Kurd rebels killed in clashes .
DIYARBAKIR , Turkey 1996-08-28
Turkish troops killed 25 Kurdish rebels in recent clashes in the east of the country , security officials said on Wednesday .
The emergency rule governor 's office said in a statement that 10 rebels from the Kurdistan Workers Party ( PKK ) were killed in fighting in Tunceli province .
Soldiers killed nine more PKK guerrillas in Sirnak province and six in Hakkari .
The statement did not report any military casualties and did not say exactly when the clashes took place .
Over 20,000 people have been killed in the PKK 's fight for independence or autonomy in southeastern Turkey .
Israel 's Levy to meet Mubarak in Egypt .
JERUSALEM 1996-08-28
Israeli Foreign Minister David Levy will visit Egypt this Sunday for talks with President Hosni Mubarak , the Foreign Ministry said on Wednesday .
The trip will be Levy 's first to an Arab state as a minister in Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu 's government .
FSA qualifies five muni bond issues for insurance .
NEW YORK 1996-08-28
Financial Security Assurance said Wednesday it qualified for bond insurance the following five municipal issues scheduled for competitive sale today :
-- Paris School District No 7 , Ark .
, $ 2.44 million refunding bonds .
-- St Ansgar Community School District , Iowa , $ 3.334 million general obligation school bonds .
-- Avalon Borough , N.J. , $ 11.4 million GOs .
-- Seaford Union Free School District , N.Y. , $ 5 million school bonds .
-- Akron , Ohio , $ 6.31 million improvement bonds .
-- U.S. Municipal Desk , 212-859-1650
Colo .
taxable health deal rated Aa2 / VMIG-1 - Moody 's .
NEW YORK 1996-08-28
Moody 's Investors Service -
Rating Announcement As of 08/26/96 .
Issuer : Colorado Health Fac .
Auth .
National
Benevolent Assoc .
- Colorado Christian Home
Proj .
Series 1996 B Taxable
State : CO
Rating : Aa2 / VMIG 1
Sale Amount : 4,300,000
Expected Sale Date : 08/26/96
Lamm will not endorse Perot for Reform ticket-CNN .
WASHINGTON 1996-08-27
Former Colorado Democratic Gov .
Richard Lamm has decided not to endorse Ross Perot as the presidential candidate of the Reform Party , CNN reported late Tuesday .
CNN quoted aides and family members as saying Lamm , who competed with Perot to head the ticket for Perot 's party , had told them he would definitely not endorse Perot , but they did not know whether he would endorse another candidate .
An announcement was planned in Chicago Wednesday .
Lamm , 60 , is a three-term Colorado governor who left office in 1987 and vied for the Reform Party nomination after becoming disillusioned with both the Democratic and Republican parties .
Lamm is a friend of President Clinton and supported him in the 1992 election .
Perot won his party 's official nomination as its presidential candidate in a secret ballot earlier this month .
RESEARCH ALERT - Career Horizons said cut .
-- Donaldson Lufkin & Jenrette cut its rating on Career Horizons Inc to market perform from outperform , according to market sources .
-- Further details were not immediately available .
-- The stock was up 3/4 at 35-7/8 .
Northern States Power Co sets payout .
MINNEAPOLIS 1996-08-28
Quarterly
Latest Prior
Amount $ 0.69 $ 0.69
Pay Oct 20
Record Oct 1
-- Chicago newsdesk 312 408-8787
US investors mull appeal of Lloyd 's decision .
Patricia Vowinkel
NEW YORK 1996-08-27
U.S. investors in troubled Lloyd 's of London were considering late on Tuesday whether to appeal a U.S. court decision in favour of Lloyd 's and pledged to continue pursuing other legal actions .
A U.S. appeals court on Tuesday gave Lloyd 's a reprieve , throwing out an injunction that the insurance giant said could have led to its collapse .
A lower court issued the injunction on Friday and ordered Lloyd 's to give investors , known as Names , more information before requiring them to decide whether to accept a settlement offer as part of a reorganisation plan .
" My prediction is that the Names will appeal , " said Kenneth Chiate , a U.S. Name and a chief negotiator for the American Names Association .
" At this point , it is a sufficiently important decision that I 'm confident that they will appeal , " he said . "
But to say that they definitely will would be premature until we determine what the exact basis for the court 's ruling is . "
Under the reorganisation plan , Lloyd 's plans to reinsure its massive liabilities into a new company called Equitas .
The arrangement calls for investors to make additional payments to fund Equitas but also provides them with 3.2 billion stg in compensation to help reduce their prior outstanding liabilities .
The Names had been scheduled to decide whether to accept or reject the offer by 1100 GMT Wednesday , but Lloyd 's chairman David Rowland said on Tuesday the offer would be extended .
At least eight U.S. states have still some form of litigation pending , said John Head , spokesman for the Association of Lloyd 's State Chairmen , a group representing U.S. Names .
" It goes without saying that we 're rather disappointed , " Head said of the decision by the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Fourth Circuit , sitting in Baltimore .
But , he said , " we still have hope that somebody is going to see our point of view in this . "
The Colorado attorney general told Lloyd 's last week it was considering a new legal action against the British insurance market , based on allegations of consumer fraud .
" We have notified them of our concerns and asked them to give us a response , " said Colorado attorney general Gale Norton .
Norton said she was concerned that the Lloyd 's agreement immunizes it from future litigation regarding Equitas and requires that all legal actions be heard outside of Colorado .
In addition , she said she was concerned the plan may not offer investors enough protection from additional , future liabilities .
Meanwhile , an appeal of a lawsuit filed by some 600 Names in California is still pending before the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit , Chiate of the American Names Association said .
That lawsuit , which seeks rescision and restitution , was dismissed in a U.S. district court .
That case " is what I call the most significant alternate remedy for us , " Chiate said .
The individual Names , however , now must decide whether to accept Lloyd 's settlement offer or reject the offer and pursue litigation .
Chiate said he has advised Names that " they must make , individually , a risk benefit analysis . "
Rejection involved forfeiting the compensation offer and risking the possibility of owing Lloyd 's two to three times more than Lloyd 's is now willing to accept , he said .
But , in rejecting the offer , the Names would retain their rights to pursue litigation , he said .
German police made Nazi gestures , officials say .
NUREMBERG , Germany 1996-08-28
German riot police made Nazi gestures at a private function earlier this month and may face dismissal for their actions , the Bavarian Interior Ministry said on Wednesday .
The ministry declined to detail gestures the Nuremberg-based policemen had made at the August 13 function but added seven had been suspended from duty pending an internal inquiry .
A spokesman for public prosecutors in the southern city , where dictator Adolf Hitler held some of his most infamous Nazi party rallies in the 1930s , said there were no plans to prosecute the officers as the gestures had not been made in public .
Gun-wielding motorist snapped by cool passenger .
BERLIN 1996-08-28
A motorist threatened a fellow driver with a starting pistol as he overtook him illegally in the inside lane on a motorway near Berlin and was photographed in the act by the driver 's wife , prosecutors said on Wednesday .
Prosecutors in the city of Potsdam said the 32-year-old man drew alongside the other car at about 110 kph ( 70 mph ) and aimed his pistol at the driver .
But the driver 's wife kept her nerve , got out her camera and photographed him .
The man has been charged with dangerous driving , coercion and threatening behaviour .
German prosecutors file sex tourism charges .
BERLIN 1996-08-28
Berlin prosecutors said on Wednesday they had filed charges against two German men for sexually abusing children in Thailand and distributing pornographic films and pictures of their degrading acts .
The case is one of only a handful in which authorities have managed to track down suspects under a law which lets them pursue Germans who commit sex offences abroad .
The pair , identified only as 43-year-old clerk Dieter U and businessman Thomas S , 33 , are alleged to have carried out acts of sexual indecency with children as young as 10 years old between 1994 and 1995 .
Their videos included pictures of one of the accused tying up a Thai boy and performing acts of sadistic torture on him , prosecutors said in a statement .
In another scene , a young girl performed oral sex with an unidentified adult man .
The new law was introduced with much fanfare in 1993 .
But prosecutors face huge difficulties in gathering evidence and bringing witnesses to testify in a German court , and only one person has so far been convicted under the law .
Investigators are probing several other cases .
The Berlin prosecutors said they had been alerted to the two men by customs officials who intercepted packages containing pornographic photographs and order forms .
France 's Juppe on official visit to Greece Sep 15 .
ATHENS 1996-08-28
French Premier Alain Juppe will pay an official visit to Greece on September 15 to celebrate 150 years of the French Archaeological Society , government spokesman Dimitris Reppas said on Wednesday .
Juppe will meet Greek Prime Minister Costas Simitis and Foreign Minister Theodoros Pangalos , Reppas told reporters .
" The French premier 's visit was planned to coincide with the Archaeological Society 's celebrations .
The Greek government was asked for an official meeting with the prime minister and the foreign minister and it said yes , " Reppas said .
Stork H1 results breakdown per sector .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-28
First 24 weeks 1996
( millions of guilders unless otherwise stated )
Industrial systems and components
- Turnover 756 vs 829
- Operating profit 46 vs 48
- New orders received 876 vs 933
- Order book ( billions ) 1.07 vs 0.98
Industrial services
- Turnover 657 vs 700
- Operating profit 9 vs 3
- New orders received ( billions ) 1.00 vs 1.09
- Order book ( billions ) 2.37 vs 2.01
NOTE - Order book figures refer to value of orders on books at end of period .
-- Amsterdam newsroom +31 20 504 5000 , Fax +31 20 504 5040
Stephanie of Monaco 's husband snapped cavorting .
ROME 1996-08-28
Two Italian magazines published pictures on Wednesday of Daniel Ducruet , Princess Stephanie of Monaco 's husband and former bodyguard , cavorting naked with another woman by a poolside in France .
The magazines , Eva Tremila and its sister publication Gente , printed up to 26 pages of photos of the woman undressing Ducruet , the pair embracing on a sunbed and finally both naked .
Eva Tremila said other even more explicit photos were taken but it did not print them .
The magazines named the woman as Fili Houteman , a 26-year-old French singer and dancer in a Belgian cabaret club .
The photographs , an Italian exclusive , raised eyebrows in the tiny principality , where Stephanie 's father Prince Rainier , had long disapproved of his daughter 's choice of husband .
Stephanie had two children with Ducruet before their marriage in July last year .
Stephanie , Caroline and Albert are the children of Rainier and former Hollywood screen goddess Grace Kelly , who was killed in a car crash in 1982 .
" We have seen the photos but for the moment the palace has no comment , " a spokeswoman for Prince Rainier told Reuters .
The magazines said the photographs were taken in Cap de Villefranche , some 15 km ( nine miles ) from Monte Carlo .
Gente said Ducruet , a keen racing driver , met Houteman during a race in Belgium and photographers had been on their trail ever since .
The magazine said video cameras had also been used to film the couple and that a sound-track existed .
Highlights of Wednesday 's Commission briefing .
BRUSSELS 1996-08-28
Following are highlights of the midday briefing by the European Commission on Wednesday :
In response to a question , Commission spokesman Joao Vale de Almeida said there had been no developments regarding the Commission 's position concerning the dispute with Germany and Saxony over state aid to Volkswagen .
He said there was some possibility of further talks with Germany before the next Commission meeting of September 4 .
- - - -
The Commission released the following documents :
- IP / 96 / 804 : Commission approves acquisition of Pao de Acucar by Auchan .
- IP / 96 / 805 : Commission finds acquisition of CAMAT by AGF-IART does not fall under the merger regulation .
- IP / 96 / 806 : Commission clears acquisition of Austrian food retail chain Billa by German group Rewe-Handelsgruppe .
- SPEECH / 96 / 202 : Speech by European Commissioner Anita Gradin at the World Congress against Sexual Exploitation of Children in Stockholm .
- Eurostat news release 51/96 : March-May 1996 EU industrial production figures .
Spanish tomato warriors paint the town red .
BUNOL , Spain 1996-08-28
Revellers painted the town red on Wednesday as the 1996 edition of the world 's biggest tomato fight began in the eastern Spanish village of Bunol .
Thousands of people pelted each other with armfuls of ripe tomatoes as streets , walls and windows were coated in a blood-red wash .
A single firework after midday signalled the start of the fruit-throwing frenzy , during which participants hurl some 100 tonnes of tomatoes trucked in for the occasion .
Local historians say the tradition began in 1945 when disgruntled locals began spontaneously to bombard the priest and mayor at the annual fiesta in Bunol ( pronounced Boo-nee-OL ) .
The festival 's fame has grown and now attracts between 15,000 and 20,000 people , many of them foreigners .
PRESS DIGEST - GREECE - AUG 28 .
ATHENS 1996-08-28
Leading stories in the Greek financial press :
IMERISIA
-- Pre-election debate heats up on economic issues as conservative New Democracy party promises seven measures includind tax relief for farmers and socialist Pasok defends progress on economic convergence with the EU
-- Finance ministry scrambles to find temporary solution to regulation which slaps a 15 percent tax rate on gains from trading of bonds and coupons by mutual funds
-- Finance ministry will cut 12-month T-bill rate by 10 basis points to 12.70 percent in the upcoming end August issue
FINANCIAL KATHIMERINI
-- Inflows of more than $ 500 million are seen in the interbank market and the bourse in the last three days reflecting confidence in the post-election economic policy
-- Athens Metro subway project hits snags which could delay delivery to the year 2000 and overshoot the original budgeted cost of 520 billion drachmas
-- State National Bank of Greece will start real auction programme September 9 to lighten up on its real estate holdings
KERDOS
-- New Democracy leader Miltiadis Evert vows support mesures for farmers and small business as he kicks off the conservative party 's campaign
-- National Economy Minister Yannos Papandoniou defends " hard drachma " foreign exchange policy , says it wo n't change
EXPRESS
-- Message of unity from the conservative New Democracy party as former prime minister Constantine Mitsotakis and Miltiadis Evert shake hands
NAFTEMBORIKI
-- Government defends " hard drachma " policy , says it will continue unchanged after the elections
-- Conservative opposition New Democracy promises series of measures on the economy 30 days after the elections aiming at 4.0 percent GDP growth rate annually -- George Georgiopoulos , Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4
HOEK LOOS H1 NET PROFIT 28.9 MLN GUILDERS .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-28
First half 1996
( in millions of guilders unless otherwise stated )
Net per shr ( guilders ) 4.38 vs 3.70
Net profit 28.9 vs 24.5
Turnover 273.6 vs 290.3
Operating profit 44.4 vs 40.7
Note - Industrial gases maker Hoek Loos NV .
Interest charges 2.20 vs 5.05
Tax 13.26 vs 11.16
-- Amsterdam newsroom +31 20 504 5000 , Fax +31 20 504 5040
Stagecoach sees Swebus deal agreed next week .
LONDON 1996-08-28
British bus and passenger rail operator Stagecoach Holdings Plc said on Wednesday that its negotiations to acquire Swedish long distance bus operator Swebus AB were set to lead to a signed agreement next week .
Four weeks ago Stagecoach said it had agreed the deal in principle , and it expected to pay 110 million stg-plus for the firm , with Swebus ' current owner , the state railway company .
" The directors report that negotiations with the vendors of Swebus AB are proceeding and they expect an agreement ( conditional on shareholder approval ) will be signed next week , " Stagecoach said in a statement .
-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717
NZ bills gain ground after see-saw session .
WELLINGTON 1996-08-28
0515 GMT
The New Zealand money market gained slightly at Wednesday 's close after what dealers described as a see-saw trading session .
Ninety-day bank bill rates shed five points to 9.93 percent and September bank bill futures rose four to 90.18 .
However , bonds finished largely flat .
" Our bonds were better bid initially but they sold off on a lack of demand , and the short end went with it too on a lower currency .
" There were big buyers at the base of where the market sold to , and when the currency got bought back on talk of a samurai the market got bought back again , " a dealer said .
Volumes were reasonable in the money market but thin in bonds .
Dealers said the market seemed to be trading a range and would wait for more political polls to provide direction .
They were confident of further eurokiwi issuance but said the timing was less of a certainty .
-- Wellington newsroom ( 64 4 ) 473 4746
RTRS - Guinness Peat expects strong full yr .
SYDNEY 1996-08-28
British-based investment company Guinness Peat Group Plc ( GPG ) said on Wednesday it expected a strong full year result .
" We think we 're in a position to produce a strong result , however a lot of our profitability must inevitably depend on a number of ( company ) results , " said GPG director Garry Weiss .
GPG earlier said its net profit for the six months to June 30 rose to 9.77 million pounds from 6.93 million in the previous first half .
The company did not declare an interim dividend as in the previous year .
Weiss said the Australian share market had been somewhat negative for much of 1996 and this had some effect on the company 's first half results .
" However , it certainly is a very pleasing result for the first six months , " he said .
Weiss said most of the company 's half year earning stemmed from the sale of its 50 percent stake in Physicians Insurance Co of Ohio .
He said the company decided to sell its U.S. investment in order to consolidate investments closer to its administrative base .
GPG said its stakes in Tyndall Australia Ltd and Mid-East Minerals Ltd both contributed strongly to GPG 's first half earnings .
-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800
RTRS - Newcrest Q4 net profit A$ 4.3 mln .
SYDNEY 1996-08-28
Gold miner Newcrest Mining Ltd said on Wednesday it posted a A$ 4.3 million profit after tax in the final quarter of the year to June 30 , 1996 .
Earlier , Newcrest reported a drop in net profit after abnormals to A$ 20.81 million for the year from A$ 42.4 million the previous year .
Newcrest said earnings from the Telfer and Boddington mines were lower than the previous year due to lower head grades at the mines , forcing gold production lower .
Production costs also rose eight percent during the year to A$ 406 per ounce .
RTRS - Queensland gunman evades police in bush hunt .
BRISBANE 1996-08-28
Australian police on Wednesday continued to hunt a gunman in dense bushland after he killed his wife and wounded three other people , warning the man is extremely dangerous and may take a hostage to escape .
The shooting occured around 6.30 a.m. ( 2030 GMT ) on Tuesday at Glenwood , south of Maryborough , about 150 km ( 93 miles ) north of Brisbane on the Queensland state coast .
Police have declared an " emergent situation " in the area , giving them powers to raid houses , search cars , close schools , quarantine the area and evacuate people .
" It is one step short of an emergency situation , " a police spokesman said via telephone from a command post in the bush .
" We have not had any sightings , but we suspect he is armed , possibly with a .22 rifle and / or a self-loading shotgun .
He is considered extremely dangerous , " he said .
" It 's a possibility , not a probability , he may take a hostage , but we have measures in place if that is the case . "
William Fox broke into his wife 's home on Tuesday morning , shooting her dead and wounding his 16-year-old son , his son 's girlfriend and a neighbour , police said .
All three wounded are in a satisfactory condition in hospital .
Fox initially fled from the shooting in a car , but then abandoned the car and entered dense bushland .
Fox is a skilled bushman who knows the area very well , police said .
About 60 police , helicopters and fixed-wing aircraft have maintained an overnight cordon around 15 sq km ( six sq miles ) of bush near Glenwood .
The area is littered with caves and police believed Fox has a hideout which has enabled him to evade capture .
Australia 's six states and two territories are involved in heated debate over the introduction of tough new firearm laws , including the banning rapid fire weapons , after a shooting massacre in the island state of Tasmania .
On April 28 , a lone gunman went on a shooting rampage at the site of the historic Port Arthur penal settlement , killing 35 people .
Shanghai Ek Chor opens new motorcyle plant .
SHANGHAI 1996-08-28
Shanghai-Ek Chor Motorcycle Co , a Sino-Thai joint venture , opened a new plant to produce gasoline engines in the Pudong New Area of Shanghai , the Xinhua news agency reported on Wednesday .
The plant , requiring an investment of three billion baht , has a floor space of 50,000 square metres and is designed to produce 600,000 gasoline engines a year , to be sold in China , South America , the Middle East and Africa , it said .
Capacity is expected to reach one million engines by the year 2000 , it said .
Shanghai-Ek Chor is jointly owned by the Shanghai Automobile Corporation and Ek Chor China Motorcycle .
It started operations in January 1985 and has registered capital of 1.56 billion baht , it said but gave no further details .
The joint venture has two motorcycle plants making Xingfu motorcycles and aims to be China 's biggest producer by the year 2000 , with output of two million units .
Khmer Rouge 's Ieng Sary confirms break with Pol Pot .
ARANYAPRATHET , Thailand 1996-08-28
Dissident Khmer Rouge leader Ieng Sary confirmed on Wednesday that he had broken with Pol Pot and other hardliners of the guerrilla group and had formed a rival movement .
Ieng Sary said in a written statement , the first since his split with Pol Pot earlier this month , that the new movement to be called the Democratic National United Movement ( DNUM ) would seek an end to civil war and work towards reconciliation with the Cambodian government .
" I would like to inform you about my decision to break away from Pol Pot , Ta Mok , Son Sen 's dictatorial group , " he said in a copy of the statement obtained by Reuters .
" We believe that our country will be reduced to nothing if the Khmer people continue to fight against each other indefinitely ....
For this reason we decided to break away from that dictatorial group and found a movement named ' Democratic National United Movement ' , " he said .
Ieng Sary was sentenced to death in absentia for his role in the mass genocide in Cambodia during the Khmer Rouge rule of terror between 1975-1979 when over a million people were executed or died of starvation , disease or overwork in mass labour camps .
The French-educated , former brother-in-law of Pol Pot was foreign minister in the Khmer Rouge government that ruled Cambodia and was seen as the group 's second in command .
Two dead in Cambodia helicopter crash .
PHNOM PENH 1996-08-28
Two people were killed and six were injured after a helicopter crashed in bad weather in northern Cambodia , a government minister said on Wednesday .
The 15 survivors who had been on board the Russian-made MI-17 helicopter were taken to hospital from the remote jungle crash site about 150 km ( 90 miles ) north of Phnom Penh , Information Minister Ieng Mouly said .
The cause of the crash of the helicopter , which went down on Sunday while on a routine resupply flight between Phnom Penh and Stung Treng , was not known .
Ieng Mouly said the aircraft went down during a rain storm .
MOF 's Kubo says believes BOJ rate policy unchanged .
TOKYO 1996-08-28
Japan 's Finance Minister Wataru Kubo told a news conference on Wednesday that he believes that the Bank of Japan 's ( BOJ ) interest rate policy which is geared towards ensuring economic growth has not changed after the release of the central bank 's " tankan " survey .
The BOJ released the August tankan , its quarterly short-term corporate survey , in the morning and it showed business outlook had worsened .
However , Kubo said it did not necessarily show a substantial worsening of the economy .
" The question is what the BOJ is going to do with its interest rate policy .
The BOJ governor has made it clear that the BOJ 's policy is aimed at ensuring basis for economic recovery .
I believe this policy has not changed , " he said .
Asked if a supplementary budget for 1996/97 was needed to support the economy , Kubo said the tankan results would not lead to any immediate decision on the need for an extra budget .
" I do n't think we should immediately draw a conclusion that the economic recovery has come to a halt or that signs of a economic contraction have emerged , " Kubo said . "
The economy is not recovering smoothly or at a fast pace . "
Kubo said he would make a decision on the need for a supplementary budget after an announcement in mid-September of Japan 's gross domestic product for the April-June quarter .
" I would like to see how the economy moved in the first half of 1996 , " he said .
China says militant Japan must face war past .
BEIJING 1996-08-28
China on Wednesday called on Japan to acknowledge its wartime past and put a stop to a tide of resurgent militarism to prevent similar atrocities in future .
" Some Japanese are still unrepentant about the atrocities committed by the Japanese militarists during the war , " said a commentary in the official China Daily .
" If they are still undecided whether the war Japan launched was aggressive in nature , it will be difficult to tell whether they will do the same again , " the newspaper said .
China raised indignant protests after several Japanese cabinet ministers visited a shrine dedicated to their country 's war dead on August 15 , the 51st anniversary of Japan 's World War Two surrender .
" Numerous Japanese politicians have tried to whitewash their country 's war atrocities in recent years , " the commentary said .
China estimates 35 million Chinese were killed or wounded by invading Japanese troops from 1931 to 1945 .
" The Japanese have never genuinely apologised for their wartime crimes , " the commentary said .
Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto marked the August 15 anniversary by expressing " remorse " for foreign victims of Japan 's World War Two atrocities .
Japan coalition party leader plans to resign .
TOKYO 1996-08-28
The leader of a junior partner in Japan 's three-party ruling coalition plans to resign to quell a political rebellion , party officials said on Wednesday .
The officials said New Party Sakigake President Masayoshi Takemura , finance minister until the beginning of this year , promised his resignation in a meeting with the politician who set off the rebellion in the smallest coalition member .
They said the date of Takemura 's resignation would be determined by party officials .
The Sakigake row has caused jitters in its coalition partners , Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto 's Liberal Democratic Party ( LDP ) , the biggest grouping , and the Social Democratic Party .
But analysts said the row was not expected to immediately destabilise the government as even if Sakigake splits apart it has so few seats a loss of support would not lead to a general election .
The dispute pits Takemura , who founded Sakigake in 1993 as a reform-oriented LDP splinter group , against party official Yukio Hatoyama , who says he will leave Sakigake to form a reformist political group next month .
Hatoyama , the 49-year-old grandson of a 1950s prime minister , on Tuesday quit as Sakigake secretary general and has publicly snubbed the 62-year-old Takemura , pointedly ruling his mentor out as a possible member of the new political force .
Marathon talks between the two former allies on Tuesday night and Wednesday morning failed to resolve the dispute over the role of Takemura , seen by Hatoyama backers as tainted by his senior role in the LDP-dominated coalition .
The presence of Takemura , whose role as finance minister in passing an unpopular plan to use taxpayer funds to wind up failed housing loan firms ruined his reputation as a reformer , has stalled Hatoyama 's efforts to attract to his new group defectors from the opposition camp , analysts said .
Media reports say that at most 10 of 23 Sakigake members , joined by a handful of Social Democrats , will follow Hatoyama when he bolts -- far short of the 50 lawmakers needed to topple Hashimoto 's eight-month-old government .
Hashimoto -- who returns from a 10-day Latin American tour on Saturday -- must call polls by mid-1997 , and has repeatedly said he would not call an early general election .
But many analysts and politicians believe he may dissolve parliament soon after it reconvenes in early October .
Liu Chong Hing interim net up 2.7 pct .
HONG KONG 1996-08-28
Six months ended June 30
( in million HK$ unless stated )
Shr ( H.K. cents ) 65.61 vs 63.87
Dividend ( H.K. cents ) 18.0 vs 18.0
Exceptional items nil vs nil
Net 249.53 vs 242.94
Turnover 119.49 vs 134.40
Company name Liu Chong Hing Investment Ltd
Books close September 23-27
Dividend payable October 8
NOTE - Liu Chong Hing engages in property development and investment , warehousing , banking and insurance services .
-- Hong Kong Newsroom ( 852 ) 2843 6368
Fire bomb hurled at U.S. consulate in Indonesia .
JAKARTA 1996-08-28
A fire bomb was thrown over the fence into the grounds of the U.S. Consulate-General in Indonesia 's second largest city of Surabaya but no one was hurt , a mission official said on Wednesday .
Craig Stromme , U.S. embassy spokesman in Jakarta , 700 km ( 430 miles ) west of Surabaya , confirmed the Tuesday morning attack .
" Somebody threw a molotov cocktail over the fence and it went into the parking lot .
It did n't hit anybody or anything , " Stromme said .
He said there was no immediate explanation for the attack or any information on those responsible .
Shanghai novelist murdered at home .
SHANGHAI 1996-08-28
A Shanghai novelist was murdered at her home on Sunday , an official of the city 's Writers Association said on Wednesday .
The victim was Dai Houying , who wrote about China 's 1966-76 leftist Cultural Revolution and the lives of Chinese intellectuals , the official said .
The killing was under investigation , she said .
She gave no further details .
Born in 1937 in the central province of Anhui , Dai came to Shanghai as a student and remained in the city as a prolific author and teacher of Chinese .
She was divorced and lived alone , leaving one daughter who received university education in Hawaii and lives in Chicago , a friend said .
Dai 's most famous book , " Ren A Ren " ( People , People ) , was translated into German and English , he said .
Hwa Kay plunges on rights issue , earnings .
HONG KONG 1996-08-28
Shares of Hwa Kay Thai Holdings Ltd plunged to an all-time low after the company announced a rights issue plan and also reported a sharp fall in earnings , brokers said .
The stock fell HK$ 0.23 , or 30.26 percent , to an all-time low of HK$ 0.53 .
" Investors unloaded their shares due to the poor earnings outlook following a sharp profit decline .
The rights issue also prompted dilution fears , " said a dealing director at a local brokerage .
Japan July refined zinc imports off 47.5 pct yr / yr .
TOKYO 1996-08-28
Japan 's refined zinc imports in July totalled 3,684 tonnes , off 47.5 percent from 7,011 tonnes in the same month a year earlier , according to Ministry of Finance data released on Wednesday .
Figures were as follows ( in tonnes ) :
July 96 June 96 July 95
Total 3,684 3,292 7,011
Major suppliers :
China 961 1,683 5,539
Refined zinc imports in the first seven months of 1996 totalled 115,941 tonnes , up 38.4 percent from 83,801 tonnes in the year-ago period .
-- Tokyo Commodities Desk ( 813 3432 6179 )
PRESS DIGEST - HK newspaper editorials - Aug 28 .
HONG KONG 1996-08-28
With 307 days to go before the British colony reverts to China , the Hong Kong media focused mainly on domestic issues concerning alleged pressure on a judge , cross straights relations and the democratic lobby 's relationship with Beijing .
The Beijing-funded WEN WEI PO said Taiwan 's government could not hope to stem the island 's economic and trade exchanges with China .
The paper said that using administrative power to limit economic activities across the Taiwan strait would not work .
MING PAO DAILY NEWS said it hoped Chinese officials would soon open dialogue with Hong Kong 's Democratic Party and the newly-established democracy lobby , Frontier , in order to ease anxieties in the lead-up to the handover .
The English language SOUTH CHINA MORNING POST said the judiciary needed to take swift and decisive action in investigating the allegations that a judge had been subjected to pressure in a New Zealand immigration case involving allegations of fraud .
The independence of the judiciary and the rule of law were of paramount importance to Hong Kong 's survival as a business centre .
The Chinese language daily HONG KONG ECONOMIC TIMES said the Legal Department had been indecisive in its handling of the judge 's case .
Such hesitancy on the part of the government had damaged public confidence in the rule of law , the paper said .
-- Hong Kong newsroom ( 852 ) 2843 6441
Palestinian Authority frees rights activist .
GAZA 1996-08-28
A human rights activist said on Wednesday he had been released after more than two weeks in detention that followed his call for an inquiry into the death of a Gaza man interrogated by Palestinian police .
Mohammad Dahman , director of the Gaza-based Addameer Prisoners Support Association , said he was freed on Tuesday without being charged .
Palestinian Attorney-General Khaled al-Qidra was not immediately available to comment .
Qidra had said Dahman was arrested on suspicion of making a false statement .
The activist was detained by Palestinian intelligence service agents on August 12 after publishing a statement demanding an investigation into the death of a Gaza man who had been questioned by Palestinian authorities .
The Palestinian Authority said the dead man , Nahed Dahlan , had committed suicide .
Human rights groups had protested about Dahman 's arrest in letters to Palestinian President Yasser Arafat and to Qidra .
PRESS DIGEST - Spain - Aug 28 .
Headlines from major national newspapers .
Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy .
EL PAIS
- Work groups and weekend arrest to quell juvenile violence in Basque Country
EL MUNDO
- Aleix Vidal-Quadras - Catalan nationalists are demanding my defenestration
DIARIO 16
- Catalan nationalists say the 1997 budget will make Spaniards sweat
ABC
- Worldwide alarm over child prostitution
CINCO DIAS
- Banco Santander starts conquest of the east .
EXPANSION
- Government will finish pension reform before the year 2000
GACETA DE LOS NEGOCIOS
- Caja de Madrid stagnates during struggle for presidency
Iran asks Bonn to extradite ex-president Banisadr .
BONN 1996-08-28
Iran has asked Germany to extradite its former president Abolhassan Banisadr for alleged hijacking , an Iranian embassy spokesman said on Wednesday .
Banisadr angered Tehran last week by accusing top Iranian leaders of ordering the assassination of Iranian Kurdish leaders in a Berlin restaurant in 1992 .
He made the allegations at the trial of an Iranian and four Lebanese accused of carrying out the attack .
An Iranian embassy spokesman said in response to an inquiry that Iran had formally requested Banisadr 's extradition for hijacking the military aircraft which he commandeered to flee Iran in July 1981 .
" We submitted the request three or four days ago , " he said .
German authorities could not immediately be reached for comment .
Banisadr lives under round-the-clock security in France , fearing Tehran could make an attempt on his life .
He is due back in Berlin on September 5 to continue his testimony , which has backed up German prosecutors ' allegations that Tehran ordered the attack on the exiled leaders .
Three dissidents and their translator were killed in the gangland-style machinegun attack .
Iran has warned Germany that bilateral relations could suffer if it pays heed to the testimony of Banisadr , an architect of Iran 's Islamic revolution who has been a sworn enemy of Tehran since he fell from favour after a year as president .
NATO military chiefs to visit Iberia .
BRUSSELS 1996-08-28
Top military officials from North Atlantic Treaty Organisation countries will tour Spain and Portugal next month for their annual inspection of alliance country installations and forces .
NATO said in a statement received on Wednesday that its military committee would visit the two countries between September 8 and 13 .
The committee consists of the chiefs of defence staff of each alliance country except Iceland , which has no armed forces .
NATO 's top military men -- General George Joulwan , Supreme Allied Commander Europe , and General John Sheehan , Supreme Allied Commander Atlantic -- will also attend .
The committee 's last tour was in September 1995 in Belgium , Luxembourg and the Netherlands .
REUTER
ISS says agreed sale of U.S. unit .
COPENHAGEN 1996-08-28
Danish cleaning group ISS on Wednesday said it had signed a letter of intent to sell its troubled U.S unit ISS Inc to Canadian firm Aaxis Limited .
An ISS statement said that Aaxis , with year-end 1996 assets of US$ 10.9 million and equity of $ 10.5 million , would be listed on the Montreal stock exchange , but did not say when .
It said that under the sale agreement , full financial details of which were not revealed , ISS would acquire a 25 percent stake in Aaxis which would become an associated company within the ISS group trading under the ISS name and logo .
ISS Inc senior management would continue to run the business under the new owners , it said .
Danish analysts recently estimated ISS Inc 's sale value at up to $ 118 million .
ISS said that the deal included ISS Inc operations in Mexico and the sale of ISS Inc interests in Brazil would be discussed .
On August 15 , ISS published first half 1996 results showing a two billion crown loss caused by falsified accounts in ISS Inc and said that charges and provisions earlier estimated at $ 100 million would have to be increased to $ 146 million .
It also wrote down all ISS Inc goodwill and Wednesday 's statement said that the Aaxis purchase would not necessitate further write down if the sale were completed according to the terms of the letter of intent .
-- Steve Weizman , Copenhagen newsroom +45 33969650
Iraq balks at U.N. staff for oil-for-food deal .
Evelyn Leopold
UNITED NATIONS 1996-08-28
Iraq has balked at the number of U.N. staff needed to implement the oil-for-food deal , blaming the United States for insisting on stringent monitoring .
In comments to reporters and a statement on Tuesday , Iraqi diplomats said the cost of the monitors and other staff , which Baghdad has to finance , surpasses funds allocated for electricity , water , sewers , education and agriculture .
At issue was a May 20 agreement allowing Iraq to sell $ 2 billion worth of oil to purchase badly needed food , medicine and other supplies to ease the impact of sanctions in force since its troops invaded Kuwait in August 1990 .
The Iraqi statement said the United States was " interfering and pressing to augment the number of international staff and this is not legal and not justified . "
Iraq 's deputy ambassador , Saeed Hasan , noted that the May 20 accord said that the number of personnel would be determined by the United Nations and that the government of Iraq would be consulted .
Saeed in his comments did not threaten to call off the deal and the U.N. officials said they expected it to go into force next month after Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali reports that arrangements are in place .
The U.N. Department of Humanitarian Affairs ( DHA ) , which has to coordinate the distribution of food , medicine and other goods , increased the number of monitors earlier this month at the insistence of the United States .
According to U.N. officials and diplomats , Iraq would have about $ 1.13 billion to spend for food , medicine and other goods after monies for a reparations fund for Gulf War victims and costs for U.N. weapons inspections were deducted .
The cost of the U.N. staff overseeing the distribution of food and other supplies was estimated to cost $ 31 million .
In addition another $ 12 million was anticipated to cover other expenses , such as oil experts and administrative costs .
For the distribution and supervision of humanitarian supplies the United Nations estimated it needed 1,190 people , including 267 international staff and 923 Iraqi support staff .
Of this number 64 foreign and 598 local staff would be in the northern Kurdish provinces , no longer the direct control of the Baghdad government .
Another 203 international staff and 325 Iraqis would run the programme in the central and southern parts of the country .
There are also 14 monitors to watch oil flows , 32 customs experts and four New York-based oil experts or overseers to approve contracts .
Yasushi Akashi , the DHA undersecretary-general , told the Security Council last week that the " financial requirements to support the ( humanitarian ) programme represent a very modest percentile of the total ...
roughly 3 percent . "
OFFICIAL JOURNAL CONTENTS - OJ C 251 OF AUGUST 29 , 1996 .
*
( Note - contents are displayed in reverse order to that in the printed Journal )
Aircraft noise and emissions Economic assessment of proposals for a common European Union position for CAEP 4 Consultancy services Call for tender ( 96 / C 251/09 )
Provision of overland transport services for material and equipment for European Commission delegations in European Third Countries and in the New Independent States ( NIS ) Contract notice No TRA / 96 / 003 / IAE-3 - Open procedure ( 96 / C 251/08 )
Microfiche production system Open procedure Invitation to tender DI 96/04 Micromation ( 96 / C 251/07 )
Aircraft noise and emissions Gaseous emissions from aircraft in the atmosphere Consultancy services Call for tender ( 96 / C 251/06 )
Tacis - support framework for the coordination and development of the Tacis information and communications programme Notice of open invitation to tender for a public service contract ( 96 / C 251/05 )
COUNCIL REGULATION ( EEC ) No 4064/89 ( 96 / C 251/04 )
FINANCIAL STATEMENTS OF THE EUROPEAN COAL AND STEEL COMMUNITY AT 31 DECEMBER 1995 ( 96 / C 251/03 )
Average prices and representative prices for table wines at the various marketing centres ( 96 / C 251/02 )
Ecu ( 1 ) 28 August 1996 ( 96 / C 251/01 ) END OF DOCUMENT .
EU Commission cool on changing beef cull plan .
BRUSSELS 1996-08-29
The European Commission said on Thursday it would study scientific reports saying Britain 's mad cow epidemic would die out by 2001 but offered little prospect the findings would change an agreed slaughter campaign .
" Obviously we are interested in this research .
We will ask the ( EU ) scientific and veterinary committee to examine it , " Commission spokesman Gerard Kiely told Reuters .
But he added that new research into the dynamics of the bovine spongiform encephalopathy ( BSE ) , a fatal brain-wasting disease suffered by cattle , was unlikely to alter a slaughter plan agreed by Britain and its 14 EU partners .
" We agreed that following detailed scientific analysis using a methodology which would take out the maximum number of BSE cases possible .
I think it would be very difficult to sell to the European Commission a programme which would involve the elimination of fewer BSE cases , " Kiely said .
" We will look at our approach ( to the plan ) but we wo n't get involved with the number of animals to be slaughtered , " he said .
" We have always avoided the question of numbers of animals to be slaughtered , that 's not the issue .
The issue is the protection of consumers ' health and the rapid eradication of BSE , " he added .
The reaction is likely to disappoint British farmers , who seized on research by Oxford scientists in the scientific journal Nature saying it would be hard to get rid of the disease any faster than 2001 without killing vast numbers of cattle .
The researchers predicted there would be 340 new infections and 14,000 new cases of BSE before 2001 .
British farmers ' leader called on Wednesday for an urgent meeting with ministers to discuss the report .
" I hope the government will now make it clear they believe there is a better way of dealing with this issue , " National Farmers Union president Sir David Naish told BBC radio .
Naish said there was no need for Britain to carry out a planned cull of some 147,000 cattle to which it had reluctantly agreed to placate its European partners .
" The new evidence to me means some of that proposal should be re-examined because we could get away with considerably less animals being culled if in fact scientists throughout Europe accepted this evidence , " Naish said .
The report could well reopen a damaging row between Britain and the EU , which slapped a worldwide ban on British beef after the government said there could be a link between BSE and the human form of the disease .
The issue flared in in March when government scientists admitted that people could become infected with Creutzfeldt-Jakob Disease ( CJD ) from eating BSE-infected beef .
French farmers set up blockades in mad cow protest .
PARIS 1996-08-29
Thousands of farmers threw up roadblocks across France overnight , stopping and checking lorries suspected of importing meat from outside the European Union , French radios reported on Thursday .
Radio stations said around 15,000 farmers , angered by a fall in beef prices following the mad cow disease crisis , staged protests in many areas and blockaded several main roads and motorways .
By 3 a.m. ( 0100 GMT ) more than 2,000 lorries had been stopped and searched .
European beef sales plunged after Britain announced the discovery of a likely link between bovine spongiform encephalopathy ( BSE ) , or mad cow disease , and its fatal human equivalent Creutzfeldt-Jakob Disease ( CJD ) .
GOLF - BRITISH MASTERS SECOND ROUND SCORES .
NORTHAMPTON , England 1996-08-29
Leading scores after
the second round of the British Masters on Thursday ( British
unless stated ) :
140 Robert Allenby ( Australia ) 69 71 , Mark Roe 69 71
141 Francisco Cea ( Spain ) 70 71 , Gavin Levenson ( South Africa )
66 75
142 Daniel Chopra ( Sweden ) 74 68
143 David Gilford 69 74
144 Peter O'Malley ( Australia ) 71 73 , Costantino Rocca ( Italy )
71 73 , Colin Montgomerie 68 76 , David Howell 70 74 , Mark
Davis 71 73
145 Peter Mitchell 74 71 , Philip Walton ( Ireland ) 71 74 , Retief
Goosen ( South Africa ) 71 74 , Ove Sellberg ( Sweden ) 71 74 ,
Peter Hedblom ( Sweden ) 70 75 , Pedro Linhart ( Spain ) 72 73 ,
Mike Clayton ( Australia ) 69 76 , Emanuele Canonica ( Italy )
69 76 , Miguel Angel Martin ( Spain ) 75 70
146 Iain Pyman 71 75 , Eduardo Romero ( Argentina ) 70 76 , Ian
Woosnam 70 76 , Miguel Angel Jimenez ( Spain ) 74 72 , Klas
Eriksson ( Sweden ) 71 75 , Paul Eales 75 71
147 Antoine Lebouc ( France ) 74 73 , Paul Curry 76 71 , Andrew
Coltart 72 75 , Paul Lawrie 72 75 , Jose Coceres ( Argentina )
69 78 , Raymond Russell 69 78 , Roger Chapman 71 76 , Paul
Affleck 74 73 .
CYCLING - SORENSEN WINS FOURTH STAGE OF TOUR OF NETHERLANDS .
DOETINCHEM , Netherlands 1996-08-29
Leading results and overall standings after the 19.6 kilometre fourth stage of the Tour of the Netherlands on Thursday , a time trial starting and finishing in Doetinchem .
1. Rolf Sorensen ( Denmark ) Rabobank 22 minutes 40 seconds
2. Lance Armstrong ( U.S. ) Motorola 1 second behind
3. Vyacheslav Ekimov ( Russia ) Rabobank 29 seconds behind
4. Erik Dekker ( Netherlands ) Rabobank 43
5. Giunluca Gorini ( Italy ) Aki 45
6. Erik Breukink ( Netherlands ) Rabobank 48
7. Wilfried Peeters ( Belgium ) Mapei 51
8. Bart Voskamp ( Netherlands ) TVM 53
9. Michael Andersson ( Sweden ) Telekom 54
10. Gregory Randolph ( USA ) Motorola 1 minute 3 seconds
Leading overall placings after three stages :
1. Sorensen 11.20:33
2. Armstrong 3 seconds behind
3. Ekimov 1 minute 7 seconds
4. Marco Lietti ( Italy ) MG-Technogym 1 minute 14 seconds
5. Dekker 1 minute 21 seconds
6. Breukink 1 minute 26 seconds
7. Maarten den Bakker ( Netherlands ) TVM 1 minute 31 seconds
8. Voskamp same time
9. Andersson 1 minute 32 seconds
10. Olaf Ludwig ( Germany ) Telekom 1 minute 44 seconds
The race continues on Friday with the 178 kilometre fifth-stage from Zevenaar to Venray .
CRICKET - ENGLAND BEAT PAKISTAN IN FIRST ONE-DAYER .
MANCHESTER , England 1996-08-29
England beat Pakistan by five wickets to win the first one-day ( 50 overs-a-side ) international at Old Trafford on Thursday .
Scores : Pakistan 225-5 innings closed ( Saeed Anwar 57 ) , England 226-5 in 46.4 overs ( M. Atherton 65 ) .
CYCLING - WORLD CHAMPIONSHIP RESULTS .
MANCHESTER , England 1996-08-29
Results at the world track cycling championships on Thursday :
Individual pursuit semifinals ( over 4,000 metres ) :
Chris Boardman ( Britain ) 4:15.006 beat Alexei Markov ( Russia ) 4:23.029
Andrea Collinelli ( Italy ) 4:16.141 beat Francis Moreau ( France ) 4:19.665
Moreau takes bronze medal as faster losing semifinalist .
Final :
Chris Boardman ( Britain ) 4:11.114 ( world record ) beat Andrea Collinelli ( Italy ) 4:20.341
Olympic sprint championship ( three-man teams ) :
1. Australia ( Darryn Hill , Shane Kelly , Gary Neiwand ) 44.804
seconds
2. Germany ( Jens Fiedler , Michael Hubner , Soren Lausberg )
45.455
3. France ( Laurent Gane , Florian Rousseau , Herve Thuet )
45.810
4. Greece ( Dimitrios Georgalis , Georgios Chimonetos , Lampros
Vasilopoulos ) 46.538
Women 's world sprint championship quarter-finals ( best of
three matches ) :
Magali Faure ( France ) beat Kathrin Freitag ( Germany ) two
matches to nil ( with times for the last 200 metres of 11.833
seconds and 12.033 seconds )
Felicia Ballanger ( France ) beat Oksana Grichina ( Russia ) 2-0 ,
( 11.776 / 12.442 )
Tanya Dubnicoff ( Canada ) beat Michelle Ferris ( Australia ) 2-0 ,
( 12.211 / 12.208 )
Annett Neumann ( Germany ) beat Galina Enioukhina ( Russia ) 2-0 ,
( 12.434 / 12.177).
CRICKET - CROFT RESTRICTS PAKISTAN TO 225-5 .
MANCHESTER , England 1996-08-29
Tight bowling from Glamorgan off-spinner Robert Croft helped England to restrict Pakistan to 225 for five in their 50 overs in the first one-day international at Old Trafford on Thursday .
Croft , who was one of the few Englishmen to make a good impression in his test debut at The Oval last week , showed great control as he first dried up the early flow of Pakistan runs and then collected the wickets of Aamir Sohail and Wasim Akram in a spell of 10-1-36-2 .
There was also a wicket each for Ronnie Irani , Allan Mullally and Darren Gough although there was no joy for Dean Headley who , along with Lancashire batsman Graham Lloyd , was making his international debut .
After Wasim had won the toss and chosen to bat first , Pakistani made an excellent start as Sohail and Saeed Anwar continued their good form with an opening partnership of 82 .
Anwar , who struck a superb 176 at The Oval , was the more aggressive as he made 57 from 75 balls before skying a catch off Irani to Mullally at long-on .
Sohail and Ijaz Ahmed then added 59 for the second wicket before England struck back with three wickets for 19 in the space of five overs .
First , Sohail , after making 48 , was bowled by Croft as he stepped back to try and hit through the off-side .
Wasim , who promoted himself to number four in the order , followed for six when Croft drifted another well-flighted delivery behind his legs .
Shortly after Ijaz was also back in the pavilion for 48 after Irani had repaid Mullally with another good catch at long-on .
Gough later bowled Moin Khan with an inswinging yorker but Inzamam-ul-Haq , 37 not out , and Salim Malik took Pakistan to 225 for five when the overs ran out .
CRICKET - ENGLAND V PAKISTAN ONE-DAY SCOREBOARD .
MANCHESTER , England 1996-08-29
Scoreboard of the
first one-day ( 50 overs-a-side ) match between England and
Pakistan at Old Trafford on Thursday :
Pakistan
Saeed Anwar c Mullally b Irani 57
Aamir Sohail b Croft 48
Ijaz Ahmed c Irani b Mullally 48
Wasim Akram b Croft 6
Inzamam-ul-Haq not out 37
Moin Khan b Gough 10
Salim Malik not out 6
Extras ( b-2 lb-4 w-7 ) 13
Total ( for 5 wickets , innings closed ) 225
Fall : 1-82 2-141 3-160 4-174 5-203 .
Did Not Bat : Mushtaq Ahmed , Waqar Younis , Ata-ur-Rehman ,
Saqlain Mushtaq .
Bowling : Gough 10-0-44-1 , Mullally 10-3-31-1 , Headley
10-0-52-0 , Irani 10-0-56-1 , Croft 10-1-36-2 .
England
N. Knight c Moin Khan b Wasim Akram 26
A. Stewart lbw b Waqar Younis 48
M. Atherton b Wasim Akram 65
G. Thorpe st Moin Khan b Aamir Sohail 23
M. Maynard b Wasim Akram 41
G. Lloyd not out 2
R. Irani not out 6
Extras ( lb-4 w-7 nb-4 ) 15
Total ( for 5 wickets , 46.4 overs ) 226
Fall of wickets : 1-57 2-98 3-146 4-200 5-220 .
Did not bat : R. Croft , D. Gough , D. Headley , A. Mullally .
Bowling : Wasim Akram 9.4-1-45-3 , Waqar Younis 7-0-28-1 ,
Saqlain Mushtaq 10-1-54-0 , Ata-ur-Rehman 3-0-14-0 , Mushtaq Ahmed
10-0-52-0 , Aamir Sohail 7-1-29-1 .
Result : England won by five wickets .
Second match : August 31 , Edgbaston ( Birmingham )
Third : September 1 , Trent Bridge ( Nottingham )
LOMBARDI WINS THIRD STAGE OF TOUR OF NETHERLANDS .
DOETINCHEM , Netherlands 1996-08-29
Leading results and overall standings after the 122 kilometre third stage of the Tour of the Netherlands on Thursday between Almere and Doetinchem .
1. Giovanni Lombardi ( Italy ) Polti 2 hours 35 minutes
29 seconds
2. Rolf Sorensen ( Denmark ) Rabobank
3. Lance Armstrong ( U.S. ) Motorola
4. Maarten den Bakker ( Netherlands ) TVM all same time
5. Marco Lietti ( Italy ) MG-Technogym 1 second behind
6. Hans de Clerq ( Belgium ) Palmans 27 seconds
7. Marty Jemison ( U.S. ) U.S. Postal
8. Servais Knaven ( Netherlands ) TVM
9. Olaf Ludwig ( Germany ) Telekom all same time
10. Jeroen Blijlevens ( Netherlands ) TVM 31
Leading overall placings after three stages :
1. Sorensen 10.57:33
2. Lombardi 1 second behind
3. Armstrong 2 seconds
4. Den Bakker 7
5. Lietti 8
6. Federico Colonna ( Italy ) Mapei 27
7. Max van Heeswijk ( Netherlands ) Motorola 28
8. Sven Teutenberg ( Germany ) U.S. Postal 31
9. Johan Capiot ( Belgium ) Collstrop 32
10. Jans Koerts ( Netherlands ) Palmans 34
The race continues on Thursday afternoon with a 19.6 fourth-stage Doetinchem-Doetinchem time trial
CRICKET - ENGLAND V PAKISTAN TOSS AND TEAMS .
MANCHESTER , England 1996-08-29
Pakistan won the toss and elected to bat in the first one-day cricket international between England and Pakistan at Old Trafford on Thursday .
Teams :
England - Mike Atherton ( captain ) , Nick Knight , Alec Stewart , Graham Thorpe , Matthew Maynard , Graham Lloyd , Ronnie Irani , Robert Croft , Darren Gough , Dean Headley , Alan Mullally .
Pakistan : Aamir Sohail , Saeed Anwar , Ijaz Ahmed , Inzamam-ul-Haq , Salim Malik , Wasim Akram ( captain ) , Moin Khan , Mushtaq Ahmed , Waqar Younis , Ata-ur-Rehman , Saqlain Mushtaq .
CRICKET - ENGLISH COUNTY CHAMPIONSHIP SCORES .
LONDON 1996-08-29
Close of play scores in English county championship matches on Thursday :
Tunbridge Wells : Nottinghamshire 40-3 v Kent
London ( The Oval ) : Warwickshire 195 ( A. Giles 50 ; B. Julian 4-66 , C. Lewis 4-45 ) , Surrey 82-0 .
Hove : Sussex 285-6 ( W. Athey 111 ) v Lancashire
Leeds ( Headingley ) : Yorkshire 290 ( C. White 76 , M. Moxon 59 , R. Blakey 57 ) , Essex 79-2 .
Chester-le-Street : Glamorgan 259 ( P. Cottey 81 ; M. Saggers 6-65 ) and 8-0 , Durham 114 ( S. Watkin 4-28 )
Chesterfield : Worcestershire 238 ( W. Weston 100 not out , V. Solanki 58 ; A. Harris 4-31 ) , Derbyshire 166-1 ( K. Barnett 83 not out )
Portsmouth : Middlesex 199 and 226-1 ( J. Pooley 106 not out , M. Ramprakash 81 not out ) , Hampshire 232 ( A. Fraser 5-55 , R. Fay 4-77 )
Leicester : Somerset 83 ( D. Millns 4-35 ) , Leicestershire 202-5
Bristol : Gloucestershire 183 ( J. Russell 50 ) , Northamptonshire 123-4 ( K. Curran 51 not out ) .
RUGBY UNION - TELFER CONFIRMED FOR LIONS COACHING ROLE .
LONDON 1996-08-30
Scotland 's Jim Telfer was officially confirmed on Thursday as assistant coach for the British Lions tour to South Africa next year .
Telfer , who has put on hold his role as Scotland team manager for a year , will act as assistant to Ian McGeechan .
The pair last worked together when Scotland won the Five Nations grand slam in 1990 .
The tour party will be announced towards the end of March .
ATHLETICS - CHRISTIE TO RUN IN BERLIN .
LONDON 1996-08-29
Linford Christie has confirmed he will run in a " Dream Team " sprint relay at the Berlin grand prix athletics meeting on Friday .
A spokeswoman for Christie said the former Olympic 100 metres champion had agreed to captain a quality quartet which also includes Canada 's Donovan Bailey , the current Olympic champion and world record holder , and Namibian Frankie Fredericks .
Christie is retiring from international competition at the end of the season , but Berlin promoter Rudi Thiel has persuaded him to join what is intended to be a special tribute to Jesse Owens , who won four gold medals 60 years ago at the Berlin Olympics .
SOCCER - GROBBELAAR NAMED TEMPORARY ZIMBABWE COACH .
HARARE 1996-08-29
England-based goalkeeper Bruce Grobbelaar has been appointed temporary head coach of the Zimbabwe national soccer team for two international matches , the Zimbabwe Football Association ( ZIFA ) said on Thursday .
ZIFA vice-chairman Vincent Pamire said Grobbelaar would take charge for a match against Tanzania in Harare on September 29 in the five-nation Castle Cup of Africa tournament and an African Nations ' Cup first round qualifier against Sudan in Khartoum on October 5 .
Grobbelaar takes over until a permanent replacement is appointed for Zimbabwe 's previous coach , Switzerland 's Marc Duvillard .
Grobbelaar now plays for English second division leaders Plymouth Argyle after years in the top flight with Liverpool and Southampton .
Grobbelaar , fellow goalkeeper Hans Segers , retired striker John Fashanu and Malaysian businessman Heng Suan Lim pleaded not guilty in May to charges of giving or accepting bribes to fix English premier league matches .
They are due to stand trial next January .
BASKETBALL - OLYMPIAKOS BEAT DINAMO 69-60 .
BELGRADE 1996-08-29
Olympiakos of Greece beat Russia 's Dinamo 69-60 ( halftime 35-23 ) in the third match of an international basketball tournament on Thursday , qualifying for the finals .
Partizan and Red Star of Yugoslavia , Alba of Germany , and Benetton of Italy are also taking part in the event which continues until Saturday .
Add results
Partizan beat Benetton 97-94 ( halftime 39-32 ) .
Final Partizan v Olympiakos .
SQUASH - HONG KONG OPEN SECOND ROUND RESULTS .
HONG KONG 1996-08-29
Second round results in the Hong Kong Open on Thursday ( prefix number denotes seeding ) :
1 - Jansher Khan ( Pakistan ) beat Simon Frenz ( Germany ) 15-12 15-7 12-15 15-10
Mark Cairns ( England ) beat Joseph Kneipp ( Australia ) 8-15 15-12 15-8 15-8
Anthony Hill ( Australia ) beat Mir Zaman Gul ( Pakistan ) 15-12 15-11 15-13
Dan Jenson ( Australia ) beat 3 - Brett Martin ( Australia ) 15-9 17-14 7-15 9-15 15-14
4 - Peter Nicol ( Scotland ) beat Jonathon Power ( Canada ) 15-10 15-9 15-9
7 - Chris Walker ( England ) beat Amr Shabana ( Egypt ) 15-13 15-10 15-6
Derek Ryan ( Ireland ) beat Paul Johnson ( England ) 10-15 15-5 12-15 15-12 15-11
2 - Rodney Eyles ( Australia ) beat Zubair Jahan Khan ( Pakistan ) 15-10 15-8 9-15 13-15 15-4 .
SOCCER - RESULTS OF SOUTH KOREAN PRO-SOCCER GAMES .
SEOUL 1996-08-29
Results of South Korean pro-soccer
games played on Wednesday .
Chonan 4 Anyang 1 ( halftime 1-0 )
Suwon 4 Pusan 0 ( halftime 2-0 )
Standings after games played on Wednesday ( tabulate under -
won , drawn , lost , goals for , goals against , points ) :
W D L G / F G / A P
Chonan 3 0 1 13 10 9
Puchon 2 1 0 4 0 7
Suwon 1 3 0 7 3 6
Pohang 1 1 1 8 8 4
Ulsan 1 0 1 6 6 3
Anyang 0 3 1 6 9 3
Chonnam 0 2 1 4 5 2
Pusan 0 2 1 3 7 2
Chonbuk 0 0 2 2 5 0
BASEBALL - RESULTS OF S. KOREAN PRO-BASEBALL GAMES .
SEOUL 1996-08-29
Results of South Korean
pro-baseball games played on Wednesday .
LG 5 OB 1
OB 4 LG 3
Ssangbangwool 12 Hanwha 0
Hanwha 12 Ssangbangwool 5
Lotte 4 Hyundai 0
Samsung 7 Haitai 1
Note - LG and OB , Ssangbangwool and Hanwha played two games .
Standings after games played on Wednesday ( tabulate under
won , drawn , lost , winning percentage , games behind first place )
W D L PCT GB
Haitai 63 2 42 .598 -
Ssangbangwool 59 2 48 .500 5
Hanwha 57 1 49 .537 6 1/2
Hyundai 56 5 48 .536 6 1/2
Samsung 48 5 55 .468 14
Lotte 45 6 53 .462 14 1/2
LG 45 5 59 .436 17 1/2
OB 42 6 61 .413 20
TENNIS - THURSDAY 'S RESULTS FROM THE U.S. OPEN .
NEW YORK 1996-08-29
Results of second round matches on Thursday in the U.S. Open Tennis Championships at the National Tennis Centre ( prefix number denotes seeding ) :
Women 's singles
Anna Kournikova ( Russia ) beat Natalia Baudone ( Italy ) 6-3 6-3
Rita Grande ( Italy ) beat Tina Krizan ( Slovenia ) 6-2 6-0
Els Callens ( Belgium ) beat Annabel Ellwood ( Australia ) 6-4
1-6 6-1
Elena Likhovtseva ( Russia ) beat Lila Osterloh ( U.S. ) 6-4 6-2
Sandra Dopfer ( Austria ) beat Nanne Dahlman ( Finland ) 2-6 6-2
6- 3
Men 's singles
13 - Thomas Enqvist ( Sweden ) beat Guillaume Raoux ( France ) 6-3
6- 2 6-3
Sergi Bruguera ( Spain ) beat Michael Stich ( Germany ) 6-3 6-2
6-4
Jakob Hlasek ( Switzerland ) beat Alberto Berasategui ( Spain ) 7-6 ( 7-5 ) 7-6 ( 9-7 ) 6-0
Women 's singles , second round
1 - Steffi Graf ( Germany ) beat Karin Kschwendt ( Austria ) 6-2 6-1
Naoko Kijimuta ( Japan ) beat Alexandra Fusai ( France ) 6-4 7-5
Natasha Zvereva ( Belarus ) beat Ai Sugiyama ( Japan ) 4-6 6-4 6-3
14 - Barbara Paulus ( Austria ) beat Elena Wagner ( Germany ) 7-5 7-6 ( 7-5 )
Petra Langrova ( Czech Republic ) beat Naoko Sawamatsu ( Japan ) 6- 4 3-6 7-5
17 - Karina Habsudova ( Slovakia ) beat Nathalie Dechy ( France ) 6-4 6-2
Women 's singles , second round
7 - Jana Novotna ( Czech Republic ) beat Florencia Labat ( Argentina ) 6-2 4-6 6-2
Men 's singles , second round
3 - Thomas Muster ( Austria ) beat Dirk Dier ( Germany ) 6-3 6-2 6-4
Pablo Campana ( Ecuador ) beat Mark Knowles ( Bahamas ) 7-6 ( 7-3 ) 3 - 6 6-3 6-7 ( 3-7 ) 6-3
Jason Stoltenberg ( Australia ) beat Kenneth Carlsen ( Denmark ) 6- 3 7-6 ( 7-1 ) 6-3
Arnaud Boetsch ( France ) beat Magnus Gustafsson ( Sweden ) 7-6 ( 8- 6 ) 6-3 6-1
Add Women 's singles , second round
16 - Martina Hingis ( Switzerland ) beat Miriam Oremans ( Netherlands ) 6-4 6-4
Tami Whitlinger Jones ( U.S. ) beat Amy Frazier ( U.S. ) 7-6 ( 7-3 ) 6-2
Judith Wiesner ( Austria ) beat Debbie Graham ( U.S. ) 6-2 7-5
Add Men 's singles , second round
6 - Andre Agassi ( U.S. ) beat Leander Paes ( India ) 3-6 6-4 6-1 6-0
Javier Sanchez ( Spain ) beat Jim Grabb ( U.S. ) 6-2 7-6 ( 7-3 ) 2-6 6-3
Hernan Gumy ( Argentina ) beat Jared Palmer ( U.S. ) 6-7 ( 5-7 ) 6-3 7-6 ( 7-4 ) 0-6 7-6 ( 7-1 )
:
Women 's singles , second round
3 - Arantxa Sanchez Vicario ( Spain ) beat Nicole Arendt ( U.S. )
6-2 6-2
Men 's singles , second round
David Wheaton ( U.S. ) beat Frederic Vitoux ( France ) 6-4 6-4
4-6 7-6 ( 7-4 )
Jan Siemerink ( Netherlands ) beat Carlos Moya ( Spain ) 7-6
( 7-2 ) 6-4 6-4
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE STANDINGS AFTER WEDNESDAY 'S GAMES .
NEW YORK 1996-08-29
Major League Baseball
standings after games played on Wednesday ( tabulate under won ,
lost , winning percentage and games behind ) :
AMERICAN LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
NEW YORK 74 58 .561 -
BALTIMORE 70 62 .530 4
BOSTON 69 65 .515 6
TORONTO 63 71 .470 12
DETROIT 47 86 .353 27 1/2
CENTRAL DIVISION
CLEVELAND 80 53 .602 -
CHICAGO 71 64 .526 10
MINNESOTA 66 67 .496 14
MILWAUKEE 64 70 .478 16 1/2
KANSAS CITY 61 73 .455 19 1/2
WESTERN DIVISION
TEXAS 75 58 .564 -
SEATTLE 69 63 .523 5 1/2
OAKLAND 64 72 .471 12 1/2
CALIFORNIA 61 72 .459 14
THURSDAY , AUGUST 29TH SCHEDULE
KANSAS CITY AT DETROIT
MINNESOTA AT MILWAUKEE
NEW YORK AT CALIFORNIA
BALTIMORE AT SEATTLE
NATIONAL LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
ATLANTA 82 49 .626 -
MONTREAL 71 60 .542 11
FLORIDA 63 70 .474 20
NEW YORK 59 74 .444 24
PHILADELPHIA 54 80 .403 29 1/2
CENTRAL DIVISION
HOUSTON 72 62 .537 -
ST LOUIS 69 64 .519 2 1/2
CINCINNATI 65 67 .492 6
CHICAGO 64 66 .492 6
PITTSBURGH 56 76 .424 15
WESTERN DIVISION
SAN DIEGO 74 60 .552 -
LOS ANGELES 71 61 .538 2
COLORADO 70 64 .522 4
SAN FRANCISCO 57 74 .435 15 1/2
THURSDAY , AUGUST 29TH SCHEDULE
SAN DIEGO AT NEW YORK
CHICAGO AT HOUSTON
CINCINNATI AT COLORADO
ATLANTA AT PITTSBURGH
LOS ANGELES AT MONTREAL
FLORIDA AT ST LOUIS
BASEBALL - YANKEES BRAWL AND CONTINUE TO SLIDE .
SEATTLE 1996-08-29
Jay Buhner hit a three-run homer and former Yankee Terry Mulholland allowed one run over seven innings as the Seattle Mariners completed a sweep of New York with a 10-2 victory in a game marred by a bench-clearing brawl .
Including the last three games of last October 's Divisional Playoff Series , the Mariners have beaten the Yankees 12 of the past 15 meetings overall and 14 of the last 16 in the Kingdome .
Five players were ejected after Yankees ' outfielder Paul O'Neill and Seattle catcher John Marzano got into a fight after O'Neill had been brushed back .
In Baltimore , Don Wengert threw a nine-hitter for his first shutout and Jose Herrera had a two-run double in a three-run fifth inning as the Oakland Athletics blanked the Baltimore Orioles 3-0 .
Wengert ( 7-9 ) , who failed to record a shutout in his previous 86 starts in either the minors or majors , did not walk a batter and struck out three for Oakland .
In Chicago , James Baldwin scattered five hits over seven scoreless innings and Ray Durham and Ozzie Guillen had RBI hits in the second inning as the Chicago White Sox blanked the Milwaukee Brewers 2-0 .
Baldwin ( 10-4 ) struck out four and did not walk a batter for Chicago , which won for only the fourth time in 15 games .
Dave Nilsson had three hits for the Brewers .
In Kansas City , Jose Offerman 's single with two out in the 12th inning scored Johnny Damon with the winning run and lifted the Kansas City Royals to a 4-3 victory over the Texas Rangers .
Rick Huisman ( 1-1 ) allowed one hit and a walk in the 12th to post his first major-league win .
In Toronto , Pat Hentgen tossed a five-hitter for his fifth consecutive complete game and three players drove in two runs apiece as the Toronto Blue Jays defeated the Minnesota Twins 6-1 for their ninth win in 11 games .
Hentgen ( 17-7 ) surrendered just three doubles and a pair of singles in tossing his major-league leading ninth complete game .
He walked three and struck out three in winning for the 10th time in his last 11 decisions .
In Detroit , Orel Hershiser recorded his fourth straight win and Albert Belle snapped a sixth-inning tie with a grand slam as the Cleveland Indians completed a season sweep of the Detroit Tigers with a 9-3 victory .
Hershiser ( 14-7 ) , who allowed three runs , eight hits and one walk with five strikeouts over seven innings , improved to 4-0 in his last six starts , including a pair of wins over Detroit in the last 11 days .
At California ,
In Seattle ,
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE RESULTS WEDNESDAY .
NEW YORK 1996-08-29
Results of Major League
Baseball games played on Wednesday ( home team in CAPS ) :
National League
COLORADO 10 Cincinnati 9
MONTREAL 6 Los Angeles 5
Atlanta 9 PITTSBURGH 4
San Diego 3 NEW YORK 2 ( 10 innings )
HOUSTON 5 Chicago 4 ( 11 innings )
Florida 3 ST LOUIS 2 ( 10 innings )
SAN FRANCISCO 7 Philadelphia 6
American League
Cleveland 9 DETROIT 3
CHICAGO 2 Milwaukee 0
Oakland 3 BALTIMORE 0
TORONTO 6 Minnesota 1
KANSAS CITY 4 Texas 3 ( 12 innings )
Boston 7 CALIFORNIA 4
SEATTLE 10 New York 2
TENNIS - MARTINEZ GETS AGGRESSIVE AT U.S. OPEN .
Larry Fine
NEW YORK 1996-08-28
Conchita Martinez decided that when in New York , do as the New Yorkers do -- and the Spaniard 's new-found aggressiveness seems to have put her in the right frame of mind for the U.S. Open .
The fourth-seeded Spaniard , who is tackling the world class traffic of New York City as a warm-up by driving to the tennis centre for her matches , ran over France 's Nathalie Tauziat 6-1 6-3 on Wednesday to take her place in the third round .
" I 've been trying my whole career to be aggressive , " said the 24-year-old Martinez after crushing Tauziat in just over an hour .
" What I 'm trying to do is be aggressive all the time , maybe go up to the net a few times like I did tonight .
That would really help . "
Martinez , the 1994 Wimbledon champion , used to struggle at the Open , but has come to terms with the noise , crowds and chaos .
" There is a lot of things that can happen , " Martinez said about her early difficulties adjusting to tennis on the cement at Flushing Meadows .
" Like traffic .
We stay in Manhattan and it 's a long way to come .
The crowds , they speak louder or they move .
That does n't happen in other Grand Slams .
That 's where the real champion wins .
You have to concentrate for these two weeks . "
It took Martinez four Opens to get as far as the quarters , and another four to match that .
Last year , Martinez , who finished 1995 ranked second in the world , reached the semifinals before bowing out to Monica Seles .
Now she feels she is in the swing of things .
" I have my own car now and that helps , " said Martinez .
" Sometimes the transportation they ( the tournament ) provide gets a little messed up .
This time it did n't happen .
I do the driving and I love it .
It gets my adrenalin going , those taxi drivers .
" We change lanes all the time in Barcelona .
I 'm used to it and I like to drive fast . "
BASEBALL - BRAVES SIGN NEAGLE .
ATLANTA 1996-08-28
The defending world champion Atlanta Braves , with the best record and best pitching in baseball , added another weapon Wednesday , acquiring Denny Neagle , the winningest left-hander in the National League , from the Pittsburgh Pirates .
The Pirates , who conceded earlier this week they would be forced to trim salary from next season 's payroll , received Ron Wright , a first baseman at Double-A Greenville ; Corey Pointer , a pitcher at Class-A Eugene , and a player to be named .
It was another stunning mid-season acquisition for the Braves , who already have an 11-game lead in the National League Eastern Division .
In the last 15 days , Atlanta has traded for third baseman Terry Pendleton , claimed outfielder Luis Polonia on waivers and called up minor-league phenom Andruw Jones , all in preparation for their fifth post-season .
SOCCER - DUTCH FIRST DIVISION SUMMARY .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-28
Summary of Dutch first division soccer match played on Thursday :
NAC Breda 1 ( Abdellaoui 20th penalty ) NEC Nijmegen 1 ( Graef 36th ) .
Halftime 1-1 .
Attendance 10,760 .
SOCCER - DUTCH FIRST DIVISION RESULTS / STANDINGS .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-29
Result of a Dutch first
division soccer match played on Thursday :
NAC Breda 1 NEC Nijmegen 1
Played on Wednesday :
Vitesse Arnhem 1 Sparta Rotterdam 1
Utrecht 0 Twente Enschede 0
Groningen 1 Roda JC Kerkrade 1
Feyenoord 2 Graafschap Doetinchem 1
Willem II Tilburg 1 RKC Waalwijk 3
Volendam 1 PSV Eindhoven 3
Ajax Amsterdam 1 AZ Alkmaar 0
Played on Tuesday :
Fortuna Sittard 2 Heerenveen 4
Standings ( tabulate under played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , goals against , points ) :
PSV Eindhoven 3 3 0 0 11 3 9
Feyenoord Rotterdam 3 2 1 0 6 2 7
Vitesse Arnhem 3 2 1 0 4 1 7
Heerenveen 3 2 0 1 7 5 6
Ajax Amsterdam 3 2 0 1 2 2 6
Twente Enschede 3 1 2 0 4 2 5
RKC Waalwijk 3 1 1 1 7 6 4
Graafschap Doetinchem 3 1 1 1 5 5 4
NAC Breda 3 1 1 1 2 2 4
Fortuna Sittard 3 1 1 1 3 4 4
Roda JC Kerkrade 3 0 3 0 3 3 3
Utrecht 3 0 2 1 2 3 2
Sparta Rotterdam 3 0 2 1 1 2 2
Groningen 3 0 2 1 2 5 2
NEC Nijmegen 3 0 2 1 2 5 2
Willem II Tilburg 3 0 1 2 1 4 1
AZ Alkmaar 3 0 1 1 0 3 1
Volendam 3 0 1 2 2 7 1
ATHLETICS - JOHNSON , CHRISTIE , BAILEY TO RUN OWENS RELAY .
Adrian Warner
BERLIN 1996-08-29
Olympic champions Michael Johnson and Donovan Bailey and former champion Linford Christie will run in a " Dream Team " sprint relay squad in honour of Jesse Owens on Friday .
Johnson , the 200 metres world record holder , and Britain 's 1992 Olympic 100 champion Christie confirmed on Thursday that they would join 100 record holder Bailey and Namibia 's Frankie Fredericks in one of the greatest 4x100 squads ever assembled .
They will run against quartets from the United States , Europe and Africa in a special race at the Berlin Grand Prix meeting to mark the 60th anniversary of Owens 's four gold medals at the 1936 Olympics in the German capital .
Christie will run the anchor leg after Canada 's Bailey , American Johnson and Olympic silver medallist Fredericks have run the first three stages of the relay .
The participation of Bailey and Fredericks had been known before Thursday .
But Christie did not announce his decision to run until the eve of the meeting when organisers also confirmed Johnson would take part .
Christie is due to retire from international competition at the end of the season although he may compete for Britain in next season 's European Cup .
Although Christie , who is not racing the individual 100 metres in Berlin , took his time to agree to run , the veteran was clearly delighted to be part of the tribute to the black American .
When five former Olympic 100 champions from 1948 to 1980 , who have been invited to watch the race , turned up at a news conference on Thursday , Christie was quick to put his autograph book in front of the them .
" I do n't normally do this but can you please sign , " he said thrusting an ornate white book in front of Americans Harrison Dillard ( 1948 ) , Lindy Remigino ( 1952 ) , Jim Hines ( 1968 ) , Trinidad 's Hasely Crawford ( 1976 ) and Britain 's Allan Wells ( 1980 ) .
" Jesse Owens inspired everyone here and it is great to have a tribute to him . "
Owens 's widow Ruth is not well enough to attend but a message from her will be read out by the sprinter 's grand-daughter Gina Tillman during the meeting
Berlin organisers hoped to have American 1984 and 1988 champion Carl Lewis in the squad but he injured himself in last Friday 's Brussels meeting .
SOCCER - GENOA AWARDED ITALIAN CUP WIN .
MILAN 1996-08-29
Italian soccer 's sports judge on Thursday ruled that Genoa , beaten 3-0 by Lecce in the first round of the Italian Cup , should be awarded a 2-0 victory because their opponents fielded a banned player .
The ruling meant that serie B club Genoa now meet local serie A arch-rivals Sampdoria in the second round .
Genoa appealed after their defeat last Saturday on the grounds that Lecce striker Jonathan Bachini , who came on in the 71st minute with his team leading 2-0 , still had a one-match suspension to serve from last season .
SOCCER - NICE SACK COACH EMON .
NICE , France 1996-08-29
Struggling French first division side Nice on Thursday announced they were parting with coach Albert Emon after a string of poor results .
Club president Andre Bois said a successor would be named on Friday .
A former player for Marseille and Monaco , Emon , 43 , has coached Nice since 1992 .
The announcement came 24 hours after the team from the French Riviera lost at home to Guingamp 2-1 in a league match .
Nice are 18th in the table .
SOCCER - THREE PULL OUT OF DUTCH SQUAD FOR BRAZIL .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-29
Three Dutch players have pulled out of the squad for Saturday 's friendly international soccer match against Brazil in Amsterdam .
Ajax defender John Veldman and his team mate Richard Witschge are injured , while PSV midfielder Philip Cocu has a fever .
Dutch coach Guus Hiddink called in Feyenoord midfielder Giovanni van Bronckhorst and Vitesse defender Ferdy Vierklau for Cocu and Veldman , but did not name a replacement for midfielder Witschge .
BRITAIN WELCOMES ROMANIA-HUNGARY TREATY ACCORD .
BUCHAREST 1996-08-29
Britain joined the United States on Thursday in welcoming Romania and Hungary 's agreement on the text of a much-delayed friendship treaty , which it said would contribute to stability in the area .
" The United Kingdom believes that such a treaty will contribute positively to the further development of good neighbourly relations between the two countries and enhance the stability of the region , " said the British Foreign office statement .
The accord , agreed two weeks ago , is expected to end years of disputes over the status of Romania 's large ethnic Hungarian minority .
It will also boost both countries ' ambitions to join NATO and the European Union .
Bucharest and Budapest say the treaty should be signed in the first half of September .
" The United Kingdom looks forward to the early signature of the treaty , " the statement said .
U.S. EMBASSY IN ATHENS CLOSED ON LABOUR DAY , SEP 2 .
ATHENS 1996-08-29
The U.S. embassy in Athens , the consulates general in Athens and Thessaloniki and all U.S. government offices in Greece will be closed on Monday , September 2 in observance of Labour Day , a U.S. national holiday , the embassy said .
-- George Georgiopoulos , Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4
ND PARTY PICKS SPOT THOMSON , BOLD / OGILVY , MATHER FOR AD CAMPAIGN .
ATHENS 1996-08-29
Greek conservative New democracy party picked Bold / Ogilvy and Mather advertising companies for its pre-election campaign and Spot Thomson to help party president Miltiadis Evert on communication strategy , it said in a statement .
Spot Thomson will also be responsible for the campaign TV and radio spots , it said .
-- Dimitris Kontogiannis , Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4
Rugby star once linked to Princess Diana divorces .
LONDON 1996-08-29
Former England rugby captain Will Carling , whose marriage broke down after he was romantically linked to Princess Diana , was divorced by his wife on Thursday , just 24 hours after Diana and Prince Charles divorced .
The Times newspaper said Diana was not named in the divorce petition heard by a court in Surrey , southern England .
But Julia Carling , a television presenter , is said to have blamed Diana for the problems in her marriage and she has repeatedly mocked the princess on her breakfast television programme .
Diana met Will Carling at an exclusive gymnasium in London .
He has always insisted that they were just friends .
London LIFFE futures APT closing prices .
LONDON 1996-08-29
London International Financial Futures Exchange automated pit trading ( APT ) tabular details :
CONTRACT ( MONTH ) APT CLOSE SETTLEMENT PREVIOUS SETTLE
LONG GILT ( SEP ) ( 1/32 ) 107-12 107-10 107-06
SHORT STERLING ( SEP ) 94.26 94.26 94.26
GERMAN GOVT BOND ( SEP ) 97.42 97.38 97.34
EUROMARK ( SEP ) 96.84 96.83 96.83
ITALIAN GOVT BOND ( SEP ) 115.62 115.58 115.32
EUROLIRA ( SEP ) 91.37 91.36 91.33
EUROSWISS ( SEP ) 97.79 97.80 97.82
FTSE 100 ( SEP ) 3,894.00 3,894.00 3,941.50
Zaire installs first election delegates .
KINSHASA 1996-08-29
A total of 116 delegates to Zaire 's National Election Commission ( CNE ) were formally installed on Thursday , launching another phase of the Central African nation 's much-delayed democratic transition .
The 116 , representing political parties in the capital Kinshasa , will help organise a voter census , a constitutional referendum planned for January and efforts to brief potential voters on what balloting involves .
A total of 9,446 delegates will be deployed throughout Zaire 's 11 provinces for the elections , which must be held by July 1997 under the transitional constitution .
Presidential , parliamentary and municipal elections are planned for May .
" We can meet the required deadlines for organising the elections .
All that is needed is for everyone to show goodwill , " Commission spokesman Yoka Lye Mudaba told reporters .
Delegates to the commission from the other 10 provinces will be installed progressively from next week with the provinces of North and South Kivu , Maniema , Shaba and Bandundu having priority , he said .
The installation of delegates was initially scheduled for July .
Officials said lack of funding had delayed the process .
President Mobutu Sese Seko , who seized power in a 1965 coup , introduced a multi-party system in 1990 but Zaire 's transition has lagged well behind that of other states in the region .
In the past , Mobutu has been elected without opposition .
Nigeria would not refuse Commonwealth officials .
LAGOS 1996-08-29
Nigeria would not object to a visit by Commonwealth officials but insists its suspension from the organisation be resolved before any other questions are addressed , Foreign Minister Tom Ikimi said on Thursday .
Ikimi reiterated his position that the Commonwealth had no mandate to send a fact-finding mission .
" The request I have received is for their officials to come and talk to my officials .
We cannot object to people wanting to visit Nigeria , " Ikimi told Reuters by telephone from the capital Abuja .
" The fundamental problem we have with the Commonwealth is our unfair suspension .
Any discussions we have at ministerial level will be a continuation of what we began in London on that .
Before that is accomplished we cannot address anything else . "
Nigeria was suspended from the Commonwealth in November after the execution of Ken Saro-Wiwa and eight other minority rights activists in defiance of international pleas for clemency .
A meeting of Commonwealth ministers in London on Wednesday said it planned to send a team of senior officials to Nigeria as soon as possible to persuade Abuja to accept a fact-finding mission .
The timing of that mission has yet to be determined .
The latest diplomatic row between Nigeria 's military government and the club of Britain and its former colonies erupted over the terms of a visit by Commonwealth ministers to discuss Nigeria 's suspension .
Nigeria said they would be restricted to a two-day meeting with government officials , but the Commonwealth said it wanted to hold meetings with people outside the government and called off the visit .
Dutch Queen Beatrix to visit S. Africa in October .
JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-29
Queen Beatrix of The Netherlands will pay a four-day state visit to South Africa in October , the first by a ruling Dutch monarch , the South African foreign ministry said on Thursday .
She will be accompanied by several officials who will sign a cultural agreement with South Africa , where the Dutch were the first European settlers in 1652 .
The queen will be accompanied by her husband Prince Claus on the September 30 to October 3 visit .
Senegal bans guns ahead of local elections .
DAKAR 1996-08-29
With tension rising among Senegal 's political parties ahead of local elections on November 24 , the interior ministry on Thursday banned the carrying of guns and ammunition until the end of the year .
" It is forbidden for holders of permits for weapons of all categories to transport the said arms and their ammunition outside their homes , " the statement said .
It said the ban applied to Senegalese nationals and foreign residents .
Chad parliamentary election set for November 24 .
N'DJAMENA 1996-08-29
Chad 's President Idriss Deby has signed a decree fixing November 24 as the date for parliamentary elections , state radio said on Thursday .
Nomads will vote at mobile polling stations around the vast Central African country between November 20 and 24 .
The electoral commission said the new 125-member national assembly would be installed on February 10 .
Deby took power in an armed uprising in 1990 .
He won 69 percent of votes in the second round of presidential elections on July 3 , 1996 ..
His supporters will contest the parliamentary election in a coalition of 30 mainly small parties , the Republican Front , led by Deby 's Patriotic Salvation Movement .
PRESS DIGEST - Ivory Coast - Aug 29 .
ABIDJAN 1996-08-29
These are significant stories in the Ivorian press on Thursday .
Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy .
FRATERNITE MATIN
- Cabinet meeting establishes five new administrative regions and four new departments as part of government decentralisation policy .
LA VOIE
- Members of parliament seek higher pay and more benefits .
The speaker of parliament , Charles Bauza Donwahi , will meet President Henri Konan Bedie on September 3 to discuss their request .
- Deputy director of animal health department Douati Alphonse says his agents have seized 46 tonnes of illicit pork in a two-week operation to ensure compliance with a ban imposed after an outbreak of swine fever .
LE JOUR
- Raphael Lakpe , publisher of the daily Le Populaire , was released on Wednesday evening after three days in custody and will appear in court on Thursday morning .
- Cabinet meeting appoints Colonel Severin Konan Kouame as gendarmerie commander , replacing General Joseph Tanny , who has been appointed secretary-general of the National Security Council .
-- Abidjan newsroom +225 21 90 90
NATO releases Serb police , crisis easing - NATO .
SARAJEVO 1996-08-29
NATO forces released a group of Bosnian Serb policemen late on Thursday and a tense confrontation appeared to be easing , an alliance spokesman said .
" The situation in Mahala seems to be very much on its way toward resolution .
My understanding is the ( Serb ) police have been released ...
In Zvornik , we think the situation is winding down as well , " NATO spokesman Lieutenant Colonel Max Marriner told Reuters .
NATO troops detained 65 Bosnian Serb policemen early on Thursday after they attacked Moslem refugees returning to homes in Mahala , a Serb-controlled village on Bosnia 's internal boundary line .
In apparent retaliation for NATO 's detention of the Serbs , an angry Serb mob including policemen trapped six unarmed U.N. police monitors and three local aides in their office in the town of Zvornik , east of Mahala .
Marriner said NATO forces confiscated 25 long-barreled AK-47 automatic assault rifles from the detained Serbs before setting them free .
" Local radio and television there ( in Zvornik ) are advising people to step back and take it easy .
We think that when the word about how things are going in Mahala which is about 35 minutes away by road reaches Zvornik that should help , " Marriner said .
Storm kills 11 at Macedonian religious festival .
SKOPJE 1996-08-29
At least 11 people were killed and 60 others injured on Thursday when lightning struck a group of people attending a religious festival in Macedonia , police and municipal officials said .
Police in Berovo , 150 km ( 90 miles ) west of the capital Skopje , said there were around 15,000 people gathered around the town 's cathedral when the lightning struck the group during a thunderstorm .
Kornblum , Milosevic discuss election crisis .
Peter Greste
BELGRADE 1996-08-29
U.S. envoy John Kornblum met Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic on Thursday in an effort to defuse a growing crisis surrounding Bosnia 's post-war elections .
The American diplomat arrived in Belgrade two days after international organisers postponed municipal elections in Bosnia due to irregularities in the registration of Serb refugee voters .
" We discussed the decision to postpone the municipal elections and I made clear it was primarily the manipulation of voter registration by the Republika Srpska ( Bosnian Serb republic ) which led to this development , " Kornblum said after three hours of talks .
But he said the United States still believed it was important to go ahead with national elections in Bosnia as scheduled on September 14 to bolster the peace process .
Kornblum gave no indication that he had won any specific commitment from Milosevic , the patron of the Bosnian Serbs , to rectify any abuses in the registration process .
Bosnia 's Moslem political parties have urged their refugees to boycott the elections until irregularities with voter registration are resolved .
Human rights workers say Serbian and Bosnian Serb authorities coerced refugees to register only in Serb-held territory in Bosnia to solidify the results of wartime expulsions and military conquest .
Serbian officials have denied any abuses occurred during a 10-day registration period and the Bosnian Serbs , angry at the postponement of municipal elections , have threatened to hold local polls on their territory without the international community 's blessing .
Kornblum said only elections endorsed by the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe ( OSCE ) would be legitimate .
" As we have said publicly before , if there is any effort to do so ( hold local elections ) these elections will not be valid , " he said . "
The elections which are valid are those conducted by the international community under the management of the OSCE . "
After meeting Milosevic , Kornblum flew to the Croatian capital Zagreb .
He was due to head to the Bosnian town of Banja Luka on Friday to meet Bosnian Serb acting president Biljana Plavsic and Bosnian Serb opposition leaders .
He also planned to travel to Sarajevo to oversee the formal dissolution of the separatist Croat mini-state in western Bosnia .
U.N. police , relief workers and NATO officers have reported a rise in political violence across Bosnia in the run-up to the September 14 elections .
Voters will be choosing a three-member presidency and a parliament to rule over a loose union of Bosnia , comprised of a Serb republic and a Moslem-Croat federation .
Gazprom rises to 2,901.48 rbls at auction .
MOSCOW 1996-08-29
A stake of 10 million shares in Russian gas monopoly RAO Gazprom was sold at auction on Thursday at an average 2,901.48 roubles a share , up from 2,891.00 roubles a week ago , the Federal Securities Corporation ( FFK ) said .
Starting price at the auction was 2,746 roubles a share and the 40 lots sold for between 2,840 and 2,998 roubles a share , the FFK said in a statement .
The stake represented 0.042 percent of Gazprom 's capital .
The FFK said that since auctions began , 139.75 million shares , equivalent to 0.59 percent of Gazprom , have changed hands .
Gazprom , Russia 's biggest company by market capitalisation , has massive reserves and potentially huge earnings .
However , its 23.6 billion shares are highly illiquid and management permission is required to sell them .
Gazprom has recently tightened these rules , making it harder for shareholders to sell to whoever they want , when they want .
The company has organised regular auctions of its shares to create an orderly market in the paper .
At the first auction on March 6 , shares sold for an average 406.6 roubles each , and prices have been rising steadily since then , but the rise in price this week and last was much less than in previous auctions .
On the Russian Trading System , Gazprom shares rose 25 percent on Thursday to $ 0.375 from $ 0.300 , after falling by over a third earlier this week .
-- Artyom Danielyan , Moscow Newsroom , +7095 941 8520
Serbian policeman shot dead in Kosovo province .
BELGRADE 1996-08-29
A policeman has been shot dead in Serbia 's troubled Kosovo province , Serbian police said on Thursday .
It was the fifth attack on police this month in the southern province , a hot spot of ethnic tension where the Albanian majority have boycotted Serbian institutions and set up their own , which are considered illegal by Belgrade .
The slain policeman Ejup Bajgora , 42 , was an Albanian who had served in the Serbian police and state security since 1987 , police told the Yugoslav news agency Tanjug .
He was shot on Wednesday afternoon as he stepped off a bus near his family home in the village of Donje Ljupce in the municipality of Podujevo .
Just hours before Wednesday 's shooting , three hand grenades were thrown at a police station in Celopek .
They caused damage but no casualties , police said .
The Serbian authorities blame Albanian dissidents for the recent spate of attacks .
None of the attackers has been caught .
Kosovo 's autonomy was revoked in 1987 and Serb police forces cracked down on Albanian protests .
Albanian moderates want autonomy restored but hardliners want to join up with neighbouring Albania .
The Serbs , who make up 10 percent of the province 's 1.8 million people , claim Kosovo as the cradle of their culture .
Viral meningitis epidemic kills 10 in Romania .
BUCHAREST 1996-08-29
Viral meningitis has killed 10 people in Romania 's capital Bucharest this month in what doctors said on Thursday was the worst epidemic of its type in the country for a decade .
Some 170 middle-aged and elderly people with the disease were being treated in hospital , doctors said .
Doctor Emanuil Ceausu , head of Bucharest 's Victor Babes hospital for infectious diseases , said the epidemic had been caused by a virus yet to be identified .
Illness from viral meningitis lasts around a week .
It affects the gastro-intestinal tract , causing high fever , headache and vomiting .
In 1986 Romania suffered an epidemic of the more dangerous bacterial meningitis which has killed some 15,000 people in central Africa this year .
Serbia 's Zastava workers protest enters 9th day .
BELGRADE 1996-08-29
Workers at Serbia 's Zastava arms factory entered the ninth day of their protest over unpaid wages on Thursday with management accused them of rejecting talks .
" The workers keep on gathering in the centre of the town , " the factory 's general manager Vukasin Filipovic told Reuters . "
But they do not want to talk to anyone . "
" They want to discuss in public , at their protest meetings , " Filipovic said . "
And that is impossible . "
The Zastava works in the central town of Kragujevac is the backbone of Serbia 's defence industry , supplying the army with a whole range of weapons .
Its workers are staging protests in the town 's main square demanding June and July wages and last year 's holiday pay .
On Wednesday , the union demanded the resignation of the factory manager .
But Filipovic said he would not quit under pressure . "
We can talk about it and I am prepared to take all the consequences of mismanagement if any . "
Venezuela FinMin to make statement midday Thursday .
CARACAS 1996-08-28
Venezuelan Finance Minister Luis Raul Matos Azocar will make an " important announcement " on Thursday at 1230 local / 1630 GMT at a Central Bank press conference , the Finance Ministry said .
The press conference replaces Matos 's scheduled appearance at an IMF-hosted seminar Thursday on Venezuela 's economic reform program , Venezuelan Agenda .
-- Caracas newsroom , 582 834405
Colombia police find marijuana on ship .
BOGOTA , Colombia 1996-08-29
Police said they found 35 metric tons of marijuana on Thursday on a ship preparing to set sail for the Netherlands from Colombia 's Caribbean port of Cartagena .
They said the drug had been packed into a shipping container and was surrounded by ground coffee .
No arrests had been made , a police spokesman said .
Venezuela non-oil exports rise 10.6 pct in July .
CARACAS 1996-08-29
Venezuela 's non-traditional exports , which exclude oil and iron , rose 10.6 percent in July to reach $ 334 million compared to $ 302 million in June , according to the Central Office of Statistics and Information ( OCEI ) .
" The rise was due to the end of exchange controls , " OCEI said .
Foreign exchange controls were removed April 22 as part of a wider IMF-sponsored program .
Nevertheless , exports over the first seven months of the year were 16.8 percent lower than during the same period last year , at $ 2.240 billion compared to $ 2.693 billion .
Over the seven months , the private sector accounted for 76 percent of total exports , with " common metals " the strongest export sector accounting for $ 951 million , or 42.5 percent of total exports .
" Chemical products " came next with a 13 percent share , then " transport materials " with nine percent , and finally foods , drinks and tobacco with 6.3 percent .
Colombia was the chief market for Venezuela 's non-traditional exports with 27.4 percent .
The U.S. followed with a 24.6 percent share .
-- Caracas newsroom , 582 834405 REUTER JPR
Buenos Aires fraud cops held in extortion racket .
BUENOS AIRES , Argentina 1996-08-29
Thirteen senior police officers from the fraud squad of Buenos Aires province have been arrested on charges of running an extortion racket , security officials said on Thursday .
They included all the top officers from the fraud division of the north of Buenos Aires province , including Commissioner Juan Carlos Lago .
Police were seeking a 14th officer .
La Nacion newspaper said the officers were suspected of demanding bribes of $ 50,000 to $ 500,000 from companies being investigated for tax evasion in order to " lose " their files .
The credibility of the Buenos Aires provincial police , the largest force in Argentina , has been undermined this year by scandals that included the indictment of three officers for links to the 1994 bombing of a Jewish community centre and the arrest of an entire drugs squad for drug trafficking .
Alberto Piotti , security chief of Buenos Aires province , told local television that 3,600 dishonest officers had been purged from the force 's ranks in the past five years .
" It is an ongoing task .
And these investigations into police corruption are only possible because there are people brave enough to denounce them , " Piotti said , promising a major overhaul of the provincial police next month .
Brazil gov't set to send 1997 budget to Congress .
BRASILIA 1996-08-29
Brazilian Planning Minister Antonio Kandir will submit to a draft copy of the 1997 federal budget to Congress on Thursday , a ministry spokeswoman said .
Congress is constitutionally obliged to approve the budget by the end of year but regularly fails to meet that requirement .
Mexico same-day Cetes rates rise on nervousness .
MEXICO CITY 1996-08-29
Mexico 's same-day Cetes rates rose 50 basis points to 24.25 percent on nervousness over a new round of attacks by guerrillas in two southern states , dealers said .
" There are people who are taking advantage of the news to put pressure on rates , however , there are enough players who will buy and that will keep rates from rising too much , " said one dealer .
Co-ordinated guerrilla attacks in two southern states overnight that left at least 13 people dead have caused nervousness in Mexico 's financial markets .
Bank notes and acceptances , including pagares , rose 46 basis points to 25.10 percent .
Dealers said that the volume of longer-term government paper declined due to market nervousness .
At least 13 people were killed when scores of masked rebels struck at police and military posts in Oaxaca and Guerrero states overnight in the biggest assaults in more than two years , officials said on Thursday .
Maturing credits are seen at 2.209 billion pesos , and there is an oversupply of 684 billion pesos from the primary auction .
Dealers estimate that the shortfall will increase due to the inflow of funds before the end of the month .
--- Patricia Lezama , Mexico City newroom ( 525 ) 728 9554
Tension builds in Mexican state ahead of elections .
[ CORRECTED 05:53 GMT ]
CHILPANCINGO , Mexico 1996-08-28
Pre-electoral bickering flared on Wednesday in the troubled western Mexican state of Guerrero as some opposition politicians demanded the army pull out of the area ahead of an upcoming state poll .
The mayor of Acatepec , a small town some 310 miles ( 500 km ) south of Mexico City , sent a letter to Mexico 's National Human Rights Commission complaining the army 's heavy presence in the town would interfere with the Oct. 6 election .
Mayor Antonio Gonzalez Garcia , of the opposition Revolutionary Workers ' Party , said in Wednesday 's letter that army troops recently raided several local farms , stole cattle and raped women .
The letter was signed by some 200 area residents and indigenous leaders .
Some electoral watchdog groups also said the presence of the army , which has fanned out across the state in the past month in search of a new guerrilla group , was likely to intimidate voters and had stirred up tension in the state .
A French group of electoral observers , Agir Ensemble pour les Droits de l'Homme , concluded the army presence exerted a heavy psychological pressure on local farmers and would prevent a fair vote .
Up for grabs in the election are the state legislature and 75 town halls .
( Corrects to show elections are not for governor ) .
Despite the criticism , acting state Gov .
Angel Aguirre pledged the elections will be free and fair and said he did not expect any trouble from the elusive new guerrilla group , the Popular Revolutionary Army .
" The electoral process has been proceeding in accordance with the new state electoral law , " Aguirre said , adding that the poll would be " an exercise in true democracy . "
Brazil police arrest wanted Italian man - report .
SAO PAULO , Brazil 1996-08-28
Brazilian authorities on Wednesday arrested a 47-year-old Italian man wanted in Italy for ties to the leftist Red Brigade guerrilla group of the 1970s , local television said .
TV Globo said the Supreme Federal Tribunal ordered the arrest of Luciano Pessina , a political scientist who owns two Rio de Janeiro restaurants , based on an extradition request from the Italian government .
The report , which could not be independently verified on Wednesday night , said Pessina was sentenced in Italy to eight years and 11 months in prison for robbery and illegal weapons and explosives possession .
Globo quoted Pessina 's lawyer as saying he had already been imprisoned in Italy and , when freed , travelled to Brazil .
Seven churches slam Brazil rural violence , impunity .
BRASILIA 1996-08-28
Seven churches joined voices on Wednesday to condemn the " day-to-day violence " of Brazil 's rural hinterland and the government 's failure to punish those responsible for massacres of landless peasants .
" In the name of Jesus , we want to bring your attention to what is going on in the Brazilian countryside , " two church umbrella groups said in a Letter to the Brazilian People .
The letter from National Council of Christian Churches of Brazil and the Coordinate of Ecumenical Service was sent to President Fernando Henrique Cardoso after a seminar on endemic violence gripping rural Brazil .
Thirty-six people have died so far this year in conflicts over land in the Brazilian countryside , including 19 landless peasants massacred by police in April in the northern state of Para .
" The problem of land is one of the most serious facing Brazil , " said Lucas Moreira Neves , president of the Catholic church 's National Conference of Bishops of Brazil .
The letter made reference to massacres of landless peasants in August 1995 and April 1996 , which claimed the lives of 27 landless peasants .
Thai official flees Hong Kong after passport scam .
HONG KONG 1996-08-29
A Thai consular official has fled Hong Kong after being questioned by anti-corruption police in connection with soliciting bribes to issue a passport , Hong Kong government radio said on Thursday .
The unnamed suspect left the British colony after being detained and then freed by the Independent Commission Against Corruption ( ICAC ) , the radio said .
The man was released after his arrest on Tuesday , pending further inquiries , the ICAC said in a statement .
The anti-graft body was discussing the case with the Thai government , especially the suspect 's status , it said .
It is not clear if the fugitive had diplomatic status in Hong Kong , and officials from the Thai Consulate were not available for comment .
The arrest came after the ICAC received a complaint that the man had demanded a bribe of HK$ 100,000 ( US$ 12,940 ) to issue a Thai passport , the ICAC said .
At the time of his arrest , ICAC officers seized HK$ 100,000 , it added .
The ICAC has kept a close eye on passport scams after a U.S. official was jailed for trafficking fake Honduran passports as part of an immigration racket aimed at Chinese .
Thai poll shows military wants PM Banharn out .
BANGKOK 1996-08-29
Thailand 's powerful military thinks the government is dishonest and Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa 's resignation might solve the nation 's political and economic woes , an opinion poll showed on Thursday .
Nearly half the 1,617 military personnel surveyed in the Rajapat Institute poll suggested that Banharn resign , while about 28 percent thought he should dissolve parliament and 24 percent thought a cabinet reshuffle could resolve the government 's problems .
Banharn , who leads a six-party , 13-month-old coalition government , faces a no-confidence debate in parliament next month .
The prime minister , who has already lost one coalition partner this month , is expected to have a tough battle in the debate because of infighting in his own party and warnings of more pullouts by other coalition partners .
The poll , conducted earlier this month after Banharn 's coalition completed one year in office , showed the military would prefer General Chatichai Choonhavan -- a former prime minister who was ousted in a military coup in February 1991 -- as prime minister .
Defence Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh , head of coalition member the New Aspiration Party , was the second choice for prime minister , the poll showed .
Banharn came in last on the list of proposed leaders with less than one percent of the votes .
Nearly two-thirds of the people surveyed thought the government was dishonest and insincere , and 65 percent blamed the government 's poor performance for the country 's economic slowdown .
The opinion of the military in Thailand , which has seen 17 coups or attempted coups since the country switched to parliamentary democracy from absolute monarchy in 1932 , always carries weight in the political scene , despite officials ' vows to distance the military from politics .
Hamas cleric jailed in Israel hospitalised briefly .
JERUSALEM 1996-08-29
Israeli prison officials took jailed Islamic militant Hamas founder Sheikh Ahmed Yassin to hospital briefly on Thursday for medical tests , officials said .
" This evening Sheikh Yassin completed medical checks and returned to Ramle prisons authority medical centre , " said a spokesman for Israel 's internal security ministry .
A prison official said Yassin had a mild case of pneumonia .
The 60-year-old Moslem cleric , jailed by Israel since 1989 , is serving a life sentence for ordering attacks by Hamas guerrillas against Israeli targets .
The ailing Yassin is the spiritual leader of the fundamentalist Hamas group which has killed scores of Israelis in suicide attacks aimed at wrecking Israel-PLO peace deals .
Palestinian President Yasser Arafat has demanded that Israel release Yassin -- who is confined to a wheelchair -- on humanitarian grounds .
Israel said last month after it recovered the body of a soldier abducted by Hamas seven years ago that it would consider freeing Yassin .
Moroccan King meets former Israel PM Peres .
SKHIRAT , Morocco 1996-08-29
King Hassan of Morocco met former Israeli prime minister Shimon Peres on Thursday at the coastal resort of Skhirat , 20 km ( 12 miles ) south of Rabat , an official source said .
" Mr Shimon Peres , who is on a purely private and family visit to Morocco , was received on Thursday by his Majesty King Hassan at the royal palace of Skhirat , " the source said .
Accompanied by his wife and grandson , Peres arrived in Morocco on August 25 .
Peres is expected to fly home on Friday , officials said .
Scandal hits Clinton campaign at vital moment .
Michael Conlon
CHICAGO 1996-08-29
President Bill Clinton 's triumphal appearance at the Democratic convention , a vital moment in his bid for a second term , was marred on Thursday by the resignation of a top adviser in a reported sex scandal .
Clinton was at work on the nomination acceptance speech that will launch his 10-week re-election campaign when political strategist Dick Morris abruptly announced his resignation on Thursday .
The tabloid Star magazine reported the married Morris had a lengthy affair with a $ 200-an-hour prostitute who he allowed to eavesdrop on telephone conversations with Clinton , and with whom he shared White House speeches before they were made .
" Dick Morris is my friend , and he is a superb political strategist , " Clinton said in a written statement . "
I am and always will be grateful for the great contributions he has made to my campaigns and for the invaluable work he has done for me over the last two years . "
Morris declined to address the allegations directly in his resignation statement but said he was quitting to avoid becoming a campaign issue .
The surprise development captivated the thousands of reporters at the convention and clearly worried some Democrats , who had planned a triumphal celebration of Clinton 's lead over Dole in the opinion polls .
Senator Dianne Feinstein , a California Democrat , called it a " big bump " in the way of the Clinton campaign .
" It comes at the worst possible time on one of the biggest days for the president , " Feinstein said .
Clinton was to deliver his acceptance speech at the final session of the Democratic Convention opening at 8 p.m. EDT ( midnight GMT ) .
The 50-year-old president has been dogged for years by allegations of financial wrongdoing , sexual misconduct and questionable judgment in selecting his advisers .
Republicans hope to seize on the " character " issue to bolster Clinton 's challenger Bob Dole in the final weeks of the campaign .
Speaking in Santa Barbara , California , Dole did not directly refer to the sexual scandal but said the departure of Morris , who had advised Clinton to chart a more centrist political course , would make Clinton drift back to the left .
" Morris has been trying to make President Clinton a Republican , now maybe he 'll revert to the liberal Democrat that he really is , " Dole told reporters .
Clinton will hit the road on Friday for a bus tour across several states in his fight to become the first Democratic incumbent re-elected to a second term since the days of Franklin D. Roosevelt .
Aides said Clinton planned to spend most of Thursday in his hotel room several miles ( km ) from the convention hall working on his speech .
It was apparently neglected on his long " whistle-stop " train trip to the convention , during which he revelled in contact with friendly crowds across the country 's heartland .
He was also hoarse and was giving his voice a rest .
But first lady Hillary Rodham Clinton told ABC television , " He 's really fired up . "
" He wants to outline to the American people what he thinks has been accomplished in the last four years , and what he would like to see done in the next four years , " she said .
" He 's very excited about this convention ...
He 's excited about the campaign .
But more than that , he 's very resolute about what he wants to do . "
" I do n't take anything for granted .
I always expect elections to get close .
I expect to have a great deal of up and down days between now and then , " she said of the November 5 election date .
Clinton is leading Dole by as much as 15 points according to some polls .
The campaign pits Dole , a man of quick and withering wit and long-time public service , but stilted speaking style , against the glib and confident Clinton , who has perfected a style that makes direct eye contact with his audience .
Montana weekly muni bond indices - Piper Jaffray .
NEW YORK 1996-08-29
The following Montana tax-exempt municipal bond indices were compiled by Piper Jaffray Inc for the week ending August 30 .
Previous
8/30 Week Change
-------------------------
Year A-rated Gen'l Obligation 4.45 % 4.40 % +0.05
10 Year A-rated Gen'l Obligation 4.90 % 4.90 % -----
15 Year A-rated Gen'l Obligation 5.40 % 5.35 % +0.05
20 Year A-rated Gen'l Obligation 5.55 % 5.50 % +0.05
30 Year A-rated Housing Rev 6.05 % 6.00 % +0.05
-- U.S. Municipal Desk , 212-859-1650
Researchers report progress in muscular dystrophy .
PHILADELPHIA 1996-08-29
University of Pennsylvania researchers on Thursday said a new gene-therapy technique for treating muscular dystrophy disease had shown progress in laboratory animals .
Word of the findings , to be published in the Oct. 1 issue of the journal " Human Gene Therapy , " came in advance of the annual Jerry Lewis Labour Day weekend telethon to raise money for muscular dystrophy research .
Several hurdles must be overcome before the method is used in human trials .
Nevertheless , " a treatment based on the new strategy .... may have the potential to benefit many patients , " the University of Pennsylvania Medical Centre said in a release .
Muscular dystrophy is a fatal illness in which the body 's muscle tissue degenerates and is replaced by fat .
Death strikes in early adulthood .
Individuals with the disease have a non-working version of a gene responsible for producing a crucial muscle protein called dystrophin .
In the study at the University 's Institute for Human Gene Therapy , researchers altered a common-cold virus to carry a version of the working dystrophin gene .
The virus , which also was altered to minimise its susceptibility to the immune system , was then injected into the muscle cells of mice bred to lack dystrophin genes .
In the experiment , between 30 to 40 percent of the muscle fibers in one group of mice produced dystrophin for two weeks before diminishing .
Similar results had been obtained previously in test-tube cell cultures , but not in live animals , the university said .
The university said methods are still needed to make enough of the altered virus to treat humans , to further decrease the immune-system response to the virus , and to deliver the virus to human muscle tissue .
Export Business - Grain / oilseeds complex .
CHICAGO 1996-08-29
Grain and oilseed exports reported by USDA and private export sources .
WHEAT SALES - Taiwan Flour Mills Assn bought 98,000 tonnes of U.S. No.1 or No.2 wheat from Cargill , Mitsui , Continental and Louis Dreyfus Corp for shipment from the Pacific Northwest .
For Sept 10-30 : 16,300 tonnes of dark northern spring ( DNS ) at $ 212.00 ; 7,000 of hard red winter ( HRW ) at $ 205.10 ; 2,700 of western white ( WW ) at $ 202.65 .
For Sept 20 - Oct 10 : 19,500 of DNS at $ 212.25 , 10,000 of HRW at $ 204.74 , 4,500 of WW at $ 199.71 .
For Sept 25 - Oct 20 : 23,500 of DNS at $ 212.25 , 9,600 HRW at $ 204.74 , 4,900 WW at $ 199.56 .
WHEAT SALES - The Commodity Credit Corp of USDA bought 18,278 tonnes of dark northern spring ( DNS ) wheat from Cargill Inc at $ 195.79 per tonne , FOB , for donation to Nicaragua .
Shipment is for Nov 15 - Dec 10 .
WHEAT / BARLEY SALE - The Japanese Food Agency said it bought 20,000 tonnes of U.S. dark northern spring wheat , 20,000 of Canadian western red spring wheat , 20,000 of Australian standard white wheat and 20,000 of Australian feed barley at its weekly tender , all for October shipment .
SOYBEAN SALES - The Taichung division of Taiwan 's Breakfast Soybean Procurement Assn bought 108,000 tonnes of U.S. soybeans .
Bunge sold the first shipment and Cargill the second , traders said .
For Nov 11-25 from the U.S. Gulf or Nov 26 - Dec 10 from PNW it paid $ 0.8584 per bushel over CBOT January soybeans and for Dec 6-20 or Dec 21 - Jan it paid $ .8787 over CBOT January .
- Pakistan bought 31,412 tonnes of PL-480 No.2 yellow soybeans from Cargill Inc for $ 303.19 per tonne , FOB U.S. Gulf , agents for the buyer said .
The soybeans were for Oct 15-30 shipment .
BARLEY TENDER - The Cyprus Grain Commission said it invited offers September 3 to supply 25,000 tonnes of feed barley , with shipment for Sept 25 - Oct 10 from Europe or Sept 15-30 from North America .
MARKET TALK - Sri Lanka plans to import up to 400,000 tonnes of rice by the end of this year to meet a crop shortfall caused by drought and rising demand , government officials said on Thursday .
MARKET TALK - USDA net change in weekly export commitments for the week ended August 22 , includes old crop and new crop , were : wheat up 595,400 tonnes old , nil new ; corn up 1,900 old , up 319,600 new ; soybeans down 12,300 old , up 300,800 new ; upland cotton up 50,400 bales new , nil old ; soymeal 54,800 old , up 100,600 new , soyoil nil old , up 75,000 new ; barley up 1,700 old , nil new ; sorghum 6,200 old , up 156,700 new ; pima cotton up 4,000 bales old , nil new ; rice up 49,900 old , nil new ...
USDA Thursday forecast U.S. agricultural exports in fiscal year 1997 would decline to $ 58 billion , down $ 2 billion from the record $ 60 billion seen for fiscal 1996 .
Oilseed exports are expected to rise by $ 800 million and livestock , poultry and fruits and vegetables are seen gaining more than $ 1 billion .
USDA pegged U.S. wheat exports at 25.0 million tonnes in fiscal 1997 versus 32.0 million tonnes the prior year ...
The European Union agreed on Thursday to increase by 300,000 tonnes the quota of German intervention barley available for export , France ONIC said .
The EU 's grain panel will add two tranches of 150,000 tonnes each to the existing allocation , it said .
-- Chicago newsdesk 312-408-8720--
USDA gross cutout hide and offal value .
DES MOINES 1996-08-29
The hide and offal value from a typical slaughter steer for Thursday was estimated at $ 9.76 per cwt live , up $ 0.03 when compared with Wednesday 's value .
- USDA
Help-wanted ad index fell in July .
NEW YORK 1996-08-29
The help-wanted advertising index fell in July , the Conference Board said Thursday , reflecting the uneven nature of the nation 's labour markets .
The monthly index fell to 83.0 in July against a reading of 85.0 in June , the private business research group said .
In July , the volume of help-wanted advertising fell in five of the nine U.S. regions .
" The labour market has been expanding throughout 1996 , but in a very uneven pattern , " Conference Board economist Ken Goldstein said . "
Recent want-ad figures indicate that conservative hiring plans are keeping job growth below the rate of overall economic activity . "
With 2.5 percent gross domestic product growth expected for 1996 , new job growth should slowly lower the unemployment rate over the rest of the year .
" With the unemployment rate staying close to about 5.5 percent over the last two years , there is a good chance the rate will slowly drop to about 5.0 percent by the end of the year , " Goldstein said .
The July index matched the reading for July , 1995 .
The greatest declines in the volume of help-wanted advertising were in the New England , Mountain and West South Central regions .
The greatest increase was in the East North Central region .
Police seek suspects in Atlantic City jewel heist .
ATLANTIC CITY , N.J. 1996-08-29
Atlantic City police said Thursday they were seeking two men and two women in connection with a $ 690,000 theft of jewelry and cash from a guest of the Showboat Hotel and Casino .
Capt .
Richard Andrews said police were seeking a man shown on a hotel videotape carrying a suitcase resembling the victim 's . "
We want to talk to him , " Andrews said of the man .
A second man and two women also were being sought .
The thefts occurred Sunday when the victim , New York jewelry wholesaler Jerry Schein , left three suitcases in a closet at Somerset Jewellers in the hotel while he checked out .
While he was gone , two women in their mid-twenties and an older man entered the jewelry store and tried to distract store owner Charles McGilley .
When Schein returned two of the suitcases were missing .
They contained $ 650,000 in jewelry and $ 40,000 in cash , Andrews said .
He said the man on the videotape did not match the description given by the jewelry store owner .
O.J. Simpson hints at more supporting evidence .
Jackie Frank
WASHINGTON 1996-08-29
O.J. Simpson said on Thursday he was financially broken by his defence against murder charges but he was hopeful new evidence to support him would be available for a civil trial next month .
The former football star was found not guilty by a criminal trial jury last October of the murders of his former wife , Nicole Brown Simpson , and her friend , Ronald Goldman , in June 1994 .
He now faces a civil suit brought by families of the victims who hold him responsible for the deaths .
He told reporters a court order not to talk about his case kept him from detailing how he has fulfilled his pledge to find the killers .
But he added without elaborating , " hopefully we will see some things come out in this next trial . "
The judge in the civil trial has imposed a sweeping gag order that prohibits lawyers , witnesses and parties to the case from discussing it with the media or elsewhere in public .
" I would love to speak about everything , " said Simpson , who vowed after his acquittal to find the killers and offered a substantial reward .
His lawyers have said his defence in the civil trial that starts Sept .
17 will be that he did not kill the victims .
Simpson said at the hotel news conference his plans include eventually writing another book .
He added that he has had job offers but more have come from abroad than at home .
" I 'm broke .
I am not crying the blues .
I can get along just fine , " he said . "
Whatever you want to send me , I need . "
He again accused the news media of erroneous reporting on his case but did not signal any plans for lawsuits as he did on Wednesday in an address at a jam-packed Washington church .
Contrary to news reports , Simpson said , he has received support from both blacks and whites .
He again dismissed charges that he had distanced himself from the black community during his successful football and commercial career , only to seek their support after he faced murder charges .
A crowd of 2,000 paid $ 10 a head to hear the former star running back for the Buffalo Bills professional football club and a Football Hall of Fame member on Wednesday night .
The crowd in the church was wildly supportive , showering Simpson with gifts and praise .
But outside , dozens of protesters from the D.C. Coalition Against Domestic Violence called for the church to support victims of violence instead .
Clinton adviser Morris announces resignation .
CHICAGO 1996-08-29
President Bill Clinton 's top political strategist Dick Morris resigned on Thursday , saying he did not want to become an issue in Clinton 's re-election campaign .
In a written statement , distributed by the Clinton campaign , Morris avoided comment on published allegations that he had engaged in a year-long affair with a $ 200-an-hour prostitute .
The statement from Morris said that he had submitted his resignation on Wednesday night . "
While I served I sought to avoid the limelight because I did not want to become the message .
Now , I resign so I will not become the issue , " he said .
The announcement followed a report in the weekly supermarket tabloid Star magazine , reprinted in Thursday 's editions of the New York Post , that the married adviser had hired a 37-year-old prostitute on a weekly basis while visiting Washington to advise Clinton on his re-election campaign .
" I will not subject my wife , family or friends to the sadistic , vitriol of yellow journalism .
I will not dignify such journalism with a reply or an answer .
I never will , " his statement said .
It was distributed to reporters at the press centre of Clinton 's Democratic convention headquarters just hours before the president was to address the delegates accepting the party 's nomination for a second four-year term in the White House .
U.S. surgeon investigated for discarding foot .
CHARLESTON , S.C. 1996-08-29
Health officials said on Thursday they were investigating the discovery of an amputated foot on a beach near Charleston to determine whether a local surgeon had improperly disposed of infectious waste .
The foot , which washed up on Sullivan 's Island beach this month , was amputated three years ago from a child whose legs were deformed .
The foot had to be removed so the infant could be fitted with a prosthesis .
An orthopedic surgeon was given permission by the child 's parents and the hospital to keep the foot for research and educational purposes .
Health officials said the surgeon told authorities he stored the foot in his freezer at home , but the freezer recently broke down and the contents spoiled .
The surgeon , who apologised for the incident , said he decided to put the foot in a crab trap to remove the flesh .
The foot later washed up on the beach .
Florida cop disguised as shrub nabs bad guys .
MIAMI 1996-08-29
It was a bush that bagged the bad guys .
When four would-be robbers , armed and masked , showed up to rob a Checker 's restaurant in the Fort Lauderdale suburb of Pembroke Pines on Tuesday , they had no idea the shrub near the drive-through window was toting a shotgun .
Detective Earl Feugill , camouflaged as a shaggy green bush , ordered them to freeze . "
They were quite surprised , " he told the Miami Herald .
Feugill said he made the hot , heavy suit , which he first used in the Marines , by attaching strips of burlap to a camouflage outfit .
Green and black face paint completed his disguise .
He was staking out the restaurant after a series of robberies at local fast-food places .
Pembroke Pines police said five people were arrested as a result of the 90-minute stakeout , including the four robbers and a restaurant employee who was allegedly prepared to let them in a back door .
U.S. DLA sets tin price at $ 2.7975 per lb .
WASHINGTON 1996-08-29
The U.S. Defense Logistics Agency set Thursday 's offering price for stockpile tin at $ 2.7975 per lb , versus $ 2.7775 per lb yesterday .
Key Clinton aide resigns , NBC says .
CHICAGO 1996-08-29
Dick Morris , the Republican political consultant who reshaped U.S. President Bill Clinton 's reelection campaign , has resigned , MS-NBC News reported Thursday .
Morris drew the ire of liberal Clinton aides for repositioning the president in the political centre .
There was no immediate comment on the report from the White House .
U.S. corn gluten meal steady-higher , feed flat .
CHICAGO 1996-08-29
U.S. corn gluten feed prices were flat while meal values were steady to firmer on Thursday .
Dealers noted a seasonal pickup in meal demand .
--
CHICAGO AREA MILLS ( dollars per short ton )
Gluten feed 21 pct bulk Spot - 117.00 unc
Gluten feed pellets Spot - unq
Gluten meal 60 pct bulk rail Spot - 320.00 up 5
DECATUR , IL / CLINTON AND CEDAR RAPIDS , IA
Gluten feed 18 pct pellets Spot - 117.00 unc
Gluten meal 60 pct bulk Spot - 310.00 unc
( Chicago newsdesk 312-408-8720 )
EU barley sale worth $ 145 / T , for Saudi - sources .
PARIS 1996-08-29
A European Union sale of 234,324 tonnes of German intervention barley is worth some $ 145 per tonne fob Germany and is mostly destined for Saudi Arabia , European grain sources said on Thursday .
The EU 's cereals management committee sold 234,324 tonnes of German intervention barley at a minimum price of 105.07 Ecus per tonne .
Saudi Arabia provisionally bought 800,000 tonnes of optional-origin barley at an August 21 tender at prices between $ 160 and $ 162 including cost , insurance and freight , traders said last week .
But European grain traders and officials said the Saudis might reduce the purchase to 600,000 tonnes .
Traders have said a substantial part of the deal was likely to come from the European Union , which enjoys a supply and freight advantage over other producers .
But subtracting freight costs , the equivalent fob price of the deal is around $ 142 , well below the $ 149 per tonne floor price which the EU put on its barley as news of the deal emerged last week .
Last Thursday the EU sold 34,277 tonnes of German intervention barley at a minimum price of 109.36 Ecus per tonne , which was seen as worth $ 149 per tonne fob .
-- Paris newsroom +331 4221 5432
French shipyard workers march against job cuts .
RENNES 1996-08-29
About 3,500 naval shipyard workers marched in the centre of the northern port town of Cherbourg on Thursday to protest against defence restructuring , a union official said .
The local police headquarters did not give a figure but said 1,800 workers at the Cherbourg yeard had stopped work .
A cutback plan could slim their numbers to 1,700 from 4,200 .
Several hundred workers also marched in the western town of Indre where 500 or 1,600 jobs are at risk .
PRESS DIGEST - Pakistan - August 29 .
Following are some of the main stories in Thursday 's Pakistani newspapers :
DAWN
- The government has decided to transfer the entire distribution network of electricity to foreign managements to curtail losses of billions of rupees .
- The government has suffered a loss of 11 billion rupees due to tax holidays at industrial estates in Hub and Gadoon .
- High Court officials have unearthed police-run human cages at Tando Allahyar near Hyderabad .
Some 27 people were rescued from the private jail set up by the police .
- Opposition leader Nawaz Sharif renewed a pledge to oust the Pakistan People 's Party government headed by Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto .
BUSINESS RECORDER
- Gas prices may go up by five percent to increase the rate of return of Sui Southern Gas and Sui Northern Gas companies .
- Japan is importing 80 percent of cotton yarn from Pakistan every year .
- The government has blamed sugar technologists for not supporting a long-term programme of research and development to increase production of sugarcane .
FINANCIAL POST
- Armed robbers pillaged 70 barrels of crude oil from a well near Gujar Khan on Wednesday .
- Pakistan will pay an additional bill of $ 244 million as private power projects with capacity of 3,225 megawatt go on-line by 1998/99 .
THE NATION
- The government is facing extreme difficulties in meeting its revenue collections targets for 1996/97 .
- Mohib Textile Mills has defaulted to nearly 23 development finance institutions , foreign and local banks , leasing companies and modarabas ( Islamic mutual funds ) .
- Investment Minister Asif Ali Zardari expressed keenness for a close working relationship with Japanese companies so that investment from Japan can multiply.q
- Karachi Stock Exchange index falls by 7.84 points .
THE NEWS
- The prime minister 's special economic assistant Shahid Hasan Khan said privatisation of thermal power plants , power generation from private plants and management contracts of Area Electricity Boards would help achieve 6.5 percent GDP growth .
- Pakistan 's Muslim Commercial Bank , Vital Information System , and Duff and Phelps of the U.S. are likely to announce a strategic alliance with Bangladesh 's only credit rating company -- Credit Rating and Information Systems Ltd -- next month .
- The Sindh High Court issued an ad-interim order restraining the Privatisation Commission from handing over Javedan Cement to Dadabhoy Investment ( pvt ) Ltd until it can consider a legal challenge mounted by unions to the deal .
THE MUSLIM
- Pakistan and Iran have agreed to expand and strengthen political , trade and economic relations .
-- Islamabad newsroom 9251-274757
Salang tunnel reopened linking Kabul with north .
SALANG TUNNEL , Afghanistan 1996-08-29
The Salang tunnel linking Kabul with northern Afghanistan was formally reopened to traffic on Thursday under an agreement between the government and an opposition militia , witnesses said .
They said dozens of trucks began moving through the tunnel from both directions after the road reopened .
The Salang tunnel , the main supply route for Soviet troops when they were occupying Afghanistan in the 1980s , had been closed since 1994 when northern militia leader General Abdul Rashid Dostum rebelled against the Kabul government .
Witnesses said wrecked tanks and vehicles littered both sides of the heavily-mined road .
Mines had been removed from the road itself , but experts of the Halo Trust mine clearance agency said it would take a week to clear the roadsides .
Afghan Deputy Prime Minister Qotbuddin Hilal officiated at the reopening ceremony , which was delayed by several hours while the two sides argued about a mutual release of prisoners .
Two Indians to die for killing 23 bus passengers .
NEW DELHI 1996-08-29
India 's Supreme Court on Thursday sentenced two men to death after finding them guilty of killing 23 bus passengers , including children .
It said the two , after robbing the passengers , burnt them alive by sprinkling the bus with petrol and setting it on fire in the southern state of Andhra Pradesh in 1993 .
" We have no doubt that this is one of the rarest of the rare cases , not merely due to the number of innocent human beings roasted alive by the appellants , but the inhuman manner in which they plotted the scheme and executed it , " Justice K.T. Thomas said in the verdict by a panel of three judges .
Elephant tramples woman to death in Nepal .
KATHMANDU 1996-08-29
A rampaging elephant dragged a sleeping 72-year-old woman from her bed and trampled her to death in the third such killing in two months , Nepal police said on Thursday .
The elephant crashed into Hari Maya Poudels house in Madhumalla village earlier this week while she was asleep , they said .
The beast dragged the woman 30 feet ( nine metres ) away from her bed and trampled her to death , a police official told Reuters in the Himalayan kingdoms capital Kathmandu .
In the past two months elephants have killed three people in remote areas of east and central Nepal .
Elephants are protected under Nepali law , which provides for jail sentences of up to 15 years for convicted elephant killers .
Sri Lankan rebels overrun police post , kill 24 .
COLOMBO 1996-08-29
Tamil Tiger rebels overran an isolated police post in Sri Lanka 's northeast early on Thursday killing 24 policemen , defence officials said .
A large group of Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam ( LTTE ) rebels stormed the Kudapokuna police post , just north of Welikanda , 200 km ( 125 miles ) from Colombo , before dawn , they said .
" The entire post was overrun , " said a defence official .
It was not immediately clear if there were any casualties among the rebels , who are fighting for independence for minority Tamils in the Indian Ocean island 's north and east .
It is the second time in three days that the rebels attacked police .
Suspected Tamil Tigers on Tuesday hurled hand grenades at a police vehicle in a crowded market in the army-controlled northern town of Vavuniya , killing at least two policemen .
More than a dozen people , including several police who were working undercover , were wounded in the attack .
Vavuniya is just south of the northern mainland area controlled by the LTTE .
The government says more than 50,000 people have died in the ethnic war , now in its 14th year .
Vicorp Restaurants names Sabourin CFO .
DENVER 1996-08-29
Vicorp Restaurants Inc said it has named Richard Sabourin as executive vice president and chief financial officer .
The company said Sabourin is the former president and chief executive at Bestop Inc of Boulder , Colo .
It said Craig Held has also joined the company as executive vice president and chief marketing officer .
-- New York Newsdesk 212 859 1610
SoCal Edison sees 2 power lines back today .
NEW YORK 1996-08-29
Southern California Edison Co said it expected two 220 kilovolt ( KV ) power lines in southern California to resume service later today after being shut late Wednesday because of a wildfire raging north of Los Angeles .
" They are expected to be placed in service later today , " said company spokesman Steve Conroy , adding repair crews have been removing smoke and other fire-related residues , which had settled on the two lines .
The shutdown of the 220 KV lines reduced by 500 megawatts ( MW ) the amount of power which the area received from SoCal Edison 's 1,200 MW Sierra hydroelectric facility , he said .
Conroy noted two 500 KV and another 220 KV line running from the Sierra plant to Los Angeles remained in operation , and continued to carry some of the production from Sierra to the region .
On Monday , the two 500 KV transmission cables were taken out of service , also for cleaning , for about a day .
Containment of the fire has been difficult because of the hot , arid , windy weather in the region , Conroy said .
" The fires keep moving back because of the winds , " he said , forcing the utility to shut those transmission lines for a second time this week .
Local authorities charged a teenager for starting the blaze .
In four days , the fire destroyed 20,000 acres of forest land .
-- R Leong , New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622
Dreyfus Strategic Munis monthly $ 0.056 / shr .
NEW YORK 1996-08-29
Monthly
Latest Prior
Amount $ 0.056 $ 0.056
Pay Sept 27
Record Sept 13
NOTE : Full name of company is Dreyfus Strategic Municipals Inc .
Sierra Semiconductor jumps on exit plan .
Martin Wolk
SEATTLE 1996-08-29
Sierra Semiconductor Corp jumped 23 percent Thursday on the expectation the company would emerge as a smaller but more profitable operation after its planned exit from the computer modem business .
The San Jose , Calif. , company was up 2-1/8 at 11-3/8 after its announcement Wednesday that it planned to pull out of the highly competitive modem-chip business and focus instead on the fast-growing market for computer networking equipment .
" Certainly the company will be a much smaller company now , but it will be a more profitable business , " said analyst Elias Moosa of Roberston Stephens & Co .
But analysts noted that Sierra still has much painful work ahead of it , including cutting as many as 150 jobs from its workforce , which currently has 500 people , and building up the business of its PMC-Sierra unit , which makes routing devices and chipsets for high-speed computer networks .
The company has announced plans to take a charge against earnings of $ 50 million to $ 80 million to write down the value of assets and inventories and cover severance payments .
Scott Randall of Soundview Financial Group said the company likely would have difficulty selling its modem-chip business .
" Once you announce your intention to exit a business , it becomes a complete buyer 's market , " he said .
And he said that while the company is focusing on the fastest-growing part of its business , the market for networking chips has begun to attract the attention of much-larger players such as International Business Machines Corp .
" As the market develops the question is , are they able to make that transition to be a much larger company ? "
Randall said .
Other analysts were more bullish , even though the company is expected to shrink to slightly more than half its current size in sales .
" It 's a positive strategic move , " said Miles Kan of Hambrecht & Quist .
" The modem business is a low-margin , commodity business , " he said .
The company 's PMC-Sierra unit generated $ 33 million of the company 's $ 117 million in sales in the first half of the year , compared with $ 45 million in sales of modem chips , Kan said .
But the PMC unit is far more profitable , he said .
Sierra 's stock has fallen from a high of nearly $ 25 this year as the computer chip sector has been battered by falling prices and concern about slowing demand .
-- Seattle bureau 206-386-4848
Housecall shares sink after profit warning .
NEW YORK 1996-08-29
Shares in home healthcare services company Housecall Medical Resources Inc fell more than 50 percent on Thursday after the company said it expected a net loss for the fiscal fourth quarter .
Morgan Stanley said it downgraded the stock to underperform from outperform .
Housecall was off 7-3/8 to 7-1/8 in morning trading .
The Atlanta-based company went public in April at $ 16 a share .
Wall Street had expected the company to earn $ 0.17 a share in its fourth quarter , ended June 30 , according to First Call .
Housecall said fourth quarter earnings and revenues were expected to fall short of expectations .
It said its non-Medicare infusion therapy , hospice and nursing services businesses failed to meet budgeted revenues .
It also cited a limitation on Medicare reimbursement for some services provided during the quarter .
First Alliance net income slips .
IRVINE , Calif. 1996-08-29
First Alliance Corporation and Subsidiaries
Quarter ended June 30 Six Months ended June 30
1996 1995 1996 1995
Unaudited
Total revenue
17,024,000 18,174,000 31,834,000 24,137,000
Total expense
7,718,000 6,828,000 14,668,000 13,091,000
Net Income 9,167,000 11,175,000 16,909,000 10,880,000
Net Income Per
Share 0.86 1.05 1.59 1.02
Weighted average number of
shares outstanding
10,650,407 10,650,407 10,650,407 10,650,407
Pro Forma :
Historical income before income
tax provision
9,306,000 11,346,000 17,166,000 11,046,000
Pro forma income tax
provision 3,820,000 4,658,000 7,047,000 4,534,000
Pro forma net
income 5,486,000 6,688,000 10,119,000 6,512,000
Pro forma net income
per share 0.37 0.45 0.68 0.44
Pro forma weighted average
number of shares
outstanding 14,775,000 14,775,000 14,775,000 14,775,000
Oasis singer heads for U.S. after illness .
LONDON 1996-08-29
Liam Gallagher , singer of Britain 's top rock group Oasis , flew out on Thursday to join the band three days after the start of its U.S. tour .
Gallagher made his usual obscene gestures and swore at journalists as he prepared to fly from London 's Heathrow airport to Chicago .
" I hate you f... ing lot , yet you 're always asking me too many things .
I 'm not a supermodel you know , " he said .
On Monday , just 15 minutes before his flight was due to depart , Liam decided not to travel with the rest of the group , which includes his brother Noel .
Liam caught a taxi back to London saying he had " problems at home " .
He was believed to be suffering from laryngitis and said he had to go house-hunting with actress girlfriend Patsy Kensit .
When they first heard that Liam had not flown out with the band at the start of the tour , many U.S. fans asked for refunds on their concert tickets .
The group began the U.S. tour , which is scheduled to last until September 18 , with a concert in Chicago on Tuesday at which Noel Gallagher filled in for his brother as lead singer .
Slough Estates helps lift property sector .
LONDON 1996-08-29
A strong set of interim results and an upbeat outlook from Slough Estates Plc helped to boost the property sector on Thursday .
Shares in Slough , which earlier announced a 14 percent rise in first-half pretax profit to 37.4 million stg , climbed nearly six percent , or 14p to 250 pence at 1009 GMT , while British Land added 12-1 / 2p to 468p , Land Securities rose 5-1 / 2p to 691p and Hammerson was 8p higher at 390 .
Traders said positive comment from investment banks Merrill Lynch and SBC Warburg also fueled the gains .
One dealer said positive stances from Merrill Lynch and SBC Warburg were the key factors behind the gains .
A spokesman for Merrill Lynch said the bank was preparing to issue a note on the sector . "
We have been very positive ( on property ) , " he said , adding : " On a technical basis it is our most favoured sector . "
SBC Warburg issued an update on the property sector on Thursday , saying that most of the predictions it made at the start of the year were being realised .
" In the property market it is a case of so far , so good , " a member of SBC Warburg 's property team said .
SBC Warburg said it is maintaining its forecast for five percent growth in rental incomes during 1996 , but it has shaved its forecast for capital growth to five percent from six .
The spokesman said SBC Warburg has also put an " add " recommendation on Slough Estates ' shares , but added that this " is a general move , not because of the results . "
Slough 's chairman Sir Nigel Mobbs added to the bullish mood in the sector , saying in a statement that " with the prospect of a period of steady economic growth and low inflation ahead , there is good reason to believe that the property sector should continue its improvement . "
-- Jonathan Birt , London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717
Canada 's international travel account gap shrinks .
OTTAWA 1996-08-29
Higher spending by foreign visitors and less Canadian tourist spending abroad cut the deficit in Canada 's international travel account by 26.5 percent in the second quarter , Statistics Canada said on Thursday .
The deficit fell to a seasonally adjusted C$ 715 million in the second quarter from C$ 973 million in the first , as foreigners spent a record C$ 3.00 billion seasonally adjusted while Canadians reduced their spending abroad by 5.1 percent to C$ 3.72 billion .
-- Reuters Ottawa Burea ( 613 ) 235-6745
Jordanian PM Kabariti meets Arafat in West Bank .
RAMALLAH , West Bank 1996-08-29
Jordanian Prime Minister Abdul-Karim al-Kabariti began talks with Palestinian President Yasser Arafat in the West Bank on Thursday on the stalled Middle East peace process , officials said .
Kabariti flew by helicopter to Palestinian-ruled Ramallah and after a brief arrival ceremony went into talks with Arafat .
The prime minister 's visit , his first trip outside the country since Jordan was shaken by food riots earlier this month , came against the backdrop of a Palestinian general strike in the West Bank and Gaza .
Arafat called the four-hour strike , which ended at noon ( 0900 GMT ) to protest against Israeli policy on settlements and Jerusalem .
Jordan 's official state news agency Petra said Kabariti would hold discussions " on the latest developments in the peace process and bilateral cooperation " .
Iran says five spy networks destroyed , 41 held .
TEHRAN 1996-08-29
Iranian security forces have broken up five espionage rings in northwestern Iran and arrested 41 people on charges of spying for unnamed countries , a daily newspaper said on Thursday .
Jomhuri Eslami quoted the West Azerbaijan province security chief as saying those held confessed to gathering confidential information , photographing strategic sites , doing propaganda against state officials and " spreading pan-Turkism " .
It was not clear if they were the same five spy rings , allegedly led by Turkish diplomats , that Iran said in April it had broken up in the same area , which borders Turkey .
The April arrests were announced shortly after a row in which Tehran asked Ankara to withdraw four Turkish diplomats accused of spying , and Turkey expelled four Iranian diplomats for their alleged links to killings of Iranian exiles .
Ties between the two neighbours , strained also over a military accord between Turkey and Israel which drew strong Iranian objections , have improved since Islamist Necmettin Erbakan took over as Turkish prime minister in June .
The daily Iran on Thursday quoted Intelligence Minister Ali Fallahiyan as saying agents arrested 137 people for allegedly spying for Iraq , the United States and other unnamed countries in the Iranian year which ended on March 19 .
Mideast Gulf oil outlook - India holds the key .
DUBAI 1996-08-29
India will continue to hold the key to the middle distillates product market in the Middle East Gulf in the short term , traders in the region said on Thursday .
They said premiums on high quality jet kerosene have widened to around $ 1 , and are likely to remain strong in the near term .
" On the jet kerosene side we must be cautious about quality .
Some are commanding a very good premium of 95 cents to one dollar .
It 's been 99 cents to Korea .
This will stay at this sort of price premium for a while , " one said .
" But for normal jet the weakened demand is quite noticeable , the premium is around 45-50 cents .
The differential is not normally as wide as this , " he added .
Another put the premium for jet kerosene at between 65 and 75 cents .
One trader said despite the fact that some kerosene was in storage at Dubai ports , demand looked to exceed supply in the near term .
Jet kerosene was assessed at $ 27.40 - $ 27.70 a barrel fob Gulf on Thursday , up from $ 27.22 last week .
Dealers expected premiums to stick around current levels for the next two or three weeks , before they get a boost in the second half of September from demand for October cargoes .
Gas oil , assessed at $ 24.00 - $ 24.20 a barrel fob Gulf , was little changed on Thursday from last week 's $ 24.10 - $ 24.24 .
" On gas oil , in the near term demand and supply are balanced to a bit short , there are some enquiries into east Africa and short covering in India , " said one trader .
" The Indians have awarded three cargoes , but the question is whether they will come out for more , " he added .
India has acquired 120,000 tonnes of diesel in three cargoes , bound for the west coast , in its October tender .
Traders said the award could be India 's lowest in recent years .
" After IOC 's very small purchase of 120,000 tonnes , I 'm still suspicious that they will buy more in the second half of October , " another said .
But traders see the market remaining tight in the short-term , with some surplus arising closer to October .
" I see an overhang of gas oil further out , " one said .
" Gas oil will remain tight in the short term up to mid-September with the premium of around $ 1 for 0.5 percent ( sulphur material ) .
In the second half of September and October we see the premium coming off to 70-75 cents . "
Traders said there was not much demand for one percent sulphur material gas oil , with the premium at 40 to 45 cents .
Egypt police catch ancient manuscript thieves .
CAIRO 1996-08-29
Egyptian police have arrested eight people who were trying to sell an ancient copy of the Old Testament , the official al-Akhbar newspaper said on Thursday .
The daily said the men had wanted to sell the undated manuscript to a Jewish group for five million pounds ( $ 1.5 million ) .
Instead an undercover police officer pretended to be interested in buying it and arrested them .
The newspaper did not give any details about the manuscript but said it had been relinquished to the Islamic Museum in Cairo .
New U.S. ambassador arrives in Saudi Arabia .
DUBAI 1996-08-29
Washington 's new ambassador to Saudi Arabia , Wyche Fowler , arrived in the kingdom to take up his post , the U.S. embassy in Riyadh said on Thursday .
Fowler , a lawyer and former senator , arrived late on Wednesday , the embassy said in a statement .
President Bill Clinton earlier this month invoked special powers to appoint Fowler during the congressional recess because the Senate delayed confirming his nomination .
Fowler 's predecessor Raymond Mabus returned to the United States in May .
Jordanian PM Kabariti leaves for West Bank .
AMMAN 1996-08-29
Jordanian Prime Minister Abdul-Karim al-Kabariti left Amman on Thursday for the West Bank town of Ramallah to hold talks with Palestinian President Yasser Arafat on the stalled Middle East peace process , officials said .
The official state news agency Petra said Kabariti would hold discussions " on the latest developments in the peace process and bilateral cooperation " .
The visit was Kabariti 's first trip outside the country since Jordan was shaken by food riots earlier this month .
Palestinians end four-hour strike .
JERUSALEM 1996-08-29
Palestinians reopened their shops on Thursday at the end of a four-hour strike called by President Yasser Arafat to protest against Israel 's policy on Jewish settlements and Jerusalem , witnesses said .
Shopkeepers in Arab East Jerusalem rolled up their shutters some 10 minutes before the scheduled noon ( 0900 GMT ) end of the stoppage .
Palestinian leaders called the strike , the first in the West Bank and Gaza since 1994 , a warning signal that the peace process with Israel was in danger .
Witnesses said most shops were closed in towns and villages in the areas , with the exception of Hebron , a West Bank city still under Israeli occupation .
U.S. wheat weekly export sales highlights - USDA .
WASHINGTON 1996-08-29
U.S. wheat major net sales activity in the week ended Aug 22 reported by exporters for the following purchasing countries , in tonnes :
Net Sales : 1996/97 1997/98
Egypt 199,900 Nil
S. Korea 149,100-A
Japan 74,600
China 55,000-B
Indonesia 55,000-B
Unknown - 161,600
A- includes 54,600 tonnes changed from unknown .
B- reflects 55,000 tonnes changed from unknown .
Primary Export Destinations : Egypt , Morocco , S. Korea , Yemen , Pakistan , Mexico and China .
Keane wins contract from ING units .
BOSTON 1996-08-29
Software services company Keane Inc said it had won a year 2000 compliance contract from Life Insurance Co of Georgia and Southland Life Insurance Co , both part of The Netherlands ' ING Group .
The company said in a statement late on Wednesday it would conduct an enterprise assessment and strategic compliance plan for preparing all the mainframe systems of Life of Georgia and Southland Life to operate in the new century .
The project will be managed by Keane 's Atlanta office .
" The client 's goal is to complete its year 2000 conversion activities by the end of 1997 , " the statement said .
-- New York newsroom , ( 212 ) 859-1610
PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Aug 29 .
NEW YORK 1996-08-29
The National Basketball Association has sued America Online Inc , alleging that the United States ' No 1 on-line service is delivering real-time information about league games without its permission , The Wall Street Journal reported on Thursday .
The suit was filed on Wednesday in federal court in Manhattan and is another legal skirmish over what constitutes a " broadcast " in the computer age .
The suit contends America Online was misappropriating NBA property by providing a site containing continually updated scores and statistics of NBA games in progress .
The newspaper also reported :
* Baxter International Inc has reached an agreement to acquire Austria 's Immuno International AG in a complex deal valued at $ 715 miilion .
* Boeing Co secures $ 5.5 billion in orders for new , larger 747s .
* President Bill Clinton is expected to propose a tax break on home sales .
* Philip Morris Cos Inc raises dividend 20 percent .
* Salomon Brothers Inc analyst is bullish on International Business Machines Corp .
* Sierra Semiconductor Corp puts modem chipset line up for sale and sets layoffs .
* Red Lion Hotels Inc says it 's holding merger talks with Doubletree Corp .
* GTE Corp , Baby Bells and their allies ready to launch challenge to telecommunications reform law .
* Economists see second-quarter gross domestic product revised down 0.1 percentage point .
* President Clinton proposes five-point plan to clean up toxic waste sites .
* Securities and Exchange Commission acts to improve stock-trade prices for investors .
* H&R Block Inc delays spinoff of its stake in CompuServe Corp .
* Stock funds see cash pour in again in July .
* The Federal Trade Commission and Justice Department issue new guidelines for formation of doctors ' networks .
-- New York newsroom , ( 212 ) 859-1610
Baker made secret trip to Syria in March 1995 .
WASHINGTON 1996-08-29
Former Secretary of State James Baker made a secret trip to Syria in March 1995 in an unsuccessful bid to break an impasse in negotiations between Syria and Israel , the Washington Post reported on Thursday .
The paper said Baker declined to discuss the trip , but authorised an associate to confirm it took place and give an account of it .
News of the secret trip came after Baker trashed the Clinton administration at the Republican National Convention two weeks ago for its efforts to nudge Syria into peace with Israel .
Baker made the March 1995 trip on the explicit understanding that it remain a secret , but after his speech at the GOP convention , Israel 's outgoing ambassador Itamar Rabinovich told a reporter about it , the Post said .
Baker was secretary of state in the Republican administration of President George Bush .
Clinton wins Democratic re-nomination .
CHICAGO 1996-08-28
President Bill Clinton was formally nominated on Wednesday as the Democratic party candidate for a second four-year term in the White House .
Clinton won the nomination in a traditional state-by-state roll call of votes at the party convention and will accept in a speech on Thursday .
He faces Republican challenger Bob Dole in the November 5 presidential election .
Beachcomber finds piece that could be TWA part .
ATLANTIC HIGHLANDS , N.J. 1996-08-28
A foot-long piece of debris bearing markings from a commercial aircraft was found on the New Jersey shore and forwarded to TWA crash investigators in Long Island , officials said on Wednesday .
A person walking on the shore at Island Beach State Park found the debris and alerted police who forwarded it to Long Island , New York , where the National Transportation Safety Board and the FBI are conducting an investigation .
The TWA jet exploded in a deadly fireball last month , killing 230 people , crashing in the Atlantic Ocean at least 80 miles from where the debris was found Wednesday .
Several other items have been reported found along the New Jersey shore , most of it such personal items as wallets , shoes and jewelry .
Investigators said they still do not have enough evidence to determine whether a bomb , a missile or mechanical failure caused the crash .
FEATURE - Rich new detail on U.S. Civil War unearthed .
Leila Corcoran
WASHINGTON 1996-08-29
A freed black man writes to his still-enslaved wife , a mother pleads with Abraham Lincoln on behalf of her son and a maimed soldier poses for an official photograph in newly reopened records that bring the U.S. Civil War back to life .
Working in the basement of the National Archives , members of the Civil War Conservation Corps are organising the military records of volunteers who fought for the North so that they can be preserved on microfilm .
The faded documents have been stowed away in the Archives since it opened in 1935 and have rarely seen the light of day .
Each soldier 's file is a gold mine of information : enlistment papers , muster rolls , medical records , discharge certificates , letters and photographs .
Since the project began almost two years ago , corps volunteers have focused on African American troops , preparing records in time for the unveiling in Washington this year of a special memorial to black soldiers who fought in the war .
More than 185,000 black soldiers fought and 37,000 died .
In one letter , a black soldier heading South wrote his wife , " though great is the present national difficulties yet I look forward to a brighter day when I shall have the oportunity of seeing you in the full enjoyment of freedom .
" I would like to no ( sic ) if you are still in slavery if you are , it will not be long before we shall have crushed the system that now oppreses you for in the course of three months you shall have your liberty .
Great is the outpouring of the coloured people that is now rallying with the heart of lions against the very curse that has separated you and me . "
In another letter dated January 1865 , a well-to-do Washington matron wrote to Lincoln to plead for her son , who faced a dishonourable discharge from the Army . "
James is a prisoner for a thoughtless act of folly , while those who have done nothing for the cause are free , " she wrote .
Lincoln 's notation on the letter read : " If his colonel will say in writing on this sheet he is willing to receive this man back to the regiment , I will pardon and send him . "
The soldier was subsequently pardoned .
While the letters speak to the anguish of separation , a photograph of a black amputee speaks to the terrible physical cost of the war .
In a picture required for his military discharge , Pvt .
Lewis Martin , with haunted eyes , posed bare-chested to reveal his missing arm and leg , blown off during a battle at Petersburg , Virginia , in July 1864 .
The work on black troops has provided new insight into the rhythms of plantation talk and culture , said John Simon , professor of history at Southern Illinois University at Carbondale and editor of Gen .
Ulysses Grant 's papers .
" These ( writings ) are not only poetic but a linguistic treasure trove .
This is the first generation of African Americans that really can express itself without fear and punishment , " Simon said .
" I think there 's probably a whole lot of material that would expand our understanding of the sociology of the war , " said Edward Smith , director of American Studies at American University in Washington .
The war between the North and South raged for nearly four years , claimed the lives of half a million Americans and forever seared the nation 's consciousness .
Southern records have already been preserved .
They were put on microfilm about 30 years ago through a grant from the United Daughters of the Confederacy .
The Civil War Conservation Corps is mostly retirees joined by students during the school year .
Director Budge Weidman , who has shepherded the project from the beginning , predicts it will take up to a decade to complete .
The work was inspired by a National Park Service plan to put computer databases at Civil War battlefields across the country so that Americans might research their ancestors .
The records also provide insight into medical thinking of the day .
One soldier was discharged because of " mental incapacity and inebetude ( sic ) of the brain , alleged by the Patient to be connected with a fall on the head but believed to arise from long continued and excessive masturbation . "
Clinton arrives in Chicago on day of re-nomination .
CHICAGO 1996-08-28
President Bill Clinton arrived in Chicago on Wednesday as the Democratic convention prepared to re-nominate him for a second four-year term .
Clinton flew in by helicopter from Michigan City , Indiana , after ending a four-day , 559-mile trip aboard a campaign train from Washington .
New bomb attacks on Corsica despite crackdown vow .
Sylvie Florence
AJACCIO , Corsica 1996-08-29
Separatist guerrillas planted two bombs overnight at government offices on the French Mediterranean island of Corsica despite fresh warnings of a crackdown by Paris , police said on Thursday .
In the latest in a wave of attacks , a two kg ( four lb ) bomb seriously damaged two floors of Agriculture Ministry offices located just 50 metres ( yards ) from a police station in the centre of the island capital Ajaccio .
No one was hurt .
A second device , packed with five kg ( 10 lbs ) of explosive , was defused before it could go off , police said .
The new attacks followed by a day a warning of a new " get-tough " policy by Paris toward the separatists , who seek greater autonomy .
Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre , under fire for staging secret talks with one of the largest of several rival underground nationalist groups , told the daily La Corse in a statement he had given " firm orders " to police to round up those responsible for the bombings and bring them to justice .
Judges on the island had accused Paris of taking a lax stance on guerrilla violence while conducting secret but widely-reported talks with separatists which have now failed .
The latest bombing , close on the heels of the new orders , brought charges that police were powerless .
" No searches , no arrests , no police reinforcements visible on the island , despite the ministry 's promises , " the daily France-Soir lamented .
" On the island , as at the Place Beauvau ( the Interior Ministry 's Paris address ) , people are well aware who is who and who is doing what .
It is time to end this nightly farce , " said the pro-government daily Le Figaro in an editorial .
No one immediately claimed responsibility for Thursday 's incidents , which brought to 23 the number of guerrilla attacks on the resort island since mid-August , when separatist guerrillas ended a shaky seven-month truce .
Corsica has been racked by low-level separatist-inspired violence , principally directed against government targets , for two decades .
The daily Le Monde reported on Wednesday some separatist movements were considering taking their attacks to the French mainland on the principle that " 300 grammes of explosives on the continent have more impact than 300 kilos in Corsica " .
The newspaper said separatists may take advantage of social unrest widely expected on the mainland in coming weeks over government austerity plans to stoke a popular backlash against the government .
Sweden 's OM to open London forest products bourse .
STOCKHOLM 1996-08-29
Swedish options and derivatives exchange OM Gruppen AB said on Thursday it would open an electronic bourse for forest industry products in London in the first half of 1997 .
" Together with subsidiaries OMLX , the London Securities & Derivatives Exchange and OM Stockholm , OM Gruppen will open an international electronic bourse for forest products in the first half of 1997 , " OM Gruppen said in a statement .
The first commodity to be traded on the PULPEX bourse will be pulp , but OM said trade would be extended to include products such as timber , recycled paper and other paper qualities .
" Through the establishment of PULPEX , London will have a commodities bourse for forest products which complements existing bourses for oil , metals and ' softs ' ( coffee , sugar and cocoa ) , " OM said .
PULPEX was the result of a three-year project run in cooperation between OM and representatives of the forest industry , the company said .
Huge swings in the price of pulp over the past few years have made pulp producers ' profitability unpredictable , and made investing in new production capacity a risky business .
" Without the ability to hedge prices , changes in the world market price for pulp has had an immediate impact on players ' profitability , " OM said .
It said global production of pulp amounted to around 200 million tonnes per year , of which around 20 percent or 40 million tonnes was sold on the spot market .
At current prices , the value of this production was around $ 25 billion .
PULPEX will be both a marketplace and a clearing house , OM said , adding that the British Securities and Investments Board had been informed of OM 's plans .
PULPEX 's clearing operation will be covered by the parent company guarantee issued by OM Gruppen to its wholly-owned bourses and clearing organisations .
-- Stockholm newsroom , +46-8-700 1006
Amsterdam-Rotterdam-Antwerp oil stock levels fall .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-29
Oil product inventories held in independent tankage in the Amsterdam-Rotterdam-Antwerp area were at the following levels , with week-ago and year-ago levels , industry sources said .
All figures in thousands of tonnes :
29/8/96 22/8/96 1/9/95
Gasoline 400 400-425 425
Naphtha 50-75 75-100 50-75
Gas oil 1,600 1,650 1,850-1,900
Fuel oil 325 325-350 425
Jet kero 15 15-20 25
Motor gasoline stocks dipped slightly as barges left for Germany , but there were few inflows of cargoes .
Naphtha inventories also dropped as Germany again took barges and no cargoes entered ARA .
Gas oil stocks fell with some cargoes arriving from the former Soviet Union , but very fast throughput to markets in Benelux , Germany and Switzerland .
Fuel oil inventories dipped slightly with some straight-run arrivals , but fair bunkering demand removing more material .
Jet fuel stocks lowered as the aviation sector bought .
-- Philip Blenkinsop , Amsterdam newsroom 31 20 504 5000
German anti-nuclear activists in pantomime protest .
BONN 1996-08-29
About 200 German anti-nuclear activists protested on Thursday against nuclear waste transportation by re-enacting scenes from a demonstration they staged in May that turned into a violent clash with police .
Activists dressed as police brandished batons and firing a theatre-prop water cannon at " demonstrators " .
Police who had turned out in force all around the government quarter fearing violence looked on in amusement .
Last May dozens of demonstrators and police were injured in violent clashes around the Gorleben nuclear waste depot as hundreds of protesters tried to block a delivery of waste by train and truck .
Italy police arrest five over double Mafia killing .
CATANIA , Sicily 1996-08-29
Italian Police said on Thursday they had arrested five people in connection with the slaying of the daughter and 14-year-old nephew of a Mafia boss earlier this week .
Santa Puglisi , 22 , and Salvatore Botta were gunned down in a cemetery in this eastern Sicilian city on Tuesday in a crime which shocked even hardened anti-Mafia investigators .
The arrests followed a tip-off from a married couple who unexpectedly showed up at investigators ' offices on Wednesday . "
They wanted to get a weight off their consciences , " a police spokesman said .
He added the couple had also shed light on the murder last year of the wife of Mafia boss Nitto Santapaola .
Puglisi was shot as she knelt praying by the tomb of her young husband , who was himself killed last year in a Mafia ambush .
Botta , who had accompanied Puglisi to the cemetary , tried to flee the lone gunman but was caught and killed .
Thieves make off with cash from prison canteen .
LIMERICK , Ireland 1996-08-29
Thieves stole almost 2,000 Irish pounds ( $ 3,000 ) from the officers ' canteen of a Limerick jail on Thursday while warders slept in a room upstairs .
Police said the thieves intercepted a woman arriving to work at the canteen , forced her to open the safe where takings were kept and made off with the cash .
While the robbery was going on , several officers were asleep in a room over the canteen , which is in the grounds of the prison on Ireland 's southwest coast .
Italians hold HIV-pensioner for harassing hookers .
GENOA , Italy 1996-08-29
Italian police said on Thursday they had arrested a 61-year-old man after he fired blank shots at prostitutes he blamed for spreading AIDS .
The pensioner , named only as Pietro T. , told investigators he was infected with HIV , the AIDS virus , and his wife had died of the disease .
He did not say how they had contracted the illness .
Police said the man had recently been spotted cruising red-light areas in this northern Italian city , hurling abuse at prostitutes and firing blank shots at them .
Police said they found in his apartment two fake guns and a pistol that would only fire blanks . "
Although fake guns are legal , the use he made of them means he could be tried , " a police official said .
Bodies found at site of Russian jet crash - officials .
OSLO 1996-08-29
Bodies have been sighted but no survivors have yet been found at the site of Thursday 's crash of a Russian airliner on Norway 's remote Arctic island of Spitzbergen , Norwegian officials said .
" We have found dead people , " said Rune Hansen , the island 's deputy governor , told Norwegian television .
The Norwegian news agency NTB quoted another official on the island as saying no survivors had been found .
The Vnukovo Airlines Tupolev 154 flight from Moscow , carrying 129 passengers and a crew of 12 , crashed in bad weather 10 km ( six miles ) east of Longyearbyen , the island 's only airstrip , officials said .
First rescuers arrived shortly after 1 p.m. ( 1100 GMT ) and reported soon afterwards that most of the three-engine jet 's wreckage was scattered around the top of the small Opera mountain while the rest had slid down the mountainside .
Air traffic officials said they had lost contact with the flight , scheduled to arrive at around 10.15 a.m. ( 0815 GMT ) , shortly before it was due to land .
Spitzbergen is a Norwegian coal-mining settlement .
The only other community is in the Russian village of Barentsburg .
Russia and Norway share the island 's resources under a treaty dating back to the 1920s .
Galeforce winds and heavy rains batter Belgium .
BRUSSELS 1996-08-29
Torrential rains and galeforce winds battered Belgium on Thursday causing widespread damage as some areas had more rainfall in 24 hours than they normally get in a month , the meteorological office said .
Cellars were flooded , trees uprooted and roofs damaged , but there were no reports of any injuries , an interior affairs ministry spokesman said .
Some trains were delayed as fallen trees blocked lines .
Brussels received 5.6 cm ( 2.24 inches ) of water in the past 24 hours -- compared to an average 7.4 cm ( 2.96 inches ) per month -- but in several communes in the south of the country up to 8 cm ( 3.2 inches ) fell , the Royal Meteorological Institute ( RMT ) said .
The RMT spokesman said that near the eastern city of Turnhout , a group of boy scouts camping in a low-lying meadow had to be evacuated as water flooded their tents .
The rain also severely hindered Belgian investigators ' excavations in the southern village of Jumet , where they are looking for bodies in one of the houses of the main character in a paedophile sex-and-murder scandal .
But the coastal towns got off lightly as the flooding that had been expected due to a combination of spring tides and high winds failed to materialise .
Repsol shares up 65 pesetas on H1 results .
MADRID 1996-08-29
Shares in Spanish oil and chemicals group Repsol were up 65 pesetas to 4,150 after the company announced net first half profits fell 1.1 percent to 61.45 billion pesetas on the previous year .
This was close to the market 's forecast of net profits of 61.94 billion .
Shares in Repsol shot up 100 pesetas to 4,175 shortly after the figures , having traded down 10 pesetas before the figures were released .
" It 's madness , " said an analyst at a Madrid brokerage , adding that the market had overreacted to the news . "
People were waiting for the results to come out before buying .
The rise has been very quick and very crazy . "
He predicted a correction , perhaps as early as this session .
-- Madrid Newsroom +34 1 585 2161
Algeria forces kill guerrillas - papers .
PARIS 1996-08-29
Algerian security forces killed four Moslem guerrillas on Tuesday in a village south of the capital Algiers , an Algerian newspaper said on Thursday .
The armed militants were shot dead in Nahar village 90 km ( 56 miles ) south of Algiers , Liberte newspaper said .
Security forces also killed an unspecified number of members of a rebel gang on Wednesday in the Leveilly suburb of Algiers , Le Matin newspaper reported .
An estimated 50,000 people , mostly Moslem militants and security forces members , have been killed in violence pitting Moslem guerrillas against government forces since early 1992 , when authorities cancelled a general election in which Islamists had taken a commanding lead .
Finns hold two men on child sex-abuse charges .
HELSINKI 1996-08-29
Finnish police said on Thursday they had arrested two men suspected of sexually abusing a captive 13-year-old girl , but did not believe the case was linked to others in Europe .
The men , both Finns aged about 40 , were arrested last Saturday in the western town of Tampere in a raid on a luxury boat owned by one of them .
The girl was being held on the boat and had sought help from a passer-by , police chief inspector Ilkka Laasonen said .
" This is an individual case and I do n't have any evidence linking the suspects to any other cases , " Laasonen said .
The girl was taken to hospital .
The men could face charges carrying up to six to 10 years in prison , he said .
Witnesses had reported seeing many young women and some girls who looked clearly underage at parties around the boat in recent weeks , the daily newspaper Iltalehti said .
Audi CEO says expects no 96 currency impact .
INGOLSTADT 1996-08-29
Audi AG management board chairman Herbert Demel said on Thursday that the German luxury carmaker , a unit of Volkswagen AG , did not expect any burden on its 1996 results from currency market volatility .
" We do not expect any burden on our 1996 results from currency markets , " Demel told Reuters in an interview .
Audi would have been able to report a profit 300 million marks higher in 1995 if exchange rates had stayed the same as in 1994 , Demel had told a shareholder meeting last April .
Demel said the carmaker had hedged about half of its currency risk for 1996 .
-- John Gilardi , Frankfurt Newsroom , +49 69 756525
KEKKILA SEES FULL-YR 1996 PROFIT VS LOSS .
HELSINKI 1996-08-29
Fertilisers and saplings maker Kekkila Oy said on Thursday in a statement it expected a falling result trend in the latter half of the year , but a full-year profit was nevertheless likely .
" Due to natural seasonal fluctuations in operations , the end-year result trend will be falling , but based on the early year result trend a profitable result is likely to be achieved , " Kekkila said in its January-June interim report .
In 1995 , Kekkila reported a 5.6 million markka loss before extraordinary items and tax .
In the first half , Kekkila posted a 6.1 million markka profit , up from 0.7 million .
-- Helsinki Newsroom +358 - 0 - 680 50 245
INTERVIEW-T&N untroubled by margin pressure .
LONDON 1996-08-29
The chairman of British-based components and engineering group T&N Plc said on Thursday the firm remained confident about the general prospects for its operating margins despite pressure from unsettled markets .
In an interview following its first-half results , which included a less optimistic forecast for the second half of this year than it had made in the past , Sir Colin Hope said T&N had taken defensive action to protect it from patchy markets .
Looking at market prospects , he said : " I think our best judgment at this stage is that it will probably bumble along in the rather mixed way it 's been in the first half . "
" It 's very difficult to predict the market ( trend ) this year .
It could be better , or it could be worse , " Hope added , echoing the demand uncertainty across automotive industries .
" You can see anxieties in Germany and France , in particular , beginning to grow and develop .
America , however , is looking a little better , " he said .
Compared with the end of last year , when T&N predicted a sluggish first half and a rebound later in 1996 , Hope said : " I think the difference ( now ) is the first half has not actually been as bad as some felt it was going to be , but equally we 're certainly not predicting a recovery in the second half . "
Against this background , Hope said the group was glad it had rationalised and destocked even though this had pressed margins , which had slipped to 9.5 percent from 11.3 percent a year ago .
" I think the figure of 9.5 percent on the first half , when you consider the fact that we 've been destocking , the fairly mixed customer demand , and the fact that we sold the ( southern African ) mines actually is not bad .
" It does show how easily we should be able to bounce back over 10 percent again , " he added , saying : " We continue to feel very relaxed about our general view that we would average 10 percent profit margins over the cycle . "
" We 've always taken the view that we are the sort of company that 's quite capable of working in difficult circumstances -- we 're rather used to it .
And we feel very confident that we 're doing all the right things , " Hope said .
" When the ( profit ) figures will bounce back up again is just a function of markets recovering just a fraction , " he added .
Commenting on the continued struggle to get control of German piston maker Kolbenschmidt , which has been hampered by regulatory obstacles , Hope said T&N 's confidence " continues to improve " that it may eventually be able to proceed .
-- Andrew Huddart , London Newsroom , +44 171 542 8716
Earthquake jolts New Zealands South Island .
WELLINGTON 1996-08-29
An earthquake measuring 5.5 on the Richter scale shook New Zealands upper South Island on Thursday but there were no reports of injuries , Television New Zealand said .
It said the quake , centred near the small town of Waiau , was strongly felt in the cities of Nelson and Christchurch .
Some minor damage had been reported in the spa town of Hanmer .
New Zealand is prone to frequent earthquakes but they rarely cause major damage .
The country has only 3.5 million people in an area about the size of Britain or Japan .
Hong Kong 's Tsang sees growth , smooth transition .
Mark Trevelyan
WELLINGTON 1996-08-29
Hong Kong Financial Secretary Donald Tsang said on Thursday he expected the territory 's economy to keep growing at around five percent but with some fluctuations from year to year .
Tsang , who made the remarks during a visit to New Zealand , also spoke strongly in favour of keeping the Hong Kong dollar pegged to its U.S. counterpart , and said negotiations with China on next year 's budget were going smoothly .
Hong Kong 's economy grew by only 3.1 percent in the first quarter , down from 5.9 percent a year earlier , and some private sector economists have revised downwards their predictions for the 1996 year .
Second quarter growth estimates will be released when the Hong Kong government issues its half-yearly economic report on Friday .
" Our trend growth rate of five percent in real terms is pretty solid , " Tsang told a news conference after meeting New Zealand Finance Minister Bill Birch .
" There will be fluctuations in individual years , but it wo n't be a big margin , " he said .
He said inflation was under control and the Hong Kong dollar was " rock solid " .
Its link to the U.S. dollar had proved an engine of growth for the past 12 years .
" There 's absolutely no economic or financial or political reason for us to change .
A lot of investment in Hong Kong , some of which ( is ) by China , is predicated on the link continuing . "
Britain will hand over Hong Kong to Chinese sovereignty at midnight on June 30 , 1997 .
Tsang said three sets of meetings with Chinese authorities on Hong Kong 's 1997-98 budget , which will span the transition period , had gone smoothly . "
None of our basic precepts have been challenged . "
Hong Kong will retain its own currency after the handover , run its own financial and monetary policy and have control over its own foreign exchange reserves .
It will have no duty to contribute any taxes to Beijing , Tsang said .
He described the condition of the property market as " very good indeed " .
" You know , we went through a little climb and a little trough over the last few years .
Because of speculation in the market we introduced certain measures , but they are not draconian measures , and we brought it down to earth . "
Tsang said the market would continue to appreciate because property and land were scarce .
The government would put land on the market to stop rentals " going through the roof " , but this would mean reclamation , with possible environmental problems .
" There will be on the whole a slightly upward climb , consistent with our economic growth rate , " he said in reference to the property market .
Tsang , the third senior figure in the government after the governor and chief secretary , said his stated aim was to serve as financial secretary for two years under British rule and three years under China .
Taiwan dollar ends higher , narrow trade seen .
TAIPEI 1996-08-29
The Taiwan dollar closed slightly firmer on Thursday amid tight Taiwan dollar liquidity in the banking system , and dealers said the rate was likely to move narrowly in the near term .
The Taiwan dollar fell in early trade on month-end U.S. dollar demand , but the downtrend was later reversed as Taiwan dollar liquidity tightened . "
Banks do not want to hold big U.S. dollar positions at this moment , " said one dealer , adding that the rate was likely to hover around current levels .
The rate closed at T$ 27.482 against Wednesday 's T$ 27.495 .
Turnover was US$ 275 million .
-- Joyce Liu ( 2-5080815 )
SIMEX Nikkei ends down but off lows .
SINGAPORE 1996-08-29
Simex Nikkei futures ended easier but off the day 's lows on Thursday .
Dealers said selling in the session was a follow-through from Wednesday 's gloomy Tankan corporate report by the Bank of Japan .
" The Nikkei is testing support at the 20,500 level .
Sentiment is a bit gloomy because people are focusing on the weak recovery in the economy at the moment , " said a dealer with a European bank .
September Nikkei settled at 20,605 after touching an intraday low of 20,530 against its previous close of 20,725 .
Volume was 19,560 contracts .
Dealers said technically , the index should see good support at 20,300 and the upside should be capped at 21,000 .
-- Doreen Siow 65-8703092
Siam Commercial wins agency bond auctions .
BANGKOK 1996-08-29
A consortium led by Thailand 's Siam Commercial Bank Plc has secured at auction the right to sell two state agency bond issues worth a combined 3.73 billion baht , an official at the bank said on Thursday .
The Government Housing Bank will issue bonds worth three billion baht and the metropolitan Waterworks Authority will issue bonds worth 730 million , an investment banker at Siam Commercial Bank told Reuters .
The consortium , made up of eight financial institutions , offered an annual interest rate of 8.46 percent for both issues , he said .
Both state agency bonds will have seven-year maturity and will be issued on September 5 , he said .
-- Bangkok newsroom ( 662 ) 652-0642
M'bishi Gas sets terms on 7-year straight .
TOKYO 1996-08-29
BORROWER - Mitsubishi Gas Chemical Co Ltd
LEAD MGR - Nomura Securities Co Ltd
FISCAL AGENT - Tokyo-Mitsubishi Bank
TYPE straight bond ISSUE NO 13 AMT 10 bln yen
COUPON 2.95 % ISS PRICE MATURITY 5 .
Sep.03
LAST MOODY 'S PAY DATE 5 .
Sep.96
FIRST INT PAY 5 .
Mar.97 INT PAY 5 .
Mar / Sep
LAST S&P SIGN DATE SUB DATE 5 .
Jul-18.Jul
LAST JCR LAST JBRI A LAST NIS
S. Korea Daewoo , Dacom units in Polish telecom JV .
SEOUL 1996-08-29
South Korea 's Daewoo Corp , unlisted Daewoo Information Systems Co Ltd , Dacom Corp and Dacom International have set up a joint venture to offer telecommunications services in Poland .
Daewoo Dacom Communications ( Poland ) Ltd , which was set up with an initial investment of $ 1.0 million , is expected to have sales of $ 60 million by the year 2000 , a Daewoo statement said on Thursday ..
Daewoo Corp will take a 31 percent stake in the venture , Dacom International 25 percent , Dacom 24 percent , and Daewoo Information 20 percent , the statement said .
Daewoo Corp and Daewoo Information are units of Daewoo Group .
-- Seoul Newsroom ( 822 ) 727 5644
Salomon & Taylor - 96/97 div forecast .
TOKYO 1996-08-29
Year to March 31 , 1997
( in billions of yen unless specified )
LATEST ACTUAL
( Parent ) FORECAST YEAR-AGO
Ord div 10.00 yen 8.00 yen
- Commem div - 2.00 yen
NOTE - Salomon & Taylor Made Co Ltd manufactures golf clubs and sells ski equipment .
Indonesia plays down U.S. consulate attack .
JAKARTA 1996-08-29
Indonesia sought on Thursday to play down a fire bomb attack on a U.S. consulate earlier this week , saying it was being treated as a criminal rather than a political act , the official Antara news agency said .
The police are still investigating the incident .
It is evident the happening is not politically motivated but just an ordinary criminal act , the news agency quoted East Java military commander Major-General Utomo as saying .
The Tuesday morning attack on the consulate in Indonesias second largest city of Surabaya , caused slight damage to a guard house before being quickly extinguished , a spokesman at the U.S. embassy in Jakarta , 700 km ( 430 miles ) west of Surabaya , said on Wednesday .
No one was injures , he said .
Nobody should try and exaggerate it by calling it a bomb because it was just a molotov cocktail , Utomo said .
He said police were investigating the incident and patrols around diplomatic offices in Surabaya would be stepped up .
Airport Facilities - 6mth parent forecast .
TOKYO 1996-08-29
Six months to September 30 , 1996
( in billions of yen unless specified )
LATEST PREVIOUS ACTUAL
( Parent ) FORECAST FORECAST YEAR-AGO
Sales 11.38 11.38 11.45
Current 1.09 1.09 918 million
Net 934 million 490 million 538 million
NOTE - Airport Facilities Co Ltd manages and rents facilities at Haneda ( Tokyo ) and Itami ( Osaka ) airports .
HK civil servants contest ban on China panel .
HONG KONG 1996-08-29
Senior Hong Kong civil servants were given the go-ahead on Thursday to challenge a government ban on them standing for the Beijing-backed panel to choose the territory 's first post-handover leader and lawmakers .
The Supreme Court ruled that a judicial hearing contesting the ban would be heard on September 11 , three days before the nomination period for the Selection Committee closes .
The government maintains the ban , announced earlier this month , is necessary to avoid a possible conflict of interest because civil servants are involved in determining government policy .
Civil servants argue the ban stymies their political rights .
The 400-strong Selection Committee will select Hong Kong 's future chief executive to replace the British governor and a provisional legislature to take over from the elected chamber which Beijing plans to dissolve .
Hong Kong , a British colony for more than 150 years , will be handed back to China at midnight on June 30 next year .
China intends to dismantle the territory 's first fully-elected legislature because it opposes Britain 's recent electoral reforms and install an interim appointed chamber , a decision that has generated considerable controversy .
The judicial review sought by directorate-grade bureaucrats will apply to only about 1,000 of the approximately 33,000 civil servants affected .
Police unions are not contesting the ban , which affects all 27,000 officers , and nor are the very top tier of Hong Kong 's mandarin class , the policy secretaries .
More than 16,000 application forms for places on the Selection Committee have been handed out since the nomination period opened .
It closes on September 14 .
Singapore Refining Company expected to shut CDU 3 .
SINGAPORE 1996-08-29
Singapore Refining Company ( SRC ) is expected to shutdown its 60,000 barrel-per-day ( bpd ) crude distillation unit ( CDU ) in September , an industry source said on Thursday .
" They think something is stuck , " the source said . "
But nothing has been decided as they are still waiting for an X-ray machine to determine the problem . "
The source said the problem was discovered during the past month during which time CDU No.3 's production has varied from maximum capacity of 60,000 bpd to as low as 40,000 bpd , depending on the crude being run .
" We are having a lot of problems , " said a source .
An earlier problem with CDU No .
3 arose on July 24 when an industry source said the CDU would be closed down briefly in August for repairs to a heat exchanger .
But by mid-August , a company spokesman said repairs had been carried out without any shutdown .
The 285,000 bpd SRC refinery is co-owned by the Singapore Petroleum Company , British Petrolem and Caltex , the joint-venture of U.S. majors Chevron Corp and Texaco Inc .
-- Singapore Newsroom ( +65-8703086 )
Loxley H1 net rises to 332.66 mln baht .
BANGKOK 1996-08-29
Reviewed financial results for the first six months ended June 30 , 1996 .
( in millions of baht unless stated )
Six months
1996 1995
Shr ( baht ) 8.32 vs 6.66
Net 332.66 vs 266.37
NOTES : Second quarter figures not available .
Full name of company is Loxley Publications Plc .
-- Bangkok newsroom 662-252-9950
INDICATORS - Spain - updated August 29 .
INDICATORS - monthly MTH / MTH PVS YR-AGO INDEX TOTAL
CPI ( % ) Jul +0.1 - 0.1 +0.0 119.3** -
Yr / yr Inflation ( % ) +3.7 +3.6 +4.7 119.3 -
Core Inflation +0.1 +0,2 +0,2 - -
Yr / yr rise +3.5 +3.6 +5.2 - -
JOBLESS ( INEM ) Jul - 63,913 - 33,149 - 65,345 - 2.17M
Rate ( % ) 13.67 14.15 15.19 - -
BALANCE OF PAYMENTS
Trade ( bln pts ) May - 196.8 - 180.6 - 279.9 - -
Cur Acc ( bln pts ) May - 9.5 - 42.0 - 110.4 - -
RESERVES ( $ MLN ) Jul +1,161 +400.9 +310.4 - 54,703.0
PRODUCER PRICES ( % ) Jun - 0.2 +0.1 +0.2 119.6** -
Yr / yr rise ( % ) +1.2 +1.5 +7.1 119.6 -
INDUSTRIAL PROD .
May - - - - -
Yr / yr figures ( % ) - 3.2 +1.0 +9.8 108.4** -
M4 MONEY SUPPLY ( % ) Jul +2.6 +4.2R +10.8 - -
Total M4 adj .
( trln pts ) - - - - 75.912
TRADE BALANCE
Exports ( bln pts ) Jun 1,100.7 1,164.1 988.2 - -
Imports ( bln pts ) May 1,315.7 1,433.4 1,236.5 - -
Deficit / surplus May - 215.0 - 269.3 - 248.3 - -
Deficit yr to date - 1,334.0 - 1,119.0 - 1,420.9 - -
GOVT.BUDGET ( bln pts ) Govt.Fcast 96
Deficit / surplus Jul +282.1 - 380.6 +230.4 -
Def .
/ surplus to date - 1,184.0 - 1,466.1 - 1,456.7 - 2.6 trln
INDICATORS - quarterly QUARTER PVS QTR YR-AGO - -
EPA Q2 +168,130 +31,230 +167,330 12.3 million
GDP
Yr-yr ( % ) Q1 +1.9 +2.3R +3.4 - -
Absolute amount ( trln pts ) 18.1 17.8 16.9 - 69.7
INTEREST RATES Latest rate Pvs rate Date changed
Key rate ( % ) 7.25 7.50 04/06/96
NOTES - Bank of Spain announces balance of payments .
Jobless figures are registered unemployed at labour ministry .
Trade data are customs-cleared , published by economy ministry .
Latest M4 , currency reserves , industrial production data are provisional .
GDP figures are quarterly on annualised basis .
EPA - Quarterly survey of employment levels ( INE ) .
Data give variation in employed persons , in thousands .
Last column - TOTAL- is latest for jobless and accumulated for the rest ( GDP total amount corresponds to 1995 ) .
Government budget figures relate to central government finances only .
**General Consumer Price Index ( 100=1992 ) , Producer Prices Index and Industrial Production Index ( 100=1990 ) .
PRESS DIGEST - Spain - Aug 29 .
Headlines from major national newspapers .
Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy .
EL PAIS
- Judge accuses government of obstructing investigation into Lasa-Zabala ( two of GAL victims ) case
EL MUNDO
- Government wants to charge for prescriptions and some medical services
DIARIO 16
- Judge Javier Gomez de Liano says government is obstructing justice
ABC
- Prime Minister Jose Maria Aznar , positive assessment
CINCO DIAS
- BCH in the hive of Chilean pensions
EXPANSION
- Coopers and Lybrand emigrates to Basque Country for fiscal reasons
GACETA DE LOS NEGOCIOS
- Government and Catalan nationalists set the scene for budget negotiations
Lenzing expects negative results in H2 .
VIENNA 1996-08-29
Austrian viscose fibre maker Lenzing AG said on Thursday it expected to post negative group results in the second half of the year after posting losses in the first six months .
" A preview of the second half of 1996 does not reveal any signs of a significant improvement in market conditions , " Lenzing said in a statement released ahead of its earnings conference .
For the first six months of the year , Lenzing said it posted a group pre-tax loss of 84.5 million schillings from a profit of 160 million in the year-ago period .
The group attributed the first-half losses to weak demand and falling prices of viscose fibres , as well as sluggish economies in the West .
-- Julia Ferguson , Vienna newsroom , +431 53112 274
Algeria faults Britain over Islamists gathering .
PARIS 1996-08-28
Algeria , fighting a vicious war against Moslem fundamentalist guerrillas , attacked Britain on Wednesday for allowing Islamist groups to meet in London .
The Islamist gathering , due to be held in London on September 8 , has triggered concern and anger in several other Arab countries like Egypt which is also fighting armed Moslem fundamentalists .
British Jewish groups have also voiced protest because they said Palestinian Islamist Hamas as well as the banned Algerian Islamic Salvation Front ( FIS ) are among those radical Islamists attending the conference .
A foreign ministry spokesman said in a statement read on Algerian television that Algeria " has received with concern the information over a meeting of terrorist groups working against the interests of the Arab and Islamic world . "
" Algeria expresses its sharp rejection of a meeting putting together masterminds and ideologists and financers of terrorism , " the spokesman said , adding the Algerian government has asked the British embassy in Algiers for clarifications .
The Algerian ambassador in London has also asked for clarification from the Foreign Office over the meeting of Islamist groups .
Algeria said " they are clearly working to undermine the stability " of Arab countries .
British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind said on Tuesday from Pakistan his government would only take action against the planned Islamists gathering in London if British law was broken .
" People who wish to hold conferences of course do n't need to seek permission from the government in Britain , " he said .
An estimated 50,000 people , including more than 110 foreigners , have been killed in Algeria 's violence pitting Moslem rebels against government forces since early 1992 when authorities in Algeria cancelled a general election in which FIS had taken a commanding lead .
OFFICIAL JOURNAL CONTENTS - OJ L 218 OF AUGUST 28 , 1996 .
*
Commission Regulation ( EC ) No 1676/96 of 30 July 1996 amending Regulation ( EEC ) No 2454/93 laying down provisions for the implementation of Council Regulation ( EEC ) No 2913/92 establishing the Community Customs Code END OF DOCUMENT .
Wall Street ponders Rubin 's role if Clinton wins .
Donna Sells
NEW YORK
The outcome of the November elections emerged as a hot topic on Wall Street this week as financial pundits debated whether Robert Rubin might forgo a second term as Treasury secretary if President Clinton is re-elected .
Concern centred on the currency markets since Rubin 's tour de force has been his unflagging support of the dollar .
Speculation that Rubin might not stay in his post grew after he sidestepped questions about any future Cabinet post during television interviews at the Democratic convention in Chicago this week .
Should Rubin leave , Wall Street would worry that he might take his strong-dollar policy with him .
Rubin 's predecessor at the Treasury , Lloyd Bentsen , was viewed with suspicion by some in the financial markets who thought he had tried to push down the dollar to gain an edge in trade negotiations with Japan .
" Obviously , under the Clinton administration , we 've seen two distinctively different dollar policies , " said Chris Widness , an international economist at Chase Securities Inc. " Under Rubin , the U.S. has certainly looked for a strong dollar . "
That strategy , backed up by timely instances of joint central bank intervention , helped the dollar battle back from post-Second World War lows of 1.3438 German marks on March 8 , 1995 , and 79.75 Japanese yen on April 19 , 1995 .
Currently , the dollar stands at about 1.48 marks and 109 yen .
Rubin was widely hailed as the architect of the dollar 's comeback , using skills and expertise gained in 26 years on Wall Street , part of which were spent as co-chairman of Goldman , Sachs and Co .
Inc .
" Rubin has done a fine job in that position , " said Michael Faust , a portfolio manager at Bailard , Biehl and Kaiser , which manages just under $ 1 billion in global stocks and bonds .
" Anyone who would come in there to replace him would have awfully big shoes to fill . "
Fear that a new Treasury secretary might favour a return to Bentsen-era policy could spell trouble for financial markets .
Some overseas investors might shy away from buying U.S. stocks and bonds or even sell them when the dollar is weakening .
As for U.S. Treasury securities , Widness explained that Alan Greenspan 's reappointment as chairman of the Federal Reserve and the outlook for the federal budget were more important than whether Rubin continues at the Treasury .
" Although , if we did get someone that was seen as looking for a dollar depreciation , it would probably hurt capital flows to the United States , " said Widness , adding that could hurt U.S. stocks and , to a lesser degree , bonds .
Still , markets may have little to fear from any Rubin successor because the firm dollar policy has yielded positive results .
If that is true , then any new Treasury chief would need to be as effective as Rubin in convincing markets that the White House does indeed want a strong currency .
" If he left , the first question people would ask the next guy is , ' What 's your view on the dollar ? '
" said Michael Perelstein , portfolio manager of MainStay International Funds .
" And all I can say as a piece of advice is that they 'd better say exactly the same thing ( as Rubin ) , if not stronger , " Perelstein said . "
Otherwise , you get selling out of Tokyo and Frankfurt again . "
SOCCER - AUSTRIA BEAT SCOTLAND 4-0 IN EUROPEAN UNDER-21 MATCH .
AMSTETTEN , Austria 1996-08-30
Austria beat Scotland 4-0 ( halftime 3-0 ) in a European under-21 championship match on Friday .
Scorers : Ewald Brenner ( 5th minute ) , Mario Stieglmair ( 42nd ) , Ronald Brunmayr ( 43rd and 56th ) .
Attendance : 800
SOCCER - WALES BEAT SAN MARINO 4-0 IN UNDER-21 MATCH .
BARRY , Wales 1996-08-30
Wales beat San Marino 4-0 ( halftime 2-0 ) in a European under-21 soccer match on Friday .
Scorers :
Wales - John Hartson ( 12th , 56th and 83rd minutes ) , Scott Young ( 24th )
Attendance : 1,800
CYCLING - BALLANGER KEEPS SPRINT TITLE IN STYLE .
Martin Ayres
MANCHESTER , England 1996-08-30
Felicia Ballanger of France confirmed her status as the world 's number one woman sprinter when she retained her title at the world cycling championships on Friday .
Ballanger beat Germany 's Annett Neumann 2-0 in the best-of-three matches final to add the world title to the Olympic gold medal she won in July .
France also took third place in the sprint , Magali Faure defeating ex-world champion Tanya Dubnicoff of Canada 2-0 .
Ballanger , 25 , will be aiming to complete a track double when she defends her 500 metres time trial title on Saturday .
The other final of the night , the women 's 24-kms points race , also ended in success for the reigning champion .
Russia 's Svetlana Samokhalova fought off a spirited challenge from American Jane Quigley to take the title for a second year .
Russia , the only nation to have two riders in the field , made full use of their numerical superiority .
Goulnara Fatkoullina helped Samokhalova to build an unbeatable points lead before snatching the bronze medal .
Quigley , a former medallist in the points event , led the race at half distance . "
I went so close this time , but having two riders certainly gave the Russians an advantage , " she said .
The first six riders lapped the field , which left former world champion Ingrid Haringa of the Netherlands down in seventh place despite having the second highest points score .
Olympic champion Nathalie Lancien of France also missed the winning attack and finished a disappointing 10th .
CYCLING - WORLD TRACK CHAMPIONSHIP RESULTS .
MANCHESTER , England 1996-08-30
Results at the world track cycling championships on Friday :
Women 's sprint semifinals ( best of three ) :
Annett Neumann ( Germany ) beat Magali Faure ( France ) 2-0 ( 12.341 and 12.348 seconds for the last 200 metres )
Felicia Ballanger ( France ) beat Tanya Dubnicoff ( Canada ) 2-0 , ( 12.130 / 12.124 )
Ride for third place :
Faure beat Dubnicoff 2-0 ( 12.112 / 12.246 )
Final :
Ballanger beat Neumann 2-0 ( 11.959 / 12.225 )
Women 's world points race championship ( 24-km ) :
1. Svetlana Samokhalova ( Russia ) 28 points ( in 32
minutes 31.081 seconds )
2. Jane Quigley ( U.S. ) 18 points
3. Goulnara Fatkoullina ( Russia ) 16
4. Tatiana Stiajkina ( Ukraine ) 11
5. Judith Arndt ( Germany ) 11
6. Tea Vikstedt-Nyman ( Finland ) 5
One lap behind :
7. Ingrid Haringa ( Netherlands ) 20
8. Sally Boyden ( Britain ) 9
9. Agnieszka Godras ( Poland ) 8
10. Nathalie Lancien ( France ) 8
SOCCER - FRENCH DEFENDER KOMBOUARE JOINS ABERDEEN .
ABDERDEEN , Scotland 1996-08-30
French central defender Antoine Kombouare has completed a 300,000 pounds sterling ( $ 467,000 ) move to Aberdeen from Swiss club Sion , the Scottish premier division club said on Friday .
Kombouare has signed a two-year contract and will make his debut against Morton in the Scottish League Cup on Tuesday .
But he will be ineligible for the rest of Aberdeen 's UEFA Cup campaign as he has already played for Sion in this season 's Cup Winners ' Cup .
Aberdeen manager Roy Aitken said : " It 's unfortunate for us that Antoine cannot play in Europe but he will help us achieve things in domestic competition .
" I have been watching him for several weeks now and have no doubts he brings real quality to the side .
He has a great deal of experience and I 'm sure he will quickly establish himself in both the team and the affection of our fans . "
The 32-year-old defender played seven seasons with Nantes and was with Paris St Germain for five seasons .
He said former PSG team mate David Ginola , who now plays for English premier league Newcastle , was influential in his move to Scotland .
" I 'm a very good friend of David and spoke to him recently about coming to Aberdeen and he was very positive about it , " Kombouare said .
" He said I would really enjoy life there and that I would settle in in terms of football as well .
That , and the fact he is only a few hours drive away , influenced my decision to come to Aberdeen . "
MOTORCYCLING - SAN MARINO GRAND PRIX PRACTICE TIMES .
IMOLA , Italy 1996-08-30
Practice times set on Friday
for Sunday 's San Marino 500cc motorcycling Grand Prix :
1. Michael Doohan ( Australia ) Honda one minute 50.250
2. Jean-Michel Bayle ( France ) Yamaha 1:50.727
3. Norifumi Abe ( Japan ) Yamaha 1:50.858
4. Luca Cadalora ( Italy ) Honda 1:51.006
5. Alex Criville ( Spain ) Honda 1:51.075
6. Scott Russell ( United States ) Suzuki 1:51.287
7. Tadayuki Okada ( Japan ) Honda 1:51.528
8. Carlos Checa ( Spain ) Honda 1:51.588
9. Alexandre Barros ( Brazil ) Honda 1:51.784
10. Shinichi Itoh ( Japan ) Honda 1:51.857
GOLF - BRITISH MASTERS THIRD ROUND SCORES .
NORTHAMPTON , England 1996-08-30
Leading scores after
the third round of the British Masters on Friday :
211 Robert Allenby ( Australia ) 69 71 71
212 Pedro Linhart ( Spain ) 72 73 67
216 Miguel Angel Martin ( Spain ) 75 70 71 , Costantino Rocca
( Italy ) 71 73 72
217 Antoine Lebouc ( France ) 74 73 70 , Ian Woosnam 70 76 71 ,
Francisco Cea ( Spain ) 70 71 76 , Gavin Levenson ( South
Africa ) 66 75 76
218 Stephen McAllister 73 76 69 , Joakim Haeggman ( Swe ) 71 77
70 , Jose Coceres ( Argentina ) 69 78 71 , Paul Eales 75 71 72 ,
Klas Eriksson ( Sweden ) 71 75 72 , Mike Clayton ( Australia )
69 76 73 , Mark Roe 69 71 78
219 Eamonn Darcy ( Ireland ) 74 76 69 , Bob May ( U.S. ) 74 75 70 ,
Paul Lawrie 72 75 72 , Miguel Angel Jimenez ( Spain ) 74 72
73 , Peter Mitchell 74 71 75 , Philip Walton ( Ireland ) 71 74
74 , Peter O'Malley ( Australia ) 71 73 75
220 Barry Lane 73 77 70 , Wayne Riley ( Australia ) 71 78 71 ,
Martin Gates 71 77 72 , Bradley Hughes ( Australia ) 73 75 72 ,
Peter Hedblom ( Sweden ) 70 75 75 , Retief Goosen ( South
Africa ) 71 74 75 , David Gilford 69 74 77 .
SOCCER - ENGLISH SOCCER RESULTS .
LONDON 1996-08-30
Results of English league matches
on Friday :
Division two
Plymouth 2 Preston 1
Division three
Swansea 1 Lincoln 2