CRICKET - LEICESTERSHIRE TAKE OVER AT TOP AFTER INNINGS VICTORY .
LONDON 1996-08-30
West Indian all-rounder Phil Simmons took four for 38 on Friday as Leicestershire beat Somerset by an innings and 39 runs in two days to take over at the head of the county championship .
Their stay on top , though , may be short-lived as title rivals Essex , Derbyshire and Surrey all closed in on victory while Kent made up for lost time in their rain-affected match against Nottinghamshire .
After bowling Somerset out for 83 on the opening morning at Grace Road , Leicestershire extended their first innings by 94 runs before being bowled out for 296 with England discard Andy Caddick taking three for 83 .
Trailing by 213 , Somerset got a solid start to their second innings before Simmons stepped in to bundle them out for 174 .
Essex , however , look certain to regain their top spot after Nasser Hussain and Peter Such gave them a firm grip on their match against Yorkshire at Headingley .
Hussain , considered surplus to England 's one-day requirements , struck 158 , his first championship century of the season , as Essex reached 372 and took a first innings lead of 82 .
By the close Yorkshire had turned that into a 37-run advantage but off-spinner Such had scuttled their hopes , taking four for 24 in 48 balls and leaving them hanging on 119 for five and praying for rain .
At the Oval , Surrey captain Chris Lewis , another man dumped by England , continued to silence his critics as he followed his four for 45 on Thursday with 80 not out on Friday in the match against Warwickshire .
He was well backed by England hopeful Mark Butcher who made 70 as Surrey closed on 429 for seven , a lead of 234 .
Derbyshire kept up the hunt for their first championship title since 1936 by reducing Worcestershire to 133 for five in their second innings , still 100 runs away from avoiding an innings defeat .
Australian Tom Moody took six for 82 but Chris Adams , 123 , and Tim O'Gorman , 109 , took Derbyshire to 471 and a first innings lead of 233 .
After the frustration of seeing the opening day of their match badly affected by the weather , Kent stepped up a gear to dismiss Nottinghamshire for 214 .
They were held up by a gritty 84 from Paul Johnson but ex-England fast bowler Martin McCague took four for 55 .
By stumps Kent had reached 108 for three .
CRICKET - ENGLISH COUNTY CHAMPIONSHIP SCORES .
LONDON 1996-08-30
Result and close of play scores in English county championship matches on Friday :
Leicester : Leicestershire beat Somerset by an innings and 39 runs .
Somerset 83 and 174 ( P. Simmons 4-38 ) , Leicestershire 296 .
Leicestershire 22 points , Somerset 4 .
Chester-le-Street : Glamorgan 259 and 207 ( A. Dale 69 , H. Morris 69 ; D. Blenkiron 4-43 ) , Durham 114 ( S. Watkin 4-28 ) and 81-3 .
Tunbridge Wells : Nottinghamshire 214 ( P. Johnson 84 ; M. McCague 4-55 ) , Kent 108-3 .
London ( The Oval ) : Warwickshire 195 , Surrey 429-7 ( C. Lewis 80 not out , M. Butcher 70 , G. Kersey 63 , J. Ratcliffe 63 , D. Bicknell 55 ) .
Hove : Sussex 363 ( W. Athey 111 , V. Drakes 52 ; I. Austin 4-37 ) , Lancashire 197-8 ( W. Hegg 54 )
Portsmouth : Middlesex 199 and 426 ( J. Pooley 111 , M. Ramprakash 108 , M. Gatting 83 ) , Hampshire 232 and 109-5 .
Chesterfield : Worcestershire 238 and 133-5 , Derbyshire 471 ( J. Adams 123 , T.O'Gorman 109 not out , K. Barnett 87 ; T. Moody 6-82 )
Bristol : Gloucestershire 183 and 185-6 ( J. Russell 56 not out ) , Northamptonshire 190 ( K. Curran 52 ; A. Smith 5-68 ) .
CRICKET - 1997 ASHES INTINERARY .
LONDON 1996-08-30
Australia will defend the Ashes in
a six-test series against England during a four-month tour
starting on May 13 next year , the Test and County Cricket Board
said on Friday .
Australia will also play three one-day internationals and
four one-day warm-up matches at the start of the tour .
The tourists will play nine first-class matches against
English county sides and another against British Universities ,
as well as one-day matches against the Minor Counties and
Scotland .
Tour itinerary :
May
May 13 Arrive in London
May 14 Practice at Lord 's
May 15 v Duke of Norfolk 's XI ( at Arundel )
May 17 v Northampton
May 18 v Worcestershire
May 20 v Durham
May 22 First one-day international ( at Headingley ,
Leeds )
May 24 Second one-day international ( at The Oval ,
London )
May 25 Third one-day international ( at Lord 's , London )
May 27-29 v Gloucestershire or Sussex or Surrey ( three
days )
May 31 - June 2 v Derbyshire ( three days )
June
June 5-9 First test match ( at Edgbaston , Birmingham )
June 11-13 v a first class county ( to be confirmed )
June 14-16 v Leicestershire ( three days )
June 19-23 Second test ( at Lord 's )
June 25-27 v British Universities ( at Oxford , three days )
June 28-30 v Hampshire ( three days )
July
July 3-7 Third test ( at Old Trafford , Manchester )
July 9 v Minor Counties XI
July 12 v Scotland
July 16-18 v Glamorgan ( three days )
July 19-21 v Middlesex ( three days )
July 24-28 Fourth test ( at Headingley )
August
August 1-4 v Somerset ( four days )
August 7-11 Fifth test ( at Trent Bridge , Nottingham )
August 16-18 v Kent ( three days )
August 21-25 Sixth test ( at The Oval , London ) .
SOCCER - SHEARER NAMED AS ENGLAND CAPTAIN .
LONDON 1996-08-30
The world 's costliest footballer Alan Shearer was named as the new England captain on Friday .
The 26-year-old , who joined Newcastle for 15 million pounds sterling ( $ 23.4 million ) , takes over from Tony Adams , who led the side during the European championship in June , and former captain David Platt .
Adams and Platt are both injured and will miss England 's opening World Cup qualifier against Moldova on Sunday .
Shearer takes the captaincy on a trial basis , but new coach Glenn Hoddle said he saw no reason why the former Blackburn and Southampton skipper should not make the post his own .
" I 'm sure there wo n't be a problem , I 'm sure Alan is the man for the job , " Hoddle said .
" There were three or four people who could have done it but when I spoke to Alan he was up for it and really wanted it .
" In four days it 's very difficult to come to a 100 percent conclusion about something like this ...
but he knows how to conduct himself , his team mates respect him and he knows about the team situation even though he plays up front . "
Shearer 's Euro 96 striking partner Teddy Sheringham withdrew from the squad with an injury on Friday .
He will probably be replaced by Shearer 's Newcastle team mate Les Ferdinand .
BASKETBALL - INTERNATIONAL TOURNAMENT RESULT .
BELGRADE 1996-08-30
Result in an international
basketball tournament on Friday :
Red Star ( Yugoslavia ) beat Dinamo ( Russia ) 92-90 ( halftime
47-47 )
SOCCER - ROMANIA BEAT LITHUANIA IN UNDER-21 MATCH .
BUCHAREST 1996-08-30
Romania beat Lithuania 2-1 ( halftime 1-1 ) in their European under-21 soccer match on Friday .
Scorers :
Romania - Cosmin Contra ( 31st ) , Mihai Tararache ( 75th )
Lithuania - Danius Gleveckas ( 13rd )
Attendance : 200
SOCCER - ROTOR FANS LOCKED OUT AFTER VOLGOGRAD VIOLENCE .
MOSCOW 1996-08-30
Rotor Volgograd must play their next home game behind closed doors after fans hurled bottles and stones at Dynamo Moscow players during a 1-0 home defeat on Saturday that ended Rotor 's brief spell as league leaders .
The head of the Russian league 's disciplinary committee , Anatoly Gorokhovsky , said on Friday that Rotor would play Lada Togliatti to empty stands on September 3 .
The club , who put Manchester United out of last year 's UEFA Cup , were fined $ 1,000 .
Despite the defeat , Rotor are well placed with 11 games to play in the championship .
Lying three points behind Alania and two behind Dynamo Moscow , the Volgograd side have a game in hand over the leaders and two over the Moscow club .
BOXING - PANAMA 'S ROBERTO DURAN FIGHTS THE SANDS OF TIME .
PANAMA CITY 1996-08-30
Panamanian boxing legend Roberto " Hands of Stone " Duran climbs into the ring on Saturday in another age-defying attempt to sustain his long career .
Duran , 45 , takes on little-known Mexican Ariel Cruz , 30 , in a super middleweight non-title bout in Panama City .
The fight , Duran 's first on home soil for 10 years , is being billed here as the " Return of the Legend " and Duran still talks as if he was in his prime .
" I want a fifth title .
This match is to prepare me .
I feel good .
I 'm not retiring , " Duran told Reuters .
But those close to the boxer acknowledge that the man who has won championships in four different weight classes -- lightweight , welterweight , junior middleweight and middleweight -- is drawing close to the end of his career .
" Each time he fights , he 's on the last frontier of his career .
If he loses Saturday , it could devalue his position as one of the world 's great boxers , " Panamanian Boxing Association President Ramon Manzanares said .
Duran , whose 97-12 record spans three decades , hopes a win in the 10-round bout will earn him a rematch against Puerto Rico 's Hector " Macho " Camacho .
Camacho took a controversial points decision against the Panamanian in Atlantic City in June in a title fight .
SQUASH - HONG KONG OPEN QUARTER-FINAL RESULTS .
HONG KONG 1996-08-30
Quarter-final results in the Hong Kong Open on Friday ( prefix number denotes seeding ) : 1 - Jansher Khan ( Pakistan ) beat Mark Cairns ( England ) 15-10 15-6 15-7
Anthony Hill ( Australia ) beat Dan Jenson ( Australia ) 15-9 15-8 15-17 17-15
4 - Peter Nicol ( Scotland ) beat 7 - Chris Walker ( England ) 15-8 15-13 13-15 15-9
2 - Rodney Eyles ( Australia ) beat Derek Ryan ( Ireland ) 15-6 15-9 11-15 15-10 .
SOCCER - RESULTS OF SOUTH KOREAN PRO-SOCCER GAMES .
SEOUL 1996-08-30
Results of South Korean pro-soccer
games played on Thursday .
Pohang 3 Ulsan 2 ( halftime 1-0 )
Puchon 2 Chonbuk 1 ( halftime 1-1 )
Standings after games played on Thursday ( tabulate under -
won , drawn , lost , goals for , goals against , points ) :
W D L G / F G / A P
Puchon 3 1 0 6 1 10
Chonan 3 0 1 13 10 9
Pohang 2 1 1 11 10 7
Suwan 1 3 0 7 3 6
Ulsan 1 0 2 8 9 3
Anyang 0 3 1 6 9 3
Chonnam 0 2 1 4 5 2
Pusan 0 2 1 3 7 2
Chonbuk 0 0 3 3 7 0
BASEBALL - RESULTS OF S. KOREAN PROFESSIONAL GAMES .
SEOUL 1996-08-30
Results of South Korean
professional baseball games played on Thursday .
LG 2 OB 0
Lotte 6 Hyundai 2
Hyundai 6 Lotte 5
Haitai 2 Samsung 0
Samsung 10 Haitai 3
Hanwha 6 Ssangbangwool 5
Note - Lotte and Hyundai , Haitai and Samsung played two games .
Standings after games played on Thursday ( tabulate under
won , drawn , lost , winning percentage , games behind first place )
W D L PCT GB
Haitai 64 2 43 .596 -
Ssangbangwool 59 2 49 .545 5 1/2
Hanwha 58 1 49 .542 6
Hyundai 57 5 49 .536 6 1/2
Samsung 49 5 56 .468 14
Lotte 46 6 54 .462 14 1/2
LG 46 5 59 .441 17
OB 42 6 62 .409 20 1/2
TENNIS - FRIDAY 'S RESULTS FROM THE U.S. OPEN .
NEW YORK 1996-08-30
Results from the U.S. Open Tennis Championships at the National Tennis Centre on Friday ( prefix number denotes seeding ) :
Women 's singles , third round
Sandrine Testud ( France ) beat Ines Gorrochategui ( Argentina ) 4-6 6-2 6-1
Men 's singles , second round
4 - Goran Ivanisevic ( Croatia ) beat Scott Draper ( Australia ) 6-7 ( 1-7 ) 6-3 6-4 6-4
Tim Henman ( Britain ) beat Doug Flach ( U.S. ) 6-3 6-4 6-2
Mark Philippoussis ( Australia ) beat Andrei Olhovskiy ( Russia ) 6 - 3 6-4 6-2
Sjeng Schalken ( Netherlands ) beat David Rikl ( Czech Republic ) 6 - 2 6-4 6-4
Guy Forget ( France ) beat 17 - Felix Mantilla ( Spain ) 6-4 7-5 6-3
Men 's singles , second round
Alexander Volkov ( Russia ) beat Mikael Tillstrom ( Sweden ) 1-6 6- 4 6-1 4-6 7-6 ( 10-8 )
Jonas Bjorkman ( Sweden ) beat David Nainkin ( South Africa ) ) 6-4 6-1 6-1
Women 's singles , third round
8 - Lindsay Davenport ( U.S. ) beat Anne-Gaelle Sidot ( France ) 6-0 6-3
4 - Conchita Martinez ( Spain ) beat Helena Sukova ( Czech Republic ) 6-4 6-3
Amanda Coetzer ( South Africa ) beat Irina Spirlea ( Romania ) 7-6 ( 7-5 ) 7-5
Add Men 's singles , second round 16 - Cedric Pioline ( France ) beat Roberto Carretero ( Spain ) 4-6 6 - 2 6-2 6-1 Alex Corretja ( Spain ) beat Filippo Veglio ( Switzerland ) 6-7 ( 4- 7 ) 6-4 6-4 6-0
Add Women 's singles , third round Linda Wild ( U.S. ) beat Barbara Rittner ( Germany ) 6-4 4-6 7-5 Asa Carlsson ( Sweden ) beat 15 - Gabriela Sabatini ( Argentina ) 7-5 3-6 6-2
Add Men 's singles , second round 1 - Pete Sampras ( U.S. ) beat Jiri Novak ( Czech Republic ) 6-3 1-6 6-3 4-6 6-4 Paul Haarhuis ( Netherlands ) beat Michael Tebbutt ( Australia ) 1- 6 6-2 6-2 6-3
Add Women 's singles , third round Lisa Raymond ( U.S. ) beat Kimberly Po ( U.S. ) 6-3 6-2
:
Add men 's singles , second round
Hendrik Dreekmann ( Germany ) beat Thomas Johansson ( Sweden )
7-6 ( 7-1 ) 6-2 4-6 6-1
Andrei Medvedev ( Ukraine ) beat Jan Kroslak ( Slovakia ) 6-4 6-3
6-2
Petr Korda ( Czech Republic ) bat Bohdan Ulihrach ( Czech
Republic ) 6-0 7-6 ( 7-5 ) 6-2
Add women 's singles , third round
2 - Monica Seles ( U.S. ) beat Dally Randriantefy ( Madagascar )
6-0 6-2
:
Add men 's singles , second round 12 - Todd Martin ( U.S. ) beat Andrea Gaudenzi ( Italy ) 6-3 6-2 6-2 Stefan Edberg ( Sweden ) beat Bernd Karbacher ( Germany ) 3-6 6-3 6-3 1-0 retired ( leg injury )
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE STANDINGS AFTER THURSDAY 'S GAMES .
NEW YORK 1996-08-30
Major League Baseball
standings after games played on Thursday ( tabulate under won ,
lost , winning percentage and games behind ) :
AMERICAN LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
NEW YORK 74 59 .556 -
BALTIMORE 70 63 .526 4
BOSTON 69 65 .515 5 1/2
TORONTO 63 71 .470 11 1/2
DETROIT 48 86 .358 26 1/2
CENTRAL DIVISION
CLEVELAND 80 53 .602 -
CHICAGO 71 64 .526 10
MINNESOTA 67 67 .500 13 1/2
MILWAUKEE 64 71 .474 17
KANSAS CITY 61 74 .452 20
WESTERN DIVISION
TEXAS 75 58 .564 -
SEATTLE 70 63 .526 5
OAKLAND 64 72 .471 12 1/2
CALIFORNIA 62 72 .463 13 1/2
FRIDAY , AUGUST 30 SCHEDULE
KANSAS CITY AT DETROIT
CHICAGO AT TORONTO
MINNESOTA AT MILWAUKEE
CLEVELAND AT TEXAS
NEW YORK AT CALIFORNIA
BOSTON AT OAKLAND
BALTIMORE AT SEATTLE
NATIONAL LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
ATLANTA 83 49 .629 -
MONTREAL 71 61 .538 12
FLORIDA 64 70 .478 20
NEW YORK 59 75 .440 25
PHILADELPHIA 54 80 .403 30
CENTRAL DIVISION
HOUSTON 72 63 .533 -
ST LOUIS 69 65 .515 2 1/2
CINCINNATI 66 67 .496 5
CHICAGO 65 66 .496 5
PITTSBURGH 56 77 .421 15
WESTERN DIVISION
SAN DIEGO 75 60 .556 -
LOS ANGELES 72 61 .541 2
COLORADO 70 65 .519 5
SAN FRANCISCO 57 74 .435 16
FRIDAY , AUGUST 30 SCHEDULE
ATLANTA AT CHICAGO
FLORIDA AT CINCINNATI
SAN DIEGO AT MONTREAL
LOS ANGELES AT PHILADELPHIA
HOUSTON AT PITTSBURGH
SAN FRANCISCO AT NEW YORK
COLORADO AT ST LOUIS
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE RESULTS THURSDAY .
NEW YORK 1996-08-30
Results of Major League
Baseball games played on Thursday ( home team in CAPS ) :
American League
DETROIT 4 Kansas City 1
Minnesota 6 MILWAUKEE 1
CALIFORNIA 14 New York 3
SEATTLE 9 Baltimore 6
National League
San Diego 3 NEW YORK 2
Chicago 4 HOUSTON 3
Cincinnati 18 COLORADO 7
Atlanta 5 PITTSBURGH 1
Los Angeles 2 MONTREAL 1
Florida 10 ST LOUIS 9
TENNIS - TARANGO , O'BRIEN SPRING TWIN UPSETS UNDER THE LIGHTS .
Larry Fine
NEW YORK 1996-08-30
Andre Agassi escaped disaster on Thursday but Wimbledon finalist MaliVai Washington and Marcelo Rios were not so fortunate on a night of upsets at the U.S. Open .
The 11th-seeded Washington fell short of reprising his Wimbledon miracle comeback as he lost to red-hot wildcard Alex O'Brien 6-3 6-4 5-7 3-6 6-3 in a two hour 51 minute struggle on the Stadium court .
Next door on the grandstand , 10th seed Rios lost to another player with a Wimbledon connection -- bad boy Jeff Tarango .
The temperamental left-hander defeated the Chilean 6-4 4-6 7-6 6-2 .
The day programme went smoothly although sixth-seeded former champion Agassi had to wriggle out of a dangerous 3-6 0-4 hole , winning 18 of the last 19 games against India 's Leander Paes .
But the night belonged to the upstarts .
Washington , who climbed back from a 1-5 deficit , two sets down in the third set against Todd Martin in the Wimbledon semifinals , looked poised for another sensational comeback .
O'Brien , a winner two weeks ago in New Haven for his first pro title , served for the match at 5-4 in the third set before Washington came charging back .
" I just kept saying to myself , ' keep giving yourself the best chance to win , keep battling , maybe something will happen , ' " said the 26-year-old O'Brien , ranked 65th .
" I kept my composure and I was proud of myself for that -- usually I would have folded up the tent and gone home . "
The hard-serving O'Brien , a former U.S. collegiate national champion , fired up 17 aces to ultimately subdue the never-say-die Washington .
The fifth set stayed on serve until the sixth game , when Washington , after saving one break point with a forehand winner down the line , netted a backhand to give O'Brien a 4-2 lead .
The Texan blasted in two aces to hold serve at 5-2 and then converted his eighth match point for victory when Washington found the net with another backhand from 40-0 .
" You just kind of keep fighting and you keep trying to make him play a little bit .
I think he got a little tight at a couple of moments , " said Washington . "
But I think he served pretty well when he had to . "
Tarango , whose Wimbledon tantrum two years ago brought him a $ 28,000 fine and suspension from this year 's tournament at the All-England Club , argued calls and taunted fans in his lively two hour , 24 minute tango with Rios on the grandstand .
A boisterous cheering section backed the distracted Chilean and booed the lanky American , who ate up all the attention .
" I 'm an emotional player , " said the 104th-ranked Tarango . "
I think I played very well tonight , very focused . "
The match turned on the third-set tiebreaker , which the American won 7-5 much to the dismay of the spectators .
" I love the crowd if they boo me every day .
It fires me up , makes me play my best tennis , " Tarango said .
" I played some of my best tennis in college when fraternities were throwing beer on me .
If tennis was like that every day , I think everybody wold be having a lot more fun . "
Rios did not appreciate Tarango 's antics .
" He 's always complaining too much , " said Rios . "
But I think it 's not that .
I think I played really bad .
It was tough to play at night .
Balls were going really fast .
I lost too many points that I never lose .
I did n't play my tennis . "
" I do n't see the ball like I see during the day .
I play an American so that 's why I play at night .
I did n't feel good on the court . "
At the end of the match , Tarango blew sarcastic kisses to the crowd , then jiggled his body to a Rios rooting section in a jeering salute .
" I support their enthusiasm , " Tarango said about the fans . "
At the same time , they 're cheering blatantly against me .
After I won I figured I could give them a little razzle-dazzle . "
NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-RANDALL CUNNINGHAM RETIRES .
PHILADELPHIA 1996-08-29
Randall Cunningham , the National Football League 's all-time leading rusher as a quarterback and one of the most athletic players ever to line up over centre , retired Thursday .
Cunningham played his entire 11-year career with the Philadelphia Eagles .
A three-time Pro Bowl selection , Cunningham rushed for 4,482 yards on 677 carries .
" I would like to thank the Eagles organisation and the wonderful fans of Philadelphia for supporting me throughout my career , " Cunningham said .
" Although it saddens me to leave , I am looking forward to spending more time with my family and pursuing other interests that have been on the back burner for sometime . "
" Randall was one of the most exciting quarterbacks in NFL history , " said Eagles owner Jeffrey Lurie . "
During his 11 years in Philadelphia , Randall was the cornerstone of the Eagles ' franchise and brought many great moments to fans in Philadelphia as well as across the NFL . "
A second-round choice in 1985 , Cunningham completed 1,874-of-3,362 passes ( 55.7 percent ) for 22,877 yards and 150 touchdowns .
Cunningham has already been signed as a broadcaster .
GOLF - LEADING SCORES AT GREATER MILWAUKEE OPEN .
MILWAUKEE , Wisconsin 1996-08-29
Leading scores in
the $ 1.2 million Greater Milwaukee Open at the par-71 ,
6,739-yard Brown Deer Park Golf Course after the first round
on Thursday ( players U.S. unless stated ) :
62 Nolan Henke
64 Bob Estes
65 Billy Andrade , Duffy Waldorf , Jesper Parnevik ( Sweden )
66 Neal Lancaster , Dave Barr ( Canada ) , Mike Sullivan , Willie
Wood , Loren Roberts , Steve Stricker , Brian Claar , Russ Cochran
67 Mark Calcavecchia , Payne Stewart , Billy Mayfair , Ken
Green , Jerry Kelly , Tim Simpson , Olin Browne , Shane Bortsch ,
Mike Hulbert , Brian Henninger , Tiger Woods , Steve Jurgenson ,
Bryan Gorman
GOLF - HENKE TAKES LEAD IN MILWAUKEE , WOODS MAKES PRO DEBUT .
MILWAUKEE , Wisconsin 1996-08-29
Nolan Henke fired a nine-under-par 62 to grab a two-shot lead after the opening round of the $ 1.2 million Greater Milwaukee Open Thursday as 20-year-old Tiger Woods shot 67 in his professional debut .
Henke stood two strokes ahead of Bob Estes and three up on Billy Andrade , Duffy Waldorf and Jesper Parnevik .
Woods , who turned pro Tuesday after winning an unprecedented third successive U.S. Amateur Championship , almost eagled the 18th hole .
He settled for a birdie and a four-under opening round that left him five shots off the pace .
" Yesterday was the toughest day I 've had for a long time , " Woods said . "
Today , I got to play golf . "
He added : " I thought I got off off to a great start .
It was a perfect start .
I 'm in a good position . "
Henke , who called his round a " pleasant surprise , " finished with six birdies on the final eight holes .
" We finally got things going in the right direction , " he said . "
It was my best round in a very long time .
My short game has improved since I 've had to use it so often .
That 's always been the worst part of my game .
All in all , playing bad 's been a good experience . "
Henke , who came within one shot of the course record set by Andrew Magee during Wednesday 's pro-am , has three career PGA Tour victories , but none since the 1993 BellSouth Classic .
Estes , whose only win came at the 1994 Texas Open and whose best finish this year was a third-place tie at the Nortel Open in January , eagled the par-five fourth hole and added five birdies to grab sole possession of second place .
" No bogeys on the card , " he noted . "
Sometimes I take more pride in that . "
Woods was among a group of 13 players at four under , including 1993 champion Billy Mayfair , who tied for second at last week 's World Series of Golf , and former U.S. Open champ Payne Stewart .
Defending champion Scott Hoch shot a three-under 68 and was six strokes back .
Phil Mickelson , the only four-time winner on the PGA Tour , skipped the tournament after winning the World Series of Golf last week .
Mark Brooks , Tom Lehman and Mark O'Meara , who make up the rest of the top four on the money list , also took the week off .
SOCCER - SILVA 'S `LOST PASSPORT ' EXCUSE NOT ENOUGH FOR FIFA .
MADRID 1996-08-30
Spanish first division team Deportivo Coruna will be without key midfielder Mauro Silva for Saturday 's game with Real Madrid after FIFA , soccer 's world governing body , suspended the Brazilian for one game for missing his national side 's European tour .
Silva excused his absence from Brazil 's game against Russia , on Wednesday , and Saturday 's match with the Netherlands by saying he had lost his passport .
But that did not prevent him from collecting the one-match suspension .
ATHLETICS - MITCHELL DEFEATS BAILEY IN FRONT OF FORMER CHAMPIONS .
Adrian Warner
BERLIN 1996-08-30
American Dennis Mitchell outclassed Olympic 100 metres champion Donovan Bailey for the third time at a major post-Games meeting in front of the most experienced sprinting crowd in the world on Friday .
Watched by an array of former Olympic sprint champions at the Berlin grand prix meeting , Mitchell made a brilliant start in the 100 metres and held off Bailey 's strong finish to win in 10.08 seconds despite cool conditions .
Bailey , who set a world record of 9.84 on his way to victory in Atlanta , could not catch his American rival and had to settle for third in a tight finish .
Jamaica 's Michael Green was second with 10.09 with Bailey finishing in 10.13 .
Last Friday Mitchell , who finished fourth at the Atlanta Games , upstaged a trio of Olympic champions including Bailey to win the 100 in Brussels .
Earlier this month he also beat world champion Bailey in Zurich .
Berlin , Brussels and Zurich all belong to the most lucrative series in the sport , the Golden Four .
Among the crowd on Friday were Olympic 100 metres champions going back to 1948 .
They had been invited to the meeting to watch a special relay to mark the 60th anniversary of Jesse Owens 's four gold medals at the 1936 Olympics in the same Berlin stadium .
" Today the concentration was the most important thing for me , " Mitchell said .
Despite the coolish conditions American Olympic champion Gail Devers looked in commanding form in the women 's 100 , clocking 10.89 to defeat Jamaican rival Merlene Ottey , who was second in 10.94 .
ATHLETICS - BERLIN GRAND PRIX RESULTS .
BERLIN 1996-08-30
Leading results at the Berlin
Grand Prix athletics meeting on Friday :
Women 's 100 metres hurdles
1. Michelle Freeman ( Jamaica ) 12.71 seconds
2. Ludmila Engquist ( Sweden ) 12.74
3. Aliuska Lopez ( Cuba ) 12.92
4. Brigita Bokovec ( Slovenia ) 12.92
5. Dionne Rose ( Jamaica ) 12.92
6. Julie Baumann ( Switzerland ) 13.11
7. Gillian Russell ( Jamaica ) 13.17
Women 's 1,500 metres
1. Svetlana Masterkova ( Russia ) four minutes 6.87 seconds
2. Patricia Djate-Taillard ( France ) 4:08.22
3. Carla Sacramento ( Portugal ) 4:08.96
4. Yekaterina Podkopayeva ( Russia ) 4:09.25
5. Leah Pells ( Canada ) 4:09.95
6. Carmen Wuestenhagen ( Germany ) 4:10.38
7. Margarita Maruseva ( Russia ) 4:10.87
8. Sara Thorsett ( U.S. ) 4:11.06
Men 's 110 metres hurdles
1. Mark Crear ( U.S. ) 13.26 seconds
2. Tony Jarrett ( Britain ) 13.35
3. Florian Schwarthoff ( Germany ) 13.36
4. Emilio Valle ( Cuba ) 13.52
5. Falk Balzer ( Germany ) 13.52
6. Steve Brown ( U.S. ) 13.53
7. Frank Busemann ( Germany ) 13.58
8. Jack Pierce ( U.S. ) 13.60
Men 's 200 metres
1. Frankie Fredericks ( Namibia ) 19.97 seconds
2. Michael Johnson ( U.S. ) 20.02
3. Ato Boldon ( Trinidad ) 20.37
4. Geir Moen ( Norway ) 20.41
5. Patrick Stevens ( Belgium ) 20.54
6. Jon Drummond ( U.S. ) 20.78
7. Claus Hirsbro ( Denmark ) 20.90
8. Ivan Garcia ( Cuba ) 20.96
Women 's shot put
1. Astrid Kumbernuss ( Germany ) 19.89 metres
2. Claudia Mues ( Germany ) 18.80
3. Irina Korzhanenko ( Russia ) 18.63
4. Valentina Fedyushina ( Russia ) 18.55
5. Stephanie Storp ( Germany ) 18.41
Men 's mile
1. Noureddine Morceli ( Algeria ) 3 minutes 49.09 seconds
2. Venuste Niyongabo ( Burundi ) 3:51.01
3. William Tanui ( Kenya ) 3:51.40
4. Laban Rotich ( Kenya ) 3:53.42
5. Marko Koers ( Netherlands ) 3:53.47
6. Isaac Viciosa ( Spain ) 3:53.85
7. John Mayock ( Britain ) 3:54.67
8. Marcus O'Sullivan ( Ireland ) 3:54.87
Men 's discus
1. Lars Riedel ( Germany ) 70.60 metres
2. Anthony Washington ( U.S. ) 68.44
3. Vasily Kaptyukh ( Belarus ) 66.24
4. Vladimir Dubrovshchik ( Belarus ) 65.30
5. Virgilijus Alekna ( Lithuania ) 65.00
6. Juergen Schult ( Germany ) 64.46
7. Andreas Seelig ( Germany ) 62.00
8. Michael Moellenbeck ( Germany ) 58.56
Women 's 100 metres
1. Gail Devers ( U.S. ) 10.89 seconds
2. Merlene Ottey ( Jamaica ) 10.94
3. Gwen Torrence ( U.S. ) 11.07
4. Mary Onyali ( Nigeria ) 11.14
5. Chryste Gaines ( U.S. ) 11.20
6. Chandra Sturrup ( Bahamas ) 11.26
7. Irina Privalova ( Russia ) 11.27
8. Inger Miller ( U.S. ) 11.37
Women 's 5,000 metres
1. Gabriela Szabo ( Romania ) 15 minutes 04.95 seconds
2. Gete Wami ( Ethiopia ) 15:05.21
3. Rose Cheruiyot ( Kenya ) 15:05.41
4. Annemari Sandell ( Finland ) 15:06.33
5. Tegla Loroupe ( Kenya ) 15:08.79
6. Gunhild Halle ( Norway ) 15:09.00
7. Pauline Konga ( Kenya ) 15:09.74
8. Sally Barsosio ( Kenya ) 15:14.34
Men 's 400 metres hurdles
1. Torrance Zellner ( U.S. ) 48.23 seconds
2. Samuel Matete ( Zambia ) 48.34
3. Derrick Adkins ( U.S. ) 48.62
4. Fabrizio Mori ( Italy ) 49.21
5. Sven Nylander ( Sweden ) 49.22
6. Eric Thomas ( U.S. ) 49.35
7. Rohan Robinson ( Australia ) 49.36
8. Dusan Kovacs ( Hungary ) 49.58
Women 's 400 metres
1. Falilat Ogunkoya ( Nigeria ) 50.31 seconds
2. Jearl Miles ( U.S. ) 50.42
3. Fatima Yusuf ( Nigeria ) 51.43
4. Anja Ruecker ( Germany ) 51.61
5. Olabisi Afolabi ( Nigeria ) 51.98
6. Phylis Smith ( Britain ) 52.05
7. Linda Kisabaka ( Germany ) 52.41
8. Karin Janke ( Germany ) 53.13
Men 's 100 metres
1. Dennis Mitchell ( U.S. ) 10.08
2. Michael Green ( Jamaica ) 10.09
3. Donovan Bailey ( Canada ) 10.13
4. Jon Drummond ( U.S. ) 10.22
5. Davidson Ezinwa ( Nigeria ) 10.24
6. Geir Moen ( Norway ) 10.33
7. Marc Blume ( Germany ) 10.48
Men 's 800 metres
1. Wilson Kipketer ( Denmark ) 1:43.34
2. Norberto Tellez ( Cuba ) 1:44.58
3. Sammy Langat ( Kenya ) 1:44.96
4. Nico Motchebon ( Germany ) 1:45.03
5. David Kiptoo ( Kenya ) 1:45.27
6. Adem Hacini ( Algeria ) 1:45.64
7. Vebjoen Rodal ( Norway ) 1:46.45
8. Craig Winrow ( Britain ) 1:46.66
Men 's pole vault
1= Andrei Tiwontschik ( Germany ) 5.86
1= Igor Trandenkov ( Russia ) 5.86
3. Maksim Tarasov ( Russia ) 5.86
4. Tim Lobinger ( Germany ) 5.80
5. Igor Potapovich ( Kazakstan ) 5.80
6. Jean Galfione ( France ) 5.65
7. Pyotr Bochkary ( Russia ) 5.65
8. Dmitri Markov ( Belarus ) 5.65
Women 's high jump
1. Stefka Kostadinova ( Bulgaria ) 2.03
2. Inga Babakova ( Ukraine ) 2.00 metres
3. Alina Astafei ( Germany ) 1.97
4. Tatyana Motkova ( Russia ) 1.97
5. Hanne Haugland ( Norway ) 1.91
6= Nele Zilinskiene ( Lithuania ) 1.91
6= Yelena Gulyayeva ( Russia ) 1.91
8. Natalya Golodnova ( Russia ) 1.85
Men 's 5,000 metres
1. Daniel Komen ( Kenya ) 13 minutes 2.62 seconds
2. Bob Kennedy ( U.S. ) 13:06.12
3. Paul Koech ( Kenya ) 13:06.45
4. El Hassane Lahssini ( Morocco ) 13:06.57
5. Shem Kororia ( Kenya ) 13:06.65
6. Brahim Lahlafi ( Morocco ) 13:08.05
7. Tom Nyariki ( Kenya ) 13:20.12
8. Fita Bayissa ( Ethiopia ) 13:21.35
Men 's triple jump
1. Jonathan Edwards ( Britain ) 17.69 metres
2. Yoelvis Quesada ( Cuba ) 17.44
3. Kenny Harrison ( U.S. ) 17.16
4. Mike Conley ( U.S. ) 16.79
5. Armen Martirosyan ( Armenia ) 16.57
6. Sigurd Njerve ( Norway ) 16.41
7. Carlos Calado ( Portugal ) 16.31
8. Charles-Michael Friedek ( Germany ) 16.12
Women 's javelin
1. Tanja Damaske ( Germany ) 66.60 metres
2. Trine Hattesta ( Norway ) 65.12
3. Isel Lopez ( Cuba ) 65.10
4. Heli Rantanen ( Finland ) 62.78
5. Louise McPaul ( Australia ) 62.06
6. Xiomara Rivero ( Cuba ) 61.94
7. Natalya Shikolen ( Belarus ) 60.74
8. Rita Ramaunaskaite ( Lithuania ) 60.74
Men 's 4x100 relay Jesse Owens memorial race
1. Donovan Bailey ( Canada ) , Michael Johnson ( U.S. ) , Frankie
Fredericks ( Namibia ) , Linford Christie ( Britain ) 38.87 seconds
2. Michael Green ( Jamaica ) , Osmond Ezinwa ( Nigeria ) , Oeji Aliu
( Nigeria ) , Davidson Ezinwa ( Nigeria ) 38.87
3. Peter Karlsson ( Sweden ) , Falk Balzer ( Germany ) , George
Panayiotopoulos ( Greece ) , Florian Schwarthoff ( Germany ) 39.93
SOCCER - THREE STANDARD LIEGE PLAYERS BANNED , CLUB FINED .
GENEVA 1996-08-30
UEFA came down heavily on Belgian club Standard Liege on Friday for " disgraceful behaviour " in an Intertoto final match against Karlsruhe of Germany .
The Belgian club were fined 25,000 Swiss francs ( $ 20,850 ) for unsporting conduct and captain Guy Hellers banned for seven games .
He was sent off for insulting the referee and then urged his team mates to protest .
Roberto Bisconti will be sidelined for six Euro ties after pushing the referee in the back as he protested about a Karlsruhe goal , while Didier Ernst was banned for four matches for a verbal attack soon after Bisconti was also dismissed .
Karlsruhe won the August 20 match 3-1 thanks to two late goals .
They took the tie 3-2 on aggregate and qualified for the UEFA Cup .
ATHLETICS - HARRISON , EDWARDS TO MEET IN SARAJEVO .
MONTE CARLO 1996-08-30
Olympic champion Kenny Harrison and world record holder Jonathan Edwards will both take part in a triple jump competition at the Solidarity Meeting for Sarajevo on September 9 .
The International Amateur Athletic Federation said on Friday that a schedule reshuffle had allowed organisers to hold a men 's triple jump as well as the women 's long jump on the " one usable runway at the war-devastated " Kosevo stadium .
Atlanta Games silver medal winner Edwards has called on other leading athletes to take part in the Sarajevo meeting -- a goodwill gesture towards Bosnia as it recovers from the war in the Balkans -- two days after the grand prix final in Milan .
Edwards was quoted as saying : " What type of character do we show by going to the IAAF Grand Prix Final in Milan where there is a lot of money to make but refusing to make the trip to Sarajevo as a humanitarian gesture ? "
SOCCER - BARATELLI TO COACH NICE .
NICE , France 1996-08-30
Former international goalkeeper Dominique Baratelli is to coach struggling French first division side Nice , the club said on Friday .
Baratelli , who played for Nice and Paris St Germain , takes over from Albert Emon who was fired on Thursday after Nice 's home defeat to Guingamp 2-1 in the league .
Nice have been unable to win any of their four league matches played this season and are lying a lowly 18th in the table .
SOCCER - MILAN 'S LENTINI MOVES TO ATALANTA .
MILAN 1996-08-30
Former Italian international winger Gianluigi Lentini , transferred to Milan in 1992 for what was believed to be a world record sum , has been loaned to serie A club Atalanta for a year , newspapers reported on Friday .
The Gazzetta dello Sport said the deal would cost Atalanta around $ 600,000 .
Lentini , 27 , joined Milan from Torino in a $ 12 million deal that many have speculated involved far more money changing hands and which has subsequently been investigated by magistrates for alleged financial irregularities .
The player suffered severe head injuries in a near-fatal car crash the following year and has since struggled to regain the form that made him a hero in Turin .
The move to Bergamo-based Atalanta reunites Lentini , who fell out with ex-Milan coach Fabio Capello last season , with his former coach at Torino , Emiliano Mondonico .
CRICKET - SRI LANKA BEAT AUSTRALIA BY FOUR WICKETS .
COLOMBO 1996-08-30
Sri Lanka beat Australia by four wickets in the third match of the Singer World Series one-day ( 50 overs ) cricket tournament on Friday .
Scores : Australia 228-9 in 50 overs , Sri Lanka 232-6 in 45.5 overs .
CRICKET - AUSTRALIA V SRI LANKA SCOREBOARD .
COLOMBO 1996-08-30
Scoreboard of the third Singer
World Series cricket match between Australia and Sri Lanka on
Friday :
Australia
M. Waugh c and b Jayasuriya 50
M. Slater run out 9
S. Law c Tillekeratne b Dharmasena 13
M. Bevan c Vaas b Chandana 56
S. Waugh b Muralitharan 22
R. Ponting not out 46
D. Lehmann st Kaluwitharana b Chandana 2
I. Healy c Ranatunga b Muralitharan 8
J. Gillespie st Kaluwitharana b Chandana 6
D. Fleming c Chandana b Jayasuriya 3
G. McGrath not out 8
Extras ( lb-3 nb-2 ) 5
Total ( nine wickets , 50 overs ) 228
Fall of wickets : 1-21 2-52 3-97 4-149 5-157 6-163 7-178
8-198 9-203 .
Bowling : Vass 7-0-29-0 , de Silva 4-0-25-0 , Dharmasena
9-0-49-1 , Muralitharan 10-0-41-2 , Jayasuriya 10-0-43-2 , Chandana
10-0-38-3 .
Sri Lanka
S. Jayasuriya c Healy b Fleming 44
R. Kaluwitharana b S. Waugh 8
A. Gurusinha run out 16
A.de Silva not out 83
A. Ranatunga lbw b Fleming 0
H. Tillekeratne lbw b Fleming 1
R. Mahanama b McGrath 50
U. Chandana not out 14
Extras ( lb-3 nb-6 w-7 ) 16
Total ( six wickets , 45.5 overs ) 232
Fall of wickets : 1-22 2-78 3-78 4-78 5-81 6-196 .
Did not bat : Dharmasena , Vaas , Muralitharan .
Bowling : S. Waugh 5-1-36-1 , Law 2-0-23-0 , McGrath 9.5-0-44-1 ,
Fleming 8-1-26-3 , Gillespie 6-0-27-0 , M. Waugh 5-0-29-0 , Lehmann
6-0-26-0 , Bevan 4-0-18-0 .
Man of the Match : Aravinda de Silva
Next Series match : India v Zimbabwe , September 1 .
CRICKET - AUSTRALIA 228-9 IN 50 OVERS V SRI LANKA .
COLOMBO 1996-08-30
Australia scored 228 for nine wickets in their 50 overs against Sri Lanka in the third day-night limited overs match of the Singer World Series tournament on Friday .
CRICKET - AUSTRALIA WIN TOSS AND CHOOSE TO BAT .
COLOMBO 1996-08-30
Australia won the toss and
elected to bat against Sri Lanka in the third day-night limited
overs cricket match in the Singer world series tournament on
Friday .
Teams :
Australia - Ian Healy ( captain ) , Michael Bevan , Damien
Flemming , Jason Gillespie , Stuart Law , Glenn McGrath , Ricky
Ponting , Michael Slater , Darren Lehmann , Mark Waugh , Steve
Waugh .
Sri Lanka - Arjuna Ranatunga ( captain ) , Sanath Jayasuriya ,
Romesh Kaluwitharana , Asanka Gurusinha , Aravinda de Silva ,
Hashan Tillekeratne , Roshan Mahanama , Kumara Dharmasena ,
Chaminda Vaas , Muthiah Muralitharan , Upul Chandana .
ROMANIA COMELF H1 PROFIT RISE BELOW TARGET .
BUCHAREST 1996-08-30
Romanian listed state engineer Comelf said it almost doubled six-month output , with net profit rising by 33 percent to 1.069 billion lei .
But the company complained inflation and the artificially high rate of the leu cut profit margins on exports , keeping profits well below its forecast of 1.4 billion lei .
Comelf 's six-month output rose to 4,378 tonnes of equipment from 2,684 tonnes in the equivalent period in 1995 , the company report to the Bucharest stock exchange showed .
Comelf , based in the central Transylvanian town of Bistrita , manufactures water purification equipment , machinery for the thermal power sector and other equipment .
" In the first six months of 1996 we concentrated on increasing the volume of our output and exports in particular and improving the quality of our products , " the report said .
From January to June Comelf exported 59 percent of its output , up from 37.3 percent in the same period last year .
The company said higher than anticipated inflation and rising raw materials and wage costs also hit profits .
Year-on-year inflation , initially estimated at 20 percent in December , was 33.8 percent in June , higher than a revised end-year forecast of 30 percent .
The 12 month figure quickened to 40.3 percent in July .
The leu currency has slipped only gradually this year , and is currently quoted at an official rate of 3,162 to the dollar , well below the 3,550 retail price that exporters say is more realistic .
-- Luli Popescu , Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264
POLISH NBP REFRAINS FROM REVERSE REPO OPERATION .
WARSAW 1996-08-30
The National Bank of Poland
refrained from staging a reverse repo operation on Friday , the
bank said .
-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700
Canada government cash balances fall in week .
OTTAWA 1996-08-30
The government of Canada 's cash balances fell in the week that ended August 28 , the Bank of Canada said on Friday .
Wk to Aug 28 Chg on wk Chg on yr
Notes in circulation 27.35 +0.435 +0.237
Government cash balances 3.54 - 0.629 +0.089
Govt securities outstanding 463.73 +1.660 +10.436
Treasury bills 152.80 +0.300 - 11.900
Canada savings bonds 30.12 - 0.004 +0.578
All figures in billions of dollars .
Chartered bank assets July June
Net foreign currency - 12.63 - 12.08
Canadian dollar 639.55 639.38
Total Canadian liquid assets 107.83 107.24
July 96 June 96 July 95
M1 63.02 62.83 57.50
M2 389.79 391.32 381.65
M3 482.13 480.72 461.42
Note - Figures are unadjusted , in billions of dollars .
-- Reuters Ottawa Bureau ( 613 ) 235-6745
Jones Medical completes acquisition .
ST. LOUIS 1996-08-30
Jones Medical Industries Inc said Friday it completed the acquisition of Daniels Pharmaceuticals Inc of St. Petersburg , Fla. , for about 2,960,000 shares of Jones common stock .
Jones stock closed down 1/8 at 40 Friday .
Daniels Pharmaceuticals manufactures prescription pharmaceutical products , the largest of which is Levoxyl , a synthetic thyroid hormone for treating hypothyroidism .
-- Chicago newsdesk , 312 408-8787
NYMEX heating oil near session lows in pre-close .
NEW YORK 1996-08-30
NYMEX refined product prices lingered at session lows amid slim volume before the close while crude experienced lackluster buying ahead of the U.S. Labor Day weekend , traders said .
" There was some profit-taking early on , and it 's just sitting there , " a Texas trader said of heating oil 's and gasoline 's losses .
September heating oil stood 1.02 cents lower at 62.65 cents a gallon .
Heat hit a session low of 62.45 shortly before the close .
September gasoline stood 0.87 cent lower at 62.85 cents a gallon .
Friday 's low in September gasoline was 62.75 .
Traders also said players were selling refined products in favor of crude ahead of the front month 's Friday expiry in the refined products .
The October heating oil-to-crude crack spread narrowed to $ 4.22 a barrel from Thursday 's $ 4.58 while the October gasoline-to-crude spread narrowed to $ 3.60 from Thursday 's $ 3.86 a barrel .
October crude stood eight cents higher at $ 22.23 barrel .
Buying interest in crude did not have enough conviction to send it much higher since many players had left early to start the Labor Day holiday weekend , traders said .
NYMEX will be closed Monday due to Labor Day .
-- Harry Milling , New York Energy Desk , +1 212-859-1761
U.S. debt futures end lower , shaken by Chicago NAPM .
CHICAGO 1996-08-30
U.S. debt futures finished a shortened pre-holiday session sharply lower , as the markets were shaken by a stronger than expected rise in the August National Association of Purchasing Management ( NAPM ) index for the Chicago area , traders and analysts said .
The August Chicago NAPM rose 8.8 points to 60.0 , its highest level since 62.6 in February 1995 and the largest monthly rise since December 1993 .
Primary dealers immediately sold Eurodollar and bond futures , after the market on average was expecting the index to rise marginally to 51.9 from July 's 51.2 .
Traders also said Japanese investors were unwinding long Eurodollar futures / short swaps , and that heavy put buying helped pressure Eurodollars to lower levels before the close .
One U.S. firm bought 35,000 September 97 mid-curve put options at a strike price of 93.25 to 93.30 in the last two sessions , while a French firm bought 4,000 September 93.30 to 93.32 put spreads .
" Even before the data came out , we were seeing put buying , " one floor trader said .
Meanwhile , funds were reportedly good sellers of five-year notes .
Rumors circulated that the Federal Reserve was buying five-year notes , and that a renowned hedge fund manager was buying 10-year notes in the cash markets .
However , December T-bonds ended below a major trendline level at 106-26/32 , as the yield in the cash bond market set its highest monthly close since April 1995 at 7.12 percent , one analyst said .
December bonds blew through the July 30 low of 107-06/32 , even though conditions were slightly oversold , traders said .
The December calendar spread continued to widen , also reflecting the market 's fear of rising inflation .
While the market continues to price-in higher U.S. interest rates , there was little conviction to the theory that the Federal Reserve would tighten rates before the next Federal Open Market Committee meeting on September 24 .
Federal Reserve governor Lawrence Lindsey , speaking on U.S. cable television network CNBC , said the U.S. economy appears on balance to be a bit strong , adding the central bank would not curb growth provided inflation remains in check .
Earlier in the day , Fed chairman Alan Greenspan said at the annual Jackson Hole symposium that the goal of price stability is within reach for major nations .
Traders said the Fed 's decision to adopt a tightening bias at the July FOMC meeting has cast more focus on every piece of U.S. economic news .
" The Fed 's stance has really sensitized us to all this data , " one analyst said . "
The revisions to GDP , for example , may not have attracted a lot of attention . "
At the end of pit trade , December bonds were off 27/32 at 106-25/32 , 10-year notes down 21/32 at 105-17/32 , munibonds off 17/32 at 111-20/32 , December Eurodollars were down 11 bps at 93.94 , March Eurodollars were off 13 bps at 93.72 and March T-bills were down 12 bps at 94.33 .
Douglas & Lomason shares rise on merger .
FARMINGTON HILLS , Mich .
1996-08-30
Shares of Douglas & Lomason Co were up 4-1/2 at 30-5/8 Friday afternoon after Thursday 's announcement that the vehicle seat maker had agreed to be acquired by Magna International Inc for $ 31 a share , or $ 135 million .
Magna was up 1/8 to 48-1/4 on the New York Stock Exchange .
Douglas & Lomason has 4.45 million common shares outstanding , some of which are option shares to be purchased at exercise prices less than the $ 31 offered price .
The acquisition will beef up Markham , Ontario-based Magna 's North American car and truck seating business , allowing it to better compete with Johnson Controls Inc and Lear Corp .
Family-controlled Douglas & Lomason , which had 1995 revenue of $ 561 million , was finding it more difficult to compete for new seating contracts from vehicle makers , said James Hoey , chief financial officer .
" Unfortunately , in the auto industry these days , a $ 500 million company is not a big company anymore , " Hoey said . "
This merger makes us much more competitive . "
He added that Douglas & Lomason 's top executives have been asked to stay on with Magna after the merger , though their future roles have not yet been defined .
Douglas & Lomason 's profits were hurt in the past year by model changeovers , which had reduced production at some important customers , but are now recovering , analysts said .
The company earned $ 11.2 million on sales of $ 299 million in the first six months of 1996 , up from year-earlier earnings of $ 4.7 million on sales of $ 285.7 million .
Ford plans to cut its roster of 2,300 tier-one suppliers -- those it deals with directly -- in half over the next five years .
" The deal really levels the seating field somewhat , " said John Casesa of Schroder Wertheim & Co . "
It should give Magna the critical mass to be a bigger player in that market . "
Magna 's traditional strength has been instrument panels , door panels and other interior components .
Magna , Johnson Controls and Lear have been working to build up their capabilties to supply complete interiors to automakers , including seats , instrument panels , door panels carpeting and headliners .
UK meals / feeds follow Chicago higher , trade slow .
LONDON 1996-08-30
UK meals and feeds sellers marked up high protein soymeal by around 1.50 stg a tonne on Friday following gains in Chicago at Thursday 's close .
Trade was very quiet with only one deal reported when spot high protein soymeal fetched 215 stg a tonne ex-store on the south coast .
" I would n't get too excited about this one becuase I think it 's for all of five tonnes , which when you think about just about sums up the state of the market at the moment , " said a trader .
-- Jim Ballantyne , London Newsroom +44 171 542 8062
Iraqi captors of Sudanese jet charged with hijack .
LONDON 1996-08-30
Seven Iraqis who seized a Sudanese airliner with 199 people aboard and forced it to fly to London were on Friday charged with hijack , ending speculation that they might be offered immediate asylum in Britain .
Police said the seven men , who freed all their hostages after the plane landed at Stansted airport on Tuesday and then appealed for asylum , would appear in court on Saturday .
The Iraqis claimed they were " ordinary people persecuted by the regime of Saddam ( Hussein ) " but interior ministry officials had consistently said it was likely the seven would be charged with hijack before any plea for asylum was considered .
Under English law the maximum sentence for hijack is life imprisonment , but there has been widespread speculation that the seven will receive lesser sentences and then be allowed to stay rather than being sent back to Iraq .
The hijack began on Monday when an Amman-bound plane was taken over shortly after it took off from Khartoum .
The hijackers threatened to blow it up during a refuelling stop in Cyprus unless they were taken to London .
After a search of the aircraft following the hijackers ' surrender , police found only knives and fake explosives .
Late bond market prices .
LONDON 1996-08-30
This is how major world bond markets were trading in late European business on Friday .
GERMANY - Bunds extended losses , flirting with session lows after falling victim to sharply higher U.S. economic data which revived fears that interest rates may soon turn higher .
The September Bund future on the London International Financial Futures and Options Exchange ( LIFFE ) was trading at 97.18 , down 0.20 from Thursday 's settlement price .
BRITAIN - Gilts struggled off the day 's lows but ended 10/32 down on the day .
A sharp plunge in U.S. Treasuries after a shock rise in the Chicago PMI pulled gilts lower , but traders said the market was nervous anyway ahead of August MO data and the PMI survey due on Monday .
The September long gilt future on LIFFE was trading at 107-2/32 , down 8/32 from Thursday 's settlement price .
FRANCE - Bond and PIBOR futures ended the day higher despite much stronger than expected U.S. data .
The September notional bond future on the MATIF in Paris settled at 123.14 , up 0.04 from Thursday 's settlement price .
ITALY - Bond futures held to easier levels in late afternoon after the sharp drop in Treasuries , but a resilient lira helped limit BTP losses .
The September bond future on LIFFE was trading at 115.45 , down 0.13 from Thursday 's settlement price .
UNITED STATES - Prices of U.S. Treasury securities were trading sharply lower near midday after a surprisingly strong Chicago Purchasing Managers ' report shook the markets ahead of the long Labour Day weekend .
The September Treasury bond future on the Chicago Board of Trade was trading at 107-11/32 , down 26/32 from Thursday 's settlement price .
The long bond was quoted to yield 7.12 percent .
JAPAN - Yield for benchmark 182nd cash bond fell on buy-backs following weaker-than-expected industrial output data , which convinced traders the BOJ would not raise interest rates soon .
Japanese Goverment Bonds futures which closed before the output data , lost much of day 's gains as Tokyo stock prices recovered from the day 's low.In after hours trading the September future on LIFFE was trading at 122.53 , up 0.26 from Thursday 's settlement price on the Tokyo Stock Exchange .
EUROBONDS - Primary market activity was sharply lower , as players wound down ahead of Monday 's U.S. Labour Day holiday and next week 's U.S. employment data .
NSW Treasury launched a A$ 100 million three-year discount bond aimed at Japanese investors .
DNIB issued a 275 million Norwegian crown bond , which was pre-placed with a European institution .
DNIB also set a 110 million guilder step-up bond .
Next week Kansai Electric Power and Kansai International Airport are likely to launch 10-year dollar deals .
Boxing-Bruno quits on doctor 's advice .
LONDON 1996-08-30
Former world heavyweight champion Frank Bruno has quit the ring on medical advice , Britain 's Sun newspaper reported on Friday .
An eye specialist told the 35-year-old Bruno that he could be blinded in one eye if he boxed again , the newspaper said .
The Briton , who lost his World Boxing Council ( WBC ) title to Mike Tyson in March , said : " I was in shock as soon as he told me and it still has n't really sunk in .
" I never wanted to end like this but at the end of the day I 'm glad I had a good innings . "
Bruno , for years one of Britain 's most popular sportsmen , had hoped to have another shot at the world title and had been in training until a routine eye test on Monday highlighted a problem with his right eye .
Professor David McLeod , who examined Bruno , told the Sun : " There is a risk he could be blinded in the eye if he steps into the ring again .
He is in danger of getting a retinal detachment and there is no point in exposing himself to that . "
Bruno lost three world title fights before finally landing the crown by beating American Oliver McCall in a unanimous points decision at Wembley in September 1995 .
He was only the third Briton ever to hold a world heavyweight title .
But Bruno lost the title on his first defence when he fought American Tyson in Las Vegas .
Bruno suffered a cut eye in the opening round and the referee stopped the fight in the third as the Briton crumbled under a flurry of punches .
Soccer - McCarthy names team to play Liechtenstein .
DUBLIN 1996-08-30
Irish soccer manager Mick McCarthy on Friday announced the team to play Liechtenstein in Saturday 's World Cup qualifying match .
Birmingham 's Gary Breen was selected ahead of Phil Babb in defence , while 18-year-old Ian Harte makes his international competitive debut .
Keith O'Neill of Norwich City joins Niall Quinn up front .
The team is as follows :
Given , Breen , Staunton , Irwin , McAteer , Harte , McLoughlin , Houghton , Townsend , Quinn , O'Neill .
-- Dublin Newsroom +353 1 676 9779
Nigerian thieves hire police truck to carry loot .
LAGOS 1996-08-30
A gang of thieves in eastern Nigeria paid a police corporal to carry off eight air conditioners they had just stolen , the national news agency reported on Friday .
" Little did I know I was dealing with robbers , " the News Agency of Nigeria quoted the unnamed corporal as saying .
He admitted to having been paid 3,000 naira ( $ 37.50 ) for his services in transporting the loot valued at 300,000 naira ( $ 3,750 ) .
Police in the town of Uyo said the corporal had been arrested , while the air conditioners had been returned to their rightful owner .
They did not comment on the whereabouts of the thieves .
( $ 1=80 naira )
East Dries miners fail to report for work .
JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-30
Workers at Driefontein Consolidated Ltd 's east gold mine have failed to report for work since Wednesday night , mine managers Gold Fields of South Africa Ltd said on Friday .
" Discussions with employee and union representatives are continuing , " the company said in a statement .
It gave no further details .
At least 17 miners have been killed in labour unrest -- sparked by ethnic differences -- at Driefontein Consolidated and Gold Fields ' Kloof Gold Mining Co this month .
-- Johannesburg newsroom , +27-11 482 1003
Chad government closes university after protests .
N'DJAMENA 1996-08-30
The government of Chad has closed N'Djamena University after two days of protests over grant arrears in which Education Minister Nagoum Yamassoum was held hostage for four hours , state radio said on Friday .
" The minister and his colleagues who were held in the rector 's office were freed thanks an intervention by gendarmes , " one university official said .
" Angry students cut the telephone , water and electricity of the university offices before smashing the windows and breaking down the doors . "
Paramilitary police detained more than 120 students in the protest .
The students ' union said second and third-year students were demanding four months of unpaid grants .
End-of-year examinations would go ahead on September 2 despite the closure , university officials said .
Yeltsin endorses Lebed Chechnya peace plan - agency .
MOSCOW 1996-08-30
Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin said on Friday that President Boris Yeltsin , who is vacationing outside Moscow , had backed security chief Alexander Lebed 's peace plan for Chechnya , Interfax news agency said .
" Lebed is now in Chechnya solving some problems , " Interfax quoted Chernomyrdin as saying . "
The main thing is his programme .
It was agreed with Boris Nikolayevich ( Yeltsin ) yesterday . "
Lebed , whom Yeltsin ordered to restore peace in Chechnya , struck a military deal with separatist rebels last week ending the worst fighting in the region in more than a year .
He later discussed with rebel chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov a framework political agreement to tackle the most painful issue of the 20-month war -- the future political status of Chechnya .
Lebed said on Friday he hoped to sign a document with the rebels later in the day which would deal with the political settlement of the conflict .
Moscow , which wants to keep Chechnya as a part of the Russian Federation , sent troops to the region in December 1994 to quell its independence bid .
Yeltsin has said any deal should preserve Russia 's territorial integrity .
Itar-Tass news agency quoted Lebed as saying that he would suggest to the rebels that the decision on Chechnya 's future political status be deferred by up to 10 years .
Lebed said he had a telephone conversation with Yeltsin late on Thursday but gave no details .
Yeltsin 's press office could not confirm the call .
Chernomyrdin said on Thursday after a meeting with Lebed and top officials , who discussed Lebed 's plans to restore peace in Chechnya , that it needed more work .
Lebed , Chechens sign framework political deal .
KHASAVYURT , Russia 1996-08-31
Russian peacemaker Alexander Lebed said he and rebel military leader Aslan Maskhadov agreed after overnight talks to defer the decision on whether Chechnya should be independent until December 31 , 2001 .
" We just now signed a statement and attached the basic principles of relations between the Russian Federation and the Chechen Republic , " Lebed told reporters after he and Maskhadov signed a package of documents .
He gave no further details .
" That 's it , the war is over , " Lebed told reporters who witnessed the signing .
Lebed said he and Maskhadov agreed to defer by more than five years the painful issue of Chechnya 's political status .
" Then , with cool heads , calmly and soberly we will sort out our relations , " Lebed said after the late-night signing ceremony in this settlement outside Chechnya 's eastern border .
Tens of thousands of people have died in the war , begun in late 1994 after Moscow sent troops to quell Chechnya 's independence bid .
But Russia failed to win control over the whole of Chechnya and its troops suffered several humiliating defeats .
President Boris Yeltsin ordered Lebed to restore peace in Chechnya and gave him unspecified sweeping powers to carry out the mission .
Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin said on Friday that Yeltsin backed a package of proposals Lebed took to the talks .
Ruling Moslem party ends vote boycott .
SARAJEVO 1996-08-30
Bosnia 's ruling Moslem nationalist party on Friday called on its refugee voters to end a boycott of absentee balloting in national elections , citing assurances provided by a U.S. envoy , government radio said .
The Bosnian government radio broadcast said U.S. Assistant Secretary of State John Kornblum had reassured SDA officials , including presumably its leader , Bosnian President Alija Izetbegovic , whom he met during a Friday visit .
But the radio report did not specify what guarantees , if any , the U.S. envoy had provided .
Absentee voting in the elections began on Wednesday , August 28 and runs for a week .
Election day for those living inside Bosnia is September 14 .
The Party of Democratic Action ( SDA ) had called on Wednesday for its followers abroad to boycott the absentee balloting because of voter registration irregularities , especially among Serb refugees .
The Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe ( OSCE ) postponed municipal elections as a result of the irregularities but decided to proceed with voting for higher offices .
The SDA , joined by two other parties , has been demanding that OSCE prohibit refugees voting from any place other than their pre-war place of residence as a means to prevent the elections from ratifying the results of ethnic cleansing .
Belgrade airport runway repairs Sept 21-26-agency .
BELGRADE 1996-08-30
Belgrade 's main airport Aerodrom Beograd will be closed to traffic for runway maintenance and modernization from September 21 to 26 , the Yugoslav news agency Tanjug reported late on Friday .
" During the works , all flights will be re-routed to the nearby airport in Batajnica , with no change in schedules , " Tanjug quotes Belgrade airport General Director Ljubomir Acimovic as saying .
The airport in Surcin will continue to carry out all other activities and has secured enough buses to transport passengers to Batajnica , Acimovic said .
The value of maintenance works , which will last 120 hours straight , is 20 million dinars and the funds have been secured by Belgrade airport , Tanjug said .
The Batajnica airport will take over complete air traffic control during this period , Federal Air Traffic Control Administration Director Branko Bilbija said .
-- Amra Kevic , Belgrade newsroom +381 11 2224305
Top Belarus politician blasts president .
Larisa Sayenko
MINSK 1996-08-30
A senior Belarus politician accused President Alexander Lukashenko on Friday of attempting to set up a dictatorship in the former Soviet republic .
The speaker of the Belarus parliament , Semyon Sharetsky , told Reuters that a draft constitution , due to be put to a national referendum on November 7 , would dangerously increase the powers of the ruler .
" The world community should not be indifferent to the fact that President Lukashenko , who leads this European state of 10 million people , is trying to establish a dictatorship with his new constitution , " Sharetsky said .
The new constitution calls for a two-chamber parliament with a 110-seat majority-elected house of representatives and a regionally-represented senate with a third of its members named by the president .
Lukashenko 's aides shrugged off Sharetsky 's charge . "
If there was a dictatorship they would n't have the right to say things like this , " Sergei Posukhov , Lukashenko 's political adviser , told Reuters .
" The people have asked us to establish order and that 's our main aim . "
Lukashenko , 41 , won presidential polls in 1994 on promises to restore order , fight corruption and repair the strong links with Russia that were disrupted by the collapse of the Soviet Union .
But during his period in office he has battled against nationalist opponents , trade unions and parliament and Sharetsky said the current parliament was ready to try to impeach him .
" This constitution , which has been prepared in secret , aims to gather all power in one man 's hands , " he said . "
We should not be fooled by his quasi-democratic rhetoric and his methods , like this referendum . "
Lukashenko signed a pact with Moscow in April to create a strong economic and political union which he believes could grow into a federation .
But nationalist groups , scared by the prospect of renewed Moscow domination and Russia 's backing for Lukashenko , protested against the deal .
Lukashenko responded by cracking down on the nationalist opposition and jailing nearly 200 people for taking part in demonstrations against the pact .
The United States last week granted political asylum to two opposition leaders , Zenon Poznyak and Sergei Naumchik .
Tajik troops now control devastated town .
Yuri Kushko
TAVILDARA , Tajikistan 1996-08-30
Tajik government troops now control of the strategically vital town of Tavildara after driving out Islamic rebels , but sporadic gunfire still echoed in the nearby Pamir mountains on Friday .
The commander-in-chief of Tajikistan 's armed forces , Major-General Nikolai Sherbatov , took a group of journalists by helicopter to the remote , and now devastated , town to show that his forces held it .
He said his troops took Tavildara without casualties on August 23 , but the crack of sniper and machinegun fire revealed the presence of opposition fighters in the surrounding mountains .
Sherbatov said the rebels were located about three km ( two miles ) east of Tavildara around the village of Layron .
Tavildara , 200 km ( 120 miles ) east of the capital Dushanbe , was in ruins .
Shells had smashed roofs and windows and empty shell cases littered the streets .
The town straddles a strategically important road linking government and rebel-held territory and has fallen succesively to both sides in a bloody tug-of-war which began last February .
Tajikistan , which borders Afghanistan and China , has been split by a dragging four-year conflict after a civil war between communists and a frail coalition of Islamic and liberal groups .
Tens of thousands of people have been killed and many more have been displaced in the fighting , which breached a shaky United Nations-sponsored ceasefire .
Tavildara is now apparently inhabited only by a few old men , women and their grubby , barefoot children .
Fruit remained on the trees as there was no one to pick it .
" Help me , help me , " said a chorus of women begging soldiers for food .
The town 's school and a shop doubling as a warehouse for humanitarian aid were destroyed in the fighting .
" We had to build our own earth shelters to survive the fighting , " said Rajab Adinayev , a bearded elderly Tajik in a long white shirt .
Although shy in front of the government soldiers , several inhabitants accused government forces of widespread looting of homes and livestock .
They also said rebel fighters had looted medicines from the local hospital .
One elderly man , who declined to give his name , said two of his sons were now refugees in Moscow and the other two had left to fight for the opposition .
He also said government soldiers had raped the wife of one of his sons . "
It 's not important who holds this town , we just need to stop the war , " he said .
Polish Foreign Minister to visit Yugoslavia .
WARSAW 1996-08-30
Poland 's Foreign Minister Dariusz Rosati will visit Yugoslavia on September 3 and 4 to revive a dialogue between the two governments which was effectively frozen in 1992 , PAP news agency reported on Friday .
During Rosati 's trip the two countries will sign an agreement on mutual protection of investments and a note easing conditions on the granting of visas , the agency quoted Foreign Ministry officials as saying .
The Federal Republic of Yugoslavia is the only country of the former Yugoslavia where Poles currently require visas .
They are also to clinch protocols on culture and understanding between the two foreign ministries .
Rosati will meet Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic and Yugoslav politicians in Belgrade , before visiting Montenegro .
Poland revived diplomatic ties at ambassadorial level with Yugoslavia in April but economic links are almost moribund , despite the end of a three-year U.N. trade embargo imposed to punish Belgrade for its support of Bosnian Serbs .
Poland is seeking pacts on avoiding double taxation and wants cooperation in fighting crime .
Yeltsin visits wife Naina in hospital - Interfax .
MOSCOW 1996-08-30
Russian President Boris Yeltsin visited his wife Naina in hospital on Friday evening , Interfax news agency quoted spokesman Sergei Yastrzhembsky as saying .
Naina Yeltsin had a kidney operation last Saturday .
Earlier Russian news reports had said Yeltsin 's children and grandchildren had visited the Russian first lady but they said only that Yeltsin , on vacation outside Moscow , had spoken to her by telephone .
" Naina Yeltsin looks well , she is active , she is clearly getting better , " Yastrzhembsky quoted Yeltsin as saying .
Naina Yeltsin is recovering in Moscow 's Central Clinical Hospital , where the president himself was treated twice last year for heart attacks .
Yeltsin , 65 , has been seen only rarely since he was elected for a second term in office on July 3 , although his aides have denied a string of rumours that he has been taken ill again .
Yastrzhembsky said Yeltsin had travelled from the hospital to spend the night at the Barvikha sanatorium outside Moscow .
He was likely to return on Saturday to his holiday resort , a hunting lodge some 100 km ( 60 miles ) from Moscow .
Lebed , Chechens start peace talks .
KHASAVYURT , Russia 1996-08-30
Russian peacemaker Alexander Lebed and Chechen separatist military leader Aslan Maskhadov started a new round of peace talks on Friday in this settlement just outside the rebel region .
Lebed , who flew into Chechnya earlier in the day , said he hoped to sign a framework agreement on a political settlement of the 20-month conflict in which tens of thousands of people have died .
Neither Lebed nor Maskhadov made any statement before the talks .
Russian judge stabbed to death over $ 7 fine .
MOSCOW 1996-08-30
A Moscow street vendor stabbed to death a woman judge in a city court on Friday after she fined him the equivalent of seven dollars for trading illegally , Interfax news agency said .
Interfax said Judge Olga Lavrentyeva , 28 , on Thursday ordered the confiscation of several overcoats , suits and shirts which vendor Valery Ivankov , 41 , was illegally trading on Moscow streets and fined him 38,000 roubles ( seven dollars ) .
The next morning , Ivankov appeared in the courtroom and stabbed Lavrentyeva .
The judge died later in hospital .
Interfax quoted Levrentyeva 's colleagues as saying that judges were generally unprotected against criminal attacks .
Cofinec plunges on H1 results .
Emese Bartha
BUDAPEST 1996-08-30
Shares of France-registered printed packaging company Cofinec S.A. plunged sharply on the Budapest Stock Exchange ( BSE ) on Friday , despite a mostly reassuring forecast by the group .
Cofinec 's Global Depositary Receipts ( GDRs ) opened at 5,200 forints on the BSE , down 600 from Thursday 's close , following the release of its first half results this morning .
Cofinec CEO Stephen Frater told reporters in a conference call from Vienna on Friday before the opening of the bourse that he expects a stronger second half , although the group will not be able to achieve its annual profit goal .
" We will not achieve the full 37 million French franc ( net ) profit forecast , " Frater said . "
Obviously , we cannot make up the unexpected decrease that has been experienced in the first half of the year . "
Frater declined to give a forecast for the full year , ahead of a supervisory board meeting next week .
Cofinec , the first foreign company to list on the Budapest bourse , released its consolidated first half figures ( IAS ) this morning .
In the conference call , Frater said he regarded Cofinec GDRs -- which are trading below their issue price of 6,425 forints -- as a buying opportunity .
" Obviously , at some point it represents a buying opportunity , " Frater said . "
I think the reality is that we operate in emerging markets , emerging markets tend to be more volatile . "
" My message is that the fundamental strategy of the company , its fundamental market position has not changed . "
The group , which operates in Hungary , Poland and the Czech Republic , reported an operating profit before interest of 21.8 million French francs compared to 34.1 million in the same six months of 1995 .
Net profit for the January-June 1996 period was 2.1 million French francs , down from 10.3 million in the first six months of 1995 , with the bulk of this decline attributable to the performance of Petofi , one of its Hungarian units .
Cofinec said Petofi general manager Laszlo Sebesvari had submitted his resignation and will be leaving Petofi but will remain on Petofi 's board of directors .
" Until a new general manager of Petofi is appointed ...
I will in fact move to Kecskemet ( site of Petofi printing house ) for the interim and will serve as acting chief executive officer of Petofi , " Frater said .
-- Budapest newsroom ( 36 1 ) 327 4040
Romania cen bank one-week rate rises to 50.19 pct .
BUCHAREST 1996-08-30
The National Bank of Romania ( BNR ) said its one-week refinancing rate has been lifted this week to 50.19 percent from 49 percent after two banks bids ' exceeded its offer at Thursday 's auction .
The two banks entered bids totalling 497.5 billion lei at rates ranging from 49 to 51 percent , against the BNR 's offer of 420 billion lei .
Traders said that over the past few days the two major banks , keen to meet minimum reserve targets , also chased funds on the money market , being ready to gulp short-term money at rates up to 49 percent .
Other banks traded one-week rates near 48 percent .
-- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264
Potent landmines found near Colombian presidency .
BOGOTA , Colombia 1996-08-30
Eight claymore mines fitted with powerful C-4 plastic explosives were found stashed in a real estate office on Friday located about two blocks from Colombia 's presidential palace , police said .
" These are powerful weapons , " a spokesman with the Municipal Police told Reuters by telephone , adding that police had not ruled out a possible terrorist attack on the ornate Casa de Narino presidential palace in Bogota 's historic downtown area .
" They could cause serious damage as much as 500 meters ( yards ) away from wherever they were detonated , " the spokesman added .
He said police backed by explosive experts were combing the area in search of other possible weapons or explosive devices .
The police spokeman said plastic explosive like C-4 is not a normal component in claymore mines .
But he said the eight mines seized by police had been " specially adapted . "
The spokesman declined further comment , except to say that two women and a man identified as a lawyer had been arrested in connection with the landmines .
Assault charges dropped against Surinam ex-rebel .
PARAMARIBO , Surinam 1996-08-30
Flamboyant former Surinamese guerrilla leader Ronny Brunswijk walked free on Friday after charges of attempted murder were dropped , police said .
Brunswijk had been in police custody for 10 days after Freddy Pinas , a Surinamese-born visitor from the Netherlands , accused Brunswijk of trying to kill him in a bar-room brawl in the mining town of Moengo 56 miles ( 90 km ) east of Paramaribo .
Brunswijk , 35 , denied the charge and reached an agreement with Pinas after replacing a golden necklace lost in the scuffle .
It was the second time Brunswijk had been charged with attempted murder in less than two years .
In 1994 he served two months for shooting a thief in the backside .
Brunswijk , who led a rebel group against the military regime of Desi Bouterse in the late 1980s , is now a successful businessman with mining and logging interests .
Cambodian opposition newspaper editor pardoned .
PHNOM PENH 1996-08-30
Cambodia 's King Norodom Sihanouk on Friday gave a royal pardon to an opposition newspaper editor who had alleged top-level corruption .
Hen Vipheak , former editor of the Sereipheap Thmei ( New Liberty ) newspaper , stepped through the gates of the run-down French colonial-era T3 prison late Friday afternoon , following intervention on his behalf by King Sihanouk .
The Supreme Court had on August 23 sent the opposition Khmer Nation Party steering committee member to jail after upholding rulings by the municipal and appeal courts that handed down a five million riels ( $ 2,000 ) fine and one year 's imprisonment .
The judge overturned a decision to shut down Hen Vipheak 's newspaper .
The editor was prosecuted following a May 1995 article alleging top-level corruption .
Sihanouk promised an amnesty to Hen Vipheak , along with fellow KNP member and journalist Chan Rattana , who was released after serving a week of a year-long jail term in June .
Co-Premiers Prince Norodom Ranariddh and Hun Sen agreed earlier this week to the king 's request for an amnesty .
Far East Gold - Moribund market seen continuing .
Mishi Saran
HONG KONG 1996-08-30
Far East gold traders thumped foreheads in frustration at the market 's foot-dragging this week and forecast on Friday that next week would not be much better .
The Southeast Asian gold market was more or less a photo-fit picture of the previous week 's position with activity slow and bullion prices trapped in a well-worn range awaiting a seasonal upturn in demand and prices into the fourth quarter .
Singapore premiums for Australian kilo bars were quoted unchanged at between 25-45 cents an ounce over spot loco London prices , with South Korean and Indonesian-origin premiums also steady at 10-20 cents an ounce .
Singapore dealers said they were concerned that there had been a marked revival in offers to sell gold by South Korean traders , following the distress sales of recent months after the Seoul government 's crackdown on bullion arbitrage trade .
" I was shocked to see these offers coming in again , though there 's been no indication of price or volume .
I dread to think what will happen to the premiums if the Koreans start selling in force , " one dealer said .
Continued dishoarding of kilo-bars by Indonesian sources ahead of next year 's presidential election has also kept a lid on premiums .
Gold closed down at $ 387.00 / $ 387.50 an ounce in Hong Kong on Friday , versus New York 's $ 387.60 / $ 388 finish on Thursday .
Dealers said the precious metal eased on a report that the International Monetary Fund might sell some of its gold to reduce the debts of the poorest developing countries .
Easier silver prices mid-week helped keep spot gold locked in a $ 386 - $ 389 an ounce range , dealers said , but they remained optimistic that the usual seasonal pick-up in jewellery fabrication demand would see gold at $ 395 by end-October .
" I still think we 'll see gold at $ 395 by the end of October , in a retracement of the $ 418 - $ 380 move we saw at the start of the year , " one said .
Silver , basis the September contract on New York 's Comex market , was expected to find support at between $ 5.12 - $ 5.15 an ounce and meet resistance from $ 5.25 - $ 5.30 , they added .
September silver closed up $ 0.004 in New York on Thursday at $ 5.255 an ounce .
Tripoli decks out for coup celebrations .
Mona Eltahawy
TRIPOLI 1996-08-30
Libyans are dressing up their capital Tripoli for celebrations on Sunday of the 27th anniversary of the coup which brought Muammar Gaddafi to power .
Green flags and banners praise the " great revolution " and promise defiance against United Nations sanctions imposed for Libya 's refusal to hand over for trial two suspects wanted in connection with the 1988 bombing of a Pan Am flight over Lockerbie , Scotland .
" We have chosen the challenge because it is our only option , " proclaimed one banner on the road to Tripoli airport which serves only internal flights because of the sanctions .
Huge stadium lights are directed at the city 's Green Square where makeshift stages await Sunday 's festivities .
Three African leaders -- from Niger , Guinea and Ghana -- are expected to attend the celebrations marking September 1 , 1969 when a group of young army officers , led by a 27-year-old Gaddafi , deposed King Mohammed Idris .
" The revolution has brought us great achievements ...
We are comfortable the revolution has taken care of us , improved our lives and given us capabilites , " Samer Ammar Soliman , 42 , told Reuters as he came out of Friday prayers .
But some Libyans have begun to show their discontent in the country 's east , which has become a hotbed of militant violence .
Tripoli-based diplomats and exiled opponents said Gaddafi 's airforce blasted in July rebel strongholds in the mountainous Jebel al-Akhdar region .
Travellers arriving in Egypt say militants and police officers clash regularly in Benghazi .
At least 20 people were killed in the capital in early July after bodyguards loyal to Gaddafi 's sons fired at spectators of a football match who were chanting subversive slogans .
Gaddafi has dismissed any unrest as the work of foreigners , and last year deported thousands of Sudanese and Egyptian workers .
Twilight zone for Wall Street as political race heats up .
Pierre Belec
NEW YORK 1996-08-30
For Wall Street , this is the season to be cautious as the presidential contest puts the stock market in the twilight zone .
President Clinton , Bob Dole and Ross Perot are hitting the road now that the partying is over , and people who have billions of dollars invested in stocks were bracing for political promises that could have an impact on their wealth .
Analysts believe that the candidates will add to the market 's list of uncertainties , which already includes the question of whether the Federal Reserve will raise interest rates to cool economic growth .
They say the politicians will need to promote legislation that helps the economy without scaring the socks off financial markets .
" The worst thing that could happen for financial markets is that if Clinton and Dole start to trade shots in the middle of the ring with one-upmanship , " said Hugh Johnson , chief investment officer at First Albany Corp. " That 's when Wall Street will need to worry . "
He said that the bond market would be the first to react if the " bidding " intensifies and stocks would quickly drop as interest rates rise .
" I do n't think it would imply the collapse of the stock market , unless the rise in rates touches off a dynamic within the market , which would include selling by portfolio managers , redemptions by individuals of mutual funds that would , in turn , pressure the portfolio managers to sell even more stock . "
This week , the market weighed Dole 's proposal to lower federal income taxes by 15 percent across the board , a package that carries a price tag of $ 548 billion .
Clinton proposes an $ 8.4 billion re-election agenda that would spare most home-sellers from capital gains taxes and give employers tax incentives to hire people off the welfare rolls .
Clinton claims Dole 's plan would increase the deficit , while the White House said some corporate taxes would be raised to offset the cost of the president 's plan .
The experts said there are some unusual risks for the market from this year 's political season because the rush to promise tax cuts to win votes could upset Wall Street 's expectations that Washington will balance the budget .
" The stock market will have to edit the promises and then do a probability study on those edited promises , " said John Geraghty at the consulting firm North American Equity Services .
During the past four presidential elections , the candidate that has favoured tax cuts has won .
Ronald Reagan 's tax cut won him a second four-year term in the White House in 1984 , while Democrat Walter Mondale , who promised higher taxes , lost .
George Bush became president in 1988 on his no-new-tax campaign and Clinton won in 1992 with a promise to fatten workers ' paychecks .
The trick , they said , will be for the candidates to continue to convince Wall Street that the Treasury 's 30-year bond -- the most closely-watched interest rate -- will fall to between 4 percent and 5 percent by the end of the decade .
Johnson said that long-term interest rates have already been spooked by the election .
The long-term bond jumped this week to 7.13 percent after starting the year at 5.95 percent .
The surge of buying in stocks during the last two years has come amid an environment of low interest rates , which has boosted corporate profits .
But the market stalled this summer after the Dow Jones industrial average set a record high of 5,778.00 points on May 22 .
" The market does n't seem to be able to make new highs and it has been back and forth in a fairly horizontal mode which looks like a holding pattern , " said Geraghty .
He said the market reflects the political uncertainty , now that Dole has sharply narrowed the gap with Clinton in the polls .
Geraghty said that the one thing that could completely turn the election around are new findings in the Whitewater scandal that would damage the Clintons .
" Stocks are on a delicate edge because if something happens that looks like it could upset the presidency , it could throw the political and , to some extent the economic , process into chaos , " Geraghty said .
Right now , Wall Street is pondering the candidates .
" We have an election where there are so many unknown variables that most people will probably want to hold fire , and even take the chance that they will have to pay higher prices for stocks after the November election , than take the risk that a shock to the system will hurt the stock market , " Geraghty said .
On Friday , the Dow Jones index closed down 31.44 points at 5,616.21 .
For the week , it was down 106.53 points .
The Nasdaq composite index closed 3.53 points lower Friday at 1,141.50 .
For the week , it was down 1.55 points .
The Standard & Poor 's index of 500 stocks was off 5.41 points at 651.99 , down 15.03 points for the week .
The American Stock Exchange index was down 1.66 points at 559.68 , and was off 1.26 for the week .
Brisk economic reports rattle markets anew .
Glenn Somerville
WASHINGTON 1996-08-30
Factory orders rose in July and manufacturing surged in the Midwest in August , reports said Friday , sparking worries about inflation that battered financial markets for a second straight day .
The Commerce Department said orders for manufactured goods climbed 1.8 percent in July to a seasonally adjusted $ 317.6 billion -- nearly twice the increase that had been expected .
Shipments of everything from new cars to food items rose , as did order backlogs , in a sign that the strength in the industrial sector would continue in coming months .
A separate report from Chicago area purchasing managers underlined the strength in manufacturing as the group 's barometer of manufacturing in the region jumped to 60 in August from 51.2 in July .
A reading above 50 indicates growth in manufacturing .
While production and orders rose at Midwest area businesses , the prices they paid for goods used in manufacturing remained well in check .
Analysts said the reports implied the economy was not slowing down in the third quarter after a burst of growth in the spring , and that the lull in late June and July was more temporary than Federal Reserve policy-makers had wanted .
" It appears that August is showing an economy again reversing course and is not moving onto a significantly slower track at this point , " said economist Lynn Reaser of Barnett Banks Inc. in Jacksonville , Fla .
The reports fanned worries on Wall Street that the Fed , the nation 's central bank , would raise rates next month in a bid to ward off inflation , driving stock and bond prices sharply lower for a second day running .
The 30-year Treasury fell almost a point , raising its yield , which moves in the opposite direction from the price , to 7.12 percent from 7.04 percent late Thursday .
The Dow Jones industrial average fell 31.44 points to 5,616.21 after a 64.73-point decline Thursday .
A third report from the Commerce Department , on July personal income and spending , pointed to a potential slowdown in consumer spending that some analysts said may help moderate growth in the second half .
It showed spending rose only 0.2 percent last month to a seasonally adjusted annual rate of $ 5.15 trillion after dropping a revised 0.4 percent in June .
Incomes from wages , salaries and all other sources gained 0.1 percent to a rate of $ 6.47 trillion after a 0.9 percent jump in June .
July 's slight gain in incomes was the weakest in six months , since January when they were flat .
Economist Joel Naroff of First Union bank in Philadelphia said consumer spending , which fuels two-thirds of the nation 's economy , may be much slower in the third quarter than in the first half , which should slow economic growth .
" The FOMC ( Federal Open Market Committee ) has been forecasting a slowing in economic activity and moderating household demand will have a large impact on overall economic growth , " Naroff said in a written comment .
The policy-making FOMC is to meet on Sept .
24 to plot interest-rate strategy .
It already has adopted a bias toward raising rates to keep a lid on wage and price rises and help sustain the 5-1 / 2-year-old economic expansion .
In an interview on the cable television network CNBC Friday , Federal Reserve Governor Lawrence Lindsey said there still were " mixed signals " about the economy 's direction .
" I think that , on balance , it is looking a little bit on the strong side , " Lindsey said .
He added that with expansion as solid as it is and with unemployment so low " the greater risks are clearly that we might see some overheating . "
While July consumer spending rose only slightly , there were ample indications that consumers remained confident .
The University of Michigan 's August index of consumer sentiment , made available on Friday to paying subscribers , rose to 95.3 from 94.7 in July .
Reaser said strong consumer confidence coupled with relatively lean inventories were providing manufacturers with a reason to gear up production .
" The economy is not going to be expanding at the 4.8 percent ( annual ) rate that we had in the second quarter but it is likely to keep expanding in the 3 percent range , " she said , above the 2 percent to 2-1/4 percent that the Fed considers to be non-inflationary .
New orders to factories were strong for durable goods like new cars and for nondurables like paper and food products .
Orders for durable goods , meant to last three years or more , rose a revised 1.7 percent in July after falling 0.2 percent in June .
Orders for nondurables jumped 1.8 percent following a 1.2 percent decrease in June .
Mexican avocados not expected in U.S .
Maggie McNeil
WASHINGTON 1996-08-30
U.S. Agriculture Department officials said Friday that Mexican avocados -- which are restricted from entering the continental United States -- will not likely be entering U.S. markets any time soon , even if the controversial ban were lifted today .
" The opportunity to import ( Mexican avocados ) probably wo n't become possible for another year , " said Paul Drazek , senior trade advisor to Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman .
" We could lift the ban tomorrow , but that would not mean anything immediately , " said Drazek . "
We probably would not see avacados come in until next season , next November . "
The Agriculture Department proposed more than a year ago to significantly ease an 82-year ban on Mexican avocados .
Under the administration 's proposal , the borders to the Mexican produce would be opened into 19 Northern and Northeastern states from November through February .
The plan has raised a storm of protest from U.S. avocado growers , who are largely concentrated in California .
California growers have charged that removing the restrictions , even on a limited basis , would endanger the $ 1 billion U.S. industry if potentially harmful Mexican insects were brought into the country along with the avocados .
Mexican officials contend that there is no scientific basis for the ban , and that it is illegal under international trading rules of the World Trade Organisation .
Proponents of the plan discount the worries of the U.S. growers and say the plan has enough safeguards built into it to eliminate any significant threat to American producers .
Under the proposal , only imports of export-quality avocados growing in approved orchards in Michoacan , Mexico , the country 's main avocado area , would be allowed .
Mexican growers and distributors would have to abide by strict rules established by the Mexican and U.S. agriculture agencies .
The California Avocado Commission -- which has spearheaded the opposition to lifting the ban -- said new data the group submitted to the Agriculture Department last spring shows the department underestimated the pest problem in Mexico and have urged that the agency reopen its study of the issue .
The administration is still studying the new data , and officials have said that if experts think the information is significant , the agency could reopen its investigation .
But U.S. avocado industry sources said that while they may have delayed the plan for a while , they ultimately do not expect the administration to change its position .
" From a common-sense view , the department should reconsider this plan , but due to politics they will probably go ahead with this , " said Tom Bellamore of the California avocado group .
Administration officials said they want to get the issue resolved as quickly as possible , but said there is no timetable they are working under .
" It 's a very complicated issue , " said the Agriculture Department 's Drazek . "
We 'll get it resolved as quickly as we can , based on the best available science . "
U.S. Cardinal Bernardin says has terminal cancer .
CHICAGO 1996-08-30
Chicago Cardinal Joseph Bernardin , head of the second-largest U.S. Roman Catholic archdiocese , said on Friday his doctors had diagnosed him as having liver cancer and he had a year or less to live .
Bernardin , 68 , underwent extensive surgery for pancreatic cancer in June 1995 followed by months of chemotherapy , which he said made him more aware of his own vulnerabilities and the need to minister to the sick .
" On Wednesday , examinations indicated that the cancer has returned , this time in the liver .
I am told that it is terminal and that my life expectancy is one year or less , " a composed Bernardin told a news conference .
In 14 years as Chicago 's archbishop , he built a prayerful , saintly image and was deeply involved in world church issues and publicly committed to rooting out abuses by clergy .
" I have been assured that I still have some quality time left , " he said , saying he would undergo a new form of chemotherapy but his doctors have told him there was only a slim chance of a cure and the liver cancer was inoperable .
" It 's not going to be easy to say goodbye to everybody .
Death does have some sad dimensions to it but I am a man of faith , " he said . "
Death is a natural phenomenom . "
He said he would " serve until the end " as cardinal .
Pancreatic cancer is among the most deadly forms of the disease , although Bernardin 's case was caught early .
Surgeons removed a cancerous kidney , parts of his pancreas and stomach , small intestine , bile duct and surrounding tissues .
He made a rapid recovery and resumed most of his duties , but then developed a deteriorating condition in his spine that caused him great pain and shortened his height by several inches .
He was scheduled to undergo back surgery next month , but that was cancelled when the cancer was discovered in his liver in order to avoid delaying the start of chemotherapy .
The spare , soft-spoken son of an Italian stonecutter took over the Chicago archdiocese , the nation 's second-largest after Los Angeles , with 2.3 million parishioners , in 1982 .
Ironically , Bernardin , who developed a progressive , much-praised programme to deal with pedophilia involving priests , became the highest-ranking church official ever accused of sexual improprieties when a former seminary student leveled charges in 1993 that he had been sexually abused by Bernardin during the 1970s .
Bernardin steadfastly denied the charges and the former student later recanted his tale of abuse .
Bernardin prayed with him before he died from AIDS last year .
Bernardin , who became archbishop of Cincinnati in 1972 , played an increasingly prominent role in the U.S. church as a moderate voice of compromise among liberals and conservatives in the ranks of the bishops .
This month , he announced that he would oversee a series of conferences to find " common ground " among American Catholics .
Previously , he was instrumental in drafting church policy on war , peace and nuclear arms , and for seven years he headed the bishops ' anti-abortion policy committee , espousing a policy describing human life as a " seamless garment . "
Boatmen 's deal could spark more mergers .
Brad Dorfman
CHICAGO 1996-08-30
The $ 9.5 billion proposed acquisition of Boatmen 's Bancshares Inc. by NationsBank Corp. could spark a flurry of other mergers involving Missouri banks , which until last year were protected from outside buyers by state regulations .
" NationsBank just strolled into the Midwest and bagged the biggest banking trophy in the landscape , " said Michael Ancell , banking industry analyst at Edward D. Jones & Co . "
Whoever wants a big market position in the Midwest has to come in and grab Mercantile or Commerce . "
St. Louis-based Mercantile Bancorp Inc. , a bank holding company with $ 18.04 billion in assets , was seen by many analysts as the most attractive Missouri franchise in size after Boatmen 's .
Kansas City , Mo.-based Commerce Bancshares Inc. , with $ 9.32 billion in assets , also could help a regional bank establish a strong presence in the lower Midwest , analysts added .
" It focuses more attention on Mercantile , Commerce and Roosevelt , " said James Weber , analyst at A.G. Edwards & Sons .
Roosevelt Financial Group Inc is a $ 9.33 billion asset-St .
Louis based thrift .
" Now ... the most coveted bank out there is Mercantile , " Weber said .
Mercantile and Commerce did not return phone calls seeking comment .
Among those seen as having an interest in buying in Missouri are Minneapolis-based First Bank System Inc. and Norwest Corp. , Ohio-based KeyCorp and Banc One Corp. , and First Chicago NBD Corp. in Illinois .
Representatives of First Bank , Norwest , Banc One and First Chicago said the banks do not comment on rumors of possible mergers or acquisitions .
KeyCorp , contacted by phone , would not comment .
With a presence in nine states and $ 41 billion in assets ,
Boatmen 's was the prize in Missouri , where barriers to outside acquirers were brought down last year by a federal banking statute .
" Boatmen 's was the plum of Missouri and was the plum of the central Midwest , " Weber said .
Talk that the Missouri banks were seeking inflated prices from buyers was seen as a reason a deal has not occurred sooner .
But NationsBank 's bid , representing a premium of 40 percent for Boatmen 's stock , was large enough to get the deal done .
" I think Boatmen 's was shopping itself , and everybody knew if you wanted to be the winning buyer here , you had to make the bid nobody would beat , " Ancell said .
But some analysts cautioned that other targets should not expect as large a premium .
They also questioned whether NationsBank can recoup shareholder value with such a large bid for Boatmen 's .
" I think initially some stocks will trade up on sympathy , but the wild premium NationsBank put on this deal here , I do n't see a lot of other deals being done at this premium , " said Michael Durante , analyst at McDonald & Co .
U.S. tight-lipped on Libya 's award to Farrakhan .
WASHINGTON 1996-08-30
The State Department refused to speculate on Friday on what might happen in the case of Louis Farrakhan , the U.S. black leader who was awarded a $ 250,000 human rights prize by Libya .
" I 'm not going to speculate about what may or may not happen in that case , " State Department spokesman Glyn Davies said . "
... The view of the U.S. government on ( Farrakhan 's ) not accepting any gifts from Libya is well-known . "
Davies also noted : " We 've talked about the passport restriction for travel to Libya " but he did not elaborate .
The U.S. Treasury Department on Wednesday denied Farrakhan 's application to receive the $ 250,000 award or a $ 1 billion donation Libyan leader Muammar Gaddafi had pledged to Farrakhan 's Nation of Islam group after they met last January .
Farrakhan organised last October 's Million Man March that brought thousands of black men to Washington for a peaceful rally .
The Treasury Department said Libya was on the U.S. list of states that sponsor international terrorism and noted that Tripoli has refused to hand over two Libyan suspects in the 1988 bombing of Pan Am flight 103 over Lockerbie , Scotland .
That refusal led to the imposition of U.N. sanctions on Libya .
U.S. Gulf rig down by one to 162 in week .
NEW YORK 1996-08-30
There were 162 rigs under contract in the U.S. Gulf as of August 30 , down one from the prior week , Offshore Data Services said .
The utilization rate for rigs working in the Gulf , based on a total fleet of 181 , was 89.5 percent .
The number of working rigs in European / Mediterranean remained unchanged this week , with 105 rigs under contract out of a total fleet of 105 , a utilization rate of 100 percent .
The worldwide rig count fell by one to 554 out of a total fleet of 608 , making the utilization rate 91.1 percent .
-- New York Energy Desk 212-859-1620
Dole team seeking to pin down debate details .
IRVINE , Calif 1996-08-30
Now that the party conventions are over , Republicans have signalled they are ready to move into the next phase of the campaign and meet with President Clinton 's aides to hammer out details of presidential debates .
The Dole campaign released a letter Friday inviting their Clinton counterparts to meet with Dole campaign manager Scott Reed to discuss particulars of the televised debates .
" Next week , a small group of representatives from each of our campaigns should meet to address participants , format , timing and logistical issues surrounding the debates , " Dole campaign manager Scott Reed wrote to Clinton campaign manager Peter Knight .
Tentative dates for the debates are Sept .
25 , Oct. 9 and Oct. 16 .
The vice presidential debate is scheduled for Oct. 2 .
Former South Carolina Gov .
Carroll Campbell , who was on Dole 's vice presidential short list before Dole decided on Jack Kemp , will head Dole 's team .
A decision is expected by mid-September on whether Texas billionaire Ross Perot , the Reform Party candidate , will be allowed to participate in the debates , which are sponsored by the Commission on Presidential Debates , a non-profit , non-partisan organisation that took over the forums in 1988 from the League of Women Voters .
Titanic recovery mission is scrapped .
NEW YORK 1996-08-30
Equipment problems and mechanical failure forced a recovery expedition to give up efforts to retrieve a giant slab of the RMS Titanic from the ocean floor , a spokeswoman said on Friday .
A 20-ton piece of the Titanic 's steel hull , which had been attached by cables to a recovery ship off the coast of Newfoundland , Canada , fell back to the bottom of the sea , said Erin Purcell of Boston-based Reagan Communications that represents two of the ships used in the expedition .
The piece of hull , lifted from the ocean floor by means of several diesel-filled bags , had been stuck about 200 feet ( about 70 metres ) below the water 's surface before it fell , she said .
It fell as recovery crews were trying to haul the piece into more shallow water and several of the bags burst and cables snapped , she said .
The steel-hulled Titanic , thought to be unsinkable , struck an iceberg on April 14 , 1912 , and sank , killing 1,523 of the 2,200 passengers and crew on board .
The wreck was located in 1985 .
Passengers who had paid $ 1,500 and up to accompany the recovery expedition on two cruise ships had returned back to port on Thursday , Purcell said .
Bonn appeals for Middle East peace .
BONN 1996-08-30
The German government urged Israelis and Palestinians on Friday to avoid any course of action that might jeopardise the peace process in the Middle East .
Israel announced this week the expansion of Jewish West Bank settlements surrounding Jerusalem and the demolition of an Arab community centre in East Jerusalem .
City officials there said the centre was being erected illegally .
But Palestinian President Yasser Arafat said the moves by Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu 's government were tantamount to war .
Tension has been rising in the region since .
" We believe that the Israeli settlement policy in the occupied areas is an obstacle to the establishment of peace , " German Foreign Ministry spokesman Martin Erdmann said .
" All concerned must avoid taking any course of action that could pose an obstacle to the peace process and which could make a peaceful solution difficult , " he said , as news came of a renewed breakdown in Arab-Israeli peace talks in Jerusalem .
Erdmann told reporters Bonn supported European Union efforts to persuade Israel to stop further Jewish settlement on the West Bank .
The foreign ministry later announced Israeli Foreign Minister David Levy would visit Bonn for talks with his German counterpart Klaus Kinkel next month .
The ministry said Levy and Kinkel would discuss the Middle East process and German-Israeli relations at their meeting on September 9 .
Levy 's visit would be the first by an Israeli cabinet minister since Netanyahu 's conservative government took power in une this year , the ministry said .
Before Levy 's arrival in Bonn , German Defence Minister Volker Ruehe will visit Israel from September 2 to 4 , the defence ministry said .
Ruehe planned to meet his Israeli counterpart Yitzhak Mordechai and Israeli President Ezer Weizman , the ministry said .
He was also expected to meet Prime Minister Netanyahu and opposition leader Shimon Peres for talks .
France expels African , Air France unions protest .
PARIS 1996-08-30
France on Friday expelled another African man seized in a police raid on a Paris church as about 100 Air France workers denounced " charters of shame " used to fly illegal immigrants home .
A Guinean man , detained in a round-up in the Saint-Bernard church a week ago , was deported on a scheduled Air France flight to Conakry after his appeals failed , a spokesman for Air France 's pro-Socialist CFDT union said .
He was apparently the eighth African deported from among 210 people evicted from the church after a 50-day occupation aimed at securing residence permits , unions said .
Most of the others have been released after a brief stay in detention .
About 100 people from the CFDT and the Communist-led CGT unions marched outside Air France headquarters at Charles de Gaulle airport north of Paris against the use of civilian jets and staff in deporting illegal immigrants .
" We must obtain a formal commitment from ( Air France chairman ) Christian Blanc that no plane , no personnel be used to transform our air companies into charters of shame , " CFDT spokesman Francois Cabrera said .
He said civilians should not be police accomplices .
Twenty-three out of 25 charters flying illegal immigrants home since Prime Minister Alain Juppe 's government took office in May 1995 have been civilian jets .
The other two were military jets .
Separately , Juppe confirmed the conservative government was preparing to submit a draft bill to parliament to tighten laws on illegal workers as part of a crackdown on immigration .
" Legislation is insufficient in several areas , notably in those concerning illegal work , " Juppe told reporters .
German police probe sex link in child kidnap case .
BERLIN 1996-08-30
German police searching for a missing 10-year-old schoolgirl said on Friday the prime suspects in the case may have been involved in running a child prostitution ring .
Police suspect Nicole Nichterwitz 's aunt and a male companion abducted the girl and took her to the Netherlands .
She was last seen being collected by the pair from school in Velten near Berlin on Monday .
Public prosecutors said they had found a list of children 's names and ages at the couple 's flat .
The list was being studied for possible links to previous child kidnappings and prostitution , a prosecutors ' spokesman told Reuters .
Missing German girl found alive at Dutch campsite .
GRONINGEN , Netherlands 1996-08-30
Dutch police said on Friday they had found missing German girl Nicole Nichterwitz alive on a campsite in the northern city of Groningen and had arrested her aunt and companion on charges of kidnapping .
" We have found Nicole on a campsite in Groningen thanks to tipoffs from the Dutch public .
We have also found and arrested her aunt and companion , " said a spokeswoman of the Dutch criminal investigation service .
Police could not yet tell whether the 10-year-old showed any signs of sexual abuse .
" We do n't know yet .
It 's too early to tell , " she said .
The girl was abducted from her school in Velten near Berlin on Monday .
German police suspected her aunt , 47 , and companion , 28 , were involved in running a child prostitution ring .
Public prosecutors said they had found a list of children 's names and ages at the couple 's flat .
The list was being studied for possible links to previous child kidnappings and prostitution , a prosecutors ' spokesman said .
The couple would probably be extradited to Germany which has requested their deportation , the Dutch police spokeswoman said .
Descriptions of the couple 's car released to Dutch media led to their arrest , she added .
Indian copper falls , state firm may cut rates .
BOMBAY 1996-08-30
Indian copper prices fell on Friday as dealers awaited an announcement relating to price cuts by state-owned producer , Hindustan Copper Ltd , traders said .
Nickel extended gains while other base metals were unchanged in narrow trade , they said .
Ready copper fell by 150 rupees at 12,350 rupees per quintal on fresh offerings by the stockists who expect Hindustan Copper to cut prices .
Nickel rose by 500 to 39,200 rupees on thin supply and fresh buying by stainless steel makers .
Tin was unchanged at 36,000 rupees , so did zinc at 6,300 rupees and lead at 4,900 rupees .
Aluminium was quiet at 7,450 rupees .
-- Bombay Commodities +91-22-265 9000
MARTELA H1 PROFIT FIM 6.3 MLN VS 21.0 MLN .
HELSINKI 1996-08-30
Six months to June 30 ,
( million markka unless stated )
Profit before extraordinaries , appropriations ,
taxes 6.3 vs 21.0
Earnings per share ( markka ) 2.2 vs 7.2
Net sales 289.1 vs 256.9
Canadian bonds open softer , spreads to U.S. shrink .
TORONTO 1996-08-30
Canadian bonds opened softer on Friday , pulled lower by a sinking U.S. market , but outperformed U.S. bonds on positive Canadian economic data , analysts said .
" I think this morning 's Canadian numbers were very supportive of narrower spreads , particularly the current account number , " said Jim Webber , director of fixed-income research with TD Securities Inc .
Canada 's 8.0 percent bond due 2023 fell C$ 0.45 to C$ 101.15 to yield 7.894 percent .
The U.S. 30-year benchmark fell 30/32 to yield 7.12 percent .
The spread between benchmark bonds narrowed 77 basis points from 81 basis points at the close of trading on Wednesday .
Statistics Canada on Friday reported Canada 's current account moved to a higher-than-expected C$ 1.15 billion second quarter surplus from a C$ 1.62 billion deficit in the first quarter .
It was the first surplus since the fourth quarter of 1984 .
The agency also reported Canada 's real gross domestic product rose a weaker-than-expected 0.3 percent in the second quarter or 1.3 percent at an annualized rate .
While the data provided support for Canadian bonds , both Canadian and U.S. markets weakened after the release of strong U.S. economic data , including a report showing the Chicago Purchasing Managers August index rose to 60 from 51.2 in July .
" The purchasing managers ' number is extremely , extremely strong , " said Webber .
In other news , the Toronto Bond Traders ' Association said it is recommending that dealings in the Canadian bond market end early at 1400 EDT / 1800 GMT on Friday .
The Canadian market typically closes early on holiday weekends and Canadian financial markets will be closed on Monday for Labour Day .
In other prices , the 7.0 percent of 2006 fell C$ 0.28 to C$ 96.89 to yield 7.437 percent .
The U.S. 10-year benchmark fell 21/32 to yield 6.95 percent .
The spread between the two bonds narrowed to 49 basis points from 54 basis points at the close of trading on Thursday .
The three-month cash bill traded at 4.04 percent against the U.S. three-month bill at 5.26 percent .
-- Jeffrey Hodgson ( 416 ) 941-8105 , e-mail : jeffrey.hodgson@reuters.com
Aw Computer Systems Inc Q2 loss widens .
NEW YORK 1996-08-30
1996 1995
Shr loss $ 0.22 loss $ 0.07
Net loss 1,071 loss 277
Revs 130 1,279
Avg shrs 4,841 3,990
First Half
Shr loss $ 0.42 loss $ 0.21
Net loss 1,967 loss 841
Revs 476 2,253
Avg shrs 4,666 3,944
( All Data Above 000s Except Per Share Numbers )
-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610 .
IPO FILING -- Homegate Hospitality Inc .
WASHINGTON 1996-08-30
Company Name Homegate Hospitality Inc
Nasdaq Stock symbol HMGT
Estimated price range N / A
Total shares to be offered N / A
Shrs offered by company N / A
Shrs outstanding after ipo N / A
Lead Underwriter Bear Stearns & Co Inc
Underwriters over-allotment N / A
Business : Company 's goal is to become a national provider of high quality extended-stay hotels in strategically selected markets located throughout the United States .
Use of Proceeds : To finance the development of additional extended-stay hotels and other general corporate purposes .
Financial Data in 000s : 1995 1994
- Revenue N / A N / A
- Net Income N / A N / A
Syria slams Israel on settlements .
DAMASCUS 1996-08-30
Syria on Friday condemned Israel 's settlement policy and said Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu was preparing for war with Arabs .
" Practices of the Israeli government , especially its settlement activities , came to confirm that dealing with this government inflicts the biggest harm on the Arab cause , " state-run Damascus Radio said in a commentary .
" When this government insists on stabbing the peace process and tearing it apart , this means that it is preparing for war , " the radio said .
Palestinian President Yasser Arafat described this week the decision to expand settlements in the West Bank as a declaration of war .
Palestinians in the West Bank and Gaza observed a strike on Thursday to protest against the Israeli move .
The radio urged Arabs to unify their ranks to thwart the policies of the right-wing Israeli government .
" Israel could not confront a united Arab stand or usurp their rights because the Arab rights could be regained when they achieve unity and solidarity , " Damascus radio said .
It welcomed the international criticism of Israel 's settlement policies but called for practical steps to force the Israeli government to abandon this policy .
" It is important to translate the criticism into pressuring action to prevent Israel from undermining the big international efforts aimed at making the peace process achieve success , " the radio said .
Syria and Arabs have been dismayed by Netanyahu 's refusal to trade the occupied Arab lands for peace , his support for the expansion of settlements and his insistance on Jerusalem as a unifed capital for Israel .
Syria has held sporadic peace talks with Israel since 1991 without achieving a breakthrough .
Egypt police detain 26 suspected Moslem militants .
CAIRO 1996-08-30
Police have detained 26 suspected members of Egypt 's largest militant group al-Gama'a al-Islamiya ( Islamic Group ) , government newspapers reported on Friday .
They said police arrested the militants in the eastern Sharqiyah province after capturing their leader Rami al-Saadani in a satellite city outside Cairo .
Al-Akhbar newspapers said the men had been plotting against " strategic institutions and prominent individuals " but gave no other details .
The newspapers said the men were being interrogated .
State security officials were not immediately available for comment .
More than 960 people have been killed in the armed struggle the Gama'a launched in 1992 to topple President Hosni Mubarak 's government and establish a purist Islamic state in its place
Israel blocks Palestinian pilgrims ' progress .
Sami Aboudi
AL-RAM , West Bank 1996-08-30
Kamil Jamil did n't have a prayer .
An Israeli roadblock stopped the 38-year-old Palestinian from answering Yasser Arafat 's call to worship at Jerusalem 's al-Aqsa mosque on Friday .
" Go home .
There are no prayers today , " an Israeli soldier yelled at Jamil in Hebrew .
Palestinian President Arafat , attacking Israel 's decision to expand Jewish settlements and its policy on Jerusalem , went before the Palestinian legislature on Wednesday to urge the two million Arabs in the West Bank and Gaza to go to the holy city .
Pilgrims stood little chance of making progress .
Palestinians have been banned by Israel from travelling from the West Bank to Jerusalem since suicide bombings by Moslem militants killed 59 people in the Jewish state in February and March .
And Israeli checkpoints have circled Jerusalem since 1993 , a concrete and constant reminder of Israel 's hold on a city it considers its eternal capital .
The PLO wants Arab East Jerusalem as the capital of a future Palestinian state .
Only a few Palestinians trickled to the roadblocks .
They were immediately turned back .
" I am heeding Abu Ammar 's ( Arafat 's ) call to pray at al-Aqsa and I came .
It is our duty towards al-Aqsa to come and pray , " Jamil said .
A tourist from Jordan was also told by Israeli soldiers at the al-Ram checkpoint that he could not enter Jerusalem .
" We have a peace treaty with them and we let them go wherever they want when they come to Jordan , " said the tourist , Khaled Hijazi , 37 . "
I feel terrible .
I am entitled to see Jerusalem , " he said .
Some Palestinians took to back roads , only to run into waiting Israeli security forces .
" The Israelis have no right to prevent us from going to pray .
What kind of peace is this that prevents us from reaching our holy places ? "
asked Mustafa Hoshiyeh , a 27-year-old West Bank labourer turned around by a police patrol on a back road .
" Abu Ammar ( Arafat ) is right .
We have signed a peace treaty with the Israelis but on the ground , we see that nothing has changed , " said 20-year-old Ali Ahmed from Qalandia refugee camp .
PRESALE - Bay Co Bldg Auth , Mich ..
AMT : 1,200,000 DATE : 09/05/96 NYC Time : 1600 CUSIP : 072261
ISSUER : Bay Co Building Authority ST : MI
ISSUE : Bldg auth ( law enforcement ctr ) Series 1996-A TAX STAT : Exempt-REV
M / SP / F : NA / NA / NA BOOK ENTRY : N
ENHANCEMENTS : None BANK QUAL : Y
DTD : 09/01/96 SURE BID : Y
DUE : 11/1/96-11 SR MGR :
1ST CPN : 11/01/96
CALL : 11/1/05 @ 101 , dtp 11/1/07 NIC
DELIVERY : 45 days approx ORDERS :
PAYING AGENT : Michigan National Bank , Detroit
L.O. : Bodman , Longely & Dahling , Detroit
F.A. : First of Michigan Corp. , Detroit
LAST SALE : None
Year Amount Coupon Yield Price Conc .
1996 45,000
1997 50,000
1998 55,000
1999 55,000
2000 60,000
2001 65,000
2002 70,000
2003 70,000
2004 75,000
2005 80,000
2006 85,000
2007 90,000
2008 90,000
2009 95,000
2010 105,000
2011 110,000
COMPETITIVE PRE-SALE CONTRIBUTED BY J.J. KENNY K-SHEETS :
Consumer spending , incomes edge up in July .
Glenn Somerville
WASHINGTON 1996-08-30
Consumer spending barely edged up in July , the Commerce Department said Friday , as income growth slowed abruptly to the weakest pace in six months .
Spending rose 0.2 percent to a seasonally adjusted annual rate of $ 5.15 trillion after dropping a revised 0.4 percent in June .
Incomes from wages , salaries and all other sources gained 0.1 percent to a rate of $ 6.47 trillion after a 0.9 percent jump in June .
Department officials said July 's slight gain in incomes was the weakest for any month since January , when they were flat .
Wages and salaries came under pressure in July as a shorter average workweek and lower hourly earnings cut into paychecks .
The department said wages and salaries decreased by $ 6.9 billion in July after climbing $ 45 billion in June .
" In July , average weekly hours and average hourly earnings declined , more than offsetting the effect of an increase in employment , " Commerce said .
But more money went into savings accounts , as savings held at 5.3 cents out of each dollar earned in both June and July .
That was the highest savings rate since October last year , when 5.5 cents out of each dollar earned was being saved .
The generally lackluster report on spending and incomes in July had been expected .
At the same time , the department said in a separate report that new orders received by U.S. factories climbed strongly in July , with widespread gains across most major categories .
Orders increased 1.8 percent to a seasonally adjusted $ 317.6 billion , significantly stronger than the 1 percent rise forecast by Wall Street economists .
That followed a revised 0.7 percent decline in June orders .
Commerce said previously that spending at retail stores was up only 0.1 percent in July , partly because of softer sales of new cars and light trucks .
In addition , the Labour Department 's July employment report had foreshadowed the muted income growth .
It showed average hourly earnings fell in July by 0.2 percent to $ 11.00 and the average workweek shortened to 34.3 hours from 34.7 in June .
Gains in personal income , which includes wages and salaries as well as income from sources such as dividends , interest and businesses , are essential for funding consumer purchases , which fuel two-thirds of national economic activity .
Spending on all types of durable goods , which includes cars , fell to an annual rate of $ 626.3 billion in July from $ 633.6 billion in June .
But spending on nondurable products increased moderately to a rate of $ 1.55 trillion from $ 1.54 trillion in June , while spending for services was up to $ 2.97 trillion in July from $ 2.96 trillion .
Payrolls of manufacturing companies rose in July by $ 2.3 billion to an annual rate of $ 678 billion .
World Markets Overnight Summary - Aug 30 .
NEW YORK 1996-08-29
WORLD MARKETS ROUND-UP
STOCKS GOLD METALS
NY Dow close London opening LME close
5647.65 ( - 64.73 ) $ 387.70 copper per tonne
Nikkei latest CRUDE OIL $ 1987.0
20202.87 ( - 350.29 ) Sept Brent zinc per tonne
FTSE close $ 21.25 $ 1000.0
3885.0 ( - 33.7 )
----- oOo-----
STOCKS SINK AS BOND RATES JUMP ON STRONG DATA
Blue-chip stocks sank to their biggest loss since mid-July Thursday as fresh signs of a surprisingly strong economy boosted long-term bond interest rates above 7 percent .
The dollar rose slightly against the German mark , but edged lower against the Japanese yen .
The Dow Jones industrial average ended down 64.73 points at 5,647.65 , its largest drop since July 15 , when it closed with a loss of 161 points .
In the broader market , declining issues beat advances 1,627 to 743 on moderate volume of 321 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange .
In the bond market , the 30-year Treasury bond fell 23/32 of a point , or $ 7.1875 on a $ 1,000 bond , raising its yield to 7.04 percent -- the highest since July 31 -- from 6.98 percent at Wednesday 's close .
" Seven percent creates psychological problems and a legitimate competitor for money from equities , " said Ralph Bloch , chief technical analyst at Raymond James .
" We could carry another 100 points lower in the Dow , " he said . "
I 'm telling clients things are dicey going into next Friday ( Sept .
6 ) so let 's be careful . "
Wall Street on Sept .
6 faces the key monthly employment report , which has been known to cause dramatic swings in stock prices .
" We had two very strong economic reports , " said David Shulman , Salomon Bros . '
chief equity strategist . "
There are more worries in bond land .
Fears of a Fed tightening next month have resurfaced for the first time since the end of July . "
The Commerce Department reported that the nation 's gross domestic product expanded at a 4.8 percent annual rate in the three months from April through June instead of the 4.2 percent estimated a month ago .
In another report , sales of new homes jumped unexpectedly in July to the briskest rate in five months , driving prices up in a strong housing market .
Sales shot up 7.9 percent last month to a seasonally adjusted annual rate of 783,000 units -- the strongest since February , when new homes were selling at a rate of 784,000 a year .
Analysts said the stock market was also worried about the impact on President Clinton 's re-election bid of his top political strategist resigning .
Dick Morris , who is credited with resurrecting Clinton 's political fortunes over the past 18 months by masterminding his turn to the political centre , quit after a supermarket tabloid reported he engaged in a yearlong affair with a prostitute , with whom he allegedly shared confidential campaign documents .
Analysts said Wall Street had grown accustomed to a moderate Republican in the form of Democratic President Clinton .
Morris ' departure raised fears that Clinton would veer more to the left in a second term .
The dollar closed at 1.4772 marks , up from 1.4767 late Wednesday .
The dollar slipped to 108.40 yen from 108.45 .
Oil markets rose sharply on a combination of low stocks , two hurricanes and allegations of illicit trading by Iraq .
September heating oil on the New York Mercantile Exchange closed 1.63 cents higher at 63.67 cents a gallon , September unleaded gasoline finished 1.39 cents up at 63.72 cents a gallon and October crude rose 44 cents to $ 22.15 a barrel .
December cotton closed 0.95 cent higher at 77.06 cents per pound on the New York Cotton Exchange despite some easing of concern about the twin hurricane threat to key U.S. growing areas with forecasts indicating both storms may remain offshore .
Overseas , London 's FTSE 100 index had earlier climbed to 3,8921.1 just below its record of 3,922.1 , before edging down through the afternoon session to finish the day at 3,885.0 , a fall of 33.7 points .
In Tokyo , the key 225-share Nikkei average shed 156.65 points , or 0.76 percent , to end at 20,553.16 .
Pirelli cables look to tap Chinese growth .
David Jones
MILAN 1996-08-30
Italian tyre and cables giant Pirelli on Friday announced its long-awaited move into China with a cables joint venture set to capitalise on the rapidly-growing Chinese telecommunications market .
Pirelli is linking with Hong Kong-based group CITIC Pacific in a venture to be called the Wuxi Tong Ling Company Ltd , which will operate in partnership with a local industrial company at its existing factory in Wuxi , Jiangsu province , Shanghai .
The partners will invest around $ 30 million in the existing copper cable plant at Wuxi to update technology and include optic fibre production , with annual turnover expected to reach $ 60 million within the next few years .
The move marks a further move by Pirelli 's cables division to expand in the fast-growing Far Eastern developing markets with the group already present in Indonesia , India and Malaysia .
" This is really positive news for Pirelli , and I expect that it will produce one of the best half-year results in late September compared to other industrial Italian companies , " said analyst Paula Buratti at Indosuez .
She emphasised that the move was positive because Pirelli will have management control of the Chinese venture , and it also showed another example of Pirelli exporting its technical know-how to developing markets .
Pirelli shares reacted favourable even though talks had been underway for some time and news about a venture had been widely expected .
The shares rose 0.2 percent to 2,555 lire by 1350 GMT in an easier Milan stock market .
This will be Pirelli 's first industrial involvement in a Chinese market where demand for telecommunication networks is expected to grow to 80-100 million new lines between 1996 and 2000 , doubling demand for optical cables .
China 's second largest telecoms operator Unicom already has a mandate from the central government to establish 15 million new phone lines by the year 2000 , which will necessitate new trunk line systems and local distribution networks .
" The starting of this production base in China has for our group an undoubted strategic value , representing an important enhancement of our presence in Asia , " said Pirelli SpA chairman and chief executive officer Marco Tonchetti Provera .
Pirelli Cables has global sales of over $ 3.5 billion , and has become a large supplier of optic cables and systems to major telecoms carriers in the U.S. , Europe and the Far East .
CITIC Pacific is a major Hong Kong-listed company focusing on infrastruture , trading , distribution and property , with 28 percent of its 1995 profits coming from telecoms .
It has investments in several industrial joint ventures in China .
Dutch bond futures revival delayed - EOE .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-30
A broad attempt to spur activity in Dutch bond futures has been delayed to give participants a chance to become familiar with the trading system , the European Options Exchange ( EOE ) said on Friday .
Market-making in the rarely-traded FTO contract was expected to begin today , but an EOE spokesman said the 10 banks and brokers involved in the initiative needed time to get accustomed to changes in the electronic trading system .
" It 's not ready yet .
We found it wise to take some time between the commitment to start and the actual start , " EOE spokesman Lex van Drooge told Reuters .
He said no date had been fixed yet for the start of price making in the 10-year contract , but the EOE had agreed to speak again to the participants in one to two weeks .
Investors in Dutch bonds currently use German bond futures to hedge their portfolios because the FTO contract is so illiquid .
A limited attempt to reinvigorate the contract two years ago failed .
-- Amsterdam newsroom +31 20 504 5000 , Fax +31 20 504 5040
OSCE defends record over Chechnya peace mission .
BONN 1996-08-30
The head of an international mediating mission defended its record on Friday in the face of criticism by pro-Moscow leaders in breakway Chechnya and insisted it was doing its best to bring peace to the region .
Flavio Cotti , the chairman of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe ( OSCE ) , told German radio the Vienna-based body viewed the conflict in Chechnya as an internal Russian problem .
" The OSCE is completely involved .
But one must not forget that the OSCE only has limited powers there , " said Cotti , who is also the Swiss foreign minister . "
Our mission in Chechnya has done all it can within the given limitations . "
Pro-Moscow leaders in Chechnya have criticised Tim Guldimann , the Swiss diplomat who heads the OSCE Chechnya mission , saying he was biased toward Zelimkhan Yandarbiyev , president of the self-declared separatist government .
Russian peacemaker Alexander Lebed and Chechen separatist military leader Aslan Maskhadov started a new round of peace talks on Friday just outside the rebel region .
Cotti said Chechnya must remain part of Russia , but the solution to the conflict would be to accord the region maximum autonomy within Russia 's borders .
" There is no doubt that Chechnya , according to OSCE principles , belongs to a state called Russia , " he said , pointing out that Russia was an OSCE member and it was not the organisation 's policy to challenge members ' sovereignty .
He added that the OSCE was the only international body which has been allowed into the Chechnya to monitor the human rights situation there , but that its means were restricted by the fact that the conflict was a " internal issue " .
" We have a small concept , the details of which have yet to be worked out .
Chechnya must be accorded the maximum autonomy possible within the framework of Russian integrity , " said Cotti .
Dutch say no reason to reopen El Al carqo enquiry .
THE HAGUE 1996-08-30
The Dutch transport minister Annemarie Jorritsma told the country ' second chamber that there is no further need to investigate the 1992 crash of an El Al freighter which left 43 dead in an Amsterdam suburb .
She said that a request from her ministry for the aircraft 's waybill documentation and further information about the contents of its hold had been complied with by El Al 's head office in Tel Aviv .
The Dutch transport ministry had come in for pressure from a cross-section of Dutch members of parliaments in May this year , some of whom believed the aircraft had been carrying unlisted , dangerous goods .
Others said they thought the aircraft was loaded with too much airfreight .
Jorritsma said the latest evidence from El Al in no way supported the allegations , and added there is no justification for a further investigation into the incident .
-- Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 8982 Fax +44 171 542 5017
Armenians , Azeris hold peace talks in Germany .
BONN 1996-08-30
Representatives from Armenia and Azerbaijan held talks earlier this week in Germany on bringing a lasting peace to the disputed Nagorno-Karabakh region , a diplomatic source close to the talks said on Friday .
The source , who spoke on condition of anonymity , said Azerbaijani presidential adviser Vafa Gulizade and his Armenian counterpart Zhirayr Liparityan met to discuss the disputed enclave on Wednesday and had now flown home .
An uneasy ceasefire has prevailed in Nagorno-Karabakh , which represents around 20 percent of Azeri territory , since May 1994 after ethnic Armenians drove Azeris out of the region .
The conflict , which began in 1988 , claimed over 10,000 lives .
" The main subject ( of the talks ) was the search for a peaceful solution for Nagorno-Karabakh , " the source said .
He declined to reveal any more details about the content of the talks or their exact location in Germany .
Azerbaijan has said it is prepared to grant autonomy to Nagorno-Karabakh if Armenian forces pull out , but will not accept Armenia 's demands for the independence of the enclave .
Russia 's Interfax news agency reported on Tuesday the officials had departed for negotiations in Germany , adding that face-to-face talks between the two sides first took place last December in Amsterdam .
Interfax said the discussions were being held in parallel with peace talks mediated by the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe ( OSCE ) and the broad-based Minsk Group of countries led by Russia and Finland .
Sombre mood on Arctic island after plane crash .
Rolf Soderlind
LONGYEAR , Norway 1996-08-30
The windblown , chilly streets of this tiny Arctic town are all but deserted and flags are flying at half-mast beneath a brooding , clouded sky .
Longyear is a town in mourning , a close-knit community that has been shattered .
Disaster struck on Thursday when a Russian airliner bringing coal miners to work crashed as it came in to land at the airport , killing all 141 people on board .
" It 's a sight I will never forget .
I will remember it for the rest of my life , " said Stig Onarheim .
He was one of a handful of rescuers who raced to the scene of the crash in a helicopter on Thursday , hoping in vain to find survivors .
The plane smashed into a snow-capped mountain on the Arctic island of Spitzbergen on Thursday , just east of Longyear .
" Imagine a big plane with a lot of luggage and people on board .
Think of all that mixed together , with twisted , wrecked parts on the slope , " Onarheim , 29 , told Reuters .
Police and local officials have sealed off the crash site , protecting it from intrusive reporters and from the polar bears that roam freely across the icy expanses .
The dead were all Russians and Ukrainians , coming to work in the mining towns of Barentsburg and Pyramiden .
Longyear is a Norwegian settlement of just over 1,000 people , but it also feels the loss keenly .
" I have trouble finding the words to express my grief .
It 's a tragedy for everyone .
We know many of the people who live in Barentsburg , some of them could have been on the plane , " said Johan Sletten , 52 .
Sletten , a caretaker who has lived on the island for 30 years , said the Norwegian and Russian communities visit frequently , competing at soccer in the summer and with snow-scooter races in the winter .
Teenage shop assistant Heidi Groenstein was blunter .
" I 'm glad it was not a Norwegian plane , " she said . "
Just think of it -- a mining village where so many workers die .
They must be having a tough time of it now . "
Barentsburg , just a few hours ride by snow-scooter or 15 minutes by helicopter from Longyear , has asked to be left alone with its grief and told reporters to stay away .
Around 100 Russian and Ukrainian miners were waiting in Longyear to fly home on the plane that crashed .
They were given shelter in the town 's church overnight and ate a sombre breakfast before getting on a bus for the airport .
Another plane had been sent from Moscow to pick them up .
At this time of year , the only colour in Longyear comes from the brightly-painted wooden houses .
Everything else is muddy , the waters of the fjord leaden .
Winter is in the air .
Barentsburg is an even grimmer place , a run-down testament to the hardships of the new Russia .
Spitzbergen lies some 500 miles ( 800 km ) off the northern tip of Norway and endures one of the most extreme climates on the planet .
Inhabited by fewer than 3,000 people in total , it sees the sun for 24 hours a day during summer and is plunged into round-the-clock darkness in the winter months .
The terrain is mountainous , the only roads are dirt tracks .
Norway rules the island group under the terms of a 1920s international treaty which gave many other nations the right to establish setttlements and exploit the coal that is still mined there .
Only Russia has chosen to do so .
Ericsson says wins 1.2 bln SKR China order .
STOCKHOLM 1996-08-30
Swedish telecoms group LM Ericsson AB said on Friday it won an order worth 1.2 billion crowns for a fixed public telecoms network in the Guangdong province of China .
Ericsson said in a statement the order was from the Guangdong Post and Telecommunications Administration ( GPTA ) .
The order included AXE switching equipment , ISDN equipment , Intelligent Network ( IN ) products , broad-band multi-media communication network products , services and training , Ericsson spokesman Per Zetterquist told Reuters .
Deliveries are due to be completed by 1999 , the company said .
-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1017
HK has infrastructure in place for post-97 - Tsang .
AUCKLAND 1996-08-30
Hong Kong Financial Secretary Donald Tsang said on Friday that the territory had the " infrastructural hardware " to make a success of its future under Chinese sovereignty from mid-1997 .
" We have the largest and most efficient port on the South China coast ; we have the best transport and telecommunications infrastructure in the world ; and we are investing in this hardware on an enormous scale , " Tsang said in a speech to Auckland during a visit to New Zealand .
Hong Kong also had the necessary " constitutional infrastructure " in place , with the promise of autonomy in running its affairs after the handover from Britain to China .
" What this means in practice is that Hong Kong will go on raising its own taxes , issuing its own currency , setting its own expenditure priorities and managing its own enormous financial reserves , " Tsang said .
He acknowledged that many Hong Kong people had decided to seek their future elsewhere and others were sure to follow in the next nine months . "
But for the great majority of us , Hong Kong is our home and Hong Kong 's future is our future . "
-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746
PRESS DIGEST - Indonesian newspapers - August 30 .
Following is a summary of major Indonesian political and business stories in leading newspapers , prepared by Reuters in Jakarta .
Reuters has not checked the stories and does not guarantee their accuracy .
Telephone : ( 6221 ) 384-6364 .
Fax : ( 6221 ) 344-8404 .
- - - -
KOMPAS
Indonesian President Suharto has asked businessmen to share their experiences with each other in an effort to boost the country 's exports .
- - - -
JAKARTA POST
Speaker of the House of Representatives Wahono has called on those serving in high state institutions to direct their efforts in the coming years towards dismantling all barriers to social justice .
An agreement to bring peace to the southern Philippines is set to be initialed on Friday after delegates from the Philippine government and the Moro National Liberation Front ( MNLF ) concluded negotiations on the treaty which is set to end almost 25 years of conflict in the region .
- - - -
MEDIA INDONESIA
Around 2,000 of Indonesia 's controversial Timor national car made by Kia Motor Corp of South Korea arrived at Jakarta 's Tanjung Priok port on Thursday .
The cars will be jointly marketed by Kia and PT Timor Putra Nasional , controlled by a son of President Suharto , which plans next year to start assembling the vehicles in Indonesia .
- - - -
REPUBLIKA
The Central Jakarta District Court has started to hear the suit filed by ousted Indonesian Democratic Party ( PDI ) leader Megawati Sukarnoputri against the government and party rivals after the parties failed to reach an out-of-court settlement .
Megawati has sued the defendants over a government-backed rebel congress which ousted her last June .
Jeans Mate Corp - 6mth parent forecast .
TOKYO 1996-08-30
Six months to August 20 , 1996
( in billions of yen unless specified )
LATEST PREVIOUS ACTUAL
( Parent ) FORECAST FORECAST YEAR-AGO
Sales 9.06 9.31 8.42
Current 818 million 979 million 882 million
Net 415 million 490 million 412 million
NOTE - Jeans Mate Corp is the full company name .
Apic Yamada - 6mth parent forecast .
TOKYO 1996-08-30
Six months to September 30 , 1996
( in billions of yen unless specified )
LATEST PREVIOUS ACTUAL
( Parent ) FORECAST FORECAST YEAR-AGO
Sales 12.50 13.00 11.27
Current 1.30 1.35 1.09
Net 650 million 680 million 600 million
NOTE - Apic Yamada Corp is a leading manufacturer of semiconductor leadframes .
Bootleg brew kills 35 in China , police nab suspects .
BEIJING 1996-08-30
Police in southwest China have arrested 30 people suspected of making and selling homemade alcohol that killed 35 people and poisoned 157 , the Xinhua news agency said on Friday .
A group of farmers in Huize county in the southwestern province of Yunnan were arrested for blending alcohol with methanol and selling the toxic liquor to local residents , the agency said .
Between late June and July , a total of 192 people were poisoned by the toxic liquor , and 35 of them died and six were left severely handicapped , it said .
Local authorities launched an investigation after they received reports of several similar deaths in the area , it said .
Post-mortem examinations showed they were all caused by methanol poisoning .
Police had confiscated the remainder of the poisonous liquor , Xinhua said .
It gave no further details .
Singapore hangs Thai drug trafficker .
SINGAPORE 1996-08-30
Singapore hanged a Thai farmer at Changi Prison on Friday for drug trafficking , the Central Narcotics Bureau ( CNB ) said .
Jeerasak Densakul , 24 , was arrested in 1995 when he was found with 11 slabs of cannabis weighing 2.2 kg ( 4.8 pounds ) , the CNB said .
Singapore has a mandatory death sentence for anyone over 18 years of age found guilty of trafficking in more than 15 grams ( half an ounce ) of heroin , 30 grams ( an ounce ) of morphine or 500 grams ( 18 oz ) of cannabis or marijuana .
Of the nearly 270 people hanged for various crimes in Singapore since 1975 , almost half have been for drug-related charges .
Arafat goes to Nablus ahead of cabinet meeting .
NABLUS , West Bank 1996-08-30
Palestinian President Yasser Arafat arrived in the West Bank self-rule enclave of Nablus from Ramallah on Friday , witnesses said .
His aides said Arafat would hold the weekly meeting of the Palestinian self-rule Authority 's cabinet in Nablus on Saturday .
In Jerusalem , Israeli security forces were bracing for thousands of Palestinians expected to answer Arafat 's call earlier this week to come to the city holy to Moslems , Arabs and Jews to pray in protest against Israel 's settlement policy in the West Bank and delay in peace negotiations .
Palestinians want Arab East Jerusalem as the capital of a future independent state .
Israel , which captured and annexed East Jerusalem in 1967 , says it will never cede any part of the city .
Arafat , who made an interim peace deal with Israel in 1993 that set up self-rule , says he will only visit Jerusalem once Israeli occupation has ended .
U.N. Council concerned about Israeli bulldozers .
UNITED NATIONS 1996-08-29
Security Council members expressed concern on Thursday that Israel 's bulldozing of a Palestinian day-care centre for the disabled might further injure the Middle East peace process .
Responding to a letter from the the Palestinian U.N. observer mission , Security Council President Tono Eitel of Germany said that members asked him to convey their views to Israel 's charge d'affaires , David Peleg .
" The members expressed their concern about the maintenance of the peace process and they urged that no action be taken that would have a negative impact on the negotiations , " Eitel said after an informal council session .
" They asked me to call in the Israeli charge d'affaires and discuss the matter with him , " he added .
The Palestinian letter from Marwan Jilani said the destruction of the Jerusalem centre was an effort by Israel to " alter the character , demographic composition and status of the Holy City of Jerusalem " and violated agreements between Israel and the Palestinian Liberation Organisation .
" This most recent measure represents a revival of old , malicious plans to confiscate the land and build units for Israeli settlers within the walls of the Old City . "
" We expect the international community to take a clear and firm position , based on international law and in accordance with U.N. resolutions , against all such Israeli violations and illegal practices , " he said .
On Tuesday , Israeli crews hoisted a bulldozer over the walls of Jerusalem 's old city and demolished the centre , saying it was being restored without a building permit .
Canada had recently donated $ 30 million to the centre , called the Burj al-Laqlaq Society .
SOCCER - REAL SCRAPE 1-1 DRAW IN SCRAPPY OPENING MATCH .
LA CORUNA , Spain 1996-08-31
A late goal by newly-signed defender Roberto Carlos saved the blushes of Real Madrid coach Fabio Capello and his multi-billion peseta line-up in the opening game of the Spanish championship on Saturday .
The Brazilian 's 79th-minute effort was enough to earn Real a point from a scrappy 1-1 draw at fellow title contenders Deportivo Coruna .
Deportivo started strongly , taking the lead midway through the first half when former Auxerre playmaker Corentine Martins headed home a corner after a flick-on by Brazilian-born Spanish international midfielder Donato .
Real looked to be in deep trouble shortly after the break when Luis Milla was sent off for committing two bookable offences in as many minutes .
But Deportivo were unable to capitalise on their numerical advantage , and were themselves reduced to ten men when Armando Alvarez was sent off 15 minutes from time .
Shortly afterwards Roberto Carlos found space in the home defence and equalised for Real with a shot that was deflected past despairing Deportivo ' keeper Jacques Songo'o .
In a frantic final five minutes there were chances at both ends , and Donato , who had earlier been booked , was sent off for protesting about the incursion of Real players at a free kick .
Before the match Deportivo chairman Augusto Lendoiro said he would ignore a FIFA decision banning Brazilian midfielder Mauro Silva from playing in the match for failing to join his national side 's tour of Europe .
In the event , coach John Toshack decided not to use Silva , who had claimed he did not join the Brazil squad because he had lost his passport .
RUGBY LEAGUE - WIGAN BEAT BRADFORD 42-36 IN SEMIFINAL .
WIGAN , England 1996-08-31
Result of English rugby league premiership semifinal played on Saturday :
Wigan 42 Bradford Bulls 36
SOCCER - ISRAEL BEAT BULGARIA IN EUROPEAN UNDER-21 QUALIFIER .
HERZLIYA , Israel 1996-08-31
Result of European under-21 championship group 5 qualifier on Saturday :
Israel 2 , Bulgaria 0 ( halftime 0-0 ) Scorers : Haim Hajaj ( 47th ) , Nir Sivilia ( 57th ) .
Attendance : 2,000 .
SOCCER - IRISH ERASE PAINFUL MEMORIES WITH 5-0 WIN .
ESCHEN , Liechtenstein 1996-08-31
The Republic of Ireland 's new-look side dispelled painful memories of their last visit to Liechtenstein by beating the Alpine part-timers 5-0 in a World Cup qualifier on Saturday .
The Irish , under new manager Mick McCarthy , took a 4-0 lead within 20 minutes through captain Andy Townsend , 20-year-old Norwich striker Keith O'Neill , Sunderland forward Niall Quinn and teenager Ian Harte .
Quinn added his second and Ireland 's fifth just after the hour to complete the rout and give the Irish their biggest-ever away win .
The result helped erase memories of Ireland 's visit to the Eschen stadium 14 months ago , when Jack Charlton 's side were held to a frustrating 0-0 draw which ultimately cost them a place in the European championship finals .
SOCCER - IRELAND BEAT LIECHTENSTEIN 5-0 IN WORLD CUP QUALIFIER .
ESCHEN 1996-08-31
The Republic of Ireland beat Liechtenstein 5-0 ( halftime 4-0 ) in a World Cup soccer European group 8 qualifier on Saturday .
Scorers : Andy Townsend ( 5th ) , Keith O'Neill ( 7th ) , Niall Quinn ( 11th , 61st ) , Ian Harte ( 19th ) .
Attendance : 3,900
GOLF - BRITISH MASTERS FINAL SCORES .
NORTHAMPTON , England 1996-08-31
Leading scores after the final round of the British Masters golf tournament on Saturday ( British unless stated ) :
284 Robert Allenby ( Australia ) 69 71 71 73 , Miguel Angel Martin ( Spain ) 75 70 71 68 ( Allenby won at first play-off hole )
285 Costantino Rocca ( Italy ) 71 73 72 69
286 Miguel Angel Jimenez ( Spain ) 74 72 73 67
287 Ian Woosnam 70 76 71 70
288 Jose Coceres ( Argentina ) 69 78 71 70
289 Joakim Haeggman ( Sweden ) 71 77 70 71 , Antoine Lebouc ( France ) 74 73 70 72
290 Colin Montgomerie 68 76 77 69 , Robert Coles 74 76 71 69 , Philip Walton ( Ireland ) 71 74 74 71 , Peter Mitchell 74 71 74 71 , Klas Eriksson ( Sweden ) 71 75 72 72 , Pedro Linhart ( Spain ) 72 73 67 78
291 Phillip Price 72 76 74 69 , Adam Hunter 70 79 73 69 , Peter O'Malley ( Australia ) 71 73 75 72 , Mark Roe 69 71 78 73 , Mike Clayton ( Australia ) 69 76 73 73
292 Iain Pyman 71 75 75 71 , David Gilford 69 74 77 72 , Peter Hedblom ( Sweden ) 70 75 75 72 , Stephen McAllister 73 76 69 74 .
SOCCER - SLOVAKIA BEAT FAROES IN WORLD CUP QUALIFIER .
TOFTIR , Faroe Islands 1996-08-31
Slovakia beat the Faroe Islands 2-1 ( halftime 1-0 ) in their World Cup soccer European group six qualifying match on Saturday .
Scorers :
Faroe Islands - Jan Allan Mueller ( 60th minute )
Slovakia - Lubomir Moravcik ( 13th ) , Peter Dubovsky ( 88th )
Attendance : 1,445 .
CRICKET - ENGLAND BEAT PAKISTAN BY 107 RUNS IN SECOND ONE-DAYER .
BIRMINGHAM , England 1996-08-31
England beat Pakistan by 107 runs in the second one-day international at Edgbaston on Saturday to take the series 2-0 .
Scores : England 292-8 innings closed ( N. Knight 113 ) , Pakistan 185 ( Ijaz Ahmed 79 ; A. Hollioake 4-23 )
CYCLING - TOUR OF NETHERLANDS FINAL RESULTS / STANDINGS .
LANDGRAAF , Netherlands 1996-08-31
Leading results of
the 205-km sixth and final stage of the Tour of the Netherlands
between Roermond and Landgraaf on Saturday :
1. Olaf Ludwig ( Germany ) Telekom 4 hours 48 mins 2 seconds
2. Giovanni Lombardi ( Italy ) Polti 5 seconds behind
3. Tristan Hoffman ( Netherlands ) TVM same time
4. Erik Breukink ( Netherlands ) Rabobank 8 seconds
5. Jesper Skibby ( Denmark ) TVM 9
6. Vyacheslav Ekimov ( Russia ) Rabobank same time
7. Luca Pavanello ( Italy ) Aki 11
8. Eleuterio Anguita ( Spain ) MX Onda
9. Michael Andersson ( Sweden ) Telekom
10. Johan Capiot ( Belgium ) Collstrop all same time
Final overall placings ( after six stages ) :
1. Rolf Sorensen ( Denmark ) Rabobank 20:36:54
2. Lance Armstrong ( U.S. ) Motorola 2 seconds behind
3. Ekimov 1:7
4. Marco Lietti ( Italy ) MG-Technogym 1:16
5. Erik Dekker ( Netherlands ) Rabobank 1:23
6. Ludwig 1:25
6. Breukink same time
8. Maarten den Bakker ( Netherlands ) TVM 1:33
9. Andersson 1:34
10. Skibby 1:45
CRICKET - ENGLAND V PAKISTAN ONE-DAY SCOREBOARD .
BIRMINGHAM , England 1996-08-31
Scoreboard of the second one-day cricket match between England and Pakistan on Saturday :
England
N. Knight st Moin Khan b Saqlain Mushtaq 113
A. Stewart b Mushtaq Ahmed 46
M. Atherton lbw b Mushtaq Ahmed 1
G. Thorpe lbw b Ata-ur-Rehman 21
M. Maynard run out 1
R. Irani not out 45
A. Hollioake run out 15
D. Gough run out 0
R. Croft b Waqar Younis 15
D. Headley not out 3
Extras ( lb-25 w-4 nb-3 ) 32
Total ( for 8 wickets , innings closed ) 292
Fall : 1-103 2-105 3-163 4-168 5-221 6-257 7-257 8-286 .
Did Not Bat : A. Mullally .
Bowling : Wasim Akram 10-0-50-0 , Waqar Younis 9-0-54-1 ,
Ata-ur-Rehman 6-0-40-1 , Saqlain Mushtaq 10-0-59-1 , Mushtaq Ahmed
10-0-33-2 , Aamir Sohail 5-0-31-0 .
pakistan
Saeed Anwar c Stewart b Gough 33
Aamir Sohail c Croft b Gough 0
Moin Khan lbw b Mullally 0
Ijaz Ahmed b Croft 79
Inzamam-ul-Haq c Thorpe b Croft 6
Salim Malik c Stewart b Hollioake 23
Wasim Akram c Knight b Hollioake 21
Mushtaq Ahmed not out 14
Saqlain Mushtaq b Hollioake 0
Waqar Younis lbw b Gough 4
Ata-ur-Rehman c Knight b Hollioake 2
Extras ( lb-2 nb-1 ) 3
Total ( 37.5 overs ) 185
Fall of wickets : 1-1 2-6 3-54 4-104 5-137 6-164 7-164 8-168
9-177 .
Bowling : Gough 8-0-39-3 , Mullally 6-0-30-1 , Headley
7-0-32-0 , Irani 2-0-22-0 , Croft 8-0-37-2 , Hollioake 6.5-1-23-4 .
CYCLING - WORLD TRACK CHAMPIONSHIP RESULTS .
MANCHESTER , England 1996-08-31
Results at the world
track cycling championships on Saturday :
Women 's 3,000 metres individual pursuit qualifying round
( fastest eight to quarter finals ) :
1. Antonella Bellutti ( Italy ) 3:31.526 ( world record )
2. Marion Clignet ( France ) 3:31.674
3. Lucy Tyler-Sharman ( Australia ) 3:31.830
4. Yvonne McGregor ( Britain ) 3:41.823
5. Natalia Karimova ( Russia ) 3:45.061
6. Svetlana Samokhalova ( Russia ) 3:46.216
7 Jane Quigley ( U.S. ) 3:46.493
8. Rasa Mazeikyte ( Lithuania ) 3:46.834
9. Tatian Stiajkina ( Ukraine ) 3:52.204
World 4,000 metres team pursuit semifinals :
Italy ( Adler Capelli , Cristiano Citto , Andrea Collinelli , Mauro Trentino ) 4:00.958 ( world record ) beat Russia ( Anton Chantyr , Edouard Gritsoun , Nikolai Kouznetsov ) 4:06.534 .
France ( Cyril Bos , Philippe Ermenault , Jean-Michel Monin , Francis Moreau ) 4:05.104 beat Germany ( Guido Fulst , Danilo Hondo , Thorsten Rund , Heiko Szonn ) 4:05.463
Germany take the bronze medal as fastest losing semifinalist .
Women 's world 500 metres time trial final :
1. Felicia Ballanger ( France ) 34.829
2. Annett Neumann ( Germany ) 35.202
3. Michelle Ferris ( Australia ) 35.694
4. Magali Faure ( France ) 35.888
5. Olga Slioussareva ( Russia ) 36.170
6. Oksana Grichina ( Russia ) 36.242
7. Tanya Dubnicoff ( Canada ) 36.307
8. Kathrin Freitag ( Germany ) 36.491
9. Donna Wynd ( New Zealand ) 36.831
10. Mira Kasslin ( Finland ) 37.273
11. Wendy Everson ( Britain ) 37.624
12. Giovanna Troldi ( Italy ) 38.285
13. Rita Razmaite ( Lithuania ) 38.546
World 4,000 metres team pursuit championship final :
Italy ( Adler Capelli , Cristiano Citto , Andrea Collinelli , Mauro Trentino ) 4:02.752 beat France ( Cyril Bos , Philippe Ermenault , Jean-Michel Monin , Francis Moreau ) 4:04.539
World sprint championship quarter finals ( best of three
matches )
Florian Rousseau ( France ) beat Ainars Kiksis ( Latvia ) 2-0
Darryn Hill ( Australia ) beat Christian Arrue ( U.S. ) 2-0
Roberto Chiappa ( Italy ) beat Frederic Magne ( France ) 2-0
Marty Nothstein ( U.S. ) beat Pavel Buran ( Czech Republic ) 2-0
Women 's world 3,000 metres individual pursuit championship
quarter-finals :
Marion Clignet ( France ) 3:30.974 ( World Record ) beat Jane
Quigley ( USA ) 3:42.852
Natalia Karimova ( Russia ) 3:40.036 beat Yvonne McGregor
( Britain ) 3:43.078
Lucy Tyler-Sharman ( Australia ) 3:35.087 beat Svetlana
Samokhvalova ( Russia ) 3:45.011
Antonella Bellutti ( Italy ) 3:32.174 caught and eliminated Rasa
Mazeikyte ( Lithuania )
CRICKET - PAKISTAN WIN TOSS , PUT ENGLAND IN TO BAT .
BIRMINGHAM , England 1996-08-31
Pakistan won the toss and put England in to bat in the second limited overs cricket international at Edgbaston on Saturday .
Surrey all-rounder Adam Hollioake was making his England debut , replacing Lancashire batsman Graham Lloyd , with seamer Peter Martin again being omitted from the 13 .
Pakistan kept the side who lost to England by five wickets at Old Trafford on Thursday in the first of the three one-day matches .
Teams :
England : Mike Atherton ( captain ) , Nick Knight , Alec Stewart , Graham Thorpe , Matthew Maynard , Adam Hollioake , Ronnie Irani , Robert Croft , Darren Gough , Dean Headley , Alan Mullally .
Pakistan : Aamir Sohail , Saeed Anwar , Ijaz Ahmed , Salim Malik , Inzamam-ul-Haq , Wasim Akram ( captain ) , Moin Khan , Saqlain Mushtaq , Mushtaq Ahmed , Waqar Younis , Ata-ur-Rehman .
BASEBALL - GONZALEZ HOMERS TWICE AS RANGERS BEAT INDIANS .
ARLINGTON , Texas 1996-08-31
Juan Gonzalez homered twice and Ivan Rodriguez added a two-run shot as the Texas Rangers defeated the Cleveland Indians 5-3 in a matchup of division leaders Friday .
Rodriguez 's 18th homer , off Chad Ogea ( 7-5 ) in the first , gave Texas a 2-0 lead .
One out later , Gonzalez smacked his 40th homer , extending his hitting streak to 20 games .
Gonzalez , who hit in 21 straight games earlier this season , joined Mickey Rivers as the only players in Texas history with two 20-game streaks in the same year .
Gonzalez hit his second homer in the third for his fifth multi-homer game of the season .
Gonzalez has three 40-homer seasons and his 121 RBI broke Ruben Sierra 's team record of 119 set in 1989 .
The Indians had their four-game winning streak stopped .
" It 's not something I 'm going to try to explain , " said Texas manager Johnny Oates about his team winning seven of the 10 meetings from Cleveland this season .
" We 've got two more regular season games against them and we might get lucky enough or unlucky enough to play them in the post-season . "
Roger Pavlik ( 15-7 ) gave up three runs and seven hits in 6 1/3 innings and became the fourth 15-game winner in the American League .
Jeff Russell pitched two perfect innings for his third save .
Brian Giles and Jim Thome homered for Cleveland .
Cleveland 's lead over the White Sox in the American League Central dropped to nine games .
Texas 's lead over Seattle in the West increased to six .
At California , Tino Martinez 's two-run homer keyed a three-run first and Andy Pettitte became the league 's first 19-game winner as the New York Yankees beat the Angels 6-2 .
New York snapped a season-high five-game losing streak and also got homers from Mariano Duncan , Darryl Strawberry and Jim Leyritz .
Pettite ( 19-7 ) allowed two runs and eight hits over eight innings with a walk and seven strikeouts .
He improved to 12-2 following Yankees ' losses .
Mariano Rivera pitched a scoreless ninth , striking out two .
Ex-Yankee Randy Velarde hit his 11th homer , his most at any professional level .
In Seattle , Pete Incaviglia 's grand slam with one out in the sixth snapped a tie and lifted the Baltimore Orioles past the Seattle Mariners , 5-2 .
It was Incaviglia 's sixth grand slam and 200th homer of his career .
Baltimore 's Eddie Murray cracked his 20th homer of the season and 499th of his career .
Jay Buhner hit his 38th homer and Edgar Martinez his 23rd for Seattle .
The Orioles remained tied with the White Sox for the American League wild card with the Mariners a game back .
In Toronto , Kevin Tapani ( 12-8 ) allowed two runs and six hits over 7 1/3 innings and Frank Thomas hit his 29th homer and drove in three runs as the Chicago White Sox cruised to an 11-2 victory over the Blue Jays .
Thomas , Harold Baines and Robin Ventura each collected three hits .
Baines homered and scored three runs .
Danny Tartabull added two hits and three RBI as all Chicago starters got at least one hit .
In Oakland , Dave Telgheder scattered seven hits over eight innings and Mark McGwire hit his major-league leading 45th homer and drove in three runs as the Athetlics blanked the Boston Red Sox 7-0 .
Telgheder ( 2-5 ) snapped a personal three-game losing streak .
Buddy Groom pitched a perfect ninth inning .
McGwire singled home a run to spark a three-run sixth and capped the scoring with a two-run homer in the seventh .
The loss was Boston 's seventh in its last 29 games .
In Detroit , Todd Van Poppel pitched a five-hitter for his first career shutout and Tony Clark homered to cap a four-run first inning as the Tigers blanked the Kansas City Royals 4-0 .
Van Poppel ( 3-6 ) walked two and struck out two in defeating the Royals for the second time this week .
He threw 108 pitches as he lowered his ERA from 8.08 to 7.24 .
Kansas City has scored only one run in two games .
In Milwaukee , Marc Newfield homered off Jose Parra ( 5-4 ) leading off the bottom of the 12th as the Brewers rallied for a 5-4 victory over the Minnesota Twins .
Milwaukee has won 10 of its last 15 .
Bob Wickman ( 6-1 ) pitched 2 2/3 hitless innings for the win , his second for the Brewers .
Matt Lawton hit a three-run homer off closer Mike Fetters with one out in the ninth to give Minnesota a 4-2 lead .
But Milwaukee tied it up in the bottom of the ninth on pinch-hitter Dave Nilsson 's two-run double .
CRICKET - ESSEX AND KENT MADE TO SWEAT IN TITLE RACE .
LONDON 1996-08-31
Essex and Kent both face tense finishes on Monday as they attempt to keep pace with title hopefuls Derbyshire and Surrey , convincing three-day victors on Saturday , in the English county championship run-in .
Essex need another 148 with five wickets in hand to beat Yorkshire after a maiden first-class century from Richard Kettleborough transformed a match which his side had seemed certain to lose .
Kent will also need to keep their nerve against struggling Nottinghamshire who will enter the final day 137 ahead with four wickets left in a relatively low-scoring match at Tunbridge Wells .
Derbyshire , nine-wicket winners over Worcestershire , and Surrey , who thrashed Warwickshire by an innings and 164 runs , can instead take the day off along with rivals Leicestershire , who beat Somerset inside two days .
Warwickshire captain Tim Munton is tipping Surrey to emerge on top , impressed by the positive influence of Australian coach Dave Gilbert , but Derbyshire 's Australian captain Dean Jones is conceding nothing as his side chase their first title for 60 years .
" We took three absolutely brilliant catches in this match and our catching all season has been pretty impressive .
Our catching will win or lose us the championship , " he said .
GOLF - LEADING MONEY WINNERS ON EUROPEAN TOUR .
LONDON 1996-08-31
Leading money winners on the
European Tour after the British Masters won by Robert Allenby on
Saturday ( British unless stated ) :
1. Ian Woosnam 510,258 pounds sterling
2. Colin Montgomerie 442,201
3. Robert Allenby ( Australia ) 407,748
4. Lee Westwood 301,972
5. Costantino Rocca ( Italy ) 297,157
6. Mark McNulty ( Zimbabwe ) 254,247
7. Andrew Coltart 248,142
8. Wayne Riley ( Australia ) 239,733
9. Raymond Russell 234,330
10. Paul Lawrie 211,420
11. Stephen Ames ( Trinidad ) 211,175
12. Frank Nobilo ( New Zealand ) 209,412
13. Paul McGinley ( Ireland ) 208,978
14. Padraig Harrington ( Ireland ) 202,593
15. Retief Goosen ( South Africa ) 195,283
16. Miguel Angel Jimenez ( Spain ) 184,180
17. Peter Mitchell 183,704
18. Miguel Angel Martin ( Spain ) 182,533
19. Jonathan Lomas 181,005
20. Paul Broadhurst 176,780
RUGBY UNION - ENGLISH , SCOTTISH AND WELSH RESULTS .
LONDON 1996-08-31
Results of English , Scottish and
Welsh rugby union matches on Saturday :
English National League one
Harlequins 75 Gloucester 19
London Irish 27 Bristol 28
Northampton 46 West Hartlepool 20
Orrell 13 Bath 56
Sale 31 Wasps 33
Saracens 25 Leicester 23
Welsh division one
Bridgend 13 Llanelli 9
Dunvant 21 Ebbw Vale 10
Treorchy 17 Newbridge 23
Newport 29 Caerphilly 10
Swansea 49 Cardiff 23
Scottish premier league division one
Boroughmuir 20 Hawick 23
Currie 45 Heriot 's F.P. 5
Jed-Forest 17 Watsonians 54
Melrose 107 Stirling County 10
SOCCER - WALES BEAT SAN MARINO IN WORLD CUP QUALIFIER .
CARDIFF 1996-08-31
Wales beat San Marino 6-0 ( halftime 4-0 ) in a World Cup soccer European group 7 qualifier on Saturday .
Scorers : Dean Saunders ( 2nd minute , 75th ) , Mark Hughes ( 25th , 54th ) , Andy Melville ( 33rd ) , John Robinson ( 45th ) .
Attendance : 15,150
SOCCER - UKRAINE BEAT NORTHERN IRELAND IN WORLD CUP QUALIFIER .
BELFAST 1996-08-31
Ukraine beat Northern Ireland 1-0 ( halftime 0-0 ) in a World Cup soccer European group nine qualifier on Saturday .
Scorer : Sergei Rebrov ( 79th minute )
Attendance : 9,358
RUGBY UNION - LYNAGH SEALS VICTORY OVER DWYER AND LEICESTER .
LONDON 1996-08-31
Former Wallaby captain Michael Lynagh began his career in English club rugby in impeccable fashion on Saturday to frustrate his old coach Bob Dwyer on his league coaching debut with Leicester .
Lynagh kicked five penalties and a conversion from his six attempts at goal to steer his multi-national Saracens side to a 25-23 home win and offer millionaire backer Nigel Wray an early return on his big investment in the north London club .
French centre Philippe Sella also enjoyed a good game alongside Lynagh , although the home team scored only one try through England scrum-half Kyran Bracken .
The new French connection at Harlequins also made a good start , Laurent Cabannes and Laurent Benezech scoring a try apiece in their side 's 75-19 victory over Gloucester .
Former England captain Will Carling , handed the kicking duties , finished with 20 points .
With the first day of the league season briefly shifting the spotlight away from the discord between the clubs and the Rugby Football Union , there were also emphatic victories for champions Bath , 56-13 winners over Orrell , and Northampton and narrow successes for Wasps and Bristol .
SOCCER - SCOTTISH LEAGUE STANDINGS .
LONDON 1996-08-31
Scottish league standings after
Saturday 's matches ( tabulated - played , won , drawn , lost , goals
for , goals against , points ) :
Division one
Greenock Morton 3 2 0 1 5 2 6
Dundee 3 1 2 0 3 2 5
St Johnstone 2 1 1 0 3 0 4
St Mirren 3 1 1 1 5 4 4
Airdrieonians 2 1 1 0 1 0 4
Falkirk 3 1 1 1 1 1 4
Clydebank 2 1 0 1 1 3 3
Partick 3 0 2 1 1 2 2
Stirling 3 0 1 2 1 3 1
East Fife 2 0 1 1 0 4 1
Division two
Livingston 3 3 0 0 6 2 9
Queen of South 3 2 0 1 5 4 6
Ayr 3 1 2 0 8 2 5
Stenhousemuir 3 1 1 1 6 1 4
Hamilton 3 1 1 1 3 2 4
Stranraer 3 1 1 1 3 3 4
Brechin 3 0 3 0 2 2 3
Clyde 3 1 0 2 2 5 3
Dumbarton 3 0 2 1 3 4 2
Berwick 3 0 0 3 1 14 0
Division three
Albion 3 3 0 0 5 0 9
Forfar 3 2 0 1 7 4 6
Cowdenbeath 3 2 0 1 4 3 6
Arbroath 3 1 2 0 4 2 5
Alloa 3 1 1 1 3 3 4
Queen 's Park 3 1 1 1 6 8 4
Montrose 3 1 0 2 3 4 3
Inverness Thistle 3 1 0 2 3 6 3
East Stirling 3 0 2 1 3 4 2
Ross County 3 0 0 3 3 7 0
SOCCER - ENGLISH LEAGUE STANDINGS .
LONDON 1996-08-31
English soccer league standings
after Saturday 's matches ( tabulated - played , won , drawn , lost ,
goals for , goals against , points ) :
Division one
Stoke 4 3 1 0 7 4 10
Barnsley 3 3 0 0 8 2 9
Norwich 4 3 0 1 5 3 9
Tranmere 4 2 1 1 6 4 7
Bolton 3 2 1 0 5 2 7
Queens Park Rangers 3 2 1 0 5 3 7
Wolverhampton 4 2 1 1 5 3 7
Swindon 4 2 1 1 5 4 7
Bradford 4 2 0 2 4 3 6
Portsmouth 4 2 0 2 4 5 6
Ipswich 4 1 2 1 9 7 5
Crystal Palace 4 1 2 1 4 3 5
Port Vale 4 1 2 1 4 4 5
Birmingham 2 1 1 0 5 4 4
Reading 4 1 1 2 5 10 4
Huddersfield 3 1 1 1 4 4 4
Oxford 4 1 0 3 6 5 3
Manchester City 3 1 0 2 2 3 3
West Bromwich 3 0 2 1 2 3 2
Oldham 4 0 1 3 5 9 1
Sheffield United 2 0 1 1 4 5 1
Grimsby 4 0 1 3 4 8 1
Southend 4 0 1 3 2 10 1
Charlton 2 0 1 1 1 3 1
Division two
Plymouth 4 3 1 0 10 6 10
Brentford 4 3 1 0 9 3 10
Bury 4 3 1 0 8 2 10
Chesterfield 4 3 0 1 4 2 9
Millwall 4 2 1 1 7 5 7
Shrewsbury 4 2 1 1 6 6 7
Blackpool 4 2 1 1 3 2 7
York 4 2 0 2 6 6 6
Burnley 4 2 0 2 6 7 6
Bournemouth 4 2 0 2 5 5 6
Watford 4 2 0 2 4 5 6
Bristol Rovers 3 1 2 0 2 1 5
Peterborough 3 1 1 1 4 4 4
Preston 4 1 1 2 4 5 4
Crewe 4 1 1 2 4 6 4
Gillingham 4 1 1 2 4 6 4
Notts County 3 1 1 1 2 2 4
Bristol City 4 1 0 3 7 8 3
Luton 4 1 0 3 4 10 3
Wycombe 4 0 3 1 2 3 3
Wrexham 2 0 2 0 5 5 2
Stockport 4 0 2 2 1 3 2
Rotherham 4 0 1 3 3 6 1
Walsall 3 0 1 2 2 4 1
Division three
Wigan 4 3 1 0 9 4 10
Fulham 4 3 0 1 5 3 9
Hull 4 2 2 0 4 2 8
Hartlepool 4 2 1 1 6 5 7
Torquay 4 2 1 1 5 3 7
Cardiff 4 2 1 1 3 2 7
Scunthorpe 4 2 1 1 3 3 7
Carlisle 4 2 1 1 2 1 7
Scarborough 4 1 3 0 5 3 6
Northampton 4 1 2 1 6 4 5
Lincoln 4 1 2 1 5 5 5
Barnet 4 1 2 1 4 2 5
Exeter 4 1 2 1 4 5 5
Cambridge United 4 1 2 1 3 4 5
Darlington 4 1 1 2 9 8 4
Chester 4 1 1 2 6 7 4
Doncaster 4 1 1 2 4 5 4
Leyton Orient 4 1 1 2 3 3 4
Brighton 4 1 1 2 3 6 4
Hereford 4 1 1 2 2 3 4
Swansea 4 1 0 3 4 9 3
Colchester 4 0 3 1 2 4 3
Rochdale 4 0 2 2 2 4 2
Mansfield 4 0 2 2 2 6 2
SOCCER - SCOTTISH LEAGUE RESULTS .
GLASGOW 1996-08-31
Results of Scottish league
matches on Saturday :
Division one
Greenock Morton 1 Falkirk 0
Partick 1 St Mirren 1
Stirling 1 Dundee 1
Postponed : East Fife v Clydebank , St Johnstone v
Airdrieonians .
Division two
Ayr 6 Berwick 0
Clyde 0 Queen of South 2
Dumbarton 1 Brechin 1
Livingston 1 Hamilton 0
Stenhousemuir 0 Stranraer 1
Division three
Albion 2 Cowdenbeath 0
Arbroath 0 East Stirling 0
Inverness Thistle 1 Alloa 0
Montrose 2 Ross County 1
Queen 's Park 1 Forfar 4
SOCCER - ENGLISH LEAGUE RESULTS .
LONDON 1996-08-31
Results of English soccer matches
on Saturday :
Division one
Bradford 1 Tranmere 0
Grimsby 0 Portsmouth 1
Huddersfield 1 Crystal Palace 1
Norwich 1 Wolverhampton 0
Oldham 3 Ipswich 3
Port Vale 2 Oxford 0
Reading 2 Stoke 2
Southend 1 Swindon 3
Postponed : Birmingham v Barnsley , Manchester City v Charlton
Playing Sunday : Queens Park Rangers v Bolton
Division two
Blackpool 0 Wycombe 0
Bournemouth 1 Peterborough 2
Bristol Rovers 1 Stockport 1
Bury 4 Bristol City 0
Crewe 0 Watford 2
Gillingham 0 Chesterfield 1
Luton 1 Rotherham 0
Millwall 2 Burnley 1
Notts County 0 York 1
Shrewsbury 0 Brentford3
Postponed : Walsall v Wrexham
Division three
Brighton 1 Scunthorpe 1
Cambridge United 0 Cardiff 2
Colchester 1 Hereford 1
Doncaster 3 Darlington 2
Fulham 1 Carlisle 0
Hull 0 Barnet 0
Leyton Orient 2 Hartlepool 0
Mansfield 0 Rochdale 0
Scarborough 1 Northampton 1
Torquay 2 Exeter 0
Wigan 4 Chester 2
CRICKET - ENGLISH COUNTY CHAMPIONSHIP SCORES .
LONDON 1996-08-31
Results and close scores of four-day English county championship matches on Saturday :
At Portsmouth : Middlesex beat Hampshire by 188 runs .
Middlesex 199 and 426 , Hampshire 232 and 205 ( A. Fraser 5-79 , P. Tufnell 4-39 ) .
Middlesex 20 points , Hampshire 5 .
At Chester-le-Street : Glamorgan beat Durham by 141 runs .
Glamorgan 259 and 207 , Durham 114 and 211 .
Glamorgan 22 points , Durham 4 .
At Chesterfield : Derbyshire beat Worcestershire by nine wickets .
Worcestershire 238 and 303 ( K. Spiring 130 not out , S. Rhodes 57 ; P. DeFreitas 4-70 ) , Derbyshire 471 and 71-1 .
Derbyshire 24 points , Worcestershire 5 .
At The Oval ( London ) : Surrey beat Warwickshire by an innings and 164 runs .
Warwickshire 195 and 109 ( J. Benjamin 4-17 , M. Bicknell 4-38 ) , Surrey 468 ( C. Lewis 94 , M. Butcher 70 , G. Kersey 63 , J. Ratcliffe 63 , D. Bicknell 55 ) .
Surrey 24 points , Warwickshire 2 .
At Headingley ( Leeds ) : Yorkshire 290 and 329 ( R. Kettleborough 108 , G. Hamilton 61 ; P. Such 8-118 ) , Essex 372 and 100-5 .
At Hove : Sussex 363 and 144 , Lancashire 218 and 53-0 .
At Tunbridge Wells : Nottinghamshire 214 and 167-6 ( C. Tolley 64 not out ) , Kent 244 ( C. Hooper 58 ; C. Tolley 4-68 , K. Evans 4-71 )
At Bristol : Gloucestershire 183 and 249 ( J. Russell 75 ) , Northamptonshire 190 and 218-9 .
MOTOR RACING - LEADING QUALIFIERS FOR VANCOUVER INDYCAR RACE .
VANCOUVER 1996-08-31
Top ten drivers in grid for
Sunday 's Vancouver IndyCar race after final qualifying on
Saturday ( tabulate by driver , country , chassis , motor and lap
times in seconds ) :
1. Alex Zanardi ( Italy ) , Reynard Honda , 53.980 ( 113.576
mph / 182.778 kph )
2. Michael Andretti ( U.S. ) , Lola Ford Cosworth , 54.483
3. Bobby Rahal ( U.S. ) , Reynard Mercedes-Benz , 54.507
4. Bryan Herta ( U.S. ) , Reynard Mercedes-Benz , 54.578
5. Jimmy Vasser ( U.S. ) , Reynard Honda , 54.617
6. Paul Tracy ( Canada ) , Penske Mercedes-Benz , 54.620
7. Al Unser Jr ( U.S. ) , Penske Mercedes-Benz , 54.683
8. Andre Ribeiro ( Brazil ) , Lola Honda , 54.750
9. Mauricio Gugelmin ( Brazil ) , Reynard Ford Cosworth , 54.762
10. Gil de Ferran ( Brazil ) , Reynard Honda , 54.774
SOCCER - CANADA BEAT PANAMA 3-1 IN WORLD CUP QUALIFIER .
EDMONTON 1996-08-31
Canada beat Panama 3-1 ( halftime 2-0 ) in their CONCACAF semifinal phase qualifying match for the 1998 World Cup on Friday .
Scorers :
Canada - Aunger ( 41st min , pen ) , Paul Peschisolido ( 42nd ) , Carlo Corrazin ( 87th )
Panama - Jorge Luis Dely Valdes ( 50th )
Attendance : 9,402
RUGBY UNION - SPRINGBOKS FINALLY BREAK ALL BLACK SPELL .
Andy Colquhoun
JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-31
South Africa managed to avoid a fifth successive defeat in 1996 at the hands of the All Blacks with an emphatic 32-22 victory in front of an ecstatic Ellis Park crowd on Saturday .
They scored three tries in recording their highest total against New Zealand , salvaging some pride in a season in which the world champions have lost five out of eight tests .
It also ended a run of nine successive victories this year for New Zealand but arrived too late to prevent a 2-1 series defeat and an historic first All Black series triumph on South African soil .
Springbok scrum-half Joost van der Westhuizen was his side 's inspiration , scoring their opening try and making the third for flanker Andre Venter from a quickly taken penalty to give his side a 29-8 lead after 54 minutes .
Fullback Andre Joubert scored the other , scorching in from 40 metres at the start of the second half to add to his three long-range penalties .
The All Blacks salvaged some pride by scoring two tries from centre Walter Little and scrum-half Justin Marshall in the final five minutes to close a gap which at one point stood at 24 points .
But they generally endured an off-day , highlighted by recalled fly-half Andrew Mehrtens who missed five out of eight kicks at goal .
Recalled fly-half Henry Honiball kicked the Springboks into a 6-0 lead after 10 minutes only to see Andrew Mehrtens launch a penalty from eight metres inside his own half to narrow the gap .
Mehrtens missed three further penalties and a conversion in the first 40 minutes which could have put his side ahead , but it was the Springboks who looked the more dangerous .
Their promise was realised when Joubert made a 40-metre break in the 25th minute and , although winger Pieter Hendriks appeared to knock on Joubert 's reverse pass , Welsh referee Derek Bevan allowed Van der Westhuizen to pick up and score under the posts .
Honiball converted and Joubert kicked a penalty before All Black hooker Sean Fitzpatrick scored a try from close range on the stroke of half-time to narrow the lead to 16-8 and hint at a comeback .
Instead Joubert kicked another long penalty and then raced around the outside of the defence to score the Springboks ' second try .
A quick penalty from Van der Westhuizen five metres from the All Black line set up the third try for Venter five minutes later and when Joubert kicked his third penalty the Springboks held an unassailable 32-8 lead going into the last quarter .
When the All Blacks did break through , it was too late .
Centre Walter Little followed up Mehrtens ' kick to score under the posts and scrum-half Justin Marshall forced himself over from a ruck close to the line in injury-time to give them some consolation .
South Africa - 15 - Andre Joubert , 14 - Justin Swart , 13 - Japie Mulder ( Joel Stransky , 48 mins ) 12 - Danie van Schalkwyk , 11 - Pieter Hendriks ; 10 - Henry Honiball , 9 - Joost van der Westhuizen ; 8 - Gary Teichmann ( captain ) , 7 - Andre Venter ( Wayne Fyvie , 75 ) , 6 - Ruben Kruge , 5 - Mark Andrews ( Fritz van Heerden , 39 ) , 4 - Kobus Wiese , 3 - Marius Hurter , 2 - James Dalton , 1 - Dawie Theron ( Garry Pagel , 66 ) .
New Zealand - 15 - Christian Cullen ( Alama Ieremia , 70 ) , 14 - Jeff Wilson , 13 - Walter Little , 12 - Frank Bunce , 11 - Glen Osborne ; 10 - Andrew Mehrtens , 9 - Justin Marshall ; 8 - Zinzan Brooke , 7 - Josh Kronfeld , 6 - Michael Jones ( Glenn Taylor , 53 ) , 5 - Robin Brooke , 4 - Ian Jones , 3 - Olo Brown , 2 - Sean Fitzpatrick ( captain ) , 1 - Craig Dowd .
RUGBY UNION - SOUTH AFRICA BEAT ALL BLACKS 32-22 .
JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-31
South Africa beat New Zealand 32-22 ( haltime 16-8 ) in the final test match of their three-test series at Ellis Park on Saturday .
Scorers :
South Africa - Tries : Joost van der Westhuizen ( 2 ) , Andre Joubert .
Conversion : Henry Honiball .
Penalties : Honiball ( 2 ) , Joubert ( 3 ) .
New Zealand - Tries : Sean Fitzpatrick , Walter Little , Justin Marshall .
Conversions : Andrew Mehrtens ( 2 ) .
Penalties : Mehrtens .
New Zealand win test series 2-1 .
SOCCER - MAURITANIA DISSOLVES NATIONAL TEAM AFTER CUP EXIT .
NOUAKCHOTT 1996-08-31
Mauritania 's soccer federation dissolved the national team and suspended this season 's domestic championship on Saturday in the wake of the country 's failure to qualify for the African Nations ' Cup .
" Since Mauritania has been eliminated on all fronts and the next commitments are not for another two years , we have reason to take a break , " federation president Mohamed Lemine Cheiguer said .
The North Africans were held to a goalless draw by Benin on Friday after losing the first leg of their qualifying tie 4-1 .
SOCCER - MAURITANIA DRAW WITH BENIN IN AFRICAN NATIONS CUP .
NOUAKCHOTT 1996-08-31
Mauritania drew 0-0 with Benin in their African Nations Cup preliminary round , second leg soccer match on Friday .
Benin won 4-1 on aggregate .
SOCCER - YUGOSLAV LEAGUE RESULTS / STANDINGS .
BELGRADE 1996-08-31
Results of Yugoslav league
soccer matches played on Saturday :
Division A
Hajduk 2 Proleter ( Z ) 0
Zemun 1 Rad ( B ) 0
Borac 1 Mladost ( L ) 2
Cukaricki 1 Vojvodina 0
Buducnost 1 Red Star 3
Partizan 6 Becej 0
Standings ( tabulate under won , drawn , lost , goals for , goals
against , points ) :
Red Star 4 4 0 0 9 3 12
Partizan 4 3 1 0 13 3 10
Mladost ( L ) 4 2 1 1 8 5 7
Vojvodina 4 2 1 1 5 3 7
Becej 4 2 1 1 5 7 7
Hajduk 4 2 0 2 5 3 6
Cukaricki 4 2 0 2 6 6 6
Zemun 4 1 2 1 3 3 5
Rad ( B ) 4 1 1 2 2 3 4
Buducnost 4 1 0 3 4 8 3
Proleter ( Z ) 4 0 1 3 2 9 1
Borac 4 0 0 4 1 10 0
Division B
Sloboda 4 Mladost ( BJ ) 0
Buducnost ( V ) 0 OFK Beograd 1
Rudar 0 OFK Kikinda 1
Obilic 2 Zeleznik ( B ) 0
Sutjeska 1 Loznica 0
Radnicki ( N ) - Spartak ( to be played on Sunday )
Standings :
Obilic 4 4 0 0 10 1 12
OFK Kikinda 4 3 0 1 8 3 9
Sutjeska 4 3 0 1 7 5 9
Loznica 4 2 0 2 7 4 6
OFK Beograd 4 1 3 0 5 4 6
Buducnost ( V ) 4 2 0 2 4 5 6
Sloboda 4 1 1 2 8 8 4
Spartak 3 1 1 1 3 3 4
Radnicki ( N ) 3 1 0 2 5 6 3
Zeleznik ( B ) 4 1 0 3 4 7 3
Rudar 4 1 0 3 1 7 3
Mladost ( BJ ) 4 0 1 3 2 10 1
SOCCER - INCE EXPOSED BY GASCOIGNE 'S LATEST PRANK .
CHISINAU , Moldova 1996-08-31
England 's irrepressible midfielder Paul Gascoigne was up to his old tricks on Saturday , pulling down his team mate Paul Ince 's trousers in front of an astonished crowd in Moldova .
Ince was clambering over a wall at the Republican stadium in Chisinau as Glenn Hoddle 's England players tried to escape heavy rain during an under-21 clash .
Gascoigne , whose compulsive practical joking has landed him in trouble in the past , tugged down the Inter Milan player 's trousers in front of a group of press photographers .
Hoddle , coaching the side for the first time , declined to comment on the incident .
England face Moldova in a World Cup qualifier in the same stadium on Sunday .
BASKETBALL - TROFEJ BEOGRAD TOURNAMENT RESULTS .
BELGRADE 1996-08-31
Results in the Trofej Beograd 96
international basketball tournament on Saturday :
Fifth place :
Benetton ( Italy ) 92 Dinamo ( Russia ) 81 ( halftime 50-28 )
Third place :
Alba ( Germany ) 75 Red Star ( Yugoslavia ) 70 ( 42-41 )
BASKETBALLSOCCER - TROFEJ BEOGRAD TOURNAMENT RESULTS .
BELGRADE 1996-08-31
Results in the Trofej Beograd 96
international basketball tournament on Saturday :
Fifth place :
Benetton ( Italy ) 92 Dinamo ( Russia ) 81 ( halftime 50-28 )
Third place :
Alba ( Germany ) 75 Red Star ( Yugoslavia ) 70 ( 42-41 )
SOCCER - ROMANIA BEAT LITHUANIA IN WORLD CUP QUALIFIER .
BUCHAREST 1996-08-31
Romania beat Lithuania 3-0 ( halftime 1-0 ) in a World Cup soccer European group 8 qualifier on Saturday .
Scorers :
Romania - Viorel Moldovan ( 21st minute ) , Dan Petrescu ( 65th ) , Constantin Galca ( 77th )
Attendence : 9,000
SOCCER - ARMENIA AND PORTUGAL DRAW 0-0 IN WORLD CUP QUALIFIER .
YEREVAN 1996-08-31
Armenia and Portugal drew 0-0 in a World Cup soccer European group 9 qualifier on Saturday .
Attendance : 5,000
SOCCER - AZERBAIJAN BEAT SWITZERLAND IN WORLD CUP QUALIFIER .
BAKU 1996-08-31
Azerbaijan beat Switzerland 1-0 ( halftime 1-0 ) in their World Cup soccer European group three qualifying match on Saturday .
Scorer :
Vidadi Rzayev ( 28th )
Attendance : 20,000
BASKETBALL - BENETTON BEAT DINAMO 92-81 .
BELGRADE 1996-08-31
Benetton of Italy beat Dinamo of Russia 92-81 ( halftime 50-28 ) in a fifth place play-off in the Trofej Beograd 96 international basketball tournament on Saturday .
SOCCER - SWEDEN BEAT LATVIA IN EUROPEAN UNDER-21 QUALIFIER .
RIGA 1996-08-31
Sweden beat Latvia 2-0 ( halftime 0-0 ) in a European under-21 soccer championship qualifier on Saturday .
Scorers : Joakim Persson 81st minute , Daniel Andersson ( 89th )
Attendance : 300
SOCCER - BELARUS BEAT ESTONIA IN WORLD CUP QUALIFIER .
MINSK 1996-08-31
Belarus beat Estonia 1-0 ( halftime 1-0 ) in a World Cup soccer European group 4 qualifier on Saturday .
Scorer : Vladimir Makovsky ( 35th )
Attendance : 6,000
SOCCER - ENGLAND BEAT MOLDOVA IN UNDER-21 QUALIFIER .
CHISINAU 1996-08-31
England beat Moldova 2-0 ( halftime 1-0 ) in a European Under-21 soccer championship group 2 qualifier on Saturday .
Scorers : Bruce Dyer ( 39th minute ) , Darren Eadie ( 53rd )
Attendance : 850
SQUASH - HILL BRANDS WORLD CHAMPION JANSHER A CHEAT .
HONG KONG 1996-08-31
Controversial Australian Anthony Hill called Jansher Khan a cheat during his acrimonious defeat by the world number one in the Hong Kong Open semifinals on Saturday .
The match boiled over when Hill made to walk off court after what he claimed was a game-winning point in the third .
When the referee called Jansher 's return good and the decision was accepted by the player , Hill shrieked at the Pakistani : " You cheat . "
" He was standing right there and knew the shot was down so I called him a cheat , " said Hill , whose squash career has been blighted by fines and suspensions for unacceptable behaviour .
" He knew it was down and accepted what I called him because of that . "
Hill won the game on the next point and said later that Jansher was generally honest on court but played by the referee 's decision .
The Australian had upset Jansher 's rhythm with his mixture of gamesmanship and fluent stroke-making but eventually succumbed 15-7 17-15 14-15 15-8 .
" I changed my strategy against him today and had him rattled , " he added .
He is not as fit as he used to be be but was too good for me in the end .
I shook him a bit but he will come out next time and be a better player for it -- that 's Jansher . "
Jansher said that he was disturbed to be called a cheat . "
What he did was bad for squash , bad for the crowd and bad for the sponsors .
" We are trying to build up squash like tennis and players should not say things like that .
" I think the Professional Squash Association should look into this matter and deal with it properly .
I am not calling for him to be banned but they have to take some action . "
Jansher , bidding for an eighth Hong Kong Open title , plays second-seeded Australian Rodney Eyles in the final .
Eyles played his best squash of the tournament to beat fourth-seeded Peter Nicol of Scotland 15-10 8-15 15-10 15-4 .
Eyles , who defeated Jansher in the semifinals of the Portuguese Open in 1993 , said that he would like to win for the good of the game .
" I have nothing against Jansher but it will be great if I could beat him , " said Eyles . "
My biggest problem against Jansher is concentration .
I want to beat him so badly that I just cannot get it together . "
SQUASH - HONG KONG OPEN SEMIFINAL RESULTS .
HONG KONG 1996-08-31
Semifinal results in the Hong Kong Open on Saturday ( prefix number denotes seeding ) : 1 - Jansher Khan ( Pakistan ) beat Anthony Hill ( Australia ) 15-7 17-15 14-15 15-8 2 - Rodney Eyles ( Australia ) beat 4 - Peter Nicol ( Scotland ) 15-10 8-15 15-10 15-4
GOLF - PARNEVIK TAKES ONE-SHOT LEAD AT GREATER MILWAUKEE OPEN .
MILWAUKEE , Wisconsin 1996-08-31
Jesper Parnevik of Sweden fired a course record-tying eight-under-par 63 Saturday to take a one-shot lead into the final round of the $ 1.2 million Greater Milwaukee Open .
Parnevik , who is seeking his first PGA Tour victory , moved to 19-under 194 for the tournament .
Parnevik tied the 18-hole record set by Loren Roberts in 1994 at the Brown Deer Park Golf Course and also equalled Saturday by Greg Kraft .
Nolan Henke , who led by two strokes entering the third round , carded a four-under 67 and was one stroke back at 18-under 195 .
He is striving for his fourth career PGA Tour victory and first since the 1993 BellSouth Classic .
Tiger Woods , who made the cut in his first tournament as a professional , shot a two-over-par 73 and was four under for the tournament .
The 20-year-old Woods , who turned professional Tuesday after winning an unprecedented third successive U.S. Amateur Championship , struggled on the front nine , bogeying the first and seventh holes and double-bogeying the par-four , 359-yard ninth hole .
After bogeying the 10th hole to move to four-over for the round , he rallied for birdies on 15 and 18 .
After Parnevik started off his round by parring the first hole and bogeying the second , the Swede birdied six of the next seven holes .
Parnevik continued to storm through the course , birdying three holes on the back nine , including two from 12 feet out on the 15th and 17th holes .
" I ca n't remember when I 've putted this well , " said Parnevik . "
I was disappointed when a 12-footer did n't go in .
" My game feels very good .
I 've been fading my driver but today whenever I set up for a fade it went straight .
Whenever everyone 's making birdies , you never want to be even par . "
Henke had a bogey-free round and birdied four holes , including a 45-footer on the par-three 215-yard seventh hole and one from 12 feet out on the 12th hole .
" I did n't hit it very well today , " said Henke . "
Jasper blew right by me .
Once he did , I knew I had to make birdies just to keep up .
I made some really good pars .
I basically picked up where I left off yesterday afternoon .
" Right now , I ca n't put my finger on what 's wrong . "
Bob Estes shot a 67 for sole possession of third place at 15-under .
Steve Stricker , who tied for second at last week 's World Series of Golf , and Stuart Appleby were both five shots off the lead at 14 under .
Duffy Waldorf , who also tied for second at the World Series of Golf , carded a 70 to lead a group of six golfers at 13 under , including Kraft .
The top four on the PGA Tour money list all skipped the tournament .
TENNIS - SPAIN , U.S. TEAMS OPEN ON ROAD FOR 1997 FED CUP .
Richard Finn
NEW YORK 1996-08-31
This year 's Fed Cup finalists -- defending champion Spain and the United States -- will hit the road to open the 1997 women 's international team competition , based on the draw conducted Saturday at the U.S. Open .
Spain travels to Belgium , while the U.S. team heads to the Netherlands for first-round matches March 1-2 .
The other two first-round ties will pit hosts Germany against the Czech Republic and visiting France against Japan .
The semifinals are July 19-20 , and the final September 27- 28 .
Life on the road this year did not slow the Americans , who will try to avenge their 3-2 defeat in the final last year when they host Spain on September 28-29 in Atlantic City .
" Last year we stood on the court after we had lost and we put out hands together and made it our committment to bring back the Cup , " U.S. captain Billie Jean King said at the draw . "
That is our sole goal . "
The United States edged Austria in Salzburg 3-2 in the opening round in April , and then blanked Japan 5-0 in Nagoya last month in the semifinals .
The victory against Japan marked the Fed Cup debut of Monica Seles , who became a naturalised U.S. citizen in 1994 .
Seles easily won both her singles matches and King is counting on the co-world number one to lead the team again .
" I told Monica we need her if we want to win , " King said .
Seles 's sore left shoulder and a wrist injury to Fed Cup veteran Mary Joe Fernandez have forced King to take a wait and see attitude regarding her squad for the best-of-five match .
Fernandez was forced to withdraw from the U.S. Open .
" We will wait until the last minute so we check with everybody and their injuries , " said King . "
What we like would be Seles , ( Olympic champion Lindsay ) Davenport and Mary Joe Fernandez . "
If she can get that threesome together , King will feel good about her chances against the Spain 's formidable duo of Arantxa Sanchez Vicario and Conchita Martinez .
" To be a great coach you have to have the right horses and I got the right horses , " said King .
TENNIS - SATURDAY 'S RESULTS FROM THE U.S. OPEN .
NEW YORK 1996-08-31
Results from the U.S. Open Tennis Championships at the National Tennis Centre on Saturday ( prefix number denotes seeding ) :
Women 's singles , third round 1 - Steffi Graf ( Germany ) beat Natasha Zvereva ( Belarus ) 6-4 6-2 16 - Martina Hingis ( Switzerland ) beat Naoko Kijimuta ( Japan ) 6-2 6-2 Judith Wiesner ( Austria ) beat Petra Langrova ( Czech Republic ) 6 - 2 6-0
Men 's singles , third round 13 - Thomas Enqvist ( Sweden ) beat Pablo Campana ( Ecuador ) 6-4 6-4 6-2
TENNIS - DRAW FOR 1997 FED CUP WOMEN 'S TEAM TOURNAMENT .
NEW YORK 1996-08-31
Draw for the women 's 1997 Fed Cup team tennis championships , as conducted at the U.S. Open on Saturday :
World Group I , first round ( March 1-2 )
United States at Netherlands
Czech Republic at Germany
France at Japan
Spain at Belgium
( semifinals July 19-20 , and finals September 27-28 )
World Group II , first round ( March 1-2 )
Austria at Croatia
Switzerland at Slovak Republic
Argentina at South Korea
Australia at South Africa
SOCCER - U.S. BEAT EL SALVADOR 3-1 .
LOS ANGELES 1996-08-30
The United States beat El Salvador 3-1 ( halftime 1-0 ) in an international soccer friendly on Friday .
Scorers :
U.S. - Joe-Max Moore ( 3rd minute , 88th on penalty kick ) , Eric Wynalda ( 61st )
El Salvador - Luis Lazo ( 61st )
Attendance - 18,661
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE STANDINGS AFTER FRIDAY 'S GAMES .
NEW YORK 1996-08-31
Major League Baseball
standings after games played on Friday ( tabulate under won ,
lost , winning percentage and games behind ) :
AMERICAN LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
NEW YORK 75 59 .560 -
BALTIMORE 71 63 .530 4
BOSTON 69 66 .511 6 1/2
TORONTO 63 72 .467 12 1/2
DETROIT 49 86 .363 26 1/2
CENTRAL DIVISION
CLEVELAND 80 54 .597 -
CHICAGO 72 64 .529 9
MINNESOTA 67 68 .496 13 1/2
MILWAUKEE 65 71 .478 16
KANSAS CITY 61 75 .449 20
WESTERN DIVISION
TEXAS 76 58 .567 -
SEATTLE 70 64 .522 6
OAKLAND 65 72 .474 12 1/2
CALIFORNIA 62 73 .459 14 1/2
SATURDAY , AUGUST 31 SCHEDULE
KANSAS CITY AT DETROIT
BALTIMORE AT SEATTLE
CHICAGO AT TORONTO
MINNESOTA AT MILWAUKEE
CLEVELAND AT TEXAS
BOSTON AT OAKLAND
NEW YORK AT CALIFORNIA
NATIONAL LEAGUE
EASTERN DIVISION
W L PCT GB
ATLANTA 84 50 .627 -
MONTREAL 71 62 .534 12 1/2
FLORIDA 65 70 .481 19 1/2
NEW YORK 59 76 .437 25 1/2
PHILADELPHIA 54 81 .400 30 1/2
CENTRAL DIVISION
HOUSTON 73 63 .537 -
ST LOUIS 70 65 .519 2 1/2
CHICAGO 66 67 .496 5 1/2
CINCINNATI 66 68 .493 6
PITTSBURGH 56 78 .418 16
WESTERN DIVISION
SAN DIEGO 76 60 .559 -
LOS ANGELES 73 61 .545 2
COLORADO 70 66 .515 6
SAN FRANCISCO 58 74 .439 16
SATURDAY , AUGUST 31 SCHEDULE
ATLANTA AT CHICAGO
HOUSTON AT PITTSBURGH
SAN FRANCISCO AT NEW YORK
FLORIDA AT CINCINNATI
LOS ANGELES AT PHILADELPHIA
SAN DIEGO AT MONTREAL
COLORADO AT ST LOUIS
BASEBALL - MAJOR LEAGUE RESULTS FRIDAY .
NEW YORK 1996-08-31
Results of Major League
Baseball games played on Friday ( home team in CAPS ) :
American League
DETROIT 4 Kansas City 0
Chicago 11 TORONTO 2
MILWAUKEE 5 Minnesota 4 ( in 12 )
TEXAS 5 Cleveland 3
New York 6 CALIFORNIA 2
OAKLAND 7 Boston 0
Baltimore 5 SEATTLE 2
National League
CHICAGO 3 Atlanta 2 ( 1st game )
Atlanta 6 CHICAGO 5 ( 2nd game )
Florida 3 CINCINNATI 1
San Diego 6 MONTREAL 0
Los Angeles 7 PHILADELPHIA 6 ( in 12 )
Houston 10 PITTSBURGH 0
San Francisco 6 NEW YORK 4
ST LOUIS 7 Colorado 4
BASEBALL - KEVIN BROWN LOWERS ERA AS MARLINS BEAT REDS .
CINCINNATI 1996-08-31
Major league ERA leader Kevin Brown threw an eight-hitter and Devon White 's RBI double snapped a fifth-inning tie as the Florida Marlins beat the Cincinnati Reds 3-1 for their seventh straight win Friday .
Brown ( 14-10 ) tied Todd Stottlemyre of the Cardinals for the National League lead with his fifth complete game and lowered his major league-leading earned run average from 1.96 to 1.92 .
He struck out eight and did not walk a batter .
Brown threw 119 pitches and won for the third time in as many starts against the Reds this season .
" Bolesy ( Florida manager John Boles ) told me yesterday , ' You have to go nine tomorrow , ' " Brown said .
" In the early innings , I was struggling , I was just trying to make it from pitch to pitch .
I gave up a lot of hits in the early innings and I was n't thinking about the seventh , eighth or ninth .
I was n't satisfied with any of my pitches and I did a better job of moving the ball around in the later innings . "
" He has a devastating sinker , " observed Reds manager Ray Knight . "
The guys say it moved more than everyone in the league .
I remember Nolan Ryan saying in ' 91 or ' 92 that he was the best young pitcher coming around in a long time and he saw ( Tom ) Seaver and ( Jerry ) Koosman when they were starting . "
In Philadelphia , Delino DeShields 's triple in the top of the 12th off Jeff Parrett ( 2-3 ) scored Chad Curtis and lifted the Los Angeles Dodgers to a 7-6 victory over the Phillies .
Los Angeles won for the seventh time in eight games .
Darren Dreifort ( 1-1 ) picked up the win after allowing a hit and a walk over 2 1/3 scoreless innings .
Todd Worrell worked the 12th to earn his league-leading 37th save .
The Phillies have dropped five of their last six overall , and nine of 11 at home .
Billy Ashley belted a three-run homer for Los Angeles .
In Chicago , the Braves and Cubs split a doubleheader .
In the first game , Ryne Sandberg snapped an eighth-inning tie with an infield single and Kevin Foster ( 6-2 ) outdueled Atlanta 's Tom Glavine ( 13-8 ) for his third straight win , 3-2 .
Foster , a .333 hitter , helped his own cause in the second with a two-run single .
The Braves took the second game when Chipper Jones singled home the tying run in the top of the ninth and Andruw Jones took advantage of a poor throw to score the go-ahead run on a sacrifice fly for a 6-5 victory .
Cubs shortstop Jose Hernandez committed three of Chicago 's four errors .
Mike Mordecai singled , doubled and homered for Atlanta , which has won 14 of its last 19 games and has the best record in the majors , 84-50 .
In Montreal , Scott Sanders allowed one hit over eight innings and Wally Joyner hit a two-run single in a four-run third as the San Diego Padres blanked the Expos 6-0 for their sixth straight win .
Sanders ( 8-4 ) struck out 10 and walked three to win his fourth straight .
He allowed a leadoff double to David Segui in the second , and won for the seventh time in eight decisions .
The right-hander retired 14 batters in a row from the second inning through the seventh .
Mike Oquist allowed one Montreal hit in the ninth .
Montreal lost for the ninth time in 14 games .
In New York , Marvin Benard 's two-run homer snapped a tie and Shawn Estes came one out away from his first complete game as the San Francisco Giants beat the Mets 6-4 .
Benard , hitting .467 ( 14-for-30 ) against the Mets this season , hit his first pitch from Pete Harnisch ( 8-10 ) in the seventh over the right-field fence to put the Giants up 4-2 .
Estes ( 3-4 ) was lifted for closer Rod Beck after yielding a single with two out in the ninth .
Beck allowed a two-run double to Alvaro Espinoza , who collected a career-high four RBI , but struck out Brent Mayne for his 31st save .
The loss was the Mets ' eighth straight , their longest slide since September 1993 , and dropped them to 0-4 under new manager Bobby Valentine .
In St Louis , Tom Pagnozzi had three hits and three RBI and Alan Benes scattered six hits over six-plus innings as the Cardinals beat the Colorado Rockies 7-4 .
Benes ( 12-8 ) allowed three runs , walked three and struck out three for the win .
St Louis defeated Colorado for just the second time in 12 meetings dating back to last season .
Ray Lankford went 4-for-5 with a pair of doubles for the Cardinals , who won for just the third time in 11 games .
Eric Anthony hit a pair of solo homers for the Rockies .
In Pittsburgh , Sean Berry tied a career high with six RBI and Donne Wall fired a seven-hitter for his first major-league shutout as the Houston Astros routed the Pirates 10-0 .
It was the third time Berry had six RBI in one game .
Wall ( 9-4 ) struck out four and walked none to post his second complete game of the season and third straight win .
TENNIS - EDBERG REFUSES TO QO QUIETLY .
Richard Finn
NEW YORK 1996-08-30
Refusing to go quietly in the night , Stefan Edberg extended his stay at his 14th and last U.S. Open when Bernd Karbacher , trailing and hurting , quit in the fourth set of their second-round match Friday .
The 30-year-old Edberg , a former two-time Open champion , had wrestled control of the match away from Karbacher when the German , hampered by a left hamstring injury , decided he could n't continue under the stadium lights at the National Tennis Centre .
" A win is a win .
I 'll take it , " Edberg , who has announced that this will be his last Grand Slam event , said of the 3-6 6-3 6-3 1-0 victory .
Ironically , Karbacher two years ago ended Ivan Lendl 's Grand Slam career here when the former champion had to retire in the middle of their first-round match .
After seeing the trainer come out early in the third set , Edberg was not surprised by Karbacher 's decision not to go on .
" I knew he had problems with something , " Edberg said . "
I really was n't surprised . "
Edberg had his own problems early in the match as the Swede battled to acclimate himself to the nighttime conditions while Karbacher was ripping passing shots and blasting serves past him .
" I did n't really feel good to begin with , I had problems finding the timing on the ball , seeing the ball , " said Edberg , who upset Wimbledon champion and fifth-seeded Richard Krajicek in the first round .
" This was one of these matches where I did n't play up to my standard .
I had to fight hard . "
Edberg 's tenacity paid off in the second set .
Edberg lost his own serve twice , but he rallied for three breaks of his own , the last to wrap up the set .
" That 's where the match sort of changed , " said Edberg . "
I think once I got that second set , I felt a lot better about my game . "
Edberg is starting to feel pretty good about postponing his swan song a lot longer .
" It does n't look all that bad , " Edberg said of his path through the draw starting next with a match against Krajicek 's Dutch countryman Paul Haarhuis .
However , the 1991 and 1992 champion is not ready to start making plans to be in next week 's final .
" I 'm always being realistic , " said Edberg . "
Like I said many times , I think it 's a very little chance , but nothing is impossible .
If I play great tennis , that could take me a long way .
" A lot of things can happen , like tonight . "
BOXING - PRINCE NASEEM RETAINS WBO FEATHERWEIGHT TITLE .
DUBLIN 1996-08-31
Britain 's Naseem Hamed retained his WBO featherweight title on Saturday when Mexico 's Manuel Medina was retired by his corner at the end of the 11th round .
SOCCER - AUSTRIA DOMINATE SCOTLAND IN WORLD CUP QUALIFIER .
Steve Pagani
VIENNA 1996-08-31
Austria dominated their World Cup group four qualifier against Scotland on Saturday with wave after wave of attacks but were unable to penetrate the visitors ' defence and had to settle for a goalless draw .
Scotland , who thrashed Belarus 5-1 in their opening group four match , were unable to repeat their performance .
Austria 's best chance came in the 63rd minute with Stephan Marasek of SC Freiburg taking advantage of a scramble in the Scottish penalty area but his shot narrowly passing the left-hand post .
They also went close a minute before the interval when a promising attack saw the ball fall to Markus Schopp but he hit his shot wide .
Everton 's Duncan Ferguson went close for Scotland in the 65th minute when he forced Austrian goalkeeper Michael Konsel to a diving save .
Two Scotland players were shown yellow cards , captain Gary McAllister for bringing down Andreas Heraf and Ferguson for arguing against the referee 's decision .
" The result is acceptable , " Scottish coach Craig Brown told reporters . "
We 'd hoped not to lose and we tried not to play for a draw but the Austrian defence was simply too good . "
SK Rapid 's Dietmar Kuehbauer , who gave an impressive performance , said the team started off well but let the game slip after the first 30 minutes .
" Somehow it seemed there were less than 11 players on the pitch .
We have lost two points .
The Scots are not really a great team and we should have won , " he said .
Austrian coach Herbert Prohaska said his team had displayed great fighting spirit but sometimes lacked ideas .
Teams :
Austria : Michael Konsel , Markus Schopp , Peter Schoettel , Anton Pfeffer , Wolfgang Feiersinger , Stephan Marasek , Dieter Ramusch ( Andreas Ogris 77th ) , Dietmar Kuehbauer , Anton Polster ( ( Herfried Sabitzer 68th ) , Andreas Herzog , Andreas Heraf .
Scotland : Andrew Goram , Craig Burley , Thomas Boyd , Colin Calderwood , Colin Hendry , Thomas McKinley , Duncan Ferguson , Stuart McCall , Alistair McCoist ( Gordon Durie 75th ) , Gary McAllister , John Collins .
BOXING - JOHNSON WINS UNANIMOUS POIUNTS VERDICT .
DUBLIN 1996-08-31
American Tom Johnson successfully defended his IBF featherweight title when he earned a unanimous points decision over Venezuela 's Ramon Guzman on Saturday .
SOCCER - FRANCE LAUNCH 1998 WORLD CUP BUILD-UP WITH 2-0 WIN .
PARIS 1996-08-31
Euro 96 absentee Nicolas Ouedec and Youri Djorkaeff scored the goals as 1998 World Cup hosts France beat Mexico 2-0 in a friendly international on Saturday .
The victory extended to 29 matches France 's unbeaten run under coach Aime Jacquet , their Euro 96 semifinal elimination having come in a penalty shoot-out , but was marred by the sending-off of Chelsea central defender Franck Leboeuf .
Leboeuf was dismissed two minutes from time for a second bookable offence , fouling Mexican substitute Ricardo Pelaez who minutes earlier had also been shown the yellow card for pushing the Chelsea defender in the back .
Both goals came early in the second half after France had surprised the Mexicans with three half-time substitutions .
After a sterile first half , France injected more sting in midfield with the introduction of Juventus 's Zinedine Zidane .
This allowed Djorkaeff to play further up and his cross from the right fell for Ouedec , who has joined Espanyol of Barcelona from Nantes since missing the European championship finals through injury , to score after a mistake by midfielder Joaquin del Olmo .
Within four minutes Ouedec was returning the compliment for Djorkaeff , playing a one-two with the Internazionale Milan forward down the middle to set him up for a cross shot past diving goalkeeper Osvaldo Sanchez .
Jacquet , beginning the 22-month countdown to France 's hosting of the World Cup finals , said : " We have an identity ( as a team ) which we are going to work on . "
Teams :
France - 1 - Bernard Lama ; 2 - Lilian Thuram ( 14 - Sabri Lamouchi 87th ) , 5 - Laurent Blanc , 8 - Marcel Desailly ( 12 - Franck Leboeuf 46th ) , 3 - Bixente Lizarazu ; 4 - Christian Karembeu , 7 - Didier Deschamps , 10 - Youri Djorkaeff , 6 - Reynald Pedros ( 13 - Robert Pires 46th ) ; 9 - Nicolas Ouedec ( 17 - Florian Maurice 64th ) , 11 - Patrice Loko ( 15 - Zinedine Zidane 46th )
Mexico - 1 - Osvaldo Sanchez ( 12 - Alfonso Rios 78th ) ; 13 - Pavel Pardo , 2 - Claudio Suarez , 5 - Duilio Davino ( Becerril 46th ) , 4 - German Villa ( 16 - Gomez 86th ) ; 14 - Joaquin del Olmo , 6 - Raul Rodrigo Lara ( 11 - Cuauhtemoc Blanco 65th ) , 8 - Alberto Garcia Aspe , 7 - Ramon Ramirez ( 15 - Jesus Arellano 71st ) ; 18 - Enrique Alfaro ( 17 - Francisco Palencia 78th ) , 10 - Luis Garcia ( 19 - Ricardo Pelaez 69th ) .
SOCCER - FRANCE BEAT MEXICO 2-0 IN FRIENDLY .
PARIS 1996-08-31
France beat Mexico 2-0 ( halftime 0-0 ) in a friendly soccer international on Saturday .
Scorers : Nicolas Ouedec ( 49th minute ) , Youri Djorkaeff ( 53rd )
Attendance : 18,000
SOCCER - BELGIUM SCRAPE PAST TURKEY DESPITE CROWD TROUBLE .
Bert Lauwers
BRUSSELS 1996-08-31
Belgium kicked off their 1998 World Cup campaign with a hard-fought 2-1 victory over 10-man Turkey in a tense match marred by Turkish crowd trouble shortly after the break .
Turkish fans , upset at their team 's 2-0 first-half deficit , ripped apart dozens of plastic seats and threw them over the fence .
Riot police took 10 minutes to restore order .
The police were given an unexpected hand by second-half substitute Sergen Yalcin who rekindled Turkish hopes in the 61st with a splendid half-volley which stunned Belgian goalkeeper Filip De Wilde .
But Yalcin , who had come on just four minutes earlier , turned from hero to villain barely two minutes after his strike when he was sent off after spitting at an opponent and arguing with English referee David Elleray .
Marc Degryse had opened the scoring for Belgium after 13 minutes , whacking a low 10-metre drive into the net after an incisive pass by defender Dirk Medved from the edge of the penalty area .
Brazilian-born Luis Oliveira then gleefully slipped the ball past goalkeeper Rustu Recber from the right of the area to make it 2-0 seven minutes before the interval , Turkey 's best first-half effort proving to be a vicious 30-metre shot by Ogun Temizkanoglu which De Wilde tipped over .
The visitors , seeking to restore some pride after failing to score a single goal in Euro 96 in June , repeatedly ripped through the left side of the home defence but De Wilde was able to block several sharply-angled efforts .
With only the group seven winners qualifying automatically for the 1998 finals in France , Belgium could not afford a slip-up at home and they frantically chased a decisive third goal .
But they were almost upset 12 minutes from time when De Wilde fumbled a hard Arif Erdem shot and Orhan Cikirikci almost pounced on the loose ball .
Belgium 's best second-half effort came three minutes later when Degryse put the ball over the bar from close range with Recber beaten .
Teams :
Belgium - 1 - Filip De Wilde , 2 - Bertrand Crasson , 3 - Dirk Medved , 4 - Pascal Renier , 16 - Geoffrey Claeys , 6 - Gunther Schepens ( 15 - Nico Van Kerckhoven , 81st ) , 10 - Enzo Scifo , 7 - Gert Verheyen ( 14 - Frederic Peiremans , 62nd ) , 9 - Marc Degryse , 8 - Luc Nilis , 11- Luis Oliveira ( 18 - Gilles De Bilde , 88th ) .
Turkey - 1 - Rustu Recber , 4 - Hakan Unsal ( 14 - Sergen Yalcin , 57th ) , 2 - Recep Cetin , 3 - Ogun Temizkanoglu , 5 - Alpay Ozalan , 7- Abdullah Ercan , 6 - Tolunay Kafkas , 10 - Oguz Cetin ( 13 - Arif Erdem , 57th ) , 11 - Tayfun Korkut , 9 - Hakan Sukur , 8 - Saffet Sancakli ( 17- Orhan Cikirikci , 76th ) .
Belgian coach Wilfried Van Moer said he had not expected Turkey to be so strong and fast .
" We started panicking a bit after the Turkish goal ...
we suffered , " said Van Moer , who succeeded Paul Van Himst as coach in April .
It was Belgium 's first victory under Van Moer after two draws in friendlies against Russia and Italy .
SOCCER - SUMMARY IN THE SPANISH FIRST DIVISION .
MADRID 1996-08-30
Summary of game played in the Spanish first division on Saturday : Deportivo Coruna 1 ( Corentine Martins , 22nd minute ) Real Madrid 1 ( Roberto Carlos 79th ) .
Halftime 1-0 .
Attendancce 35,000 .
SOCCER - RESULT IN SPANISH FIRST DIVISION .
MADRID 1996-08-31
Result of game played in the
Spanish first division on Saturday :
Deportivo Coruna 1 Real Madrid 1
SOCCER - BELGIUM BEAT TURKEY 2-1 IN WORLD CUP QUALIFIER .
BRUSSELS 1996-08-31
Belgium beat Turkey 2-1
( halftime 2-0 ) in a World Cup group seven soccer qualifier on
Saturday :
Scorers :
Belgium - Marc Degryse ( 13th ) , Luis Oliveira ( 38th )
Turkey - Sergen Yalcin ( 61st )
Attendance : 30,000
SOCCER - AUSTRIA DRAW 0-0 WITH SCOTLAND IN WORLD CUP QUALIFIER .
VIENNA 1996-08-31
Austria and Scotland drew 0-0 in a World Cup soccer European group four qualifier on Saturday .
Attendance : 29,500
BOXING - KNOCK-OUT SPECIALIST MILLER DEFENDS TITLE .
DUBLIN 1996-08-31
A powerful right hook followed by a straight left gave defending champion Nate Miller a seventh round knock-out win over fellow American James Heath in their WBA cruiserweight title bout on Saturday .
Miller , who went into the contest with a record of 24 knock-out wins in 32 fights , took charge from the opening bell and had his opponent on the canvas inside 90 seconds when he landed a deft left-hook to the head .
Heath did score with two brusing lefts to Miller 's head in the third round but failed to put his opponent under any real pressure .
Miller raised the pace of the contest at the start of the fifth round and , once he started to get his right-left combinations working for him , the fight was never likely to go the distance .
SOCCER - DUTCH DRAW 2-2 WITH BRAZIL IN FRIENDLY INTERNATIONAL .
AMSTERDAM 1996-08-31
The Netherlands drew 2-2 with
Brazil ( half-time 0-1 ) in a soccer friendly on Saturday .
Scorers :
Netherlands - Ronald de Boer ( 52nd minute ) , Van Gastel
( 90th , pen )
Brazil - Giovanni ( 14th ) , Marcello Goncalves ( 55th )
BOXING - MILLER DEFENDS WBA CRUISERWEIGHT TITLE .
DUBLIN 1996-08-31
American Nate Miller successfully defended his WBA cruiserweight title when he knocked out compatriot James Heath in the seventh round of their bout on Saturday .
HORSE RACING - TATTERSALLS BREEDERS STAKES RESULT .
DUBLIN 1996-08-31
Result of the Tattersalls Breeders
Stakes , a race for two-year-olds run over six furlongs ( 1,200
metres ) at The Curragh on Saturday :
1. Miss Stamper 3-1 joint-favourite ( ridden by David Harrison )
2. Paddy Lad 16-1 ( Peter Bloomfield )
3. Pelham 10-1 ( Warren O'Connor )
Distances : Three lengths , two-and-a-half lengths .
Winner owned by John and Beryll Remblance and trained in
Britain by Richard Hannon .
Value to the winning owner : $ 233,600
SOCCER - KLINSMANN TO RETIRE AFTER 1998 WORLD CUP .
BONN 1996-08-31
German international striker Juergen Klinsmann has said he will retire after the 1998 World Cup in France .
" For myself , personally , I 've planned things so that that will be the end of me , " the 32-year-old national team captain was quoted as saying by the daily Sueddeutsche Zeitung on Saturday .
Klinsmann said he believed Germany could win in France with the same nucleus of players which won the European championship in England this summer .
" I think it can be done , " he said , " especially as experience is becoming more and more valuable in sport .
I think we can do it with the same body of players .
That 's what we 're all aiming for . "
Coach Berti Vogts has called up a virtually identical squad for next week 's friendly against Poland -- Germany 's first match since Euro 96 .
SOCCER - GERMAN CUP SECOND ROUND RESULTS .
BONN 1996-08-31
Results of German Cup second round
matches on Saturday :
Karlsruhe 2 Hansa Rostock 0
Borussia Neunkirchen 1 St Pauli 3
Duisburg 1 Luebeck 0 ( after extra time )
SOCCER - ROMANIA BEAT LITHUANIA IN U-21 QUALIFIER .
BUCHAREST 1996-08-30
Romania beat 2-1 ( halftime 1-1 ) Lithuania in their European Under-21 soccer match on Friday .
Scorers :
Romania - Cosmin Contra ( 31st ) , Mihai Tararache ( 75th )
Lithuania - Danius Gleveckas ( 13rd )
Attendence : 200
Paper says Thatcher 's office consulted astrologer .
LONDON 1996-09-01
A British newspaper said Margaret Thatcher was so shaken by an IRA attempt on her life when she was prime minister in 1984 that an astrologer was asked to warn her against future threats .
The Sunday Telegraph quoted Majorie Orr as saying she did a horoscope chart for Thatcher , a Libran , after she narrowly escaped death in the Irish guerrilla bombing of a hotel during the Conservative Party conference more than a decade ago .
Orr said Thatcher 's press secretary Bernard Ingram asked her to telephone if she saw any threatening indications in the future .
" Bernard Ingham told me that if I ever heard anything that indicated danger I was to let him know , " Orr said .
Orr said she never had to telephone .
She added that the horoscope was purely for security purposes and she was never consulted about political moves .
Ingram was quoted as telling the newspaper he thought astrology was " a load of rubbish " and that he could not recall asking Orr to keep a watch on Thatcher 's stars .
Thatcher , dubbed the " Iron Lady " for her driven , forceful personality , was never known to have an interest in the occult and in fact has a university degree in chemistry .
Former U.S. president Ronald Reagan 's wife , Nancy , admitted in her biography My Turn that she regularly consulted an astrologer to help her plan her husband 's schedule .
Reuters historical calendar - September 7 .
LONDON 1996-08-31
Following are some of the major events to have occurred on September 7 in history .
1533 - Queen Elizabeth I born .
Daughter of Henry VIII and his second wife Anne Boleyn , she was queen of England 1558-1603 .
One of the great monarchs who presided over a period of English assertion in Europe in politics and the arts .
1706 - French troops under Duke of Orleans besieging Turin were defeated by the Austrians under Prince Eugene , the French army was destroyed and they ceased trying to capture northern Italy .
1714 - The Treaty of Baden was signed between the Holy Roman Emperor Charles VI and France , ending War of Spanish Succession .
Charles ceded Alsace and Strasbourg to France and got back Breisach , Kehl and Freiburg .
1812 - Russian army under General Kutuzov was defeated at heavy cost by Napoleon at the battle of Borodino 70 miles west of Moscow .
Napoleon entered Moscow a week later .
1822 - Brazil proclaimed independence from Portugal and Pedro I became first Emperor of Brazil in December 1822 .
1836 - Scottish politician Sir Henry Campbell-Bannerman born .
As Liberal prime minister 1905-1908 he granted self-government to the Transvaal .
He also got the House of Lords to pass his Trades Disputes Act which gave labour unions more freedom to strike .
1860 - Giuseppe Garibaldi leading his " Red Shirts " seized Naples in the Italian war of liberation against the Austrians .
1901 - In China , the Boxer Rising which attempted to drive out all foreigners officially ended with the signing of the Peking Protocol .
This imposed an indemnity to be paid to the great powers for Boxer crimes .
1909 - Elia Kazan born as Elia Kazanjoglus .
A U.S. stage and screen director , he is best known for " Viva Zapata " and " On the Waterfront " .
1913 - Sir Anthony Quayle born .
British actor of stage and screen in films from 1948 .
Best known for appearances in " Ice Cold in Alex " , " Lawrence of Arabia " and , as Cardinal Wolsey , in " Anne of a Thousand Days " .
1914 - James Alfred Van Allen born .
U.S. physicist who discovered the two zones of radiation encircling the earth to which he gave his name .
1930 - Belgian King Baudouin I born .
He succeeded to the throne in 1951 on the abdication of his father Leopold III .
1940 - In World War Two the German airforce under Hermann Goering began its " Blitz " bombing campaign on London .
Over 300 people were killed on this day alone .
1969 - Scottish motor racing driver Jackie Stewart won the Italian Grand Prix to secure his first world championship .
Four years later , after winning his third world crown , he announced his retirement .
1986 - Bishop Desmond Tutu was enthroned as Archbishop of Cape Town , South Africa .
He was the first black head of South Africa 's Anglicans .
1990 - The United States won Saudi and Kuwaiti pledges to help pay for forces in the Gulf .
Iraq ordered many restaurants to close indefinitely to save food in face of a blockade .
1990 - British historian Alan John Percivale ( A.J.P. ) Taylor died .
He won acclaim for the insights that he gave into the events which shaped modern Europe and was one of Europe 's leading authorities on the great conflicts of the 20th century .
1993 - Six former Soviet republics , Russia , Belarus , Kazakhstan , Uzbekistan , Armenia and Tajikistan , signed framework agreement to keep the Russian rouble as their common currency .
1994 - The Stars and Stripes flag was lowered for the last time over U.S. army headquarters in Berlin , formally ending the American presence in the once-divided city after nearly half a century .
Escaped British paedophile recaptured .
LONDON 1996-08-31
A convicted British paedophile was arrested on Saturday , two days after escaping from custody during a supervised day trip to a zoo , police said .
Trevor Holland , a 52 year-old with who has been convicted twice of gross indecency with children , was captured after being spotted in Worthing , a town on England 's southern coast .
" A member of the public recognised Holland in a newsagent shop as he was reading the headlines about himself , " a police spokesman said .
Police launched a nationwide search on Thursday after he disappeared during an unsupervised trip to the toilet while visiting a popular zoo and theme park south of London .
Holland was moved to a more secure centre earlier this year after a similar incident .
His escape at the zoo caused outrage in Britain .
A child sex scandal in Belgium in which two eight-year-old girls were murdered and two other sexually abused girls were rescued has focused new attention on the problem .
Scottish Labour Party narrowly backs referendum .
STIRLING , Scotland 1996-08-31
British Labour Party leader Tony Blair won a narrow victory on Saturday when the party 's Scottish executive voted 21-18 in favour of his plans for a referendum on a separate parliament for Scotland .
Blair once pledged to set up a Scottish parliament if the Labour won the next general election , which must be held by May 1997 .
But many activists were dismayed when he abruptly decided earlier this year to hold a two-question referendum on the issue , asking Scots if they wanted a separate parliament and if it should have tax-raising powers .
Many party members argued that a general election win would demonstrate popular support for a separate parliament and others said a single question referendum would suffice .
Prime Minister John Major says the 300-year-old union of the Scottish and English parliaments will be a main plank in his Conservative Party 's election platform .
Conservatives have only 10 of the 72 Scottish seats in parliament and consistently run third in opinion polls in Scotland behind Labour and the independence-seeking Scottish National Party .
Britain condemns Iraq involvement in Arbil attack .
LONDON 1996-08-31
Britain on Saturday condemned Iraqi involvement in an attack on the Kurdish city of Arbil and said it was in close touch with its allies .
" We condemn Iraqi involvement .
In no way can Iraqi involvement be seen as helpful , " said a Foreign Office spokesman .
U.N. officials said that a Kurdish rebel faction backed up by Iraqi tanks , heavy artillery and helicopters had taken control of half of the city after heavy fighting .
Arbil lies within the so-called safe haven set up at the end of the 1991 Gulf War on the suggestion of British Prime Minister John Major to protect Iraqi Kurds from attack by the Iraqi military .
The area is patrolled by U.S. , French and British planes .
" We are in close touch with all our allies , " said the Foreign Office spokesman .
He declined to give any further information .
Seven Iraqis charged with hijack .
LONDON 1996-08-31
Seven Iraqi men appeared in court on Saturday charged with air piracy following the hijacking to Britain of a Sudanese airliner with 199 people aboard .
The seven , including a carpenter and a businessmen and whose ages ranged from 25 to 38 years old , were ordered to be held in jail until another hearing next week .
No pleas were entered at the preliminary hearing .
They were accused of taking over Flight 150 which was flying from Khartoum , Sudan , to Amman , Jordan .
All the hostages were freed on Tuesday after the plane landed at Stansted airport , north of London .
The men have claimed political asylum in Britain saying they were persecuted while in Iraq .
Their court appearance means they will face trial and possible imprisonment in Britain before their applications for asylum are considered .
Under English law the maximum sentence for hijack is life imprisonment but there has been widespread speculation that the seven will receive lesser sentences .
After a search of the aircraft following the hijack , police found only knives and fake explosives .
Opposition group says Iraqis advance in north Iraq .
LONDON 1996-08-31
An Iraqi opposition group in exile said on Saturday it had received reports that Iraqi forces were shelling and advancing on the Kurdish town of Arbil in northern Iraq .
A London-based spokesman of the Iraqi National Congress said Iraqi artillery was shelling the city and Iraqi tanks had advanced to within 10 km ( six miles ) of Arbil , the administrative centre of the Kurdish rebel-controlled region of northern Iraq .
" At 4.50 a.m. Iraq time ( 0050 GMT ) Iraqi forces began an artillery attack on the outskirts of Arbil , " the spokesman , who asked not to be identified , told Reuters in a telephone call .
There was no independent confirmation of the report which the spokesman said came from the organisation 's members in Arbil .
He said damage and casualties in the city were heavy and Kurdish forces were defending the city .
President Bill Clinton on Friday ordered the U.S. military to ready itself for any possible action as Washington turned up the heat in an escalating crisis over Iraqi troop movements in northern Iraq .
On Thursday , Iraq accused Iran of aggression and said it reserved the right to retaliate for Tehran 's alleged deployment of troops into northern Iraq , where fighting broke out between the two main Iraqi Kurdish rebel groups two weeks ago .
Two die in Algeria restaurant blast - radio .
LONDON 1996-08-31
Two people were killed when a hand grenade exploded in a restaurant near Algiers late on Friday , Algerian radio reported on Saturday .
The report , monitored by the British Broadcasting Corporation ( BBC ) , quoted security services as saying six other people were injured in the blast in the town of Staouelli .
An estimated 50,000 people had been killed in political violence in Algeria since 1992 , when army-backed authorities cancelled a general election that Islamic fundamentalists had been expected to win .
Baseball-Results of S. Korean pro-baseball games .
SEOUL 1996-08-31
Results of South Korean pro-baseball games played on Friday .
OB 5 Samsung 0
Ssangbangwool 2 Hyundai 1
Standings after games played on Friday ( tabulate under won , drawn , lost , winning percentage , games behind first place )
W D L PCT GB
Haitai 64 2 43 .596 -
Ssangbangwool 60 2 49 .550 5
Hanwha 58 1 49 .542 6
Hyundai 57 5 50 .531 7
Samsung 49 5 57 .464 14 1/2
Lotte 46 6 54 .462 14 1/2
LG 46 5 59 .441 17
OB 43 6 62 .414 20
S. African Afrikaners still seek own territory .
CAPE TOWN 1996-08-31
South African right-wing Afrikaners on Saturday revived their campaign for a form of self-rule , identifying a sparsely-populated area in Northern Cape province as the best place for a home of their own .
Constand Viljoen , leader of the Freedom Front party , told a news conference in Pretoria self-determination for Afrikaners could begin at local government level .
" Certain powers can be delegated from the provincial level , towards the sub-regions , " he said .
" We think that the Afrikaner model within this new , multi- ethnic society of South Africa will have to develop experimentally with world thinking in this regard . "
Viljoen broke with other right-wing whites in 1994 by taking part in the country 's first all-race elections in April of that year , saying the only way to attain self-determination was by cooperating with President Nelson Mandela 's majority African National Congress .
Some right-wingers demanded sovereignty in their own territory in the run-up to the elections , saying the alternative was war .
Their threats came to nothing .
Viljoen has hailed clauses in South Africa 's new constitution as making possible a form of self-rule for the Afrikaners , descendants of the country 's Dutch , German and French settlers .
According to state television , Viljoen told the news conference the self-rule model should be introduced in parts of the Northern Cape provinces where a majority of people -- whites and mixed-race Coloureds -- speak Afrikaans .
Rwandan refugee group calls for calm over census .
NAIROBI 1996-08-31
A Rwandan refugee lobby group called on Saturday for calm in refugee camps in eastern Zaire during a census from Sunday to be conducted by aid workers .
The Rally for the Return of Refugees and Democracy in Rwanda ( RDR ) urged the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees to avoid any " policing approach " and to calm refugees by explaining the aims of the operation .
" The RDR appeals to all refugees to prepare themselves calmly for the demands of the census agents because it will be in their ultimate interest , " the group said in a statement .
It said refugees feared census takers would use indelible ink to mark them so they could be detected by Rwandan government troops and mistreated if they were forced back into Rwanda .
U.N. officials said more than 1,000 aid workers will take part in the census from Sunday until Tuesday of the estimated 727,000 refugees in camps around the eastern Zairean border town of Goma .
Only about 100 refugees a week are returning voluntarily to Rwanda in contrast to the 600 babies born in the camps weekly .
Zairean Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo said at the end of a visit to Rwanda last week that the Zairean and Rwandan governments agreed on an " organised , massive and unconditional repatriation " of the 1.1 million Rwandan refugees in Zaire .
He said the repatriation would be carried out swiftly and would be enormous , starting with the closure of refugee camps .
RDR said it feared forced expulsions would start in days .
Zairean troops expelled 15,000 refugees in August last year .
Many of the 1.1 million Rwandan Hutu refugees in Zaire and nearly 600,000 in Tanzania refuse to go home , saying they fear reprisals for the 1994 genocide in Rwanda of up to a million people by Hutus .
NATO monitors Moslem move towards tense village .
MAHALA , Bosnia 1996-08-31
NATO said it was closely monitoring the movement of about 75 Moslem men towards the village of Mahala in Bosnia 's Serb republic on Saturday , two days after a violent confrontation with Serbs .
" I have to report this morning that we have in fact received reports ...
that up to 75 Moslem men are believed to be approaching Mahala , " NATO spokesman Lieutenant-Colonel Max Marriner said in Sarajevo .
Marriner said that NATO troops had set up a checkpoint on the road between Tuzla and Mahala to establish the identities and intentions of the men headed towards the village .
Mahala is a Moslem village on Bosnian Serb republic territory .
Moslems were driven from the village during the 43- month Bosnian war and most of their houses were destroyed .
Some Moslems began returning to rebuild their properties earlier in the week .
Fights and shooting broke out between the Moslems and Serb police on Thursday and NATO troops finally brought restored order .
A Reuters reporter who entered Mahala on Saturday morning found it tranquil but NATO troops and U.N. police were seen on the ground and NATO helicopters flew overhead .
Chechens exuberant but cautious on peace deal .
Liutauras Stremaitis
URUS-MARTAN , Russia 1996-08-31
Crowds of pro-independence Chechens greeted a newly-signed peace deal by singing , dancing and firing guns in the air on Saturday , but the celebrations held a trace of uncertainty .
More than a thousand women , children and men gathered in a field to the north of the town of Urus-Martan on Saturday to wait for a column of rebels to withdraw from the capital Grozny about 25 km ( 12 miles ) away .
The men fired weapons into the air as groups of women danced .
Adults in the crowd carried posters of former Chechen leader Dzhokhar Dudayev -- who declared independence in 1991 -- and children , carrying photographs of him , called " Troops out ! "
.
Russian military officials have expressed fears that the rebels and their supporters will see the deal signed by Russian peace envoy Alexander Lebed in the early hours of Saturday as a military victory for the separatists .
It involves the withdrawal of Russian troops sent to Chechnya in December 1994 to crush the separatists and a postponement of the issue at the heart of the conflict -- the status of the mainly-Moslem North Caucasus region .
But the people in the crowd on Saturday , who had turned out in support of the rebels , did not seem sure that the war was over .
" We hope for the best , that it really has ended so we can live in peace .
It 's our only dream , " said a 30-year-old woman , Mubatik Dagayeva .
Aiza Dudayeva , with her 10-year-old son beside her , shared the guarded optimism . "
We really want the war to end , we hope and believe that our sons and brothers will win , " said Dudayeva , adding that she was from Urus-Martan .
Urus-Martan is a traditionally anti-separatist pocket in Chechnya and Moscow-backed leader Doku Zavgayev , who has been sidelined in the peace deal , has warned that it and places like it could become centres of civil war if Russian troops leave .
But on Saturday the people gathered just outside the town seemed to be united in favour of the separatists .
Two columns of rebels appeared in jeeps and cars , firing their guns in the air , as the crowd rushed towards them .
Mouldi Mamatuyev , in his late 20 's , dressed in black and carrying a machine gun , was welcomed by his mother and sister .
" Two sons have come back , " said his mother Nurbika Mamatuyeva . "
It 's the end .
We believe in God . "
Mamatuyev joked that his sister Lisa was a rebel too , and she responded by grabbing hold of his gun and shouting the Chechen war cry " Allahu Akhbar " ( God is Greatest ) and " Freedom for Chechnya ! "
.
The fighter , sitting next to a man dressed in green and carrying a grenade-launcher , said that the strict Islamic law adopted by the rebels during the conflict was now needed to impose peace .
" The war has ended if everything works out , if there is law there will be power .
Only Sheriat ( Islamic law ) can end the war . "
Polish group to bid for Ruch newsstand chain - paper .
WARSAW 1996-08-31
A Polish consortium including the Bank Rozwoju Exportu SA ( BRE ) plans to rival France 's Hachette in bidding for Polish state-owned press distribution chain Ruch SA , Zycie Warszawy daily said on Saturday .
Zycie Warszawy said its own publisher , mineral water firm Multico , and a group headed by Polish businessman Zygmunt Solorz were forming a consortium which would offer about $ 120 million , with finance provided by BRE .
The consortium wanted 40 percent of Ruch 's shares , the state would get 20 percent of Ruch and 40 percent would be offered on the Warsaw stock exchange .
" This division would guarantee a dispersal of capital , preventing anyone from taking total control over Ruch and dictating market conditions , " the paper quoted one of the initiators of the move as saying , without giving a name .
A consortium of press distributor Hachette and Polish publishers group UWP are seeking more than than 50 percent of Ruch and French President Jacques Chirac is likely to support its case when he visits Poland in September , the daily said .
News-stand chain Ruch , which controls about 65 percent of Poland 's press distribution market , had a net profit of 16.2 million zlotys on sales of 2.7 billion zlotys in 1995 .
It has about 17,000 news-stands and was the country 's sole press distributor before the 1989 fall of communism .
Zycie Warszawy said the new , open consortium , which also included several listed Polish firms , would on Monday inform Privatisation Minister Wieslaw Kaczmarek of its plans .
It aims to invest $ 200 million in Ruch over five years -- more than the sum Ruch says it needs to upgrade its outlets .
Initially Poland offered up to 75 percent of Ruch but in March Kaczmarek cancelled the tender and offered a minority stake with an option to increase the equity .
Two consortia -- UWP-Hachette and a consortium of a Polish SPC group and Swiss firms -- placed initial bids .
But after the change of tender conditions Swiss investors pulled out and SPC decided to bid jointly with UWP-Hachette .
Kaczmarek said in May he was unhappy that only one investor ended up bidding for Ruch , in which the government was initially offering up to 35 percent of shares with an option to extend the holding after investment promises are fulfilled .
-- Anthony Barker +48 22 653 9700
Three Russian soldiers killed in gun attack .
MOSCOW 1996-08-31
Three Russian servicemen were killed on Saturday when unidentified gunmen attacked guards at an anti-aircraft installation outside Moscow , Interfax news agency said .
It quoted military officials as saying the attack took place in Sergiyev Posad 70 km ( 45 miles ) from the capital .
The officials said the attackers had seized two Kalashnikov assault rifles and disappeared .
Attacks on servicemen aimed at seizing their guns have become frequent in Russia where the number of violent crimes committed with the use of fire arms is growing .
Cuban novelist Jose Soler Puig dies at 79 .
HAVANA 1996-08-31
One of Cuba 's most acclaimed authors , Jose Soler Puig , died at the age of 79 , the official newspaper Granma reported on Saturday .
Puig 's first novel , " Bertillon 166 , " was published in 1960 , a year after the Cuban revolution brought President Fidel Castro to power .
The book , which has been translated into 40 languages , deals with a day in the life of Santiago de Cuba , Puig 's native city , under the pre-Castro government of Fulgencio Batista .
The titles of his other novels translate as " In the Year of January " ( 1963 ) , " The Collapse " ( 1964 ) , " Sleeping Bread " ( 1975 ) , " The Decaying Mansion " ( 1977 ) and " A World of Things " ( 1982 ) , followed by " The Knot , " " Soul Alone " and , most recently , " A Woman . "
Granma called " Sleeping Bread " Puig 's " greatest gift to the modern novel in our America . "
The author said in an interview shortly before his death that his own experiences had lent his books their strong sense of realism . "
I 'm a thief of ideas , " he said . "
The stories have been given to me by people . "
In the same interview , published by Prensa Latina on Saturday , Puig was asked if he feared death . "
Death is not a punishment -- death is the end of life 's punishment , " he said .
U.N. Ambassador Albright arrives in Chile .
SANTIAGO 1996-08-31
The U.S. ambassador to the United Nations , Madeleine Albright , arrived in Chile late Friday for talks on various Security Council issues with Chilean officials as part of a five-nation Latin American tour .
Albright will meet Foreign Minister Jose Miguel Insulza Monday for talks on issues currently up for debate on the council , of which Chile is a non-permanent member , a U.S. embassy statement said .
The two will also discuss various issues affecting relations between the United States and Chile , local officials said .
Albright , who arrived from Uruguay , will rest most of the weekend in Chile , officials said .
Her official programme will begin on Monday , and she will leave that day for Bolivia to attend a Latin American summit meeting in the city of Cochabamba .
Her tour will also include Honduras and Guatemala .
Mexican army attacked in Michoacan state - report .
MEXICO CITY 1996-08-30
A group of heavily-armed men attacked a military convoy in the western Mexican state of Michoacan on Friday , killing one soldier and wounding two , radio reports said .
Radio Red quoted local police in the town of Tacambaro , Michoacan , 80 km ( 50 miles ) south of the state capital Morelia , as saying 40 to 50 armed men attacked the convoy .
Gonzalo Montoya , a police commander in Tacambaro , told Radio Red the group was armed with AK-47s and other high-powered assault rifles and wore military-style fatigues .
Montoya said he thought the attackers were criminals linked to drug trafficking or kidnapping in the area . "
We often see people dressed in military-style clothing here , " he said .
The attack comes a day after rebels of the self-styled Popular Revolutionary Army ( EPR ) launched coordinated attacks in at least three Mexican states , killing up to 14 people and wounding about 20 .
China said to fear dissidents more than criminals .
MANILA 1996-08-31
The detention of veteran dissident Wang Donghai showed China 's determination to crush any vestige of dissent during the current profound transitions in the nation 's leadership , a human rights activist said on Saturday .
Xiao Qiang , executive director of the New York-based group Human Rights in China , said Wang 's arrest on Friday appeared to be part of the national " Strike Hard " campaign that has imprisoned thousands and sent hundreds to their death .
Although supposedly aimed at criminals , dozens of human rights activists have been detained in the campaign , which is meant to strengthen the Communist Party 's grip on power as senior leader Deng Xiaoping nears death , Xiao said in an interview .
" China is going through this power transition period .
The authorities are apparently extremely afraid of any political and social discontent , " said Xiao , in Manila to attend an Amnesty International conference on human rights in China .
He said one of Wang 's apparent offences was to write a public letter in May suggesting that a free press and an independent judicial system were vital if the government really meant to stamp out rampant corruption .
Xiao said crushing legitimate dissent was only making the problem worse and one day China would pay a high price .
" Those issues are not going to go away by repression .
You only make things more hidden but potentially more explosive , " he said .
Wang was arrested in the east China city of Hangzhou by security officers who told the dissident 's family he would be sent to a study class -- a euphemism for coercive ideological reform .
Wang , 45 , was sentenced last month to one year 's " re-education by labour " but was released because of ill-health .
Xiao said conditions in the labour camp were so brutal they drove another activist sentenced with Wang to attempt suicide .
Police beat Wang and his colleague , Chen Longde , and encouraged other camp inmates to attack them as well , Xiao said .
Manila hails Indonesia , OIC for peace deal support .
MANILA 1996-08-31
Philippine president Fidel Ramos expressed gratitude to Indonesian president Suharto and the Organisation of Islamic Conference ( OIC ) on Saturday for supporting talks that ended a conflict with local Moslem rebels .
" I extend the deepest gratitude ... to your excellency for your untiring and invaluable friendship and support , " Ramos told Suharto in a letter .
The full text of the letter was released to reporters on Saturday .
Jakarta served as the host to the series of negotiations which culminated in the initialling of the agreement last Friday .
The formal signing of the peace agreement is scheduled on Monday in Manila .
Ramos said the peace agreement " shall bring down the curtain on a long and storied era of strife in Philippine history . "
The war claimed more than 125,000 lives in the southern Mindanao island over a quarter of a century .
Burma 's Suu Kyi says military rulers abuse law .
Deborah Charles
RANGOON 1996-08-31
Burma 's democracy leader Aung San Suu Kyi hit out at the government on Saturday for recent arrests and jailing of activists , saying the military abused the law to try to crush the democracy movement .
" The main purpose of this press conference is to make it known to the world that the authorities are misusing the law all the time in order to try to crush the democracy movement , " Suu Kyi told reporters at her Rangoon home .
Suu Kyi said at least 61 democracy supporters had been arrested since May , and about 30 of them had been sentenced , most to long prison terms .
In May the government launched a sweeping crackdown on the democracy movement , detaining over 260 members of Suu Kyi 's National League for Democracy ( NLD ) ahead of a party congress .
Most were released but several dozen remain in custody .
The Burmese government last week confirmed the recent sentencing of nine democracy activists who were arrested in the May crackdown , including Suu Kyi 's assistant Win Htein .
The military government , which in May said it had detained the politicians to prevent anarchy , said the activists were charged with attempting to destroy the peace and stability of the state .
But Suu Kyi disagreed with the methods , saying officials often arrested NLD supporters in the middle of the night , then did not give them the opportunity to defend themselves in trials .
" When our people are tried , they are tried in a very secretive way .
Their families are not told , " she said .
Suu Kyi , who spearheads a campaign for sanctions on Burma 's government , was under house arrest for six years without being tried before being released in July 1995 .
Several other leading members of the NLD have served prison terms .
The NLD party won a landslide victory in a 1990 election but the State Law and Order Restoration Council ( SLORC ) , which assumed power in 1988 after crushing pro-democracy demonstrations , never recognised the poll .
" This lack of rule of law is an indication that the authorities are not interested in fair play , " she said . "
They are using a travesty of the law to try and crush our movements and to sentence our people to long terms in prison without proper trial . "
Suu Kyi said once the activists were sentenced , they suffered inhuman conditions and lack of rights in prison .
" Almost all of the prisoners start suffering from various health problems after a couple of years in jail , " she said . "
Some of our people have been in prison for five to six years . "
Most political prisoners are held in Rangoon 's Insein Prison .
Some who have been released have recounted torture methods like sleep and food deprivation and physical abuse .
" If there are any more instances of death in custody it will be further proof that a prison sentence for political prisoners is sometimes almost the same as a death sentence , " Suu Kyi said .
Hla Than , an elected member of parliament for the NLD , died in early August after being at Insein for six years .
His death came five weeks after James Leander ( Leo ) Nichols , a close friend of Suu Kyi and Danish honorary consul , died while serving a prison term at Insein .
Suu Kyi said the government had increased its repression tactics on the democracy movement because it feared the growing popularity of the movement .
But she said she and the NLD would not stop their efforts to bring democracy to Burma even if it meant more arrests of party members or even herself .
" We will carry on .
Nobody is free from arrest in Burma . "
Dow Chemical in China ethylene venture .
BEIJING 1996-08-31
The Dow Chemical Co of the United States will invest $ 4 billion to build an ethylene plant in Tianjin city in northern China , the China Daily said on Saturday .
The plant will have annual production of 400,000 tonnes , the newspaper said .
It gave no further details of the venture .
Tianjin boasts a range of infrastructure facilities , attracting several multinational oil companies to invest in recent years .
Caltex Petroleum Corp plans to build a lubricants blender in a bonded zone in Tianjin , the newspaper said .
Multinational firms including Mobil , Shell and Caltex , were also attracted to Tianjin due to China 's rising demand for lube and oil-based products , the newspaper said .
It gave no further details .
N. Korea urges S. Korea to return war veteran .
SEOUL 1996-08-31
North Korea demanded on Saturday that South Korea return a northern war veteran who has been in the South since the 1950-53 war , Seoul 's unification ministry said .
" ...I request the immediate repatriation of Kim In-so to North Korea where his family is waiting , " North Korean Red Cross president Li Song-ho said in a telephone message to his southern couterpart , Kang Young-hoon .
Li said Kim had been critically ill with a cerebral haemorrhage .
The message was distributed to the press by the South Korean unification ministry .
Kim , an unrepentant communist , was captured during the Korean War and released after spending more than 30 years in a southern jail .
He submitted a petition to the International Red Cross in 1993 asking for his repatriation .
The domestic Yonhap news agency said the South Korean government would consider the northern demand only if the North accepted Seoul 's requests , which include regular reunions of families split by the Korean War .
Government officials were not available to comment .
South Korea in 1993 unconditionally repatriated Li In-mo , a nothern partisan seized by the South during the war and jailed for more than three decades .
Chinese police hold veteran dissident .
BEIJING 1996-08-31
Chinese police have detained veteran dissident Wang Donghai , the New York-based pressure group Human Rights in China said on Saturday .
Police in Hangzhou , capital of the eastern province of Zhejiang , told Wang 's family that Wang would be sent to a study class , a euphemism for coercive ideological reform , the group said .
Police gave no reason for detaining Wang on Friday and would not let his family meet him or say where he was being held , the group said .
Police also would not say why Wang was being sent to a study class -- a holdover from the chaotic 1966-76 Cultural Revolution -- or say when he would be released , the group said .
Wang 's family and Hangzhou police could not be reached for immediate comment .
The group demanded Wang 's release and said his detention was a dangerous signal China was returning to its Cultural Revolution days .
Last month , Wang , 45 , a veteran dissident of the 1979 Democracy Wall movement , was ordered to serve one year of " re-education through labour " , but released because of poor health .
Re-education through labour is an administrative punishment with a maximum of three years that can be imposed by police without recourse to prosecutors or the courts .
Wang was jailed for two years for organising street protests after the military crushed pro-democracy demonstrations by students at Beijing 's Tiananmen Square on June 4 , 1989 , with heavy loss of life .
Chinese authorities appeared to be using administrative punishment more frequently to take dissidents out of circulation without having to go through a more complicated judicial process to impose criminal sentences , Western diplomats have said .
China police detains dissident Wang Donghai .
BEIJING 1996-08-31
Chinese police have detained dissident Wang Donghai , the New York-based pressure group Human Rights in China said on Saturday .
Police detained Wang on Friday and would not let his family meet him or say where he was being held , the group said .
The pressure group said Wang would be sent to a study class , often a euphemism in China for ideological reform .
Wang 's family could not immediately be reached for comment .
Last month , Wang , 45 , a veteran dissident of the 1979 Democracy Wall movement , was ordered to serve one year of " re-education through labour " , but released because of poor health .
Re-education through labour is an administrative punishment with a maximum of three years that can be imposed by police without recourse to prosecutors or the courts .
Wang was jailed for two years for organising street protests after the military brutally crushed pro-democracy demonstrations by students at Beijing 's Tiananmen Square on June 4 , 1989 , with heavy loss of life .
Hong Kong jails 88-year-old drug trafficker .
HONG KONG 1996-08-31
An 88-year-old army veteran was jailed for 15 years by a Hong Kong court for drugs trafficking after he admitted he had stashed heroin under his mattress , a newspaper said on Saturday .
" I am sorry to my ancestors for five generations , " Chen Chun-yeh told the High Court after sentencing on Friday , the Hong Kong Standard said . "
Tell my sons to collect my bones , " he said after hearing he was likely to die behind bars .
Chen , a former army secretary of the Chinese Nationalist regime which fled from mainland China to Taiwan in 1949 , pleaded guilty to trafficking 42 kg ( 92 pounds ) of drugs that could have been turned into 25 kg ( 55 pounds ) of heroin .
The ex-officer admitted stashing heroin under his mattress .
China cities to ban disposable plastic containers .
BEIJING 1996-08-31
Two Chinese cities are to ban the use of disposable plastic containers as part of efforts to fight pollution , the China Daily said on Saturday .
Authorities in Wuhan , capital of the central province of Hubei , would punish those who sell or use disposable plastic containers from September 1 , the newspaper said .
It did not elaborate .
The city 's industrial and commercial departments would confiscate disposable plastic containers and police would prevent new ones from entering the city , it said .
Wuhan consumes more than 200 million disposable plastic containers a year , the newspaper said .
The boomtown of Guangzhou , capital of the southern province of Guangdong , would ban disposable plastic containers by the end of 1996 , it said .
Guangzhou uses up 500,000 such containers each day , the newspaper said .
It gave no further details .
Iraqi Kurds say Iranian troops enter north Iraq .
ISTANBUL 1996-08-31
Iranian troops on Saturday entered Kurdish-controlled northern Iraq in the wake of an assault backed by Baghdad into the region , an Iraqi Kurdish group told Reuters .
" They entered this morning .
They have occupied the area to the depth of 40 km ( 25 miles ) .
They have established a headquarters in Chuman , " Faik Nerweyi of the Kurdistan Democratic Party ( KDP ) told Reuters by telephone from Ankara .
Nerweyi said he did not know the size or nature of the Iranian force in northern Iraq , but said KDP fighters had been easily outgunned in the area close to the Iranian border and had quickly withdrawn further west .
" They were far too strong , " he said .
Nerweyi said he did not know if there were any casualties .
A U.N. official in Baghdad said the KDP , backed by Iraqi tanks , heavy artillery and helicopters had taken control of the main northern Iraqi city of Arbil after fighting on Saturday .
U.S. President Bill Clinton has authorised the repositioning of U.S. firepower in the Gulf region in response to the Iraqi attacks .
The KDP charges that the rival Patriotic Union of Kurdistan , which took control of Arbil in fighting in December 1994 , has backing from Iran .
The PUK accuses the KDP of collaborating with Baghdad .
Northern Iraq has been under Iraqi Kurdish control since after the 1991 Gulf War .
U.S.-led allied planes based in Turkey are intended to protect the Kurds from Baghdad .
Ceasefire monitors to meet in south Lebanon .
JERUSALEM 1996-08-31
A committee monitoring the ceasefire agreement between Israel and Hizbollah guerrillas will meet in south Lebanon on Sunday to discuss an Israeli complaint against the Islamic group , the Israeli army said .
Representatives of the five nations making up the committee -- Israel , Lebanon , Syria , France and the United States -- will meet at 11 a.m. ( 0800 GMT ) in Naqoura , the coastal headquarters of the U.N. Interim Force in Lebanon ( UNIFIL ) .
" The committee will meet following a complaint by Israel over an incident in which two Lebanese residents were injured by Hizbollah fire in the Sikhin village ...
on August 29 , " an Israeli army spokeswoman said on Saturday .
The monitoring committee was set up to deal with violations of an April 25 ceasefire understanding that ended 17 days of fighting between Israel and the guerrillas .
The understandings forbid firing from or at civilian targest but do not rule out guerrilla attacks on Israeli troops and their local militia allies in south Lebanon .
Around 1,000 Israeli troops patrol a 15 km ( nine-mile ) south Lebanon occupation zone which the Jewish state carved out in 1985 to prevent attacks on its northern bordder .
Hizbollah ( Party of God ) gunmen have waged a guerrilla war to oust Israel from the area .
KPD confirms Iraqi military aid-U.N. official .
BAGHDAD 1996-08-31
Kurdistan Democratic Party ( KDP ) of Massoud Barzani said that it was being backed by Iraqi heavy armour and artillery in a battle with rival Kurds for the city of Arbil , a senior U.N. official in Baghdad said .
" They have confirmed to us that Iraqi troops are taking part in the attack on Arbil ...
We got the information from KDP leaders in KDP headquarters in Saladdin , " the official , who asked not to be identified , told Reuters .
Fire destroys restaurant in Bahraini village .
MANAMA 1996-08-31
A fire has completely gutted a Turkish-operated restaurant in a Bahraini village , residents said .
They said a fire broke out at Shul'ala restaurant in the early hours on Saturday in al-Daih village , five km ( three miles ) west of the capital Manama .
It was not immediately clear what caused the fire or if there were any casualties .
Government officials had no immediate comment .
Iraq 's Aziz says Baghdad aiding KDP against rivals .
BAGHDAD 1996-08-31
Iraq 's Deputy Prime Minister Tareq Aziz said on Saturday Iraqi troops were fighting in northern Iraq to aid Kurdish rebel leader Massoud Barzani against rival forces .
" The leadership has decided to provide support and military aid to Mr Massoud Barzani and his comrades to enable them confront the vicious aggression ...
from ( Patriotic Union of Kurdistan chief ) Jalal Talabani , " Aziz said in a statement carried by the official Iraqi News Agency ( INA ) .
Aziz said Iraq 's military intervention , the first on such scale since the U.S. and allies decided to protect Iraqi Kurds against Baghdad , was in response to a plea from Barzani to President Saddam Hussein to back him militarily and save his people from attacks by Iran and Talabani .
He said Barzani sent a message to Saddam on August 22 in which he said : " The conspiracy is beyond our capability therefore we plead with your excellency to order Iraqi armed forces to interfere to help us to evade the foreign threat and put an end to Talabani 's treason and conspiracy . "
U.N. relief officials said they were not aware that the tanks advancing on Arbil were manned by Iraqi troops as they advanced from KDP-controlled areas and raised KDP flags .
U.N. denies reports of Iraqi tank assault on Arbil .
BAGHDAD 1996-08-31
United Nations relief officials said on Saturday the fighting in Arbil in northern Iraq was between rival Kurdish factions and they were not aware of any Iraqi military advance on the city .
" KDP ( Kurdistan Democratic Party ) is trying to overtake the city .
They are using tanks .
I think they will succeed .
We have in no way seen any Iraqi troops in the city or in its approaches , " a U.N. relief official told Reuters .
PRESS DIGEST - Tunisia - Aug 31 .
TUNIS 1996-08-31
These are the leading stories in the Tunisian press on Saturday .
Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy .
LA PRESSE
- After Tunisia called on France to respect Tunisian immigrants ' dignity , France says it welcomes legal Tunisian residents .
- Tunisia 's exports of spare parts amounted to 220 million dinars in 1995 .
LE TEMPS
- Trade talks between Tunisia and the Palestinian Authority .
- Speaker of parliament Habib Boulares arrives in Tripoli to represent President Zine al-Abidine Ben Ali at the Libyan revolution anniversary celebrations .
( $ 1 = 0.96 dinar )
Automakers , U.S. agency plan air bag safety ads .
DETROIT 1996-08-31
Automakers , suppliers , insurers and the federal government 's auto safety agency Saturday launched a $ 10 million safety awareness campaign aimed at reducing the number of children killed accidentally by air bags in cars and trucks .
Officials said they will work with law enforcement agencies , pediatricians and media to warn parents about the dangers that air bags pose to children and adults not wearing seatbelts .
Since 1993 , 24 children have been killed by the explosive force of automotive air bags , which inflate at speeds up to 200 miles per hour .
The first portion of the campaign involves pickup trucks equipped with billboards that were driving along some of the nation 's busiest interstate highways during the Labor Day weekend , including Interstate 95 on the East Coast , Interstates 80 and 90 in the Midwest and Interstate 5 in California .
The boards read : " Air Bag Safety : Everyone Buckled , Kids in Back . "
Janet Dewey , executive director of the industry-funded National Automobile Occupant Protection Campaign , said most of the injuries to children occurred because they were not wearing seatbelts .
A child 's chances of being killed in a car accident , whether the vehicle was equipped with an air bag or not , is reduced by 29 percent when they are in the rear seat , she said .
The auto industry was about three to six years away from introducing " smart " air bags with the ability to detect the size and position of an occupant and adjust inflation pressures accordingly .
Current air bags were designed to halt the forward momentum of an average-sized , unbelted adult male , not a small child .
Automakers petitioned the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to allow them to introduce air bags that inflate less aggressively to help reduce unwanted injuries .
" Even if changes are made to airbags today , we 'd still have 20 million vehicles on the road with current technology , " Dewey said . "
The public has n't been getting the message . "
Two die as New Hampshire motel explodes and burns .
ROCHESTER , N.H. 1996-08-30
Adds deaths , other details )
An explosion leveled Rochester 's one-story Lilac Falls Motel , killing two people , fire officials said Friday .
" It was an explosion , and then it got involved in fire .
As far as I know , it 's been to four alarms -- more trucks , more people , " said Don Penney of the Rochester Fire Department said .
Eyewitnesses told Boston television stations they saw a gasoline truck parked behind the Lilac Falls Motel and smelled gasoline shortly before the explosion .
Fire department officials said they were investigating the cause of the blast and searching for any more casualties .
Officials did not immediately identify the victims .
Local hospital officials said a few firemen were treated for smoke inhalation but there were no other injuries .
Car kills two trying to avoid Texas drag race .
DALLAS 1996-08-31
An illegal drag race on a Dallas street turned deadly when another vehicle veered into the crowd , killing two people and injuring a dozen more , police said Saturday .
Organisers tried to block off traffic while preparing the drag race late on Friday , but an allegedly drunk driver was unable to slow down in time and ran into a group of spectators as he swerved to avoid one of the cars that was to take part in the race .
A 26-year-old man and an 18-year-old woman were killed .
The driver , aged 51 , was arrested and charged on two counts of intoxicated manslaughter .
A police spokesman said the straight , flat stretch of road was often used illegally as a drag strip by Dallas youths .
U.S. warplanes , ships in Gulf await Clinton order .
Jim Adams
WASHINGTON 1996-08-31
More than 300 U.S. warplanes and 20 ships were available on Saturday in case President Bill Clinton ordered the use of U.S. force against Iraqi military action in northern Iraq , U.S. defense officials said .
They said 200 fighter planes , including 79 on the aircraft carrier Carl Vinson , were already in the Gulf ; the aircraft carrier Enterprise was in the eastern Mediterranean with 79 more , and an air expeditionary force with up to 40 more was ready to fly from the United States if ordered .
" Yesterday the president ordered the Department of Defense to take prudent planning steps to have forces ready to deploy to the region should he direct us to do so , " Pentagon spokesman Doug Kennett said . "
We have taken those prudent planning steps . "
Clinton said on Saturday he had ordered U.S. forces in the Gulf to go on high alert and was reinforcing them in response to Iraqi attacks on Kurdish dissidents in northern Iraq .
" These developments ... cause me grave concern , " Clinton said at a campaign stop in Troy , Tennessee .
But he added , " It is premature at this time , and I want to emphasize that , highly premature to speculate on any response we might have . "
The U.S. defense officials said military flights to enforce no-fly zones in both northern and southern Iraq doubled over the weekend .
Clinton said Iraqi military forces overran the city of Arbil , which has been held since 1994 by Kurdish rebels who Baghdad says are backed by Iran .
There were unconfirmed reports that Iran had sent troops into northern Iraq in response to Iraq 's attack .
U.S. plans rely heavily on U.S. air attacks on Iraqi forces , but there are also 23,000 U.S. troops in the region , according to defense officials .
In addition to the 158 F / A-18 , F-14 and other fighter planes on the aircraft carriers Vinson and Enterprise , the Air Force air expeditionary force of 30 to 40 F-15 and F-16 fighter planes and fuel tankers is ready to fly from three U.S. bases in the United States , they said .
The expeditionary force would include nearly 1,000 Air Force personnel in ground and support crews , they said .
The 23,000 U.S. military people already in the Gulf consist of 15,000 sailors and Marines , 6,000 U.S. servicemen based primarily in Saudi Arabia and 2,000 U.S. troops in the area for military exercises .
Most of the Marines are on three ships in the Tarawa Amphibious Readiness Group .
The Carl Vinson leads a battle group that includes seven other ships , and there are nine other U.S. ships in the Gulf for a total of 20 .
Two missing Belgian teenagers found unharmed .
BRUSSELS 1996-08-31
Two Belgian teenage girls missing since Thursday have been found unharmed , police said on Saturday .
" The girls , Rachel and Severine , have been found .
They are unharmed , " a police official in Liege said .
He declined to say whether the girls had been kidnapped or whether they had gone away of their own accord .
Late on Friday , the two girls -- Rachel Legeard , 18 , and Severine Potty , 19 -- were reported missing after failing to return home from a shopping trip to the eastern town of Liege on Thursday .
Earlier , police declined to comment on whether it suspected a link with the Marc Dutroux case , the paedophile kidnap , sex abuse and murder scandal which has rocked Belgium in the past two weeks .
Algeria restaurant bomb kills seven - newSpaper .
PARIS 1996-08-31
A bomb explosion in a restaurant west of Algiers on Friday killed seven people , an Algerian newspaper said on Saturday .
Algerian security forces said in a statement that two people were killed and six were wounded when a home-made bomb ripped through a restaurant in the coastal town of Staoueli .
But Le Matin newspaper , quoting witnesses , said the bomb killed seven people and wounded 20 .
Liberte newspaper said the bomb was hidden in a bag in front of the restaurant and that a booby-trapped car was defused near the restaurant shortly before the bomb went off .
A week ago a home-made bomb exploded in a market in the western coastal town of Bou Haroun , 65 km ( 40 miles ) from Algiers .
Newspapers said it killed two women and five children .
Algerian newspapers quoted the Human Rights National Observatory ( ONDH ) , a government-appointed watchdog , as saying earlier in August that about 1,400 civilians had been killed in bomb attacks blamed on Moslem guerrillas in the past two years .
An estimated 50,000 people have died in Algeria 's violence pitting Moslem rebels against government forces since early 1992 when the authorities cancelled a general election in which radical Islamists had taken a commanding lead .
Iran agents stormed German diplomat 's home -- Bonn .
BONN 1996-08-31
Iranian security forces burst into the home of a German cultural attache in Tehran a month ago and seized his guests for questioning , Bonn 's foreign ministry said on Saturday .
A spokesman said he could substantially confirm a report in the news weekly Der Spiegel , which said Iranian secret police burst in while attache Jens Gust was entertaining six Iranian writers and their wives .
Gust was threatened with violence , then locked into a room to be interrogated on suspicion of " promoting activities hostile to the state " while his guests were taken away , the magazine said .
The ministry spokesman said the German embassy immediately made a sharp protest to the Tehran government .
The Iranian ambassador was also summoned to the ministry in Bonn to hear a sharp protest and " disapproval of this glaring breach of the principles of international law " , he added .
Iran subsequently said it regretted the incident , which it said had been the result of a misunderstanding .
All those detained appeared to have been freed , the spokesman said .
Relations between the two countries are currently under strain because of the testimony in a Berlin court of former Iranian president Abolhassan Banisadr .
Banisadr , an avowed opponent of the Tehran government who now lives in exile , accused top Iranian leaders of personally ordering the assassination of three exiled Kurdish leaders in a Berlin restaurant in 1992 .
Iran has asked Germany to extradite Banisadr , who is due is due back in Berlin next Thursday to continue his testimony .
Banisadr , who received political asylum in France after fleeing there in 1981 , told Der Spiegel he did not plan to ask for a guarantee of safe conduct .
If Germany were to extradite him , he said , it would " lose face before the whole world " .
German prosecutors have already accused Iran 's intelligence minister Ali Fallahiyan of ordering the killing of the Kurdish leaders .
Iran , which denies the allegations , urged German authorities to disregard Banisadr 's testimony and said it could hurt relations .
Italy 's Dini meets Burundi negotiator Nyerere .
ROME 1996-08-31
Italian Foreign Minister Lamberto Dini on Saturday met former Tanzanian president Julius Nyerere , the international negotiator for Burundi , the ministry said .
Nyerere arrived in Rome this week on a private visit and held talks with the U.S. special envoy to Burundi , Howard Wolpe , and the Sant ' Egidio Community , an Italian Roman Catholic organisation which has been monitoring Burundi closely .
" ( Nyerere ) informed Minister Dini of the latest developments in the ( Great Lakes ) region , with particular respect to Burundi following the military coup d'etat on July 25 , " the ministry said in a statement .
It gave no details of their talks .
Nyerere was due to be presented with an " Artisans for Peace " prize by the Lay Volunteers ' International Organisation on Sunday .
He leaves Rome on Monday .
The U.N. Security Council on Friday condemned the coup by retired Tutsi major Pierre Buyoya and for the first time said in a resolution it intended to pressure Buyoya into unconditional negotiations with all parties and factions " without exception " .
Buyoya on Saturday dismissed its threat of an arms embargo against Burundi and flatly ruled out talks with Hutu rebels .
Some 150,000 people -- mostly civilians -- have died in Burundi since 1993 when the country 's first democratically elected Hutu president was killed in an attempted army coup .
Nato declines comment on fighting in Iraq .
BRUSSELS 1996-08-31
The North Atlantic Treaty Organisation 's spokesman on Saturday declined all comment on reports of armed conflict in northern Iraq .
But a NATO official told Reuters : " We are watching the situation closely . "
Earlier on Saturday , an Iraqi Kurd leader said both Iraqi troops and Kurdistan Democratic Party ( KDP ) forces were attacking the city of Arbil in northern Iraq .
More automatic weapons stolen in Belgium .
BRUSSELS 1996-08-31
More than 10 weapons , including automatic Kalashnikov rifles , were stolen from an arms store in Belgium , police said on Saturday .
A policeman in the southern Belgian town of Chatelet told Reuters that thieves used a car to ram the window of an arms store in neighbouring Chatelineaux last night .
It was the second arms robbery this week .
On Tuesday , thieves stole about 40 forearms from a shooting range in southern Belgium , including Kalashnikov , Uzi and Fal automatic weapons .
No trace of two missing teenagers in Belgium .
BRUSSELS 1996-08-31
Belgian police said on Saturday they had found no trace of two teenage girls reported missing during a shopping trip three days ago .
" There is no trace so far , the enquiry is continuing , " a Liege police official told Reuters .
Late on Friday , Liege police said in a statement that on Thursday , Rachel Legeard , 18 , and Severine Potty , 19 , had gone shopping to the eastern town of Liege on Thursday , where Legeard 's wallet had been stolen .
After reporting the theft to the police , they took a bus home and reportedly got off the bus before arriving in their home village of Nandrin .
They have not been seen since .
Police declined to comment on whether it suspected a link with the Marc Dutroux case , the paedophile kidnap , sex abuse and murder scandal which has rocked Belgium in the past two weeks .
Controversial IRA film screened at Venice festival .
Vera Haller
VENICE , Italy 1996-08-31
Dublin-born director Neil Jordan says he never lost more sleep over a film than over " Michael Collins " , his controversial epic about the IRA which has its premiere on Saturday at the Venice Film Festival .
The film , starring Liam Neeson and Julia Roberts , recounts the life of Michael Collins , the Irish Republican Army 's Director of Intelligence who fought for Irish independence from 1919 to 1921 .
Although not due for release in Britain until early next year , some politicians have already said they feared it would fan sectarian tensions in British-ruled Northern Ireland .
Jordan defends his decision to make the film , whose screenplay he wrote himself after years of research , saying it was " more about history than any political statement " .
" The film spares neither the Irish nor the British in its depiction of the savagery of the time , " Jordan said in a statement released by Warner Bros . "
How often has independence been achieved without bloodshed ?
Very rarely . "
Jordan , whose 1992 film " The Crying Game " also came under fire for what was perceived as a sympathetic portrayal of the IRA , said Collins was more than just a revolutionary .
" He developed techniques of guerilla warfare later copied by independence movements around the world , from Mao Tse-Tung in China to Yitzak Shamir in Israel , " Jordan said .
" Collins would never be a proponent of contemporary terrorism as practised today .
He was a soldier and a statesman and , over time , a man of peace . "
Leeson , the Northern Ireland-born actor who was nominated for an Oscar for best actor for his performance in " Schindler 's List " , plays the lead role in Jordan 's film .
Aidan Quinn portrays Harry Boland , Collins ' best friend , and rival for the love of Kitty Kiernan , played by Roberts .
Much of the film was shot on location in Dublin with Jordan using thousands of its citizens as unpaid extras .
A set , however , was used for the fighting scenes .
Noting that information about Collins was " as mysterious as the existence he maintained " , Jordan said he made some historical assumptions in the film .
" I have made choices about certain events based on my own extensive research into his letters and reported speeches , " he said . "
I wanted to make this a story as accurate as possible without killing it dramatically and I think I have .
It is a very true film . "
One of the assumptions is his interpretation of the murky circumstances surrounding the shooting death of Collins , who had broken with his comrades when he sought a negotiated settlement with Britain , in an ambush in 1922 .
" I have never lost more sleep over the making of a film than I have over ' Michael Collins ' , but I 'll never make a more important one , " Jordan said .
" In the life of one person you can tell the events that formed the north and south of Ireland as they are today . "
Dhaka stocks seen steady in absence of big players .
DHAKA 1996-08-31
Shares on the Dhaka Stock Exchange ( DSE ) may remain steady as small investors are expected to target mainly blue chips while overseas investors will prefer to keep to the sidelines when the market reopens after Moslem Friday weekend , brokers said .
" The market is expected to remain steady .
There will be both buying and selling pressure , " said broker Shakil Rizvi .
Broker Khurshid Alam said : " The market sentiment will remain strong .
But the prices may move in a close range following a continued market uptrend . "
Brokers said blue chips like IDLC , Bangladesh Lamps , Chittagong Cement and Atlas Bangladesh were expected to rise .
They said there was still demand for blue chips in engineering sector despite their persistent rise over the past several sessions .
The DSE all share price index closed 2.73 points or 0.22 percent up at 1,196.35 on a turnover of 133.7 million taka on Thursday .
-- Dhaka Newsroom 880-2-506363